<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par15">Crystallization of the amorphous alloy ribbons was investigated using time-resolved synchrotron-based HEXRD (71.77 keV energy, 0.1729 Å wavelength), utilizing the 1-ID-E beamline of the Advanced Photon Source (APS) at Argonne National Laboratory. Specimens for HEXRD were prepared by cutting melt-spun ribbon into lengths of approximately 10 mm, stacking multiple segments to a thickness of ~0.5 mm, and inserting into a 2 mm ID thin walled SiO
 <sub>2</sub> capillary tube which was sealed under argon. An infrared heater was used for 
 <italic>in-situ</italic> heating and isothermal holding. HEXRD pattern revealed that the 
 <italic>ε</italic>-Al
 <sub>60</sub>Sm
 <sub>11</sub> phase and a small amount of fcc-Al were the first phases to appear during devitrification. There were several minor XRD peaks that cannot be indexed, as marked by diamonds in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(a)</xref>, suggesting a small fraction of an unknown phase mixed with the 
 <italic>ε</italic>-Al
 <sub>60</sub>Sm
 <sub>11</sub> phase and fcc-Al. With an isothermal hold at 464 K (about 5 K lower than the onset temperature for crystallization) for 70 mins, the unknown phase grew as indicated in the enhanced peaks in XRD as shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(b)</xref>. Post-devitrification samples were analyzed using TEM (Tecnai G
 <sup>2</sup> F20). TEM specimens were prepared using a dual-beam focused ion beam (FIB) instrument (FEI Helios NanoLab G3 UC). BF-TEM, HAADF-STEM images and SAD pattern (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(a–d)</xref>) were obtained to analyze the post-devitrification samples. The BF-TEM image shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(a)</xref> and the HAADF-STEM image in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(b)</xref> clearly demonstrated a fully crystallized polyphase material. The nanocrystals uniformly distributed in the matrix with grain size of ~20–30 
 <italic>nm</italic> in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(a)</xref> were fcc
 <italic>-</italic>Al, which corresponded to the dark region (low 
 <italic>z</italic>-contrast) in HAADF-STEM image of Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2(b)</xref>.
</p>
