<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In our previous works, the antioxidant activity and mimetic were evaluated for a series of binuclear Cu
 <sup>2+</sup> and Fe
 <sup>3+</sup> complexes with cyclophanes derived from EDTA and aromatic diamines, and all the complexes were found to be capable of inhibiting ABTS (2,2′-azino-bis(3-ethylbenzothiazoline-6-sulfonate) disodium salt) free radicals with high activity comparable to that of ascorbic acid [
 <xref rid="B5-molecules-24-03556" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-molecules-24-03556" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. The chelating EDTA moiety in the cyclophanes permits the metal complexation with sufficient stability to avoid the pro-oxidant effects caused by metal ions in their free state, and the activity is expected to be enhanced by the binuclear metal center surrounded by three types of donor sites: carboxylate, amino, and amide groups. In line with these results and with the objective of studying the effects of the metal centers, the present work examined the antioxidant capacity of the mononuclear Cu
 <sup>2+</sup>, Fe
 <sup>3+</sup>, and Mn
 <sup>2+</sup> chelates that had identical coordination geometries. The selected ligand was a 14 membered aliphatic macrocycle (abbreviated as H
 <sub>2</sub>L14) shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-24-03556-f001">Figure 1</xref>. The framework of this macrocycle is moderately flexible so that the Ni
 <sup>2+</sup> complex forms a [NiL14·H
 <sub>2</sub>O] molecule with well-defined octahedral coordination in the X-ray structure (
 <xref ref-type="app" rid="app1-molecules-24-03556">Figure S1 in the Supplementary Materials</xref>); the same type of geometry is maintained for Cu
 <sup>2+</sup> as well as Ni
 <sup>2+</sup> in solution [
 <xref rid="B7-molecules-24-03556" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. The antioxidant activities of the metal complexes are therefore expected to be controlled by the nature of the central metal ions. This paper reports the characterization of the three metal complexes in relation to their antioxidant activities.
</p>
