<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>
 </xref>a shows the crystal structure of V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub>, which is a periodic array of unit V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> SCACs. Bulk V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> crystals were prepared via the flux method using excess molten selenium as a solvent. When the V–Se liquid at 330 °C was cooled to room temperature, dark grey needles precipitated. 
 <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>
 </xref>b shows a scanning electron microscopy (SEM) image of the V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> needles prepared in this study. To demonstrate the characteristics of the chain-stacked structure of the V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub>, the bulk V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> crystal was cleaved using a conventional peeling method.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref>
 </sup>
 <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>
 </xref>c shows the AFM images of V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> chains exfoliated from bulk V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> crystals. The exfoliated chains had thicknesses of 1.1, 6.9, and 7.5 nm, indicating that single chains (1.1 nm) or bundles (6.9 and 7.5 nm) could be generated by mechanical exfoliation (
 <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>
 </xref>d). This result shows that weak vdW interactions among the chains in the bulk crystal results in V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> crystals cleaved to V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> chains, as in typical 2D materials.The bulk structure of V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> has a monoclinic symmetry (
 <italic>C</italic>2/
 <italic>c</italic>). The unit of V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub> chain structures consists of four vanadium and 18 selenium ions, as in Nb
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>9</sub>. A V
 <sub>4</sub>Se
 <sub>18</sub> chain structure is composed of two V
 <sub>2</sub>Se
 <sub>4</sub> octahedrons connected by Se
 <sub>5</sub>; each octahedron faces the other octahedron (
 <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>
 </xref>a).
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref40">40</xref>
 </sup> The relative coordinates of ions in the reference direct the chains to [1 0 1]. We rotated the lattice vectors to a set of ([1 0 1], [0 1 0], and [1 0 1̅]). Then, 1D structures consisting of the number of finite chains could be constructed by repeating 
 <italic>k</italic>-points into the 
 <italic>x</italic>-axis in computational chemistry software. This rotated unit cell has three whole chain units and two half-chain units (
 <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>
 </xref>b,c). To validate the rotated frame, we calculated the band structures for the original and rotated lattice vector choices and compared the band gaps (see 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.9b02655/suppl_file/ao9b02655_si_001.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Figure S9</ext-link>).
</p>
