<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The Y
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>5−x</sub>Ga
 <sub>x</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub> nanocrystals doped with 0.1% concentration of V ions were synthesized via a modified Pechini method, where the Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> amount was set to x = 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5. The amount of V ions was set to 0.1% due to the fact that this V concentration provides the most significant temperature sensing properties of YAG:V, Ln
 <sup>3+</sup> luminescent nanothermometers [
 <xref rid="B23-nanomaterials-09-01375" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]. The first step was the creation of yttrium nitrate from yttrium oxide (Y
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub>, 99.995% purity from Stanford Materials Corporation, Lake Forest, CA, USA) using the recrystallization process, including the dissolution in distillated water and ultrapure nitric acid (65%). All nitrates, namely appropriate amounts of Ga(NO
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub>·9H
 <sub>2</sub>O (Puratronic 99.999% purity from Alfa Aesar, Kandel, GERMANY), Al(NO
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub>·9H
 <sub>2</sub>O (Puratronic 99.999% purity from Alfa Aesar, Kandel, GERMANY) and Y(NO
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub> were dissolved in water and mixed together. After that, NH
 <sub>4</sub>VO
 <sub>3</sub> (99% purity from Alfa Aesar, Kandel, GERMANY) were added to the solution. To enable the dissolution of ammonium metavanadate and the complexation of each metal, calculated quantity of citric acid (CA, C
 <sub>6</sub>H
 <sub>8</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> with 99.5+% purity from Alfa Aesar, Kandel, GERMANY), used in six-fold excess in respect to the total amount of metal ions, was mixed with all reagents and heated up to 90 °C for 1 h. Next, PEG-200 (poly(ethylene glycol), from Alfa Aesar, Kandel, GERMANY) was added dropwise to the CA-metal complex and stirred for 2 h at 90 °C (CA: PEG-200 was 1:1) to conduct the polyestrification reaction. Then, the resin was obtained by heating at 90 °C for 1 week. In turn, the nanopowders were received via annealing of resin at 1100 °C for 16 h in air atmosphere. 
</p>
