<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Becker and Leineweber [
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>] have recently reported that the η″ phase possesses 
 <italic>incommensurately</italic> modulated structures using powder X-ray diffraction. The approximant structures
 <xref rid="EN0003">
  <sup>3</sup>
 </xref> they derived for the Al-29.3 and 29.4 at.%Fe alloys without taking the structural incommensurability into account are shown in 
 <xref rid="F0008">Figure 8(c</xref>). These approximant structures are similar to the commensurate long-period structures determined in the present study in at least two aspects. First, the approximant/superlattice structures are based on the stacking of the parent orthorhombic unit cell of the η phase along the orthorhombic 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis (the two structural models of 
 <xref rid="F0008">Figure 8(c</xref>) can be expressed with M = 13 and 21). Second, the twin domains are stacked along the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis, with the diagonal glide planes at 
 <italic>z</italic> = 1/4 and 3/4 being the twin boundaries. The key difference between the models of Becker and Leineweber [
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>] and ours (
 <xref rid="F0008">Figure 8(c</xref>) vs. 
 <xref rid="F0008">8(a</xref>)) is thus in how the Al/Fe atoms occupy the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites. The average distances of atoms located in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain in these approximant structures (0.29 ± 0.02 and 0.29 ± 0.05 nm respectively for M = 13 and 21) are almost identical to that (0.29 ± 0.01 nm) in the commensurate long-period structure with M = 19 refined by SXRD in the present study (
 <xref rid="F0006">Figure 6(a</xref>)). This indicates that the atom packing density in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain in these two structural models does not significantly differ from each other. However, their atomic arrangements along the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites are quite dissimilar. In our model, almost every fourth of the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites is ‘regularly’ occupied with the sequence of …Al2/Al3/Al3/Al2/Al3/Al3… (except for the twin-boundary regions), so that the motif structure is defined within twin domains for our commensurate structures (
 <xref rid="F0006">Figure 6(a</xref>) and 
 <xref rid="F0008">8(a</xref>)). However, such regularity in the occupied-site sequence is lost in the approximant structures deduced by Becker and Leineweber [
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>]. This is evident from the fact that the atomic distance in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain in their approximant structures ranges widely, from 0.256 to 0.323 nm for M = 13 and from 0.217 to 0.354 nm for M = 21 (
 <xref rid="F0008">Figure 8(c</xref>) and 
 <xref rid="T0003">Table 3</xref>). Clearly, the atomic arrangement within each of twin regions varies significantly depending on the M value, so that no motif structure can be defined in the approximant structures deduced by Becker and Leineweber [
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>]. We speculate that the contradiction between these two studies comes from the difference in the analyzed sample size. Becker and Leineweber [
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>] may have deduced the incommensurately modulated structures because their powder sample included various crystallites with different M values. This is evidenced by the significant broadening of superlattice diffraction spots, which they had noticed [
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>]. On the contrary, our STEM and SXRD experiments were performed on a very limited volume (~100 nm
 <sup>3</sup> for STEM and ~0.005 mm
 <sup>3</sup> for SXRD) compared to that of conventional powder X-ray diffraction (usually ~10 mm
 <sup>3</sup>). As a result, in both our STEM and SXRD analyses, the structure was homogeneous throughout the small volume of specimen, and as a result no broadening of superlattice diffraction spots was noticed (
 <xref rid="S0003-S2003-S3002">Section 3.3.2</xref>).
</p>
