<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>TiO
 <sub>2</sub> and YSZ (Yttria Stabilized Zirconia; Y
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub>-ZrO
 <sub>2</sub>) were investigated as high refractive index nanoparticle materials for scattering layer. The refractive index of TiO
 <sub>2</sub> nanoparticles is 2.5 and that of YSZ is 2.13, respectively. Both TiO
 <sub>2</sub> and YSZ nanoparticles are suitable for high refractive index materials compared to that of glass substrate. The size of the TiO
 <sub>2</sub> nanoparticle was 250–300 nm, while the size of the YSZ nanoparticle was 100–150 nm. The nanoparticles were dispersed in propylene glycol methyl ether acetate (PGMA) solvent for applying to the slit coating method, which is used in the conventional display manufacturing process for large areas. The nanoparticle suspension was coated on the glass substrate, forming the high refractive index scattering layer, followed by a thermal curing process at 300–500 °C in a furnace for 30 min. The curing temperature can be controlled according to the state of the coating layer, without any deformation. A SiO
 <sub>2</sub> solution, which was normally used at spin-on glass (SOG), was used as a planarization material, which was coated on the nanoparticle scattering layer. The refractive index of the SiO
 <sub>2</sub> planarization layer was 1.45, which was similar to that of the glass substrate. The planarization layer was formed on the scattering layer with the same method as the scattering layer. It was cured at 500 °C in a furnace for 30 min. The planarization layer had a flat surface covering the roughness of the scattering layer caused by the distribution of nanoparticles. Therefore, subsequent manufacturing process can be performed easily, like on the glass substrate surface. Next, the conventional low temperature poly silicon (LTPS) thin film transistor (TFT) manufacturing process was performed on the planarization layer. In the LTPS TFT manufacturing process, the thermal annealing process is required at the highest temperature, approaching 580 °C, which can cause deformation of the nanoparticle scattering layer and the planarization layer. The proposed materials should endure the high temperature during LTPS TFT manufacturing process without any deformation.
</p>
