<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Near-infrared (NIR) light source has attracted attention for applications in medical fields, bio-sensing, food processing industry, and night-vision technologies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup>. Traditional NIR light sources, such as halogen lamps and tungsten-halogen lamps, suffer from large sizes, low efficiency, short lifetime, and heat dissipation
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. As an emerging field, researchers have made considerable efforts to explore new NIR emitters, such as InAs-ZnSe polymer nanocrystal, CH
 <sub>3</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>PbI
 <sub>3–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>Cl
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> organometal halide perovskite, PbS@MAPbX
 <sub>3</sub> (X = I, Br) quantum dots, and Pt(II) complex based organic light-emitting diodes (LED)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>. However, the low efficiency, poor stability or complex fabrication technique restrict their development. As a contrast, the high luminous efficiency, long operating life, and compact sizes make NIR LEDs useful, however, a narrow full-width at half maximum (FWHM) below 50 nm seriously limit their applications in 3D sensing, food analyzing, and other specific fields
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>. Therefore, discovery of broadband-emitting NIR light sources is a necessary and urgent requirement. In this regard, phosphor-converted light-emitting diodes LEDs (pc-LEDs) have attracted increasing interests considering more opportunities for tunable emission during the phosphors’ screening, and availability of simpler strategies for both materials design and fabrication of NIR pc-LEDs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. Furthermore, the low cost of NIR phosphors is beneficial. However, one of the most significant challenges is the discovery of blue light pumped and efficient broadband NIR-emitting phosphors.
</p>
