<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">Numerous studies on exploring NIR phosphors have been realized by doping transition metal ions (Cr
 <sup>3+</sup>, Ni
 <sup>2+</sup>, and Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>), Bi
 <sup>3+</sup> or rare earth ions (Pr
 <sup>3+</sup>, Nd
 <sup>3+</sup>, Tm
 <sup>3+</sup>, and Yb
 <sup>3+</sup>) into inorganic host materials
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. However, the sharp line emission of rare earth ions with 4
 <italic>f</italic>-4
 <italic>f</italic> transition is not broad enough for the desired applications, and the absorption region is also very narrow and weak. The Ni
 <sup>2+</sup> doped materials show broad emission band around NIR region, but the low efficiency and IR laser excitation suspends the application
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. Recently, Cr
 <sup>3+</sup> ion has been considered as an ideal NIR luminescent center, which can exhibit broad-band emission ~650–1200 nm with 
 <sup>4</sup>T
 <sub>2</sub> → 
 <sup>4</sup>A
 <sub>2</sub> transition
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>. However, mixed valence of Cr
 <sup>6+</sup> ions simultaneously exist in most Cr
 <sup>3+</sup> doped phosphors, which seriously quench NIR luminescent efficiency
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>. As one of important rare earth activators with 4
 <italic>f</italic>-5
 <italic>d</italic> transition, Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>-activated phosphors normally possess high efficiency and have been applied in the field of commercial white LEDs. More importantly, the tunable emission in the visible range is very popular to discover useful phosphors, and the typical examples include Sr[LiAl
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>]:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (red), 
 <italic>β</italic>-SiAlON:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (green) and BaMgAl
 <sub>10</sub>O
 <sub>17</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (blue)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>
 </sup>. If Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>-doped phosphors can realize NIR emissions, it would launch a new era in NIR light source. However, in addition to the recent report on Ca
 <sub>3</sub>Sc
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>, no other Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>-doped phosphors can achieve NIR emissions with the peak beyond 700 nm
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. Unfortunately, though Ca
 <sub>3</sub>Sc
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> gives a broad-band emission ranging from 720 to 1100 nm, it cannot be pumped by blue LEDs due to the lack of blue light absorption of the sample
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. Therefore, discovery of Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> activated NIR phosphors for blue light-pumped LEDs is an essential and difficult task for the emerging photonic, optoelectronic and biological applications.
</p>
