<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Vibrational spectroscopy stands out as a non-invasive, widely applicable, low-cost, and quick time-to-result analytical method. Therefore, it combines advantages that are highly valued in analytical chemistry. Despite being grouped together, the key differences among these three kinds of techniques should be noted. IR (4000–400 cm
 <sup>−1</sup>) spectroscopy elucidates chemical information from the fundamental vibrational transitions. In contrast, the signal that was measured in NIR (10,000–4000 cm
 <sup>−1</sup>) spectroscopy originates from the excitations of higher quanta transitions, mostly first overtones and binary combinations [
 <xref rid="B16-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B18-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. Raman spectroscopy also provides information regarding fundamental vibrations, but through a distinctly different working principle than IR spectroscopy. The differences in the wavelength regions and underlying physical background translate into distinct differences in the instrumentation and applicability of these methods. Each of these techniques offer unique advantages, but for the detection/quantification of melamine content in milk, NIR spectroscopy may be favored [
 <xref rid="B9-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. A number of factors contribute to this fact [
 <xref rid="B19-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. Higher sample volume resulting from low NIR absorptivity of matter in general, and water, in particular, allows for more straightforward measurement of transmittance or reflectance of the milk sample. The same may be achieved with ATR-IR (Attenuated Total Reflection IR) approach; however, the fiber probe compatibility of NIR instrumentation gives it superior flexibility in high-volume analysis. NIR spectroscopy also benefits from the largest tolerance for the sample inhomogeneity. Raman spectroscopy is suitable for the measurement of aqueous samples, but for similar analytical applications Raman instrumentation is often more expensive. Finally, in NIR spectroscopy, a strongly stimulated development for miniaturization [
 <xref rid="B20-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>] has culminated in highly affordable micro-spectrometers, which are available under 300 USD nowadays [
 <xref rid="B22-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. In a strict application to melamine detection/quantitation, all three techniques have been successfully used in the literature 9]. However, NIR spectroscopy demonstrates the best analytical performance in this case [
 <xref rid="B9-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>], on top of its practical advantages [
 <xref rid="B23-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-molecules-24-01402" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>].
</p>
