<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Clearly, many experimental efforts can be saved for preparing the desired 2D materials by vapor deposition of the atoms if the suitable surface of a substrate and the optimum temperature can be precisely predicted. The predictions might be made in principle by calculations of the free energy, but the calculation for condensed matter has been an open problem since statistical physics was born at the end of 19th Century. In the past 30 years, substantial progress has been made in the calculations of the partition function (PF) for condensed matter, from which the free energies, as well as other thermodynamic state functions can be obtained. Among the advanced methods including parallel tempering [
 <xref rid="B28-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>], umbrella sampling [
 <xref rid="B29-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>], metadynamics [
 <xref rid="B30-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>], Wang–Landau sampling [
 <xref rid="B31-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>], and nested sampling [
 <xref rid="B32-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>], an algorithm of nested sampling (ANS) developed by Do et al [
 <xref rid="B33-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>] may be the state-of-the-art and is able to compute PF for a condensed system composed of hundreds of atoms if empirical pairwise potentials are applied for the interaction of atoms. In ANS, all the atoms in the system are moved artificially in real space so as to generate enough configurations, usually on the order of 10
 <sup>8</sup> for a system of hundreds of atoms, with the total potential energy of each configuration being calculated, which will cost too many computer hours if the interactions between atoms are described by quantum mechanics or by an empirical many-body potential, such as the Brenner function [
 <xref rid="B34-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>] for carbon atoms of graphene, instead of a pairwise force field. Moreover, when the algorithm is applied to calculate the PF of a given 2D material, such as a graphene sheet with a perfect hexagons structure, artificially moving the C atoms in real space may produce structures approaching those of graphyne or others, so the final obtained PF may not be related uniquely to the graphene sheet. Obviously, artificial constraints must be applied in ANS to move the atoms so that the generated molecular configurations are closely related to the structure of the given 2D materials, which will result in large uncertainties of the PF. In such a case, the difference of the free energy derived from the PF between two different 2D structures will depend too much on the artificial constraints, leading to the failure of the free energy criteria to judge which 2D structure would be more favorable.
</p>
