<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the present work, a direct integral approach (DIA) [
 <xref rid="B35-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>] was developed to calculate the PF (or free energy) of 2D materials and was demonstrated by graphene and γ-graphyne on a Cu substrate, as well as silicene on a silver substrate. In order to test the accuracy of the approach, the empirical many-body interaction function, Brenner potential [
 <xref rid="B34-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>], and Tersoff potential [
 <xref rid="B36-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>] were employed to calculate the PF of graphene (or γ-graphyne) and silicene, respectively, and the same potential was used in MD simulations to produce internal energy to be compared with the one derived from the PF. The high efficiency of DIA enables us to obtain the PF of the systems of 510 carbon atoms (or 336 Si atoms) in about one hour on a desktop computer, and the relative error between the derived internal energies and the ones of the MD simulations for the system at temperatures from 100–1300 K are smaller than 0.03%, which is far beyond the precision (~10%) usually achieved by ANS [
 <xref rid="B37-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>]. Certainly, the calculation precision of free energy cannot be determined directly because MD simulations can hardly produce free energy [
 <xref rid="B38-nanomaterials-09-00978" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>]. The calculations with DIA show that the free energy of graphene is always smaller than that of γ-graphyne in the temperature range from 100–3000 K, which is in agreement with the experimental fact that the growth of graphene under such conditions is much easier than that of γ-graphyne. Furthermore, DIA was applied to search for the optimum conditions for silicene growth on a Ag substrate based on density functional theory (DFT), and the results were in good agreement with previous experimental observations.
</p>
