<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Aluminium and Sn improve the oxidation of Nb-silicide based alloys [
 <xref rid="B4-materials-12-03217" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-materials-12-03217" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Individually, both elements affect the βNb
 <sub>5</sub>Si
 <sub>3</sub> → αNb
 <sub>5</sub>Si
 <sub>3</sub> transformation and destabilise the tetragonal (stable) Nb
 <sub>3</sub>Si [
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-03217" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-03217" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-materials-12-03217" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>], and in synergy affect the volume fraction of the Nb
 <sub>ss</sub>, which can increase or descrease depending on other alloying additions. In general, the concentrations of Al and Sn are restricted to low values (≤5%) because of the adverse effect that these two elements have on toughness. The A15–Nb
 <sub>3</sub>Sn can be stable in the microstructure of Nb-silicide based alloys depending on the concentration of Sn in the alloy [
 <xref rid="B5-materials-12-03217" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. The impact of each of these two elements on oxidation depends on their concentration and the concentrations of the other elements in the alloy and on the oxidation temperature. Both elements improve the oxidation of Nb-silicide based alloys in the pest regime and Sn is more effective than Al. For example, in isothermal oxidation at 1073 K, the weight gain of the alloy Nb–24Ti–18Si–5Al was higher than that of Nb–24Ti–18Si–5Sn (20.1 and 4.8 mg/cm
 <sup>2</sup>, respectively). The latter alloy was also more resistant to pest oxidation below 1173 K. Improvement of the oxidation of Nb-silicide based alloys at higher temperatures depends on the synergy of Al and Sn with the other alloying additions. For example, the alloy Nb–24Ti–18Si–5Al gained more weight at 1473 K compared with Nb–24Ti–18Si based alloys with additions of Al, Cr and Ta. The same was the case for Nb–24Ti–18Si based alloys with Sn, where oxidation at high temperatures was improved in the presence of Al, Cr and other transition metal (TM) and refractory metal (RM) elements [
 <xref rid="B9-materials-12-03217" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. Such alloys had lower parabolic oxidation rate constants and better adhering oxide scale than alloys without Sn.
</p>
