<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Ingots with two different nominal compositions, Al-30.0 and 31.0 at.%Fe, were prepared by arc-melting Fe and Al (4N purity) under an Ar gas flow. Mass loss after the arc-melting was less than 0.1%. The solidified ingots encapsulated in a quartz ampoule with Ar gas were heat-treated under two different conditions: (i) at 900°C for 1 day and then at 300°C for 28 days followed by iced-water quenching, and (ii) at 1000°C for 1 day followed by iced-water quenching. The microstructures and chemical compositions of phases present in the specimens were examined by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and transmission electron microscopy (TEM). Thin foils for TEM observations were prepared by twin-jet electro-polishing in a solution of perchloric acid and methanol (1:9 by volume) at −40°C and 10 V. Bright-field images and electron diffraction patterns were obtained with a JEOL JEM-2000FX TEM operated at 200 kV, while atomic-resolution images were obtained with a spherical-aberration-corrected JEOL JEM-ARM200F STEM operated at 200 kV. The probe convergence angle and the inner/outer detector angles for high-angle annular dark-field (HAADF) imaging were 22 and 90/370 mrad, respectively. Energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS) was employed in atomic-resolution STEM observation. Simulations of STEM images and electron diffraction patterns were performed with the 
 <italic>WinHREM</italic> software package [
 <xref rid="CIT0032">32</xref>] and 
 <italic>CaRIne</italic> software [
 <xref rid="CIT0033">33</xref>], respectively. SXRD experiments were carried out at 300 K with a large cylindrical image-plate camera installed at BL02B1 of SPring-8 synchrotron radiation facility. A columnar specimen was machined from the η″ phase in the Al-31.0 at.%Fe alloy quenched from 300°C with a JEOL JIB-4000 focused ion beam (FIB) apparatus at an operating voltage of 30 kV. The size of the columnar specimen was approximately 18 μm in diameter and 20 μm in length. The crystal structure was solved by 
 <italic>SHELXT</italic> [
 <xref rid="CIT0034">34</xref>] and refined by full-matrix least-squares techniques on 
 <italic>F</italic>
 <sup>2</sup> (
 <italic>SHELXL-97</italic>) [
 <xref rid="CIT0035">35</xref>] within the 
 <italic>WinGX</italic> crystallographic software package [
 <xref rid="CIT0036">36</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0037">37</xref>].
</p>
