<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par5">Chirality is key to impart sophisticated motile behavior
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>. Movement at small scales requires a shape transformation of the body that breaks a time-reversal invariance
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>, and this is arguably why swimming microorganisms must be able to change the shape of their chiral bodies. For example, 
 <italic>E. coli</italic> uses a rotating helical flagellum to swim
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>, whereas helix-shaped body of 
 <italic>Helicobacter pylori</italic> and 
 <italic>Campylobacter jejuni</italic> mediates their efficient swimming in challenging media
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>
 </sup>. Besides often relying on chiral body shape transformations, the vast majority of aquatic microorganisms and cells actually swim along helical trajectories, including zooplankton, ciliates, and bacteria
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>
 </sup>. Although the evolutionary advantages of helical motion remain unclear, it appears that the directionality of helical motion is less sensitive to extracellular and intracellular random variations, compared with rectilinear motion
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. Significantly, swimming in a screw-like fashion offers opportunity for efficient reorientation behaviors set to follow chemical and physical gradients
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup>. Besides the well-known ‘run and tumble’ behavior of 
 <italic>E. coli</italic>, these chirality-derived reorientation mechanisms often feature deterministic directional changes, such as in the ‘run, reverse, and flick’ of 
 <italic>Vibrio alginolyticus</italic>, a marine bacterium that also moves along helical pathways, and for which the flick angle is pre-programmed, i.e., the re-direction does not occur randomly
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
