<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The observation of the FIB section using diffraction contrast (bright‐ and dark‐fields) yielded additional information. First, the grains indexed as wadsleyite by the ACOM‐TEM indeed contain the characteristic stacking faults (Figure 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-fig-0003" ref-type="fig">3</xref>a) usually found in this mineral. The 320‐nm‐thick lamella (observed at the SEM) shows no defects. At the TEM, we see that this lamella located at the interface between two olivine grains is not unique in the FIB section. Some much thinner (10‐20 nm) lamellae with the same orientation are found in the olivine grain at the bottom of Figure 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-fig-0003" ref-type="fig">3</xref>. We assume that all those lamellae are constituted of the same phase. This assumption has not been demonstrated but is at least compatible with the chemical analyses performed (see Figure 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-fig-0004" ref-type="fig">4</xref>). A striking observation is the existence of topotactic relationships between the lamellae and the parent olivine. This is illustrated by Figure 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-fig-0003" ref-type="fig">3</xref>b, which shows that both the lamella and olivine can be imaged in weak‐beam dark‐field with very close diffraction vectors (
 <italic>g</italic> = 004 for olivine and 
 <italic>g</italic> = 400 for Anh‐B). On this figure, one can see the network of interfacial dislocations, which accommodate the small lattice parameter difference between the two structures in contact. The topotactic relationship between the two structures is along the (100)
 <sub>ol</sub> plane of olivine, which corresponds to the (010)
 <sub>Anh‐B</sub> plane of Anh‐B. Indeed, the crystal structures of olivine and Anh‐B are very close. The [100]
 <sub>Anh‐B</sub> direction of Anh‐B in 
 <italic>Pmcb</italic> corresponds to [001]
 <sub>ol</sub> in olivine. The [010]
 <sub>Anh‐B</sub> direction of Anh‐B corresponds to [100]
 <sub>ol</sub> in olivine and represents a superstructure of it. The [001]
 <sub>Anh‐B</sub> direction of Anh‐B corresponds to [010]
 <sub>ol</sub> in olivine. These relationships are well illustrated when superimposing diffraction patterns from both phases as shown on Figure 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-fig-0009" ref-type="fig">9</xref>. Additional examples (from calculated diffraction patterns) are presented in Figure 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-supitem-0001" ref-type="supplementary-material">S4</xref>.
</p>
