<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The determination of crystal structure models is now possible from electron diffraction data (Kolb et al., 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0026" ref-type="ref">2007</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0027" ref-type="ref">2008</xref>; Palatinus, Corrêa, et al., 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0038" ref-type="ref">2015</xref>; Palatinus, Petříček, &amp; Correa, 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0039" ref-type="ref">2015</xref>; Wan et al., 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0052" ref-type="ref">2013</xref>). This allows, as in the present case, to characterize phases with volumes so small that single‐crystal X‐ray diffraction is precluded. Here some lamellae are large enough for selected area electron diffraction to be performed without sampling the matrix. The analyzed volume is smaller than 0.005 μm
 <sup>3</sup>. To get the maximum coverage of the reciprocal space, which is necessary to produce reliable structure model, we use here precession electron diffraction tomography, which combines precession electron diffraction (Vincent &amp; Midgley, 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0051" ref-type="ref">1994</xref>) and electron diffraction tomography. For the tomography, we use a tilt range of 
 <bold>±</bold> 45° in the microscope. Combined with the use of precession, this allows a broad coverage of the reciprocal space, which is satisfactory for three‐dimensional structure determination. In precession electron diffraction, the electron beam is tilted away from the optical axis of the microscope and precessed on a conical surface with a semi‐angle usually between 1 and 3° (here 1.20°). This technique has two advantages: precession electron diffraction patterns are less dynamical and they display a larger number of reflections. Despite that, taking into account dynamical effects is important for the accurate structure refinement (Palatinus, Petříček, &amp; Correa, 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0039" ref-type="ref">2015</xref>). The crystal structure model obtained from this data processing is characterized by having part of silicon in sixfold coordination.
</p>
