<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The transition from mono- to multivalent ion-based batteries is a key strategy to substantially enhance the energy density of currently available battery technologies, especially if metal anodes can be used.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
 </sup> This concept becomes particularly attractive if earth-abundant and nontoxic metals are used as the overall battery technology would benefit from reduced cost and lower environmental impact. Ca and Mg are the fifth and eighth most abundant elements on the earth’s crust, respectively, and the metals display theoretical volumetric energy densities of 3833 and 2073 mA h/mL, significantly larger than that of graphite, which is used as the negative electrode material in most commercial lithium ion batteries (∼800 mA h/mL).
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>
 </sup> On the positive electrode side, divalent charge carriers would enable to double the capacities when compared to single valent ones for the same amount of reacted ions. Alternatively, reaction of only a half of the ions would be needed to achieve the same capacity. These prospects have been prompting increased interest from the scientific community, with Mg batteries having deserved the most attention so far.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
 </sup> Progress in this topic is difficult, as significant bottlenecks exist both at a fundamental and technical level, and the understanding of the multivalent battery chemistry is still elusive in many aspects. Indeed, know-how gained in the development of Li-ion batteries cannot be directly imported and even a reliable electrochemical full cell setup is missing.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>
 </sup> On the crystal chemistry side, unraveling materials allowing fast and reversible ion mobility is a major challenge to address. The main issues arise from the high polarizing character of multivalent ions inducing strong Coulombic interactions within the electrode host framework and high (de)-solvation energy barriers, which dramatically affect the electrode intercalation kinetics and power performances. The use of Mo
 <sub>6</sub>S
 <sub>8–
  <italic>y</italic>
 </sub>Se
 <sub>
  <italic>y</italic>
 </sub> (
 <italic>y</italic> = 1, 2) Chevrel phases exhibiting fast and reversible Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> migration as positive electrode materials represents a milestone in Mg battery chemistry,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
 </sup> despite its redox potential being rather low. A vast array of other materials, including layered and spinel oxides, chalcogenides, Prussian blue analogues, vanadates, silicates, and polyanionic phosphates, have been studied, but none of them has resulted in suitable performance.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
 </sup> Calcium systems are even less explored, as the feasibility of reversible calcium plating/stripping got only recently unveiled.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref>
 </sup> Encouraging results have been achieved with traditional layered materials such as TiS
 <sub>2</sub>, for which reversible insertion of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> at 100 °C has been recently demonstrated.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref>
 </sup> Traditional layered oxides such as V
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>5</sub> and MoO
 <sub>3</sub> have been recently revisited for applications in Ca batteries: while poor (if any) Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> intercalation has been proved in V
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>5</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
 </sup> reversible electrochemical activity has been reported for MoO
 <sub>3</sub>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> Calcium transition metal ternary oxides have also drawn increasing attention: while too high Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> migration barriers were determined for CaMoO
 <sub>3</sub> and CaMn
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> electrochemical extraction of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> from 1D Ca
 <sub>3</sub>Co
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>6</sub> was achieved at high potential (3.2–3.6 V vs Ca), encouraging further optimization of the cathode and electrolyte compositions to achieve reversibility of the process.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
