<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Within this research context, we decided to further explore non-oxidic compounds, turning our attention to ternary A
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>Ta
 <sub>
  <italic>y</italic>
 </sub>N
 <sub>
  <italic>z</italic>
 </sub> (A: Mg, Ca) tantalum nitrides. As compared to transition metal oxides, nitrides exhibit analogous crystal chemistry and a higher degree of covalency of the metal–anion bonds, which results into unique chemical, magnetic, and optical properties.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> The high covalency of transition metal nitrides can be conceived as a tool to mitigate coulombic interactions with multivalent ions and hence facilitate their solid state migration. Furthermore, the high electronic conductivity exhibited by several transition metal nitrides could play a key role in promoting fast multivalent ion migration kinetics, in agreement with what has been recently evidenced for the Mg
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>Zr
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>4</sub> thiospinel phase,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>
 </sup> exhibiting, despite its large unit cell volume and almost zero-strain upon insertion, lower Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> diffusion coefficient than the Mg
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>Ti
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>4</sub> phase
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> as a consequence of its much lower electronic conductivity. While covalency is also expected to result in a penalty in the redox operating voltage, this can be in principle compensated by the proper selection of transition metal redox centers. Although few reports on the study of ternary alkali transition metal nitrides as Li-ion battery electrode materials exist,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>
 </sup> such compounds have not been considered for multivalent technologies, the only exception being MgMoN
 <sub>2</sub>, for which Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> extraction was not possible.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>
 </sup> Among the available alkaline earth metal transition metal nitrides, the ternary A–Ta–N (A: Ca, Mg) system represents an interesting playground for research, as the electronic configuration of tantalum allows in principle to explore a broad spectrum of phase compositions, with potentially high operating voltage and high specific capacities. Hexagonal Mg
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>Ta
 <sub>2+
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>N
 <sub>3</sub> and cubic Mg
 <sub>2.6–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>Ta
 <sub>2+
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>N
 <sub>3</sub> phases were originally prepared by Brokamp and Jacobs by solid state reaction between Mg(NH
 <sub>2</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub> or Mg
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>2</sub> and Ta
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>5</sub>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>
 </sup> Analogously, CaTaN
 <sub>2</sub> was synthesized by Disalvo et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>
 </sup> from Ca(NH
 <sub>2</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub> and Ta
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>5</sub> and suggested to have rhombohedral symmetry, being isostructural to α-NaFeO
 <sub>2</sub>.
</p>
