<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Vezzoli et al. compared energy level diagrams for both quantum dots and rods, as shown in Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0002" ref-type="fig">2</xref>c.[qv: 17b] The left part of Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0002" ref-type="fig">2</xref>c presents the band structure of CdSe, showing the heavy‐hole, light‐hole, and split‐off sub‐bands and the net‐splitting Δ at 
 <italic>k</italic> = 0. The middle part of Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0002" ref-type="fig">2</xref>c demonstrates the band‐edge exciton fine structure energy states for a positive net‐splitting Δ. The | ± 2〉 states and the |0
 <sup>
  <italic>L</italic>
 </sup>〉 states are optically inactive and represented as dashed lines. The degenerate 2D dipole emission from the | ± 1
 <sup>
  <italic>L</italic>
 </sup>〉 and | ± 1
 <sup>
  <italic>U</italic>
 </sup>〉 levels is symbolized by the double blue arrows. The 1D dipole emission from the |0
 <sup>
  <italic>U</italic>
 </sup>〉 state is symbolized by the red arrow. The right part of Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0002" ref-type="fig">2</xref>c illustrates the band‐edge exciton fine structure energy states for a negative net‐splitting Δ, showing a swapping of the levels. The polarized emission in these figures can be illustrated as follows. The valence band of CdSe is made of 3 sub‐bands, the heavy‐hole, light‐hole, and split‐off sub‐bands (Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0002" ref-type="fig">2</xref>c). The | ± 2〉 and |0
 <sup>
  <italic>L</italic>
 </sup>〉 state do not contribute to the emission at the room temperature, when it is a mixture of recombination from the |0
 <sup>
  <italic>U</italic>
 </sup>〉 state and from the degenerate | ± 1
 <sup>
  <italic>L</italic>
 </sup>〉, | ± 1
 <sup>
  <italic>U</italic>
 </sup>〉 states.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0018" ref-type="ref">18</xref> The |0
 <sup>
  <italic>U</italic>
 </sup>〉 state is associated with a linear 1D dipole that oscillates along the 
 <italic>c</italic>‐axis of the crystal and emits linearly polarized photons. The | ± 1
 <sup>
  <italic>L</italic>
 </sup>〉 and | ± 1
 <sup>
  <italic>U</italic>
 </sup>〉 can be seen as 2D dipoles, oscillating inside a plane, as schematically shown in 
 <bold>Figure</bold>
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0003" ref-type="fig">
  <bold>3</bold>
 </xref>a. Because of the level degeneracy, the emission from these transitions is an incoherent superposition of σ
 <sup>+</sup> and σ
 <sup>−</sup> components,
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0019" ref-type="ref">19</xref> and the corresponding dipole is called a degenerate 2D dipole. It is equivalent to two linear dipoles, oscillating perpendicularly and in quadrature. These dipoles are contained in the plane perpendicular to the 
 <italic>c</italic>‐axis of the crystal and because of this the polarization azimuth for the two oscillators are mutually perpendicular as illustrated in Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0003" ref-type="fig">3</xref>b. Therefore, the degree of the polarization for the total emission strongly depends on the relative oscillator strengths of two oscillators mutually oscillating in an orthogonal plane.
</p>
