<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The core size, the shell thickness, and the aspect ratio affect the polarized emission properties of core/shell QRs.[qv: 14,17b,20] For larger core sizes, wurtzite CdSe cores tend to grow into a prolate shape, which strongly enhances optical anisotropies. Due to the shape dependence of the energy level structure, the degree of the polarization for the emitted light increases with the aspect ratio of the QRs, and it is further increased by the anisotropic dielectric environment.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0021" ref-type="ref">21</xref> Murray's group has shown that the thickness of the shell along the core is critically important to achieve a higher degree of polarization.[qv: 20b] Although a rod‐shaped shell geometry is a necessary condition to observe the polarized optical properties, the degree of polarization is not a direct consequence of the increasing aspect ratio. Rather, tuning the local anisotropy of the emissive core materials by changing the thickness of the anisotropic shell may change the degree of optical anisotropy more dramatically.[qv: 20b] Thus, the degree of polarization depends on first, on the fluorescence anisotropy of the nanoparticle and second the quality of alignment. Talapin's group studied the anisotropy for different shapes of colloidal semiconductor nanostructures, including dots, rods, and platelets, all illustrated in 
 <bold>Figure</bold>
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0004" ref-type="fig">
  <bold>4</bold>
 </xref>.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0014" ref-type="ref">14</xref> Among these different types of nanostructures, QRs show enhanced absorption and emission of light along their long axis.[qv: 17b,20b,22] Furthermore, among the core/shell elongated nanoparticles, dot‐in‐dot and rod‐in‐rod heterostructures have higher anisotropy in comparison to the other nanoparticles. Particularly, the rod‐in‐rod nanoparticles show the highest anisotropy. Thus, these heterostructures show a high degree of linear polarization for emission and are highly suitable for modern LCDs. Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0004" ref-type="fig">4</xref>e shows the size‐dependent anisotropy for the nanoparticles. The wavelength‐dependent anisotropy for various core/shell structures has been plotted in Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0004" ref-type="fig">4</xref>f. It is clear from the figure that the anisotropy increases close to the band edge. However, it is not very suitable for LCD backlight applications, where a fixed blue light is used to excite the PL layer. The same figure also conveys that the thin shell and medium size core provide a higher anisotropy.
</p>
