<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0165">On the basis of the above-mentioned studies and obtained results one can draw the following conclusions:
 <list list-type="simple" id="olist0010">
  <list-item id="o0010">
   <label>1.</label>
   <p id="p0170">The zeolites of the Yagodninsky deposit of the Kamchatka region are promising sorbents for extracting heavy metal ions from aqueous solutions.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item id="o0015">
   <label>2.</label>
   <p id="p0175">Within the concentration ranges of heavy metals relevant to this study, from 0.5 to 3.5 mg-equ/L, sorption is described satisfactorily by the Lengmur equation.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item id="o0020">
   <label>3.</label>
   <p id="p0180">The values of the maximum sorption capacity of the zeolites of the Yagodninsk deposit of the Kamchatka region have been determined. They are, in mg-equ/L,: for copper – 0.023; for iron – 0.021; for nickel – 0.020; for cobalt – 0.011.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item id="o0025">
   <label>4.</label>
   <p id="p0185">The calculated values of the Gibbs energy which are equal to for copper ΔG = –25.6 кJ/mol, for iron – ΔG = –23.7 kJ/mol, for nickel – ΔG = –21.5 kJ/mol and for cobalt – ΔG = –20.0 kJ/mol corroborate the assumption about the steady attaching of nonferrous metal ions on the zeolite surface.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item id="o0030">
   <label>5.</label>
   <p id="p0190">On the basis of the analysis of the parameters of the mordenite crystal lattice a decrease in sizes in the direction of the 
    <italic>a</italic>- and 
    <italic>b</italic>-axes and, consequently, of the elementary cell volume of the treated zeolite is observed as compared with the initial zeolite in the Cu &gt; Ni &gt; Co &gt; Fe row.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item id="o0035">
   <label>6.</label>
   <p id="p0195">New knowledge about the sorption properties of the Yagodninsky deposit zeolites can be interesting for the industrial areas of South- Eastern Asia such as China, Japan, Korea, etc.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
