<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data">
 <p>Supplementary material for this article is available at 
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://advances.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/full/5/7/eaar8027/DC1" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://advances.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/full/5/7/eaar8027/DC1</ext-link>
 </p>
 <p>Section S1. Similar observation in a superconducting sample (fig. S6)</p>
 <p>Section S2. Scaling factor used in 
  <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3C</xref> and fig. S6C
 </p>
 <p>Section S3. Canted angle between adjacent MoO
  <sub>6</sub> octahedra
 </p>
 <p>Section S4. Theory of dark excitons and its contribution to resistivity and MR along the 
  <italic>a</italic> axis
 </p>
 <p>Section S5. Deconvolution of the anisotropic MR in LMO</p>
 <p>Table S1. Location of the maxima and minima in the angular MR in LMO above 
  <italic>T</italic>
  <sub>min</sub>.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S1. Mirror reflection of the ADMR curves at various temperatures about the 
  <italic>c</italic> axis.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S2. The magnitude of asymmetry as a function of temperature for MR curves of current along the 
  <italic>b</italic> axis.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S3. Contrast in the asymmetric MR response upon rotation within the three crystallographic planes.</p>
 <p>Fig. S4. Normalized ADMR curves obtained at various temperatures as a constant magnetic field of 13 T, rotated within the 
  <italic>bc</italic> plane.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S5. Absence of asymmetric MR (
  <italic>I</italic>//
  <italic>b</italic>) with increasing field strength for 
  <italic>B</italic> rotated within the 
  <italic>bc</italic> plane.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S6. Origin of the asymmetric MR and determination of the critical angle for a second, superconducting LMO crystal.</p>
 <p>Fig. S7. Scaling factor used in 
  <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3C</xref> and fig. S6C, respectively.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S8. A close view of the canted MoO
  <sub>6</sub> octahedra in LMO.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S9. Configurations of electric contacts applied to our LMO crystals.</p>
 <p>Fig. S10. Schematic of crystallization of dark excitons.</p>
 <p>Fig. S11. Power-law behavior of resistivity along the 
  <italic>b</italic> axis in both insulating and superconducting LMO crystals.
 </p>
 <p>References (
  <xref rid="R45" ref-type="bibr">
   <italic>45</italic>
  </xref>–
  <xref rid="R51" ref-type="bibr">
   <italic>51</italic>
  </xref>)
 </p>
</supplementary-material>
