<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">Along with the development of advanced QPM theories, NPCs with complicated 
 <italic>χ</italic>
 <sup>(2)</sup> structures have been utilized for nonlinear beam shaping strategies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. Beam shaping in linear optics has been widely applied to produce various spatial beams for applications in optical communication, optical tweezers, and optical microscopy
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>. The nonlinear version, i.e., shaping nonlinear beam at a new frequency, provides a compact way to perform frequency conversion and wavefront manipulation at the same time. However, the frequency conversion efficiency is normally sacrificed for achieving nonlinear beam shaping in previous methods
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup>. In traditional electric poling technique, the modulations of 
 <italic>χ</italic>
 <sup>(2)</sup> in NPCs are limited to two dimensions. High conversion efficiency requires one dimension for QPM while nonlinear beam shaping in free space requires two additional dimensions for full wavefront modulations. Therefore, except for few cases that investigate nonlinear beam characteristics within 2D space
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>
 </sup>, most previous works have suffered from low conversion efficiency. The general scheme is to input a fundamental light beam along the 
 <italic>z</italic>-axis of a LiNbO
 <sub>3</sub> NPC and utilize the 2D binary phase modulation of a second-harmonic (SH) wavefront in the 
 <italic>x–y</italic> plane (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>). This configuration has been applied to generate SH vortex beam, nonlinear superfocusing spot, SH non-diffracting beam, etc
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>
 </sup>. Unfortunately, the conversion efficiencies are typically below 1 × 10
 <sup>−6</sup> in a mm-long sample due to the lack of phase matching and the use of a small nonlinear coefficient 
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sub>22</sub> of the LiNbO
 <sub>3</sub> crystal, which badly hampers the practical applications of nonlinear beam shaping.
</p>
