<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par26">To explore the 2D nature of triplon excitations in Ba
 <sub>2</sub>CuSi
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>6</sub>Cl
 <sub>2</sub>, its magnetic excitations were investigated using the cold-neutron disk chopper spectrometer AMATERAS installed in the Materials and Life Science Experimental Facility at J-PARC, Japan
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>
 </sup>. As shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>, twenty pieces of single crystals were coaligned on a rectangular Al plate so that an 
 <italic>a</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> or 
 <italic>b</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> direction for every crystal coincided with the edge directions of the Al plate. The Al plate was fixed in a vertical direction to set the 
 <italic>a</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> and 
 <italic>c</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> axes or 
 <italic>b</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> and 
 <italic>c</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> axes in the horizontal plane. Note that 
 <italic>a</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> and 
 <italic>b</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> axes cannot be distinguished with each other because of crystallographic domains. Thus, both 
 <italic>a</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> and 
 <italic>b</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> components of a scattering vector are converted to a reciprocal lattice unit by the average of 
 <italic>a</italic> and 
 <italic>b</italic>-axis lengths, which is 13.88 Å. The mixed domains do not matter in our analysis, because 
 <italic>a</italic> and 
 <italic>b</italic> axis lengths are almost the same, and triplet bands along 
 <italic>a</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> and 
 <italic>b</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> directions can be easily distinguished with each other, as described in the main text. Incident neutron energies were set to 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>i</italic>
 </sub> = (23.65, 5.924) meV and (7.732, 3.135) meV by using repetition multiplication
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>
 </sup>. The coaligned crystals were rotated between a direction that forms a bond angle of −35° and 55° with respect to the 
 <italic>c</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> axis for 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>i</italic>
 </sub> = (23.65, 5.924) meV, while incident neutrons were kept parallel to the 
 <italic>c</italic>
 <sup>*</sup> axis for 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>i</italic>
 </sub> = (7.732, 3.135) meV. The sample was cooled down to 0.3 and 2.5 K by using a 
 <sup>3</sup>He refrigerator. All the data collected were analyzed using the software suite UTSUSEMI
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
