<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par31">In the experiment, we collected 1295 reflections, which were merged based on the crystal symmetry to 833 independent reflections with 
 <italic>R</italic>
 <sub>int</sub> = 3.29%. At 
 <italic>d</italic> = 0.8 Å, completeness of the data was 25.3%. The structure was determined by a direct method using SHELXS
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>
 </sup> software. After the structure solution, most of the atoms were found and the rest of them were located from a series of difference Fourier map cycles. The crystal structure was refined against 
 <italic>F</italic>
 <sup>2</sup> on all data by full-matrix least squares with the SHELXL
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>
 </sup> software. The amount of the collected data allowed us to refine the structure only in an isotropic approximation. The resulting ratio between data (833) and the number of parameters (143) was ~6. Five reflections were omitted from the refinement due to their overlap with diamond peaks. The final structure converged with 
 <italic>R</italic>
 <sub>1</sub> = 14.81%, 
 <italic>wR</italic>
 <sub>2</sub> = 36.32%, and GOF = 1.625 for all 833 unique reflections [
 <italic>R</italic>
 <sub>1</sub> = 13.64%, 
 <italic>wR</italic>
 <sub>2</sub> = 34.72%, for those 681 data with 
 <italic>I</italic> &gt; 2σ(
 <italic>I</italic>)]. On a final difference Fourier map, we observed no peaks higher than 1.4 e·Å
 <sup>−2</sup>. The most of the intense peaks were within 1 Å of the Si atoms, but several peaks of about 1 e·Å
 <sup>−2</sup> were found nearby oxygen atoms (1.1–1.2 Å) probably due to the twinning present. Values of thermal parameters of all atoms except O(5) are within the normal interval (0.015–0.027 A
 <sup>2</sup>). Atom O(5) is located on a special position (0 0 0.5) and has a larger thermal parameter (0.05 A
 <sup>2</sup>) probably due to the twinning present or even lower symmetry (
 <italic>P</italic>1) of the structure.
</p>
