<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Efficient white light-emitting diodes (LEDs) have attracted considerable attention in solid-state illumination recently. Several methods are developed to fabricate white light LEDs, the phosphor-converted emission is the most commonly used technique.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
 </sup> Up to now, various materials such as inorganic phosphors,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
 </sup> organic dyes,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>
 </sup> and quantum dots (QDs)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>
 </sup> have been employed to test the possibility to replace the common phosphors in white LEDs. In these materials, QD is an innovative material because it has advantages over the commonly used phosphors. The emission wavelength adjustment of the QDs is generally completed by controlling the size of the crystal or varying the chemical composition. In addition, the scattering effects of QDs are rarely observed because the size of QD particles is relatively small compared to inorganic phosphors. Compared to organic dyes, QDs are not easily bleached, demonstrating a longer lifetime and a wider absorption range. A QD-based white LED is generally fabricated using a spin-coating technique, in which QDs are mixed with epoxy resins and are then coated on the excited chips.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>
 </sup> However, an alternative photoactive packaging (PAP) method has also been used to fabricate the white LEDs.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
 </sup> In the PAP method, a bare blue LED chip was covered with a red and green QD-dispersed photosensitive resin film to make the white LED illuminate when the current is passed through the blue LED chip. This packaging method eliminates the additional facilities that are used to package LEDs in the present process. Here, the white balance of this hybrid LED was achieved by mixing red and green QDs in the photosensitive resins.
</p>
