<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Quantum dots possess some characteristics such as a size-tunable energy bandgap, high quantum efficiency of photoluminescence (PL), solution processing, and adjustable absorption and emission wavelength.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>
 </sup> QDs have been widely used in photoelectronic devices of solar cells
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
 </sup> and light-emitting diodes.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> Encapsulation of quantum dots (QDs) into polymers can improve the photoluminescence stability and device performance of optoelectronic and light-emitting diodes (LEDs).
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup> In the fabrication of LEDs, the dispersion and quantum efficiency of QDs in the polymer matrix are the most important factors. The optical properties of QDs are affected by several factors, such as the QD size, the type of ligand molecule, and the type of matrix. The structure and interaction of organic compounds on the surface of the QD affect the fluorescence of the QD. Green’s group
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> has reviewed the properties of capped ligands such as trioctylphosphine oxide, amines, carboxylic acids, or thiols on the surface of the QDs. The defects on the surface of the QDs can work as the hole of electrons or holes. Therefore, surface passivation of quantum dots can reduce their recombination leading to the enhancement of fluorescence. A common method of surface passivation of CdSe-QDs is made using a thin shell of a wider bandgap material such as ZnS for surface protection,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>
 </sup> thereby forming a core–shell structure.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> The shell forms a more passivated surface, resulting in the reduction in nonradiative pathways with an effective increase in quantum efficiency. One-step synthesis has been employed to prepare CdSe/ZnS quantum dots.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
 </sup> The one-step synthesis method is much faster than the two-step in the manufacturing process, which is in favor of mass production in the future. Because the quantum confinement effect and the core–shell structure existed in the QDs having few defects on the crystal surface, the light-emitting efficiency of photoexcitation is extremely high. Another approach uses a dangling bond formed by a suitable surface passivation ligand to reduce surface traps.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>
 </sup> There are two challenges in the incorporation of QDs into the polymer matrix, that is, QD aggregation and fluorescence quenching. QDs can be incorporated into the polymeric matrix by a number of methods, including the in situ synthesis of QDs in the polymer,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>
 </sup> the direct incorporation of QDs into the polymer,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>
 </sup> and the in situ polymerization of monomer-containing QDs forming a cured resin hybrid.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> The structure and molecular polarity of the polymer matrix have obvious interactions with the capping ligands on the surface of QDs. It needs to select the molecular structure and molecular polarity to be completely miscible with the prepared quantum dots, forming a uniformly transparent precursor solution. After curing, the coating of the precursor solution generates a hybrid film of the light-emitting diode with good light transmittance. Recently, the incorporation of phosphine ligand-coupled CdSe and CdSe/ZnS QDs into poly(methyl methacrylate) demonstrated no phase separation during polymerization.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>
 </sup> Without modification of the surface of the QDs, a stable and bright green photoluminescent CdSe/poly(butyl acrylate) nanocomposite was obtained by in-situ miniemulsion polymerization.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref>
 </sup> Wang et al. dispersed CdSe/ZnS QDs in photosensitive epoxy resin to produce a white LED by means of an active packaging method.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
 </sup> On the other hand, the incorporation of CdSe/ZnS QDs into poly(2-methoxy-5(2-ethylhexyloxy)) to produce organic LEDs can significantly improve the performance of this hybrid device.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref>
 </sup> Organic silicone resins have good transparency, flexibility, stress relief, thermal stability, moisture resistance, and high gas permeability, which have been widely used in packaging CdSe/ZnS QD LEDs.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref>
 </sup> The quantum dots are directly dispersed in the organic resin and mounted on the surface of the semiconductor chip to emit white light.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref>
 </sup> The CdSe/ZnS core–shell QDs are encapsulated in the polymer matrix of cyanoacrylate and epoxy resin, resulting in the loss or increase of QD light emission in these polymers.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> The QD light-emitting film was commonly prepared by adding the solution of quantum dots into the polymer, coating on the substrate, and then heating to remove the solvent. This process often takes much time to perform the polymerization/curing reaction at relatively high temperatures (∼120–150 °C), leading to a decline in QDs. Alternatively, in 2008, an epoxy acrylate monomer using photopolymerization has been employed to make QD light-emitting films achieve a white LED.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref>
 </sup> This epoxy resin system having benzene rings in the polymer chains would result in the yellowing phenomenon by extending the use time, leading to a decline of the light-emitting efficiency.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
