<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The structures of α-B
 <sub>12</sub>-derived icosahedral boron-rich solids arise when inserting three-atom chains CBC or NBN (leading to B
 <sub>4</sub>C
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> and B
 <sub>13</sub>N
 <sub>2</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>
 </sup> respectively) or pairs of atoms (dumbbells) at the position of the octahedral voids in the ccp arrangement of icosahedra, and orienting them along [111]
 <sub>r</sub>/[001]
 <sub>h</sub> (
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>
 </xref>c).
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>
 </sup> This replaces the intralayer 3c2e bonds between B
 <sup>e</sup> atoms by 2c2e exo-links between B
 <sup>e</sup> and an atom of the inserted entity, whereas the exo-links between B
 <sup>p</sup> atoms of neighboring icosahedra between layers are retained. Substitution of B atoms within B
 <sub>12</sub> units occurs rarely and is mostly seen with boron carbides, where it affects the polar position. B
 <sub>4</sub>C may be written as CBC(B
 <sub>11</sub>C
 <sup>p</sup>).
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref>
 </sup> Optimum electron counts for the various materials (yielding electron-precise semiconducting phases) follow from the optimum electron count of an all exo-linked icosahedral cluster (i.e., 13 electron pairs for skeleton bonding and 12 electrons for exo-bonding),
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>
 </sup> which may be expressed as, e.g., (CBC)
 <sup>+</sup>(B
 <sub>11</sub>C
 <sup>p</sup>)
 <sup>−</sup>, (P
 <sub>2</sub>)
 <sup>2+</sup>B
 <sub>12</sub>
 <sup>2–</sup>, and (O
 <sup>+</sup>)
 <sub>2</sub>B
 <sub>12</sub>
 <sup>2–</sup> (cf. 
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>
 </xref>c). However, as initially mentioned, α-B
 <sub>12</sub>-derived materials are rarely stoichiometric with respect to the electron-precise composition. Compositional deviations frequently originate from disorder within the three-atom/dumbbell entities, according to B
 <sub>12</sub>(B
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>X
 <italic>
  <sub>x</sub>
 </italic>) for, e.g., X = P, S, Se or B
 <sub>12</sub>Y
 <sub>2–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> for, e.g., Y = As, P, O,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>
 </sup> in addition to the above-mentioned substitution of B
 <sup>p</sup> by C
 <sup>p</sup>. Although phase relations may be complicated, homogeneity ranges remain rather narrow and semiconductor properties are maintained.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
