<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>SiB
 <sub>3</sub> represents a special case among α-B
 <sub>12</sub>-derived materials. Although rhombohedral SiB
 <sub>3</sub> has been known for a long time—first reports date back to Moissan and Stock
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref>
 </sup>—its composition is still discussed controversially and will be hereafter referred to as SiB
 <sub>3–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>. In contrast to B
 <sub>4</sub>C, the larger size of Si permits only the presence of Si dumbbells in the octahedral voids. This is analogous to B
 <sub>6</sub>P
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
 </sup>—but in contrast to B
 <sub>6</sub>P (
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>
 </xref>c), an electron-precise composition (conforming to a semiconductor phase) will require the substitution of a substantial concentration of B within icosahedra. Early single-crystal diffraction work indicated that the preferred location for this substitution is, as for B
 <sub>4</sub>C, the polar site.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref>
 </sup> The electron-precise composition Si
 <sub>2</sub>(B
 <sub>10</sub>Si
 <sup>p</sup>
 <sub>2</sub>), i.e., SiB
 <sub>2.5</sub>, however, does not seem to be realized. Thus, in contrast to other α-B
 <sub>12</sub>-derived materials, SiB
 <sub>3–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> attains a composition that deviates considerably from the optimum electron count and, accordingly, this phase should be truly metallic. Obviously, substitution of Si for boron atoms on the polar site implies highly strained icosahedra. This follows simply from a comparison of atomic radii, which are rather similar for B and C (0.82 and 0.77 Å, respectively), whereas there is a large disparity in size with respect to the third period element Si (1.11 Å).
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref>
 </sup> As seen in the molecular analogues, such strained icosahedra are clearly unfavorable: There are numerous derivatives of icosahedral dicarboranes (C
 <sub>2</sub>B
 <sub>10</sub>H
 <sub>12</sub>), where H can be substituted for, e.g., alkyl, acyl, or halogens. Icosahedral dicarboranes exist in all three isomers (ortho, meta, para) and the C
 <sub>2</sub>B
 <sub>10</sub> skeleton may be stable up to 600 °C.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref>
 </sup> In contrast, icosahedral disilaboranes are only known as air-sensitive 1,2-diphenyl-, 1,2-methylphenyl-, and 1,2-dimethyl-
 <italic>ortho</italic>-disilaborane.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref>
 </sup> The latter, (CH
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>2</sub>B
 <sub>10</sub>H
 <sub>10</sub>, was discovered first.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref>
 </sup> The actual composition of SiB
 <sub>3–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> will represent a balance of the two extremes SiB
 <sub>2.5</sub> (electron-precise with all bonding states occupied but highly strained B
 <sub>10</sub>Si
 <sup>p</sup>
 <sub>2</sub> icosahedra) and SiB
 <sub>6</sub> (partially empty valence band but unstrained B
 <sub>12</sub> icosahedra). In this context, it is interesting to note that recently a new boron carbide phase B
 <sub>2.5</sub>C was predicted, which is more stable than B
 <sub>4</sub>C at high-pressure conditions.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>
 </sup> The structure of B
 <sub>2.5</sub>C corresponds to electron-precise C
 <sub>2</sub>(B
 <sub>10</sub>C
 <sup>p</sup>
 <sub>2</sub>). Furthermore, it has been suggested that microalloying B
 <sub>4</sub>C with silicon—where CBC units are (partially) replaced by Si
 <sub>2</sub> dumbbells—could afford a ternary material with decisively improved ductility.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref30">30</xref>
 </sup> And it has been shown that also hypothetical Si
 <sub>2</sub>(B
 <sub>10</sub>Si
 <sup>p</sup>
 <sub>2</sub>) displays improved ductility with respect to B
 <sub>4</sub>C.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">31</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
