<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>According to the energy analysis mullite tends to avoid the formation of vacancies, and the linear dependence on the composition also confirms that none of the turnover compositions is energetically favoured in agreement with the above conclusions. Hence, the observed stability of mullite must be related to the kinetics and structural dynamics at the temperature of formation. Although all calculations of this study neglect any dynamics arising from temperature or pressure, some indications on the dynamics can be derived from structural elements of the unified superspace model: it may be expected that Si tetrahedra are the most rigid structural units in mullite. This is supported by the volume of the Si tetrahedra forming part of the Si–Si diclusters in the relaxed structures. The smallest volume and largest volume are 2.296 Å
 <sup>3</sup> (M11 AS1) and 2.304 Å
 <sup>3</sup> (M45 AS1), respectively. In Section 3.1
 <xref ref-type="sec" rid="sec3.1"/> it was shown that Si–Si diclusters are preferably found stacked between vacancies, indicating that the geometry of vacancies may adapt effectively to the requirements of other structural units. This effect is likely to be more pronounced at higher temperatures. Then, the stability of mullite will depend mainly on the vacancy concentration and the temperature, but less on the actual vacancy distribution, in agreement with the above-mentioned observations. In this picture, the silica-rich border of the solid solution range is defined by the low-temperature limit at which mullite forms under equilibrium conditions. Even lower vacancy concentrations cannot form because the corresponding vacancy concentrations require a temperature at which the formation of mullite is not observed, which explains the miscibility ‘gap’ for 
 <italic>x</italic> &lt; 0.2. The alumina-rich border in turn corresponds to the vacancy concentration that is most stable at temperatures just below the melting point. Higher vacancy concentrations are achievable by quenching melts from 
 <italic>e.g.</italic> 2100°C if the presence of α-Al
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> nuclei can be avoided (Cameron, 1977
 <italic>b</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb16"> ▸</xref>; Kriven &amp; Pask, 1983
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb43"> ▸</xref>; Aksay 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1991
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb3"> ▸</xref>). Increasing the pressure decreases the structural flexibility of mullite and above 2 kbar it decomposes into Al
 <sub>2</sub>SiO
 <sub>5</sub> and α-Al
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> (Schneider &amp; Komarneni, 2005
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb72"> ▸</xref>) in agreement with our interpretation of the present results. Although the suggested mechanism is consistent with many experimental observations, a deeper structural and thermodynamic study should be carried out for verification and also to investigate the role of entropy. We believe that the results offer a good starting point for a study applying molecular dynamics to finally understand better the stability and high-temperature applications of mullite (Aksay 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1991
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb3"> ▸</xref>; Schneider 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2015
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb71"> ▸</xref>).
</p>
