<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The material in question is the purple bronze Li
 <sub>0.9</sub>Mo
 <sub>6</sub>O
 <sub>17</sub> (LMO) (
 <xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>9</italic>
 </xref>), a quasi-1D metal hosting a particularly robust Tomonaga-Luttinger liquid (TLL) state—the 1D analog of the Fermi liquid for an interacting electron system (
 <xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>10</italic>
 </xref>). At high temperatures, both spectroscopic (
 <xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>11</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>12</italic>
 </xref>) and transport (
 <xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>13</italic>
 </xref>) measurements have provided evidence for TLL physics, including signatures of spin-charge separation. Below a certain temperature 
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sub>min</sub> ~ 25 K, the resistivity passes through a minimum (
 <xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>14</italic>
 </xref>) and begins to rise sharply before, finally, superconductivity sets in below around 2 K, possibly with an unconventional pairing symmetry (
 <xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>15</italic>
 </xref>). Despite three decades of experimental effort (
 <xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>16</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>22</italic>
 </xref>), the underlying mechanism of this resistive upturn remains elusive: There is no accompanying structural distortion (
 <xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>23</italic>
 </xref>), no signature of magnetic order (
 <xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>24</italic>
 </xref>), disorder can be ruled out by the presence of an anisotropic superconducting phase (at the lowest temperatures) (
 <xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>15</italic>
 </xref>), while the transition to a more insulating state excludes the simple dimensional crossover scenario (
 <xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>25</italic>
 </xref>). Moreover, the lack of any clear signal of a standard Peierls phase transition [e.g., in the specific heat (
 <xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>16</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>22</italic>
 </xref>)] suggests an exotic, higher-order transition that involves only a small fraction of the carriers. All this makes LMO exceptional among the family of bronzes.
</p>
