<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The packing features of a crystal can be expressed using a cluster. As a crystal with 
 <italic>P</italic>2
 <sub>1</sub>/
 <italic>n</italic> and 
 <italic>Z</italic>′ = 1, the cluster contains a center LLM-105 molecule and its 14 closed neighbors, which form 14 dimers as shown in 
 <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>
 </xref>. Further, 14 dimers can be divided into eight groups according to the structure similarity. In 
 <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>
 </xref>, the molecules with same color means the same dimer can be constructed with one of them and the center molecule. 
 <xref rid="tbl4" ref-type="other">Table 
  <xref rid="tbl4" ref-type="other">4</xref>
 </xref> lists the intermolecular interaction energies of the dimers and the corresponding energy decomposition with CE-B3LYP
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref53">53</xref>
 </sup> based on the experimental structure. In the energy decomposition scheme, the interaction energy (
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>int</sub>) is expressed in terms of electrostatic (
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>ele</sub>), polarization (
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>pol</sub>), dispersion (
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>disp</sub>), and exchange-repulsion (
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>rep</sub>) as the following equation
 <disp-formula id="eq8">
  <graphic xlink:href="ao9b02410_m008" position="anchor" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  <label>8</label>
 </disp-formula>where, 
 <italic>k</italic>
 <sub>i</sub> (i = es, pol, disp, and rep) is the fitted scale factor for the corresponding energy component. Because of the lack of explicit physical meanings, total energies (
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>tot</sub>) without any scale factors were also provided in 
 <xref rid="tbl4" ref-type="other">Table 
  <xref rid="tbl4" ref-type="other">4</xref>
 </xref>. Overall, π–π stacking and the HB should dominate the crystal packing. Among all dimers, π–π stacking interactions are slightly stronger than those of the HB in either 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>tot</sub> or 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>int</sub>. π–π1, π–π2, HB1, and HB2 in 
 <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>
 </xref> possess the greatest 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>int</sub>. Although the number of π–π stacking dimers is less than HBs, the overall 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>tot</sub> of π–π stacking is similar to that of HBs because of their greater strength. From the energy decomposition, it is found that the interaction is contributed mainly by the electrostatic and dispersion. The dispersion effect plays a main role in π–π stacking, while the electrostatic term governs HB interaction.
</p>
