<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par14">The microstructure morphology of the MGMCs Au
 <sub>55.5</sub>Cu
 <sub>24.4</sub>Ag
 <sub>6.2</sub>Pd
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>11.9</sub>, Au
 <sub>58</sub>Cu
 <sub>24</sub>Ag
 <sub>7.5</sub>Pd
 <sub>1.5</sub>Si
 <sub>9</sub>, and Au
 <sub>60</sub>Cu
 <sub>23.5</sub>Ag
 <sub>9.1</sub>Pd
 <sub>1</sub>Si
 <sub>6.4</sub> is investigated by scanning electron microscopy performed on finely-polished cross sections of 2-mm diameter rods. Micrographs are presented in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>. The dark-colored regions are the metallic glass matrix phase while the light-colored is the primary-Au dendritic phase. No other phases are detectable in the micrographs. Using secondary ion mass spectroscopy, the compositions of the matrix and particulate phases in all MGMCs were verified (within expected error) to be Au
 <sub>50</sub>Cu
 <sub>25.5</sub>Ag
 <sub>3</sub>Pd
 <sub>3</sub>Si
 <sub>18.5</sub> and Au
 <sub>65.2</sub>Cu
 <sub>22.4</sub>Ag
 <sub>12.4</sub>, in accordance with Eq. (
 <xref rid="Equ1" ref-type="">1</xref>). The dendrites appear to be uniformly and homogeneously distributed through the matrix. The dendrite trunks appear to have developed radially along the direction of the temperature gradient established during the quench of the sample. Visually, the volume fraction of the metallic glass phase appears to increase roughly linearly with 
 <italic>x</italic> (i.e. going from Au
 <sub>60</sub>Cu
 <sub>23.5</sub>Ag
 <sub>9.1</sub>Pd
 <sub>1</sub>Si
 <sub>6.4</sub> to Au
 <sub>58</sub>Cu
 <sub>24</sub>Ag
 <sub>7.5</sub>Pd
 <sub>1.5</sub>Si
 <sub>9</sub> to Au
 <sub>55.5</sub>Cu
 <sub>24.4</sub>Ag
 <sub>6.2</sub>Pd
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>11.9</sub>), in accord with the “tie line” construction assumed in Eq. (
 <xref rid="Equ1" ref-type="">1</xref>). Lastly, the micrographs reveal fairly uniform and rather fine MGMC microstructures, displaying features (i.e. dendrite arm and trunk diameters, interdendritic spacing, etc.) characterized by an average size of less than ~5 μm. Specifically, the average dendrite trunk and dendrite arm diameters appear to be ~3–5 μm in Au
 <sub>60</sub>Cu
 <sub>23.5</sub>Ag
 <sub>9</sub>Pd
 <sub>1.1</sub>Si
 <sub>6.4</sub>, (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>), ~2–4 μm in Au
 <sub>58</sub>Cu
 <sub>24</sub>Ag
 <sub>7.5</sub>Pd
 <sub>1.5</sub>Si
 <sub>9</sub> (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref>), and ~1–3 μm in Au
 <sub>55.5</sub>Cu
 <sub>24.4</sub>Ag
 <sub>6.2</sub>Pd
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>11.9</sub> (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref>) while the average interdendritic spacing appears to be ~1–3 μm in Au
 <sub>60</sub>Cu
 <sub>23.5</sub>Ag
 <sub>9</sub>Pd
 <sub>1.1</sub>Si
 <sub>6.4</sub>, (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>), ~2–4 μm in Au
 <sub>58</sub>Cu
 <sub>24</sub>Ag
 <sub>7.5</sub>Pd
 <sub>1.5</sub>Si
 <sub>9</sub> (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref>), and ~4–6 μm in Au
 <sub>55.5</sub>Cu
 <sub>24.4</sub>Ag
 <sub>6.2</sub>Pd
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>11.9</sub> (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref>). It is noted that for each MGMC composition, the microstructural morphology remains roughly unchanged when changing the sample geometry or size (e.g. plates with thickness of up to 2 mm or rods with diameters of up to 4 mm), suggesting a minimal effect of cooling rate on the microstructure morphology.
</p>
