<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">Metallic glasses offer a wide range of attractive properties, including unique mechanical performance
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup> that sometimes leads to exceptional damage tolerance
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>
 </sup>, excellent corrosion resistance
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup>, and processing capabilities unparalleled in other metals
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>. But these qualities are confined over very narrow compositional ranges where formation of the bulk metallic glass is possible
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>. As such, it is often difficult to “design” metallic glass alloys that offer an optimized combination of desired properties, particularly properties that are mutually exclusive in a metallic glass such as strength and toughness
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. One known strategy to “design” such metallic glasses is by precipitating crystalline dendrites into the metallic glass, thus forming a so called “metallic glass matrix composite” (MGMC)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>. In this concept, the overall composite properties are controlled by features of the dendritic microstructure rather than by the nominal alloy composition. With this approach, combinations of desirable properties may be “designed” in the MGMC by “fine tuning” the dendrite morphology and volume fraction. Damage-tolerant MGMCs have been developed demonstrating unusual combinations of strength and toughness
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>. The bulk of the MGMC development effort to date was directed to optimizing mechanical properties for engineering applications. However, other non-structural properties, like optical properties desirable in cosmetic applications, are rapidly gaining importance in the field. Here, we introduce a MGMC development approach that takes advantage of the glass-forming ability of gold-based alloys and the broad chromaticity range of gold-based solid solutions to design gold MGMCs with controlled color and high hardness.
</p>
