<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par6">MGMCs are generally produced by quenching an initially molten glass former that first undergoes partial crystallization forming a semisolid, followed by vitrification of the remaining glass-forming liquid. The final microstructure consists of isolated dendritic crystals embedded in a continuous metallic glass matrix. These dendritic composites were first reported in (Zr,Ti)-Be glass forming systems
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. The isolated dendritic inclusions are essentially single crystals having the lattice structure of the primary solid solution. The volume fraction of the dendritic phase can range from as low as 10% to as high as 90%, while characteristic sizes of the microstructural features (dendrite trunk and arm diameter, interdendritic spacing, etc.) can range from tens to hundreds of micrometers. While the microstructural feature size appears to be closely dependent on the cooling rate applied to quench the semisolid, the volume fraction of dendrites is controlled almost exclusively by the composition of the overall alloy. Calorimetry and composition analysis reveal that the compositions and phase fractions of the primary phase and the metallic glass matrix are consistent with thermodynamic phase equilibrium
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>. Specifically, the compositions and molar fractions of the dendritic and glassy phases are found to be consistent with a “lever rule” construction between a bcc primary phase and the eutectic liquid. The large lattice mismatch between the primary solid solution and the competing equilibrium intermetallics is believed to be behind the ability of this system to form MGMCs. Such mismatch prevents heterogeneous nucleation of the equilibrium intermetallics over the primary phase dendrites. This lattice mismatch is thought to arise primarily from the large atomic size difference between Be and (Zr,Ti). Aside from the (Zr,Ti)-Be eutectic system, the only other alloy system reported to form “equilibrium” MGMCs is the La-(Cu,Ni)-Al (ref.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>), which also likely arises from the large atomic size difference between La and (Cu,Ni).
</p>
