<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Herein we explore how the synthesis of a diquaternary organic structure‐directing agent (SDA) results in different isomeric versions of the SDA, and how a small difference can lead to the formation of a different zeolite framework. Figure 
 <xref rid="anie201905049-fig-0001" ref-type="fig">1</xref> shows the synthesis path that produces the isomers and their labelling from an earlier work.
 <xref rid="anie201905049-bib-0004" ref-type="ref">4</xref> Initially, we focused on the production of zeolite SSZ‐26 (
 <bold>CON</bold>) and showed that it could be made from two well‐described isomers (isomers I and III).
 <xref rid="anie201905049-bib-0004" ref-type="ref">4</xref> The concept for developing these isomers was to break the fit of an SDA into either 1) a cage accessed by smaller portals, or 2) a single large pore. A past study, juxtaposing the size of the SDA and the SAR conditions, shows a breakdown into 5 types of zeolite products.
 <xref rid="anie201905049-bib-0005" ref-type="ref">5</xref> At the time, we succeeded in creating a material with intersecting pores. In fact, this was the first discovery of a zeolite (SSZ‐26) with both large‐ and medium‐sized pores.
 <xref rid="anie201905049-bib-0006" ref-type="ref">6</xref> During the course of the synthesis explorations for SSZ‐26, we occasionally encountered a different product. Early microporosity studies on the impurity phase, which we termed SSZ‐27, indicated that it had only small pores and selective hydrocarbon uptake. At the time, these materials were not of much developmental interest for catalysis or for separations, so further characterization of SSZ‐27 was not pursued. However, interest in small pore zeolites has recently taken a dramatic upward turn. We therefore revisited the synthesis of SSZ‐27, and show here that the conformation of one of the isolated isomers of the diquaternary SDA (isomer III) is such that it fits particularly well into one of the cavities of SSZ‐27. Here we present the reaction conditions and modelling results that led to the synthesis of SSZ‐27 and to an understanding of how it forms, and its structure determination from electron diffraction data. 
</p>
