<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>At first sight, mullite seems to be the opposite of the ideal candidate for computational studies: the average structure model contains two split-site positions with four partially occupied sites (Sadanaga 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1962
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb66"> ▸</xref>; Burnham, 1963
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb12"> ▸</xref>). The real structure can be understood by the presence of oxygen vacancies which cause significant changes to the surrounding tetrahedral environment (Fig. 1
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> ▸</xref>). The concentration of oxygen vacancies 
 <italic>x</italic> is determined by the Al/Si ratio on the tetrahedral sites and may range from 0 to 1, but most mullite samples grown by solid-state reactions and from the melt exhibit a vacancy concentration between 
 <italic>x</italic> ≃ 0.25 and 
 <italic>x</italic> ≃ 0.4 (Schneider 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2015
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb71"> ▸</xref>). The precise positions and intensities of satellite reflections with a modulation wavevector 
 <bold>q</bold> = (α 0 ½) depend on the chemical composition as the structural modulation changes with the Al/Si ratio (Agrell &amp; Smith, 1960
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb2"> ▸</xref>; Cameron, 1977
 <italic>b</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb16"> ▸</xref>; Ylä-Jääski &amp; Nissen, 1983
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb89"> ▸</xref>). Different degrees of ordering exist, but the tendency to long-range vacancy ordering is rather low in mullite (Klar 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb39"> ▸</xref>). For most samples only weak, low-order satellite reflections are visible in reciprocal space and diffuse scattering is present in all reciprocal-space sections due to correlated disorder (Tokonami 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1980
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb79"> ▸</xref>; Welberry &amp; Butler, 1996
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb84"> ▸</xref>; Freimann &amp; Rahman, 2001
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb27"> ▸</xref>). The complexity of mullite in reciprocal space must originate from vacancy and Al/Si ordering because sillimanite (Al
 <sub>2</sub>SiO
 <sub>5</sub>), which has a very similar average structure, is fully ordered and not modulated (Smith &amp; McConnell, 1966
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb75"> ▸</xref>). Despite several nuclear magnetic resonance measurements and neutron diffraction studies, a clear Al/Si ordering pattern cannot yet be identified (Angel 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1991
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb5"> ▸</xref>; Schmücker 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2005
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb69"> ▸</xref>; Birkenstock 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2015
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb11"> ▸</xref>; Schneider 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2015
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb71"> ▸</xref>). From the modulation of the volumes of tetrahedra it was suggested that Si–Si diclusters tend to be sandwiched between vacancies (Klar 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb39"> ▸</xref>).
</p>
