<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Recently, a vacancy ordering pattern in mullite was identified using the superspace approach (Klar 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017
 <italic>b</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb38"> ▸</xref>). So-called ‘vacancy blocks’ and ‘vacancy-free blocks’ alternate along the 
 <bold>a</bold> and 
 <bold>c</bold> directions (Fig. 2
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> ▸</xref>). The block lengths can be adapted so that superstructures with any vacancy concentration in the range 0 ≤ 
 <italic>x</italic> ≤ 0.5 can be constructed. In the underlying superspace model in the superspace group 
 <italic>Pbam</italic>(α0½)0
 <italic>ss</italic> the block lengths and the chemical composition are related by the relationship between the modulation wavevector 
 <bold>q</bold> = (α 0 ½) and the vacancy concentration 
 <italic>x</italic>, which is α = (1 − 
 <italic>x</italic>)/2 (Klar 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017
 <italic>a</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb37"> ▸</xref>). This superspace description allows one to predict the block structure for an arbitrary composition in the range 0 ≤ 
 <italic>x</italic> ≤ 0.5 based on the concept of unified superspace models (Elcoro 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2000
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb24"> ▸</xref>; Izaola 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2007
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb34"> ▸</xref>). For rational values of 
 <italic>x</italic>, α must also be rational and then the denominator of α determines the length 
 <italic>L</italic> of superstructures with size 
 <italic>L</italic>
 <bold>a</bold> × 1
 <bold>b</bold> × 2
 <bold>c</bold>. The size of each vacancy block can be characterized by the number of vacancies between two vacancy-free blocks counting along the block length. In Fig. 3
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> ▸</xref> the length 
 <italic>L</italic> and the corresponding mean of the number of vacancies, 〈
 <italic>N</italic>
 <sub>V</sub>〉, of commensurate cases are plotted against 
 <italic>x</italic>. If 〈
 <italic>N</italic>
 <sub>V</sub>〉 is integer, then 〈
 <italic>N</italic>
 <sub>V</sub>〉 = 
 <italic>N</italic>
 <sub>V</sub> and all vacancy blocks contain the same number of vacancies. In terms of the vacancy distribution two ranges can be distinguished. For 0 &lt; 
 <italic>x</italic> &lt; 1/3 vacancy blocks are shorter than vacancy-free blocks. For 1/3 &lt; 
 <italic>x</italic> ≤ 0.5 it is the other way around and vacancy blocks are longer than vacancy-free blocks. As a result, mullite superstructures with 
 <italic>x</italic> &lt; 1/3 contain dicluster chains extending along 
 <bold>c</bold> like the dicluster chains in sillimanite. In superstructures with 
 <italic>x</italic> &gt; 1/3 all diclusters either alternate with vacancies or with triclusters. The vacancy concentration 
 <italic>x</italic> = 0.5 marks the endmember because the block pattern cannot be extended to higher vacancy concentrations. In the special case 
 <italic>x</italic> = 1/3 the vacancy blocks and vacancy-free blocks have an infinite length along 
 <bold>a</bold> and 
 <bold>b</bold> which turns the block structure into a layer structure perpendicular to 
 <bold>c</bold> with alternating vacancy layers and vacancy-free layers (Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>). The description of mullite with 
 <italic>x</italic> = 0 is not identical to sillimanite and therefore sillimanite should not be regarded as an endmember of the mullite solid solution range.
</p>
