<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="sec1">Compound copper chalcogenide nanocrystals (NCs) offer a promising alternative to the widely studied CdX and PbX NCs (X = S, Se, Te), as they consist of less toxic elements and display exciting optoelectronic properties, such as photoluminescence (PL) tunability in the visible to the near-infrared (NIR) spectral window and localized surface plasmon resonances (LSPR) in the NIR.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
 </sup> Another advantage of these nanomaterials is the wide range of compositions that can be obtained, ranging from binary to multinary compounds with up to five different elements.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>
 </sup> This makes them a versatile class of materials, offering ample opportunities for property engineering.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>
 </sup> However, some morphologies and compositions are not easily accessible by direct approaches due to synthetic limitations, such as the lack of suitable precursors for multinary compounds.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
 </sup> Nanoscale cation exchange (CE) has emerged as a promising postsynthetic tool to circumvent these limitations, providing pathways to NCs and hetero-NCs with compositions, morphologies, crystal structures, and heteroarchitectures that would otherwise remain unavailable.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
 </sup> The extent of the CE (ranging from doping, 
 <italic>e.g</italic>., Ag:CdSe NCs,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> Zn:CsPbBr
 <sub>3</sub> NCs,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> Mn:ZnTe magic-size clusters,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup> to full replacement)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
 </sup> and the elemental distribution profile of the product NCs (
 <italic>i.e</italic>., homogeneous or gradient alloys, 
 <italic>e.g</italic>., (Cd,Zn)Se NCs,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> or heterostructured NCs, 
 <italic>e.g</italic>., ZnSe/CdSe,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> PbSe/CdSe
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>
 </sup> core/shell quantum dots) depends on a number of physicochemical properties, such as the miscibility of the parent and product phases and the diffusion rates of the incoming and outgoing cations within the NCs and can be tailored by adjusting reaction variables, such as reaction temperature and concentration of guest cations in solution.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
