<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We investigated different GaCl
 <sub>3</sub>–L Lewis acid–base adduct complexes [L = trioctylphosphine (TOP), triphenylphosphite (TPP), and diphenylphosphine DPP)] as reagents for the exchange of Cu
 <sup>+</sup> for Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> and found that the choice of ligand has a profound impact on the reaction outcome. Noncomplexed GaCl
 <sub>3</sub> is a strong Lewis acid that yields hollow NCs through etching by sulfide extraction, whereas the complex GaCl
 <sub>3</sub>–trioctylphosphine leads to neither etching nor cation exchange. In contrast, both GaCl
 <sub>3</sub>–triphenylphosphite and GaCl
 <sub>3</sub>–diphenylphosphine successfully converted Cu
 <sub>2–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>S NCs in CuGaS
 <sub>2</sub> NCs through Cu
 <sup>+</sup> for Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> exchange. These different reactivities are attributed to the stability and geometry of the activated Cu
 <sub>2–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>S–GaCl
 <sub>3</sub>–L complex that must be formed at the surface of the NCs prior to the cation exchange. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that, in these complexes, the Ga–P bond strength decreases with increasing electron-withdrawing nature of the side groups on the phosphine ligands (
 <italic>i.e.</italic>, the Ga–P bond strength ε follows the trend ε
 <sub>GaCl
  <sub>3</sub>–TOP
 </sub> &gt; ε
 <sub>GaCl
  <sub>3</sub>–DPP
 </sub> &gt; ε
 <sub>GaCl
  <sub>3</sub>–TPP
 </sub>). Complexing GaCl
 <sub>3</sub> with DPP or TPP lowers the activation energy barrier for the CE reaction, while kinetically favoring the Cu
 <sup>+</sup> for Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> place exchange over the sulfide extraction. These insights were used to successfully convert CuInS
 <sub>2</sub> NCs into Cu-poor (Cu,In,Ga)S
 <sub>2</sub> NCs through Cu
 <sup>+</sup> for Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> exchange, yielding NCs with vastly improved photoluminescence quantum yields with respect to the parent NCs. The findings presented in this work are thus generally applicable, resulting in nanomaterials with combinations of size, shape, composition, and crystal structure that are not directly accessible by conventional synthesis routes.
</p>
