<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This work presents results of research regarding elastic properties of a hard sphere system with a periodic stack of monolayer inclusions oriented perpendicularly to 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm5">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mo>[</mo>
     <mn>001</mn>
     <mo>]</mo>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>-direction. The selection of the hard potential, infinite when any pair of particles overlap and zero otherwise, is not incidental. The model of hard spheres is the simplest example of the class of hard body models which are governed by the entropy [
 <xref rid="B1-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. It serves as a fundamental reference model for melting and theory of liquids [
 <xref rid="B2-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Moreover, models with purely geometrical, hard interactions between particles are athermal. As a result, their phase diagrams are simplified as the pressure, 
 <italic>p</italic>, and the temperature, 
 <italic>T</italic>, occur only as the 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm6">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mi>p</mi>
     <mo>/</mo>
     <mi>T</mi>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> ratio. In the theory of elasticity, the hard potential acts as the limiting case for anharmonic interactions. For these reasons, various properties and behaviors of hard spheres were the subject of intense studies [
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. As an example, one might refer to the study of elastic properties of the face-centered cubic (f.c.c.) crystal of hard spheres, where it has been shown that by increasing concentration of vacancies one can modify its elastic properties, in particular increase Poisson’s ratio (PR) [
 <xref rid="B16-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. The PR is a negative ratio of the relative changes of lateral to longitudinal dimensions of a body subjected to an infinitesimal change of uniaxial stress applied in the longitudinal direction, and is one of the parameters that characterize how materials deform when subjected to an external stress [
 <xref rid="B17-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. The value of Poisson’s ratio can vary in the range between 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm7">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mo>−</mo>
     <mn>1</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> and 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm8">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mn>1</mn>
     <mo>/</mo>
     <mn>2</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> for isotropic three-dimensional systems. However, for most of the materials that we know from our surrounding, its value falls in the range between 0 (e.g., cork) and ∼0.5 (e.g., rubber) [
 <xref rid="B17-materials-12-00700" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>].
</p>
