<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The example of Fig. 2(
 <italic>b</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> ▸</xref> was calculated for an initial kinetic energy of 4 keV and an acceptance of 18 Å
 <sup>−1</sup> diameter in 
 <italic>k</italic>-space. The extractor field was switched on (1 kV mm
 <sup>−1</sup>), yielding the 
 <italic>k</italic>-image of the near-normal-emission region. The example on the right of Fig. 2(
 <italic>b</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> ▸</xref> is the Kikuchi pattern of a graphite single crystal, recorded on the C 1
 <italic>s</italic> core-level signal; the ToF spectrum is shown in (
 <italic>a</italic>). The new objective lens allows working without an acceleration field between sample and anode; in this mode the lens elements behind the first electrode focus the beam. The ray-tracing calculation of this mode is shown in Fig. 2(
 <italic>c</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> ▸</xref>, simulated for an initial energy of 8 keV. The example on the right of Fig. 2(
 <italic>c</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> ▸</xref> is the off-normal C 1
 <italic>s</italic> Kikuchi pattern of a graphite single crystal, recorded for a sample tilt of 30° with respect to the optical axis of the microscope. Patching many such patterns would allow large angular ranges to be observed. Despite zero extractor field, 
 <italic>k</italic>-fields as large as 16 Å
 <sup>−1</sup> can be recorded without visible aberrations (corresponding to a full cone angle of 35° at 2.765 keV). For the same kinetic energy at the sample, a moderate extractor field of 1.5 kV mm
 <sup>−1</sup> yields 
 <italic>k</italic>-fields up to 22 Å
 <sup>−1</sup>, a larger field of 3 kV mm
 <sup>−1</sup> yields 
 <italic>k</italic>-fields up to 25 Å
 <sup>−1</sup> on the 80 mm image detector and even larger fields for larger detectors. For a given signal strength this instrument yields an order-of-magnitude higher total intensity in comparison with the low-energy ToF 
 <italic>k</italic>-microscope used in the soft X-ray range (Medjanik 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb47"> ▸</xref>). For full-field imaging microscopes the resolved number of 
 <italic>k</italic>-points is limited by the detector, hence large 
 <italic>k</italic>-fields like in Fig. 2
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> ▸</xref> come at the expense of 
 <italic>k</italic>-resolution. The 
 <italic>k</italic>-resolution limit is defined by a typical value of 500 resolved 
 <italic>k</italic>-points along the image diameter. This translates into a 
 <italic>k</italic>-resolution of 0.03 Å
 <sup>−1</sup> for large image fields like Fig. 2(
 <italic>b</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> ▸</xref>. Reduction of the 
 <italic>k</italic>-field via the electron optics (zoom optics 2) improves the 
 <italic>k</italic>-resolution accordingly.
</p>
