<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Among the possible terminations, the (101) facet is found to be the most stable anatase surface (Labat et al., 
 <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">2008</xref>) and represents a significant portion of the exposed surface area in the equilibrium crystallites that are characteristic of polycrystalline surfaces (Lazzeri et al., 
 <xref rid="B29" ref-type="bibr">2001</xref>; Barnard and Curtiss, 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">2005</xref>). The large anatase band gap (3.2 eV) limits its photocatalytic activity to the small ultraviolet portion of the solar spectrum (Hagfeldt and Grätzel, 
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">1995</xref>). This has led to the use of a wide variety of approaches to engineer the band gap in order to enhance the activity. These include the incorporation of metallic and non-metallic ion impurities (Hoffmann et al., 
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">1995</xref>). Hydrogen impurities are also usually introduced during processing and have significant influence on material properties, and therefore on the device performance. It is well established that hydrogen defects affect the ionic conductivity, electronic, and optical properties of both the bulk crystal and its surfaces (Amano et al., 
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>). Hydrogen binds to lattice O
 <sup>2−</sup> ions to form OH
 <sup>−</sup> and this n-dopes the crystal modifying its electronic structure and, at elevated temperatures, proton transport makes a significant contribution to the ionic conductivity (Amano et al., 
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>). Oxygen vacancies also play an important role in determining the surface chemistry and electronic properties of TiO
 <sub>2</sub> (Morgan and Watson, 
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>; Pan et al., 
 <xref rid="B37" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; Hongfei et al., 
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). Under typical processing conditions the dominant intrinsic defect is the oxygen vacancy, which also n-dopes the crystal and significantly affects photocatalytic properties (Liborio and Harrison, 
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">2008</xref>). Previous DFT calculations have shown that TiO
 <sub>2</sub> typically accommodates n-doping in localized states within the band gaps approximately 1eV below the CBM. These states could extend optical absorption to the visible region (Justicia et al., 
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">2002</xref>; Liborio and Harrison, 
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">2008</xref>). An alternative, and potentially complementary, approach is to enhance light absorption through surface species as happens in dye-sensitized solar cells (Graetzel, 
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">2001</xref>). The details of the binding of the dye molecules to the surface are crucial for the improvement of device performance, with phthalocyanines being the most widely studied sysetm (Godlewski and Szymonski, 
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>).
</p>
