<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The 
 <italic>valence-band 
  <italic>k</italic>-patterns
 </italic> in Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref> have been corrected for an underlying background originating from quasi-elastic phonon scattering. The ratio of non-scattered photoelectrons from the direct transition [as sketched in Fig. 6(
 <italic>a</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>] to all emitted electrons is governed by the Debye–Waller factor. The case of rhenium is favorable because it is heavy (
 <italic>Z</italic> = 75) and has a high Debye temperature (416 K). Due to its high Debye–Waller factor at 30 K, one expects a fraction of 25% non-scattered photoelectrons for a kinetic energy of 3.5 keV. This background has a spectral distribution given by the matrix-element-weighted density of states (Osterwalder 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1990
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb51"> ▸</xref>, 1996
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb52"> ▸</xref>; Herman 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1992
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb26"> ▸</xref>; Trehan 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1987
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb72"> ▸</xref>; Krüger 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2011
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb35"> ▸</xref>), and can be corrected as described by Gray 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2011
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb23"> ▸</xref>). In addition, this background carries a Kikuchi-type diffraction signature because after phonon scattering the electrons are diffracted at the lattice. In fact, the diffraction pattern of the background is identical to a core-level diffraction pattern taken at the same final-state energy and identical settings of the microscope (
 <italic>k</italic>-field-of-view, energy). Moreover, also the valence-band patterns themselves show diffraction effects. We found that an efficient way to remove the diffraction modulation of background and true valence-electron signal is pixel-by-pixel division of the as-measured valence-band map by a core-level XPD pattern at the same final-state energy. This procedure was applied to the rhenium valence-band maps shown in Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref>. For more details on the correction procedure and its relation to the Debye–Waller factor, see Babenkov 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2019
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb2"> ▸</xref>). So far, we have not studied the recoil effect of the photoelectrons as discussed for example by Takata 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2008
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb68"> ▸</xref>) and Suga &amp; Sekiyama (2014
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb67"> ▸</xref>). Given our energy resolution of 60 meV [with the Si(333) monochromator crystal], it should be easily possible to observe this effect, especially in compound materials or heterogeneous systems containing heavy and light elements.
</p>
