<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>At first sight, the patterns in Fig. 8
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig8"> ▸</xref> do not exhibit systematic features that allow for an analysis. Instead, all patterns look strongly different and seem to have nothing in common except for the sixfold symmetry. In large angular ranges, XPD patterns are dominated by strong forward scattering along atom rows (Fadley, 1987
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb14"> ▸</xref>, 1992
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb18"> ▸</xref>, 2012
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb16"> ▸</xref>; Winkelmann 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2008
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb78"> ▸</xref>), allowing for an analysis in real-space (polar) coordinates. Luckily, some of our small-angle diffractogram, Figs. 8(
 <italic>b</italic>), 8(
 <italic>c</italic>) and 8(
 <italic>f</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig8"> ▸</xref>, exhibit patterns with straight 
 <italic>Kikuchi lines</italic>, which allow for an orientation in 
 <italic>k</italic>-space. Kikuchi lines are conveniently explained in terms of Bragg reflection at lattice planes (Kikuchi, 1928
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb32"> ▸</xref>). In the small angular range close to normal emission, we expect to see a sixfold-symmetric pattern of Kikuchi bands, originating from Bragg reflection at sets of lattice planes perpendicular to the surface. Fig. 8(
 <italic>g</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig8"> ▸</xref> shows a model of the Re lattice with marked lattice planes with spacing 
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="s-26-01996-efi5.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula>. In a momentum image this set of planes leads to a Kikuchi band of width 
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="s-26-01996-efi6.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> (4.552 Å
 <sup>−1</sup>), confined by dark lines on both sides. Owing to the small photoelectron wavelength, the Bragg angle is very small. At 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>final</sub> = 5.970 keV we have |
 <bold>
  <italic>k</italic>
 </bold>
 <sub>final</sub>| = 38.4 Å
 <sup>−1</sup> [taking into account the photon momentum contribution according to equation (4)
 <xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="fd4"/>] and θ
 <sub>Bragg</sub> = 3.4°, so that the Bragg-scattered electrons appear in our field of view. Note that the lower part of Fig. 8(
 <italic>g</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig8"> ▸</xref> is a real-space model, whereas the upper part is drawn in 
 <italic>k</italic>-space coordinates. The clearest signature of Kikuchi bands crossing under ±60° is visible at 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>final</sub> = 3.370 keV as indicated by the dashed lines in the lower part of Fig. 8(
 <italic>b</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig8"> ▸</xref>. Particularly prominent points in all patterns are the crossing points of dark lines confining the Kikuchi bands. These points can be identified in all diffractograms (
 <italic>a</italic>–
 <italic>f</italic>); two of these dark crossing points are marked by circles in all panels of Fig. 8
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig8"> ▸</xref>. We conclude that, although patterns (
 <italic>a</italic>–
 <italic>f</italic>) look quite different, they all carry the signature of the sixfold Kikuchi band, originating from Bragg reflection at the 
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="s-26-01996-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> lattice planes.
</p>
