<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is eye-catching that the sharpness of the features in Fig. 8
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig8"> ▸</xref> increases with energy. When increasing the final-state energy from 2.77 to 5.97 keV [sequence (
 <italic>a</italic>)–(
 <italic>f</italic>)], two trends are important: the photoelectron wavelength drops from 23.2 pm to 15.8 pm and the inelastic mean free path λ
 <sub>IMFP</sub> increases from ∼3 nm to ∼5.4 nm. Photoelectron diffraction can be described in a real-space cluster model (Trehan 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1987
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb72"> ▸</xref>; Krüger 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2011
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb35"> ▸</xref>), which is equivalent to the Bloch-wave model (Winkelmann 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2008
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb78"> ▸</xref>) if both are fully converged. Significant diffraction contributions can be expected until the amplitudes of the scattered wave have dropped to ∼10% of the initial intensity, 
 <italic>i.e.</italic> for a linear distance from the emitter atom up to 2.3λ
 <sub>IMFP</sub> (the information depth is usually assumed to be ∼3λ
 <sub>IMFP</sub>). Given the nearest-neighbor distance of the Re atoms of 0.276 nm, we estimate that in a cluster-type real-space model about 100000 to 400000 atoms [in the sequence (
 <italic>a</italic>) to (
 <italic>f</italic>)] contribute significantly to the diffraction pattern. We have found that the XPD results for graphite [an example is shown in Fig. 2(
 <italic>b</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> ▸</xref>] can be perfectly described using the Bloch-wave approach to XPD (Fedchenko 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2019
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb21"> ▸</xref>). Since the photoelectron wavelength is more than an order of magnitude smaller than the nearest-neighbor distance, phase differences caused by small changes in the lattice structure are ‘amplified’ by this factor. The rich structure in Figs. 2(
 <italic>b</italic>), 2(
 <italic>c</italic>), 7 and 8
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> ▸</xref> indicates that high-resolution small-angle XPD has the potential of being a very sensitive structural tool, in particular due to the inherent element specificity of XPD.
</p>
