<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par14">The morphologies of the hydrated Na-bir and dehydrated Na-bir were characterized by field-effect scanning electron microscopy (FE-SEM; JEOL JSM-6700F, operated at 10 and 30 kV), and high-resolution-transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM, FEI Tecnai G2 F30, operated at 300 kV), using the Gatan Digital Micrograph program. Annular dark field (ADF) imaging mode was employed to observe the structures of the partially dehydrated Na-bir samples on an aberration-corrected scanning transmission electron microscope (STEM, JEM-ARM200CF, JEOL) equipped with a cold-field emission electron gun at an accelerating voltage of 80 kV. The detector angle range for the ADF imaging was ~45–180 mrad and the probe forming angle was ~23 mrad. Experimental ADF-STEM images were denoised by the Wiener filtering method implemented in a commercial software program (HREM Filter Pro, HREM research Ltd.). Energy-dispersive X-ray mapping for the Na-bir samples before and after charging was performed on the same ADF-STEM imaging mode with a dual-type silicon drift detector (JED-2300T, JEOL Ltd.) providing a large effective solid angle (~1.2 sr). The residual moisture content in the products was determined by thermogravimetric analysis (TGA). The compositions and concentration of Mn
 <sup>2+</sup> deposited on Na anode were determined by ICP-AES (OPTIMA 7300 DV, Perkin-Elmer). The XPS spectra were analyzed by K-Alpha+, ThermoScientific installed at Hanyang Center for Research Facilities (Seoul). The Mn K-edge XAFS was conducted under the transmission mode at the 8C (Nano XAFS) beamline in the Pohang Light Source-II (PLS-II). The soft X-ray absorption spectra were obtained at beamline 10D XAS KIST (Korea Institute of Science and Technology) in the PLS-II. The Na K-edge XANES were collected under total electron yield mode in vacuum ~5 × 10
 <sup>–8</sup> Torr. The in situ XRD measurements of partially dehydrated Na-bir was performed at beamline 9A (U-SAXS) PLS-II using a ccd image plate detector with wavelength of 0.62147 Å and beamline 3D-XRS PLS-II using a MAR3450 image plate detector with wavelength of 1.03337 Å in the transmission mode. The storage ring was operated at electron energy of 3.0 GeV and a current of 320 mA. The X-ray exposure time was 10 s, and it took about 3 min to get a single pattern. The two-theta angles of all the patterns presented have been recalculated to the corresponding angles for 
 <italic>λ</italic> = 1.54 Å, which is the wavelength of conventional X-ray tube source with CuKα radiations, for an easy comparison with other published results.
</p>
