<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par19">Since the straightforward explanations of the 
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sub>N</sub> increase, based on disorder-induced structure modification, do not explain this rather unusual behavior, it is necessary to consider other possibilities. For example, in materials near a magnetic instability, it has recently been posited
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>
 </sup> that charge doping can induce a magnetic transition based on Stoner physics, and one could plausibly imagine a similar enhancement in magnetic character of an already magnetic material. However, the generally stoichiometric character of both samples studied here argues against such a possibility. An additional possibility is provided by the theoretical work of Gastiasoro 
 <italic>et al</italic>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup>, which finds (for superconductivity, and extended to magnetic order) density-of-states increase from either resonant states or Anderson localization leading to enhancements in ordering points. We here suggest a different possibility: spin fluctuations are known to be exceptionally strong in the iron arsenides, and in fact are a leading candidate for the interaction causing superconductivity. It is commonly believed
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>
 </sup> that these fluctuations also play an important role in reducing the Néel point of these materials from a much higher ‘bare’ value. It is also known from several recent theory works
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>
 </sup> that disorder can play a substantial role in weakening spin fluctuations and inducing magnetism, and this role is especially prominent
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>
 </sup> in the case of stripe magnetic order, as is observed in the iron-arsenides. Putting such arguments together, we suggest that the disorder evident in our specific heat and neutron data is weakening the spin fluctuations and thereby enhancing the magnetic order.
</p>
