<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>For a typical synthesis, boron and silicon starting material were intimately but gently mixed in an agate mortar, avoiding grinding. Considered molar proportions Si/B ranged from 1:1 to 1:4. Mixtures were subsequently pressed into pellets with 4 or 6 mm diameter. For this, the highest pressure tolerable with the pressing tool was applied (∼250 MPa). The height of a pellet was between 1 and 1.5 mm, the weight of 4 mm pellets was around 15 mg, and that of 6 mm pellets about 40 mg. It is important to mention that reproducible results could only be obtained with well-pressed and homogenously dense pellets and using starting materials from the same batch. One or several pellets were placed in a BN crucible, which in turn was inserted in a niobium ampule. Alternatively, a Nb ampule was filled with slightly compacted BN powder into which Si–B pellets were embedded. Nb ampules were sealed shut by arc welding, removed from the glovebox, and then placed in a high-temperature furnace, in which they were heated in an Ar atmosphere. Target temperatures were in a range of 1100–1300 °C, and dwelling times varied from several hours to several days, up to 2 weeks. The typically applied heating rate was 200 °C/h. After dwelling, the samples were cooled by switching off the furnace. To achieve complete and precise control of the sample/reaction temperature, systematic investigations were performed in a Netzsch STA 449 F1 Jupiter thermal analysis apparatus using a thermogravimetric analysis sample rod. For this, 4 mm pellets of reaction mixture were placed in polycrystalline sapphire crucibles (5 mm ID, 6 mm OD, 5 mm height) from CoorsTek, which were covered with a thin corundum lid. Heating ramps were 10 °C/min. All Jupiter experiments were performed using a continuous Ar gas flow (5 N, 85 mL/min) and in the presence of an oxygen getter (Zr metal). Pellets were broken into pieces after sintering, which were either ground for powder X-ray diffraction (PXRD) or used for scanning electron microscopy analysis.</p>
