<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is well known that quasi‐2D perovskites are usually multiphase structures, and the phase impurity and disordered materials increase the likelihood to trap carriers, causing nonradiative recombination, thereby reducing emission efficiency. Thus, the precise regulation of components is crucial for effective radiation. However, the defects of 3D perovskites are caused by the halide vacancies in the material, or the surface dangling bonds made by the falling off of the surface ligands.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0146" ref-type="ref">146</xref> In addition, the perovskite film obtained through the solution process, whether 3D or 2D perovskites, is treated at a low temperature, meaning that there is a great possibility to form surface defects.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0113" ref-type="ref">113</xref> Therefore, improving the crystallinity of thin films is an important way to reduce defects. In addition to quenching temperature, the quasi‐2D perovskite films obtained by the solution process have a smaller crystal size than 3D perovskite films, which will increase the defect concentration on the surface and grain boundary of the films and the defects become the centers of nonradiative recombination, thereby reducing the emission efficiency. In addition, high surface area and porosity will also provide a greater probability of oxygen or water penetration. Recent reports have confirmed that 2D perovskites have a lower defect trap density due to the presence of ligands (organic amine cation) compared with 3D perovskites.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0122" ref-type="ref">122</xref> In 3D perovskite LEDs and solar cells, surface passivation and doping are extensively studied as effective ways to reduce surface defect density. However, for quasi‐2D perovskite, these reports are relatively few. Stability is also an important indicator of device performance. The reported (quasi‐) 2D perovskites' electroluminescent lifetimes are listed in 
 <bold>Table</bold>
 <xref rid="advs1307-tbl-0004" ref-type="table">
  <bold>4</bold>
 </xref>.
</p>
