<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A series of LEDs with perovskite films that contain 1‐naphthylmethylamine iodide (NMAI), FAI/FABr, and PbI
 <sub>2</sub> with a molar ratio of 2:1:2 was reported by Huang's group.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0121" ref-type="ref">121</xref> A wide range of EL was achieved by adjusting the proportion of halogen components in the precursor solution, and the highest EQE of up to 11.7% at 763 nm with a radiance of 82 W sr
 <sup>−1</sup> m
 <sup>−2</sup> was achieved by (NMA)
 <sub>2</sub>Pb
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>6</sub>Br (NFPI
 <sub>6</sub>Br) perovskite. Good device performance resulted from the complete surface coverage of the film, which reduces defects and leakage current, thereby suppressing nonradiative recombination. More importantly, the LEDs show improved lifetime due to the device's high efficiency and the perovskite film's superior stability. As shown in 
 <bold>Figure</bold>
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0009" ref-type="fig">
  <bold>9</bold>
 </xref>a, after 2 h continuous working at a current density of 10 mA cm
 <sup>−2</sup>, the EQE only decreases to half of its initial value. In order to reduce the efficiency roll‐off at high current density, Huang's group tuned the QW width by increasing the proportion of FA cation (the molar ratio of NMAI, FAI, and PbI
 <sub>2</sub> changed from 2:1:2 to 2:1.9:2 in the precursors). The formation of wider QWs is proved by a 5.6 nm redshift of the PL peak. The wider QWs also suppress the luminescence quenching, so the EQE of LEDs is further improved to 12.7%. Additionally, the efficiency roll‐off is greatly reduced, and the efficiency is still maintained at about 10% under a current density of 500 mA cm
 <sup>−2</sup> (Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0009" ref-type="fig">9</xref>b). The device has a highest radiance of 254 W sr
 <sup>−1</sup> m
 <sup>−2</sup> in solution‐processed near‐infrared LEDs.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0132" ref-type="ref">132</xref> The highest EQE of 20.1% of 2D perovskite LEDs to date in the near‐infrared range was reported by Friend's group,
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0136" ref-type="ref">136</xref> which is based on (NMA)
 <sub>2</sub>(FA)Pb
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>7</sub> 2D perovskite and poly‐HEMA (HEMA = 2‐hydroxyethyl methacrylate). This excellent EQE results from the ultrafast migration of excitons, which takes only ≈1 ps. It makes nonradiative recombination uncompetitive in dynamics and thus greatly suppresses bulk and interfacial nonradiative recombination.
</p>
