<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The burgeoning field of flat panel displays now encompasses both inorganic and organic electroluminescent LEDs;
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0043" ref-type="ref">43</xref> nevertheless, LCDs have maintained their dominant position in this field. The main advantages of LCDs are their low power consumption, low driving voltages, and cheap fabrication. There has been a vivid discussion in the display technology field on the topic “
 <italic>LCD versus OLED (organic light emitting diodes), who wins?</italic>”
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0044" ref-type="ref">44</xref> Both technologies have their own merits. Generally speaking, LCDs are leading in lifetime, brightness, and manufacturing cost, and they are comparable to OLEDs in resolution density, power consumption, ambient contrast ratio, and viewing angle but inferior to OLEDs in black state, panel flexibility, color gamut, and response time. However, recently introduced QD backlight technology has narrowed the performance gap between the LCD and OLED
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0044" ref-type="ref">44</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0045" ref-type="ref">45</xref> and offered wider color gamut and lower power consumption. Furthermore, local dimming boosts the dynamic contrast ratio to 1 000 000:1.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0046" ref-type="ref">46</xref> The remaining challenge for LCDs is the response time, which is ≈100 times slower than in OLED. In reality, this is only a superficial challenge due to the limitation imposed by the addressing time of the thin film transistors. A range of approaches to improve the response time versus polymer‐stabilized blue phase LCs,
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0047" ref-type="ref">47</xref> low viscosity nematic LCs,
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0048" ref-type="ref">48</xref> and ferroelectric LCs
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0049" ref-type="ref">49</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0051" ref-type="ref">51</xref> have been suggested; however, their limited brightness and energy efficiency, as well as their often unsatisfying viewing angle leave ample room for further improvements. The severe brightness and efficiency limitations of LCDs arise primarily because of the polarizers and absorbing color filters, that results in a large fraction of optical loss for the backlight.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0050" ref-type="ref">50</xref> A simple illustration of the LCD components, along with an estimation of their light efficiency and brightness are provided in 
 <bold>Figure</bold>
 <xref rid="advs1374-fig-0013" ref-type="fig">
  <bold>13</bold>
 </xref>.
</p>
