<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The first 2D layered perovskite solar cells based on (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>(MA)
 <sub>2</sub>Pb
 <sub>3</sub>I
 <sub>10</sub> were reported to have a PCE of 4.7%.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0039" ref-type="ref">39</xref> Compared to MAPbI
 <sub>3</sub>, the 2D perovskite is more resistant to moisture, and due to the wider bandgap, the 2D structure is also suitable for the higher‐bandgap absorber in the dual‐absorber devices. Moreover, in terms of material optimization, 2D perovskite structure presents greater tunability at the molecular level. To date, a large number of 2D perovskite absorbers have been synthesized with significantly improved efficiencies.[qv: 35,64a,149] Sargent's group reported a PCE of 15.3% for quasi‐perovskite PEA
 <sub>2</sub>(CH
 <sub>3</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>−1</sub>Pb
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>I
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>+1</sub> (
 <italic>n</italic> = 60). It shows an excellent stability with the efficiency remaining at about 13% after 2 weeks in a humid environment, while the efficiency of 3D MAPbI
 <sub>3</sub> perovskite decreases from 16.6% to 4.3% in 3 days.[qv: 149d] (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(MA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>3</sub>‐based solar cell with PCE of 4.02% was obtained by Cao et al.[qv: 15a] Although the introduction of BA organic cation promotes resistance to moisture more than the 3D counterparts, it also causes out‐of‐plane charge transport inhibition. Notably, Tsai et al. overcame this disadvantage and achieved a vertical orientation of perovskite layers to the substrate by means of a hot‐casting deposition method. From the synchronous diffraction data, the main growth direction of perovskite is along (101) plane parallel to the 
 <italic>q
  <sub>z</sub>
 </italic> direction. This unique orientation enables the photogenerated electrons and holes to move along the inorganic layer to the device's electrodes, respectively, avoiding the inhibition of organic layers. Such an efficient charge transport results in a PCE of 12.5% for (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(MA)
 <sub>3</sub>Pb
 <sub>4</sub>I
 <sub>13</sub> absorber solar cells.[qv: 35]
</p>
