<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the present mini-review, we briefly analyzed the state of art in the field of R&amp;D of organic-inorganic and all-inorganic lead-free perovskites as crystal materials of different dimensionality with improved functional (detection and emission) properties for modern nanophotonics and photovoltaics. The main attention was paid to the recent publications on the development of active media based on lead-free perovskite materials for light sources demonstrating stimulated emission (lasing). The choice and design of laser resonators, influence of morphology of the perovskite active media, and methods for tuning the wavelength of laser emission were discussed. The almost 100% emission QY, possibility to change the lasing wavelength by changing the perovskite chemical composition and morphology, as well as by choice of type and design of resonators make perovskite-based active media very attractive for implementing in laser and lighting sources. It is important to mention that synthetic routes and device fabrication previously developed for lead-based perovskite materials can be efficiently inherent and adopted for their lead-free relatives, hence paving the way to perovskite “green” photonics. Although the number of scientific papers devoted to lead-free perovskite materials have increased in the past few years, there is still plenty of room for further development and improvement of their optical and electronic properties. According to the literature, at least 600 lead-free compounds with double perovskite crystal structure have not been investigated yet [
 <xref rid="B16-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. Along with the variety of chemical composition of lead-free perovskite materials, the chemical approaches of their synthesis and passivation are still unexplored. Thus, we highlight perspectives in the field of lead-free perovskites for lighting applications:
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p>Chemical composition and morphology. To date, Bi-based perovskite materials provide a wide variety of morphology of materials with perovskite symmetry, including double perovskites, along with the excellent and stable performance. The other direction is the search of novel chemical compounds for substituting the lead atom in lanthanide series, such as Yb;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Synthetic approaches. Inspired by the chemical routes implemented for lead-based perovskites, the vapor deposition approaches might be admitted as synthesis route for formation micrometer-sized lead-free perovskites, the shape of which can meet the resonance conditions for stimulated amplification of the emission;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Active medium protection. The use of the matrices for in-situ synthesis or as host matrices for perovskite materials can expand the variety of chemical compounds used, i.e., unstable in ambient, together with simple control of the architecture of the active medium defined by matrix morphology.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
