<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In order to clarify the electronic structure of 
 <bold>2</bold>, DFT calculations at the B3LYP/def2‐TZVP level of theory were performed. The orbital interaction diagram (Figure 
 <xref rid="anie201909423-fig-0002" ref-type="fig">2</xref>) shows that the π orbitals of the As
 <sub>2</sub>H
 <sub>2</sub> ligand are stabilized while the As−As σ bond is slightly destabilized upon coordination. The overlap of the Highest Occupied Molecular Orbital (HOMO) of the As
 <sub>2</sub>H
 <sub>2</sub> ligand with the Lowest Unoccupied Molecular Orbital (LUMO) of the Fe(CO)
 <sub>4</sub> fragment represents the π‐donor coordination mode. The Fe‐As backbonding becomes obvious by the overlap of the HOMO orbital of the Fe(CO)
 <sub>4</sub> fragment with the LUMO orbital (which is the As=As π* orbital) of the As
 <sub>2</sub>H
 <sub>2</sub> ligand, which leads to the HOMO−1 orbital in 
 <bold>2</bold>. Considering the main fragment contribution to the HOMO−1 and HOMO−2 orbitals, complex 
 <bold>2</bold> can be best described as an olefin‐like complex. The NBO analysis
 <xref rid="anie201909423-bib-0021" ref-type="ref">21</xref> shows NBO orbits corresponding to an As−As bond, which is realized by almost pure p orbitals (sp
 <sup>11</sup> hybrid orbital) and two Fe−As bonds. The occupancy of the latter two is 1.75e and polarized toward iron. The lone pair of the arsenic atoms are of high s character (sp
 <sup>0.3</sup> hybrid orbitals). The Wiberg Bond Indices show an As−As bond order of 1.18, which indicates the multiple bond character and a bond order of 0.73 for the Fe‐As bonds. For comparison, the WBI of the As−Fe bond in 
 <bold>1</bold> is 0.58, while the WBI of the As−As bond in the free 
 <italic>trans</italic>‐As
 <sub>2</sub>H
 <sub>2</sub> is 2.05. Further, the electronic structure of 
 <bold>2</bold> was investigated by the Bader's theory of atoms in molecules (AIM).
 <xref rid="anie201909423-bib-0022" ref-type="ref">22</xref> Bond Critical Points (BCPs) could be located corresponding to the As−As and two As−Fe bonds with electron densities of 0.090 e a.u.
 <sup>−3</sup> and 0.057 e a.u.
 <sup>−3</sup>, respectively. The Laplacian at the BCP corresponding to the As−As bond is negative (∇
 <sup>2</sup>
 <italic>ρ</italic>=−0.046 e a.u.
 <sup>−5</sup>), while the one at the BCPs corresponding to the As−Fe bond is positive (∇
 <sup>2</sup>
 <italic>ρ</italic>=0.046 e a.u.
 <sup>−5</sup>). The positive Laplacian at the BCPs of the Fe−As bond and the negative energy density values (−0.273 hartee a.u.
 <sup>−3</sup>) indicate a moderately polar Fe−As bond. The pronounced ellipticity at these BCPs of 0.24 and 0.28 for the BCPs corresponding to the As−As as well as the As−Fe bonds, respectively, indicates the concentration of the electron density in the FeAs
 <sub>2</sub> plane. Based on the WBIs, complex 
 <bold>2</bold> can be described as a diarsa‐metallacyclopropane while, based on the fragment contribution to the molecular orbitals, complex 
 <bold>2</bold> can be better described with a Dewar–Chatt–Duncanson model. The latter is also confirmed by the torsion angles of the As
 <sub>2</sub>H
 <sub>2</sub> unit being close to 90°.
 <xref rid="anie201909423-bib-0003c" ref-type="ref">3c</xref>, 
 <xref rid="anie201909423-bib-0003d" ref-type="ref">3d</xref>, 
 <xref rid="anie201909423-bib-0018" ref-type="ref">18</xref>
</p>
