<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Intensities of IFRB calculated using equation (16)
 <xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="fd16"/> are shown in Figs. 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>), 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>), 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>c</italic>) for β = −0.02, −0.01 and 0.0 mm
 <sup>−1</sup>, respectively. The integer value at each peak denotes the value of Δθ in equation (17)
 <xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="fd17"/>. The distance between two adjacent peaks increases as the distance 
 <italic>x</italic> increases or the value of 
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="a-75-00842-efi26.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> decreases. The inset of Fig. 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref> shows the variations of IFRB (the solid curve) for β = −0.02 mm
 <sup>−1</sup> in the range of 
 <italic>x</italic> between 5.5 and 8.5 mm, which corresponds to the shaded area in Fig. 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>). For comparison, the calculated intensity variation of IFMRB is also shown for β = 0.02 mm
 <sup>−1</sup>. The IFMRB intensities are calculated by assuming the interference between the mirage diffraction beam 
 <bold>S</bold>′
 <sub>m1</sub> and the beam 
 <bold>S</bold>′
 <sub>2</sub> reflected from the back surface in Fig. 1
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>) and using the formula given by Jongsukswat 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2012
 <italic>b</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb17"> ▸</xref>). The number of interference fringes of IFRB is ten and that of IFMRB is three. The distance between two adjacent peaks increases as the distance 
 <italic>x</italic> increases in both the IFRB and IFMRB. The calculated results in Fig. 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>) and the inset agree quite well with the observed results in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref> at least qualitatively. Based on this good agreement the strain gradient parameter of the present crystal is determined to be β = −0.02 mm
 <sup>−1</sup>. In order to determine the value of β only from IFRB, it is necessary to measure the interference fringes for 
 <italic>x</italic> more than 17 mm as the difference in the period of the fringes becomes conspicuous for large 
 <italic>x</italic> as can be seen in Fig. 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>. It is possible for the beams 
 <bold>S</bold>′
 <sub>m1</sub> and 
 <bold>S</bold>′
 <sub>2</sub> (in the BbB mode) to interfere with the beam in the B3bB mode to form the IFMRB. However, as described in Section 3.2
 <xref ref-type="sec" rid="sec3.2"/>, the amplitude of the beam in the B3bB mode is much smaller than that of the mirage diffraction beam 
 <bold>S</bold>′
 <sub>m1</sub> because of three more reflections than 
 <bold>S</bold>′
 <sub>m1</sub>.
</p>
