<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par30">where 
 <bold>F</bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>eff</italic>
 </sub> is the effective confining force due to the neighboring clusters
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>
 </sup>. The mean cluster positions, 
 <bold>R</bold>
 <sup>(
  <italic>j</italic>)
 </sup>, are located on a hexagonal structure as in the purely Brownian case (
 <italic>U</italic>
 <sub>0</sub> = 0) since the inter-cluster distance does not change significantly by the presence of the active force. The complex dynamics of interacting microswimmers is approximated by a set of independent particles in the presence of a grid of confining potential wells. The validity of this approximation has been discussed in
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup> in the passive case, and basically follows by a Taylor expansion of the GEM-
 <italic>α</italic> potential truncated at the second order, since the inter-cluster distance is always larger than the typical cluster-size in the cluster crystal phase. Within this approximation, particles belonging to the same cluster are treated as independent and only experience the effective force generated by the particles in the neighboring clusters
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR63">63</xref>
 </sup>, which is described by the linear shape, 
 <bold>F</bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>eff</italic>
 </sub>(
 <bold>x</bold>) ≈ −
 <italic>k</italic>(
 <bold>x</bold> − 
 <bold>R</bold>
 <sup>(
  <italic>j</italic>)
 </sup>). We stress that the same equations are obtained if using interaction potentials different from GEM, the only difference being the particular value of the spring constant 
 <italic>k</italic>. At variance with the equilibrium case where the pattern does not move and each cluster fluctuates around its equilibrium position, in the presence of the self-propulsion the positions 
 <bold>R</bold>
 <sup>(
  <italic>j</italic>)
 </sup> change. However, since particle relative distances remain constant within the cluster we shall neglect this movement and only consider the particle dynamics inside each cluster and study a system of independent particles confined in a harmonic well in the presence of the self-propulsion. Taking the center of the cluster (
 <bold>R</bold>
 <sup>(
  <italic>j</italic>)
 </sup> = 
 <bold>0</bold>) as the origin of coordinates, the effective particle dynamics reads
 <disp-formula id="Equ8">
  <label>8</label>
  <alternatives>
   <tex-math id="M31">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal} \usepackage{amsmath} \usepackage{wasysym} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{upgreek} \setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt} \begin{document}$$\gamma \dot{{\bf{x}}}=-k{\bf{x}}+\sqrt{2\gamma T}\,\eta +\gamma {\bf{f}},$$\end{document}</tex-math>
   <math id="M32" display="block">
    <mi>γ</mi>
    <mover accent="true">
     <mi mathvariant="bold">x</mi>
     <mo mathvariant="bold">˙</mo>
    </mover>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mo>−</mo>
    <mspace width="-0.25em"/>
    <mi>k</mi>
    <mi mathvariant="bold">x</mi>
    <mo>+</mo>
    <msqrt>
     <mrow>
      <mn>2</mn>
      <mi>γ</mi>
      <mi>T</mi>
     </mrow>
    </msqrt>
    <mspace width=".25em"/>
    <mi>η</mi>
    <mo>+</mo>
    <mi>γ</mi>
    <mi mathvariant="bold">f</mi>
    <mo>,</mo>
   </math>
   <graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_52420_Article_Equ8.gif" position="anchor" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  </alternatives>
 </disp-formula>where we dropped the indices 
 <italic>i</italic> and 
 <italic>j</italic> for the sake of simplicity.
</p>
