<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The proton hole diffusion coefficients, or equivalently, the proton diffusion coefficients, give a measure of the proton conductivity at the interface. In this work, the substrate (ZnO) is in contact with pure liquid water. This can be contrasted to previous simulation work exploring long-range proton and proton hole diffusion at solid/liquid interfaces (for example 
 <xref rid="cit3" ref-type="bibr">ref. 3, 10 and 11</xref>), where the diffusing species was explicitly added to the system. In such simulations, the substrate can interact with the diffusing species by influencing its preferred direction of diffusion, as well as aiding or inhibiting Grotthuss-like diffusion (as opposed to vehicular diffusion), but the surface has not “created” the diffusing species from reactions with the solvent. In the present work, we did not introduce any additional (“extrinsic”) protons or proton holes to the system, but instead followed the proton hole diffusion arising from the spontaneous dissociation and recombination of water on the surface. As a result, there is no net charge on the surface, and the present results for proton hole diffusion effectively concern ZnO surfaces at the point of zero charge (pzc), in the absence of specifically adsorbed counterions. The pzc of ZnO particles depends on the method of preparation, but is normally found at slightly basic pH, around pH 9.
 <xref rid="cit46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref> A higher pH would result in more deprotonation of O
 <sub>s</sub>H
 <sup>–</sup> and O*H
 <sub>2</sub> groups, and a lower pH in the protonation of O
 <sub>s</sub>
 <sup>2–</sup> and O*H
 <sup>–</sup> groups. Thus, the concentrations of species that contribute to proton conductivity at the interface depend on the pH. Adlayer-PT, which is the major contributor to PHC diffusion at both ZnO(101[combining macron]0) and ZnO(112[combining macron]0), requires that a mixture of O*H
 <sup>–</sup> and O*H
 <sub>2</sub> be present at the interface; thus, the pH may neither be too low nor too high for proton conduction to be efficient using the mechanisms presented in this work. Such pH-dependent differences in the physical behavior of the interface is of great interest for example for the application of ZnO-based materials as pH sensors.
 <xref rid="cit15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref> At low pH, other proton transfer mechanisms may become important; for example, proton conduction could potentially occur 
 <italic>via</italic> O*H
 <sub>3</sub>
 <sup>+</sup>, which in our simulations at the pzc only transiently forms (ESI Fig. 2–5
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref>). Characterizing the proton diffusion network at different pH values would serve as an excellent avenue for further exploration.
</p>
