<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We prepared CsPb(Br
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>I
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>)
 <sub>3</sub> perovskite NCs by a hot-injection method and investigated the relationship between the halide composition and their optical properties. The band gap and PL peak energy of the NCs decreased with increasing iodine content. The emission color changed from bluish-green to red. The chromaticity coordinates (0.184, 0.763) at 
 <italic>x</italic>
 <sub>a</sub> = 0.23 were closest to the coordinates (0.170, 0.797) of the green vertex of the BT.2020 standard. Thus, it is useful to substitute an appropriate amount of I
 <sup>–</sup> for Br
 <sup>–</sup> in CsPbBr
 <sub>3</sub> NCs for their application as the green emitter in wide color gamut displays. The FWHM of the mix-halide NCs at 
 <italic>x</italic>
 <sub>a</sub> ∼ 0.5 was 0.127 eV, which was broader than the 0.105 eV FWHM of the monohalide CsPbBr
 <sub>3</sub> NCs. This result should be due to the compositional inhomogeneity among the individual NCs. On the other hand, the PLQY decreased from ∼70% for the monohalide CsPbBr
 <sub>3</sub> NCs to 25% as 
 <italic>x</italic>
 <sub>a</sub> approached 0.5. This result may be attributed to the lattice distortion induced by the difference in the ionic radii of Br
 <sup>–</sup> and I
 <sup>–</sup>. Homogenization of the halide composition among the individual NCs and relaxation of the lattice distortion would improve the green color and PLQY of the CsPb(Br
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>I
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>)
 <sub>3</sub> NCs, respectively. The appropriate mixed-halide composition almost realized the ideal green emission satisfying the BT.2020 standard, but increase in the iodide ratio may decrease the stability of the CsPb(Br
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>I
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>)
 <sub>3</sub> NCs. Improvement on the stability would be required for practical applications.
</p>
