<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To date, numerous methods for obtaining phosphors to be used either over blue LED or UV LED have been reported. However, these materials require harsh synthesis conditions such as high temperature and high pressure, and water-free solvents, which can restrict their commercialization. In this context, several methods have been widely used such as sol–gel, hydrothermal, combustion, emulsion, and precipitation methods [
 <xref rid="R31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>–
 <xref rid="R34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. Among those, the sol–gel and co-precipitation methods are, in general, slow and usually involve additional steps. On the other hand, there is a huge waste of organic solvents during the emulsion process, which makes this method inefficient in terms of cost and toxicity [
 <xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]. Therefore, facile synthesis methods involving water-based reactions at ambient conditions are needed for phosphor fabrication. In this study, a promising strategy has been introduced in order to meet these requirements especially in the case of lanthanide-doped hydroxide-based phosphor fabrication, which is facile, water-based, and rapid. More specifically, acetate-based reagents of both the host and dopant are dissolved in LiOH/water solution together under room temperature. The presence of Li ions during the reaction process may distort the crystal structure and lead to an increase in the formation of substitutional defects, which may facilitate the incorporation of dopant ions into the system [
 <xref rid="R36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>–
 <xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>]. As an example, luminescent red Y(OH)
 <sub>3</sub>:Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> phosphors were fabricated via employing this method. The doping process and complete crystallization were achieved in 60 min. State-of-the-art first-principle calculations were performed on Y(OH)
 <sub>3</sub>:Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> to investigate its crystallographic structure and resulting electronic and optical properties. In summary, a novel water-based, rapid, and simple method was developed in this study. As an application, the red emitting phosphor has been fabricated at ambient conditions in a short time. This method can be a promising strategy for fabricating phosphors to be employed as down-converting materials for pc-converted WLED systems [
 <xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,
 <xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>–
 <xref rid="R43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>].
</p>
