<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The other big class of lead-free perovskites is the double perovskites where Pb (II) atom is substituted by pair of Ag (I) and Metal atom of 3+ valence. The most spread chemical composition for lead-free double perovskites is Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiX
 <sub>6</sub>. In the work [
 <xref rid="B44-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>], the dependence of the energetic structure of Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub> thin films on the molar ratio of precursors CsBr:AgBr:BiBr
 <sub>3</sub> was investigated. Precise solution processing allows obtaining accurate composition stoichiometry of Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub> multicomponent perovskite films, and hence good optoelectronic properties. The highly stable Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub> thin film was used as an active material for sensor due to the fact that its electrical properties are significantly dependent on humidity in [
 <xref rid="B48-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>]. Fast response and recovery of this Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub> thin film can be explained by the reversible physical adsorption of water molecules at the surface of thin film. A convenient solution method of synthesis to deposit high-quality Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub> film with long lifetimes, low trap densities, and large grain sizes was developed in work [
 <xref rid="B49-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>]. In this paper, authors optimized the precursor solution using a mixture of DMSO and DMF as the solvents and found that the introduction of a small amount of DMF is helpful to increase the grain size of the obtained Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub> films. As a result, the incorporated excess of DMF may change the ratio of precursors CsBr:AgBr:BiBr
 <sub>3</sub> in the solution and prevent the AgBr to fit within the crystal lattice and to form the impurity in Cs
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>Br
 <sub>9</sub>. However, the use of 10% DMF resulted in formation of double perovskite film and the PL intensity increase with preserved absorption spectrum. This was accompanied with an increase in PL lifetimes, suggesting that reducing the trap densities is consistent with the enlarged grain size and improvement of crystallinity. It was recently shown [
 <xref rid="B47-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>] that these Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub> perovskite materials can be implemented in the photocatalytic system for dye degradation. It was found that during photocatalytic processes, Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub> is stable in ethanol. Acceleration of the reaction between free radicals and dye molecules indicates the unique catalytic properties of the Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub> surface. Also, the deposition of metal clusters, such as Pt onto Cs
 <sub>2</sub>AgBiBr
 <sub>6</sub>, effectively enhances the photocatalytic activity.
</p>
