<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="P2">Molecules of fullerenes encapsulating metal atoms or clusters (
 <italic>aka</italic> endohedral metallofullerenes, EMFs
 <sup>
  <xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>
 </sup>) can be considered as molecular ball-bearings or gyroscopes consisting of two semi-independent structural units. Despite the strong interactions between the metal atoms and fullerene π-system, the potential energy surface for the rotation of the clusters inside the cages is often rather shallow, leading to quasi-free rotations of endohedral species. A prominent example is found in nitride clusterfullerenes M
 <sub>3</sub>N@C
 <sub>80</sub>-
 <italic>I</italic>
 <sub>h</sub>, where M can be Sc, Y, lanthanides, or any combination of them.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>
 </sup> The icosahedral C
 <sub>80</sub> cage is almost a sphere with many equivalent bonding sites for metal atoms. NMR spectroscopy confirms that in solutions the M
 <sub>3</sub>N cluster rotates freely at room temperature.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>
 </sup> For Sc
 <sub>3</sub>N@C
 <sub>80</sub>, early computational studies have predicted the barrier to this rotation to be below 10 kJ mol
 <sup>−1</sup>,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>
 </sup> and similar estimations have been made based on STM
 <sup>
  <xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>
 </sup> and NMR measurements.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>
 </sup> Obtaining ordered assemblies of such molecules in crystals or in layered structures on surfaces is a challenging task, which, however, may have a high practical impact because the orientation of endohedral clusters affects the electronic and magnetic properties of EMF materials. Furthermore, molecular structure determination by single-crystal X-ray diffraction is complicated by a severe disorder caused by a loosely bound endohedral cluster and rotation of the fullerene cage itself.
</p>
