<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="P5">The endohedral cluster in the isolated M
 <sub>3</sub>N@C
 <sub>80</sub>-
 <italic>I</italic>
 <sub>h</sub> molecule has 2–3 energy minima with small energy differences. Obviously, the interaction of the EMF molecule with Ni(OEP) changes this situation, else the ordering effect would not be observed experimentally. In other words, the potential energy surface (PES) for the cluster inside the cage becomes more prolific when it interacts with Ni(OEP) with the appearance of pronounced orientational minima. But since EMF–Ni(OEP) interactions are non-bonded, the energetic effect on the endohedral cluster cannot be very strong. To make the theoretical depiction of the systems complete and consistent, it is necessary to ensure that all energy minima corresponding to the different orientations of the cluster inside the fullerene are found. It would be insufficient to optimize one particular structure with an arbitrary orientation of the endohedral cluster. As illustrated schematically in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Fig. 1b</xref>, for the complex PES as a function of the order parameter 
 <italic>Θ</italic>, with multiple energy minima, a single optimization will most probably proceed into the closest energy minimum in the configurational space (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Fig. 1b</xref>, the green dot and trajectory line), and not necessarily into the global energy minimum. Only if the configurational space is properly sampled (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Fig. 1b</xref>, all starting points and trajectories), the reliable reconstruction of the PES minima is feasible. Exhaustive and regular sampling of the orientational phase space is achieved here by the Fibonacci sphere sampling. Namely, for each system 120 conformational isomers were generated by rotating the internal cluster along the Fibonacci sphere with respect to the nitrogen as shown for 
 <bold>CRS-0</bold> in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Fig. 1</xref>. Herewith one of the Sc atoms in Sc
 <sub>3</sub>N@C
 <sub>80</sub> or the Y atom in YSc
 <sub>2</sub>N@C
 <sub>80</sub> walks over the sphere, while the M
 <sub>3</sub>N cluster is kept rigid through relevant rotation in polar coordinates (see the 
 <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM">ESI†</xref> for generation script). The angle between the M–N bond and the 
 <italic>Z</italic>-axis defines the order parameter 
 <italic>Θ</italic> (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Fig. 1</xref>). Since each conformer tends to relax to the closest minimum, insufficient and/or biased sampling may lead to unfair judgments about the energy minima distribution. The proposed homogenous sampling ensures maximum conformation space coverage for a given number of nodes.
</p>
