<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The procedure described by Taborga et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>
 </sup> was used to precipitate the Li-carbonate phase, with the exception that LiBr was used instead of LiCl so that we could examined the effects of Cl
 <sup>–</sup> ions on the synthesis. Experiments were conducted using a multiplate stirrer (IKA RT 15) allowing four solutions to be tested in duplicate for each experimental set. New reactant solutions were produced for each set of experiments. A water bath was heated to 80 °C prior to each experiment, and aluminum foil was used as a lid to maintain the temperature and water levels during the experiment. Twenty milliliters of a 0.5 M LiBr solution with or without additional salts (NaCl, KCl, MgCl
 <sub>2</sub>, CaCl
 <sub>2</sub>, Na
 <sub>2</sub>SO
 <sub>4</sub>) at ionic strengths of 1 or 0.1 M was added to 150 mL glass bottles sitting in the water bath. Each bottle contained a magnetic stirrer and was sealed with a rubber septum. The Li-bearing solution was stirred at 300 rpm for 20 min to allow it to reach the temperature of the water bath prior to addition of the carbonate-bearing solution. Twenty milliliters of the carbonate-bearing solution (0.5 M Na
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub>, pH: 12.04) was then slowly added to the Li solution at a rate of 3 mL/min using a syringe pump. A list of the experiments conducted and the pH of the solutions measured at room temperature can be found in 
 <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table 
  <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref>
 </xref>. The solution was continuously stirred for another hour before the precipitate was extracted from the solution using gravity filtration. In preparation for analysis of the crystal morphology and phase identification, the precipitate was dried in a desiccator for at least 24 h. Phase identification of the bulk samples was conducted using a Bruker D8 Advance X-ray diffractometer equipped with a Cu source.
</p>
