<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3" class="p">In the RP series, the members with odd 
 <italic class="italic">n</italic> are particularly interesting. For Sr
 <sub class="sub">2</sub>RuO
 <sub class="sub">4</sub> with 
 <italic class="italic">n</italic> = 1, the RuO
 <sub class="sub">6</sub> octahedron rotates about 9° at the surface
 <sup class="sup">
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10" class="xref">10</xref>
 </sup>, even it is absent in bulk. Such rotation may stabilize ferromagnetism at the surface, which is ultimately connected to the Cooper pair formation with parallel spins in bulk. For Sr
 <sub class="sub">4</sub>Ru
 <sub class="sub">3</sub>O
 <sub class="sub">10</sub> with 
 <italic class="italic">n</italic> = 3, the RuO
 <sub class="sub">6</sub> octahedron in the central layer apparently rotates double amount (~11.2°) than that in the two outer layers (~5.6°), corresponding to different magnetic moment as well
 <sup class="sup">
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16" class="xref">16</xref>
 </sup>. According to density functional calculations
 <sup class="sup">
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11" class="xref">11</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12" class="xref">12</xref>
 </sup>, the orthorhombic structure with the rotation of the RuO
 <sub class="sub">6</sub> octahedron is in favor of ferromagnetic coupling. In the previous study of Sr
 <sub class="sub">3</sub>(Ru
 <sub class="sub">1−x</sub>Mn
 <sub class="sub">x</sub>)
 <sub class="sub">2</sub>O
 <sub class="sub">7</sub>, partial replacement of Ru by smaller Mn leads to the decrease of (Ru/Mn)O
 <sub class="sub">6</sub> octahedral rotation, and long-range antiferromagnetic (AFM) ordering at T
 <sub class="sub">N</sub>
 <sup class="sup">
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8" class="xref">8</xref>
 </sup>. Intriguingly, T
 <sub class="sub">N</sub> versus 
 <italic class="italic">x</italic> is dome-like with both T
 <sub class="sub">N</sub> and the rotation vanishes at the same doping level. This suggests that the correlation between octahedral rotation and magnetic coupling is more complex than simple monotonic response. Given its magnetic ground state and the difference in local structure between outer and central layers
 <sup class="sup">
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19" class="xref">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20" class="xref">20</xref>
 </sup>, Sr
 <sub class="sub">4</sub>Ru
 <sub class="sub">3</sub>O
 <sub class="sub">10</sub> could be much more susceptible to Mn doping than the case of n = 2. In this article, we report, for the first time, the experimental investigation of Mn doped Sr
 <sub class="sub">4</sub>Ru
 <sub class="sub">3</sub>O
 <sub class="sub">10</sub> single crystals, including the crystal structure, magnetization, and electrical transport properties. The partial replacement of Ru by Mn results in the modification of (1) crystal structure by removing octahedral rotation, (2) magnetic interaction by changing the easy axis from the 
 <italic class="italic">c</italic> direction to the 
 <italic class="italic">ab</italic> plane, and (3) electrical conduction from metallic to semiconducting with unusual magnetotransport behavior.
</p>
