<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par5">Recently, the development of narrow-emitting phosphors has been continuously pursued for versatile applications in solid-state lighting or backlight units for liquid crystal displays, and understanding structure-property relations for the creation of narrow-band emission is also a great challenge
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>. The mineral-inspired prototype evolution and new phase construction proposed by our group have demonstrated great potential in discovering new phosphors for emerging applications
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. For example, the newly reported narrow-band materials, Be-containing phosphors, SrLi
 <sub>2</sub>[Be
 <sub>4</sub>O
 <sub>6</sub>] is related to the BaLi
 <sub>2</sub>[(Al
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>2</sub>)N
 <sub>6</sub>] prototype, and Sr[BeSi
 <sub>2</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>] originates from the Sr[Be
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub>] model
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>. Moreover, narrow-band nitride phosphors are extensively investigated in the UCr
 <sub>4</sub>C
 <sub>4</sub>-type model, and one of the typical examples is red-emitting Sr[LiAl
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>]:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> with a highly condensed, rigid network, and highly symmetric dopant sites
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>
 </sup>. Therefore, oxide-based UCr
 <sub>4</sub>C
 <sub>4</sub>-type compounds with narrow-band emission can also be expected
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>. Inspired by these findings, an emerging ultra-narrow-band cyan-emitting phosphor in silicate materials was demonstrated in this work, and we adopted structural modeling in this system to design a novel narrow-band cyan-emitting silicate phosphor. Accordingly, the totally new [Na
 <sub>0.5</sub>K
 <sub>0.5</sub>][Li
 <sub>3</sub>Si]O
 <sub>4</sub> phase, originating from the UCr
 <sub>4</sub>C
 <sub>4</sub>-type compound NaLi
 <sub>3</sub>SiO
 <sub>4</sub>, was discovered in this host family. The relationship between the ultra-narrow-band cyan emission and three different cations with high-symmetry cation sites leading to almost ideal cubic coordination was analyzed. Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>-doped [Na
 <sub>0.5</sub>K
 <sub>0.5</sub>][Li
 <sub>3</sub>Si]O
 <sub>4</sub> (abbreviated as NKLSO:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>) phosphor exhibits an ultra-narrow-band emission with a peak at 486 nm, FWHM = 20.7 nm and a Stokes shift = 1069 cm
 <sup>−1</sup>. Compared to that of the red-emitting Sr[LiAl
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>]:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> phosphor, the emission peak of NKLSO:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> has a significant blueshift. Because the formation energy of N
 <sup>3-</sup> from atomic N ( + 2300 kJ mol
 <sup>−1</sup>) is higher than that of O
 <sup>2−</sup> from atomic O ( + 700 kJ mol
 <sup>−1</sup>), the bonding in nitrides is notably more covalent than that in oxides
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>. Therefore, the 5
 <italic>d</italic> energy levels of Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> in nitride would be lower compared to that in oxide, which results in the lower 5
 <italic>d</italic> −4
 <italic>f</italic> transition energy of the Sr[LiAl
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>]:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> nitride phosphor than that of the NKLSO:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> oxide phosphor. Moreover, this NKLSO:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> phosphor possesses good thermal stability with an integrated emission intensity of 93% at 150 °C. By combining the cyan phosphor NKLSO:8%Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>, the commercial yellow phosphor YAG:Ce and the commercial red phosphor K
 <sub>2</sub>SiF
 <sub>6</sub>:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>(KSF:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>) with a blue LED chip, a white LED with a high 
 <italic>R</italic>
 <sub>a</sub> of 95.2 was acquired, which demonstrated that the phosphor can cover the cyan gap to enhance the CRI in the as-fabricated white LED.
</p>
