<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In 1991 Nakamura invented the first efficient blue LED [
 <xref rid="B1-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. This invention has started the revolution in lighting industry. Besides the conventional incandescent and fluorescent lamps, the new alternative appeared to produce white light. The very first solid state light (SSL) sources used to combine the emission form a blue-emitting InGaN semiconductor chip with a yellow luminescence from a Y
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>5</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>:Ce
 <sup>3+</sup> phosphor, commonly known as YAG:Ce. Unfortunately, such combination of the blue and yellow emissions yielded bluish white light. Such light sources also possessed high correlated colour temperatures (CCT) and low colour rendering indices (CRI) due to lack of intensity in the red area [
 <xref rid="B2-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. One of the ways to solve this problem is to shift the Ce
 <sup>3+</sup> emission in garnet type materials to the red spectral region. Based on this concept, some novel garnet phosphors emitting in the orange-red region were recently developed, for instance, Lu
 <sub>2</sub>CaMg
 <sub>2</sub>(Si,Ge)
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>:Ce
 <sup>3+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B2-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>], Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Y
 <sub>2</sub>(Si,Ge)
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>:Ce
 <sup>3+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>], Y
 <sub>3</sub>Mg
 <sub>2</sub>AlSi
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>:Ce
 <sup>3+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B4-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>], and some others [
 <xref rid="B5-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. The other option to compensate the lack of intensity in the red area is to use the extra red phosphor. This research, in turn, resulted in several very efficient and stable orange/red-emitting nitride and oxynitride phosphors activated with Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> ions: Ca
 <sub>15</sub>Si
 <sub>20</sub>O
 <sub>10</sub>N
 <sub>30</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>], (Ca,Sr)AlSiN
 <sub>3</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>], (Ba,Sr,Ca)
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>5</sub>N
 <sub>8</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B8-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>], Sr[LiAl
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>]:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B9-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>], and many others [
 <xref rid="B10-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. On the other hand, the synthesis of nitride/oxynitride phosphors usually requires protective gas atmosphere due to high reactivity of reagents, complicated equipment, high annealing temperatures, and, therefore, is very costly. Moreover, because of the rather broad emission band of Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> ions, some of the emission lies in the deep red region (λ
 <sub>em</sub> &gt; 650 nm), where the human eye sensitivity is very low. According to Zukauskas et al., the emission at wavelengths higher than 650 nm can be considered as waste, because it reduces the luminous efficacy of the light source [
 <xref rid="B11-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. In this sense, the phosphor with narrow emission band or line in the red spectral region would be much superior.
</p>
