<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>With regular improvement of LEDs, the efficiency of near-UV emitting LEDs also was recently considerably improved and this has opened the new way for generating white light. The near-UV emitting LED can be combined with orange/red, green, and blue-emitting phosphors to yield white light source. This concept is somewhat superior if compared with blue LED driven light sources because more phosphors can be excited with near-UV radiation if compared to the blue LED. The efficient blue (BaMgAl
 <sub>10</sub>O
 <sub>17</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>, BAM) [
 <xref rid="B12-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>] and green (Ba
 <sub>2</sub>SiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>, (Ca,Sr,Ba)Si
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub>N
 <sub>2</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>) [
 <xref rid="B13-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>] phosphors are already developed and are commercially available. Therefore, the main issue is finding the new narrow band or line emitting red phosphors with high efficiency, thermal stability and low production costs. In such research, the Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> doped phosphors gained a lot of attention, especially the ones based on molybdate and tungstate host matrices. In these matrices Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> possess unusually strong absorption due to admixing of charge transfer (CT) and Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> excited states [
 <xref rid="B15-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Recently, some efficient Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> doped red-emitting molybdate phosphors were reported (LiEu(MoO
 <sub>4</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub> [
 <xref rid="B16-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>], Y
 <sub>2</sub>Mo
 <sub>4</sub>O
 <sub>15</sub>:Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B15-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], K
 <sub>2</sub>Bi(PO
 <sub>4</sub>)(MoO
 <sub>4</sub>):Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B17-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], Tb
 <sub>2</sub>Mo
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>:Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> [
 <xref rid="B18-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]) and the search for novel materials in this class is still ongoing [
 <xref rid="B19-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. Besides, recently interest in Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> doped inorganic materials is also gaining lots of attention as an alternative for narrow band red-emitting phosphors. Elimination of lanthanide ions from the luminescent material would of course significantly reduce the phosphor price, what is a great benefit for industrial application. The research in this area now mostly concentrates on oxide and fluoride host matrices with the aim to shift Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> emission from deep red to red region [
 <xref rid="B20-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B22-materials-12-03275" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>].
</p>
