<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The AE–LCAO approach is a robust and efficient ab initio method to correctly describe the defects and adsorption of molecules on oxide surfaces. In this work, we have documented the performance of two widely used methods based on Density Functional Theory: linear combination of atomic orbitals (AE–LCAO) and plane waves (PP–PW) to describe the properties of the stoichiometric and defective TiO
 <sub>2</sub>(110) anatase surface. Full relaxation of stoichiometric and defective anatase (101) surfaces has been carried out using the PBE functional and the hybrid PBE0, B3LYP and HSE functionals. For the PP–PW calculations, only the PBE and PBE+U levels of theory have been considered due to the high computational cost of using hybrid functionals for systematic studies. Hybrid functionals, and, in particular, HSE, lead to a computed band gap in excellent agreement with the experimental data. PBE+U underestimates the gap by 20 % but the predicted gap states induced by the defect with respect to the bottom of the conducting band are in good agreement with the hybrid functionals. An understanding of the defective anatase surface is very important for many technological applications. It has been argued that vacancies are very important in the photocatalytic property of surfaces. The formation of mid-gap states, as the ones described here, could improve the photoactivity of the system in the visible light region. Once we have proved that the AE–LCAO approach with the HSE functional is able to accurately describe this surface, we went one step further by studying the adsorption of the phthalocyanine H
 <sub>2</sub>Pc on anatase (101). H
 <sub>2</sub>Pc was placed both on top of the oxygen and titanium rows of anatase (101), with the latter lower in energy by 0.36 eV. This work presents an ab initio study of the adsorption of H
 <sub>2</sub>Pc on anatase (101), and makes clear the influence of the adsorption site in the phthalocyanine-anatase interaction. The AE–LCAO method presented here opens a way to correctly describe the defects and adsorption of molecules on oxide surfaces by using hybrid exchange functionals at a reasonable computational cost, which will be a valuable tool in order to improve the efficiency of dye-sensitized solar cells.
</p>
