<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//Springer-Verlag//DTD A++ V2.4//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName A++V2.4.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.4?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName springer2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Scientific Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2045-2322</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group UK</publisher-name><publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6536543</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">44326</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-44326-9</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Post-tilleyite, a dense calcium silicate-carbonate phase</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-1119-5056</contrib-id><name><surname>Santamaria-Perez</surname><given-names>David</given-names></name><address><email>David.Santamaria@uv.es</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ruiz-Fuertes</surname><given-names>Javier</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7056-7158</contrib-id><name><surname>Pe&#x000f1;a-Alvarez</surname><given-names>Miriam</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chulia-Jordan</surname><given-names>Raquel</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Marque&#x000f1;o</surname><given-names>Tomas</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zimmer</surname><given-names>Dominik</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Guti&#x000e9;rrez-Cano</surname><given-names>Vanessa</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>MacLeod</surname><given-names>Simon</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-9080-8756</contrib-id><name><surname>Gregoryanz</surname><given-names>Eugene</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff6">6</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-6613-4739</contrib-id><name><surname>Popescu</surname><given-names>Catalin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff7">7</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Rodr&#x000ed;guez-Hern&#x000e1;ndez</surname><given-names>Pl&#x000e1;cida</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff8">8</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Mu&#x000f1;oz</surname><given-names>Alfonso</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff8">8</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 2173 938X</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.5338.d</institution-id><institution>MALTA-Departamento de F&#x000ed;sica Aplicada-ICMUV, </institution><institution>Universidad de Valencia, </institution></institution-wrap>46100 Valencia, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1770 272X</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.7821.c</institution-id><institution>DCITIMAC, Universidad de Cantabria, MALTA Consolider Team, </institution></institution-wrap>39005 Santander, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1936 7988</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.4305.2</institution-id><institution>Centre for Science at Extreme Conditions and School of Physics and Astronomy, </institution><institution>University of Edinburgh, </institution></institution-wrap>EH9 3JZ Edinburgh, UK </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1936 9721</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.7839.5</institution-id><institution>Institute of Geosciences, Goethe-University Frankfurt, </institution></institution-wrap>60438 Frankfurt am Main, Germany </aff><aff id="Aff5"><label>5</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000000406437510</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.63833.3d</institution-id><institution>Atomic Weapons Establishment, Aldermaston, </institution></institution-wrap>RG7 4PR Reading, UK </aff><aff id="Aff6"><label>6</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.410733.2</institution-id><institution>Center for High Pressure Science Technology Advanced Research, </institution></institution-wrap>201203 Shanghai, China </aff><aff id="Aff7"><label>7</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.423639.9</institution-id><institution>CELLS-ALBA Synchrotron, Cerdanyola del Vall&#x000e8;s, </institution></institution-wrap>08290 Barcelona, Spain </aff><aff id="Aff8"><label>8</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000000121060879</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.10041.34</institution-id><institution>Departamento de F&#x000ed;sica, Instituto de Materiales y Nanotecnolog&#x000ed;a, </institution><institution>Universidad de La Laguna, MALTA Consolider Team, </institution></institution-wrap>38206 La Laguna, Tenerife, Spain </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>27</day><month>5</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>27</day><month>5</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>9</volume><elocation-id>7898</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>6</day><month>2</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>14</day><month>5</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2019</copyright-statement><license license-type="OpenAccess"><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this license, visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">Calcium carbonate is a relevant constituent of the Earth&#x02019;s crust that is transferred into the deep Earth through the subduction process. Its chemical interaction with calcium-rich silicates at high temperatures give rise to the formation of mixed silicate-carbonate minerals, but the structural behavior of these phases under compression is not known. Here we report the existence of a dense polymorph of Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> tilleyite above 8 GPa. We have structurally characterized the two phases at high pressures and temperatures, determined their equations of state and analyzed the evolution of the polyhedral units under compression. This has been possible thanks to the agreement between our powder and single-crystal XRD experiments, Raman spectroscopy measurements and <italic>ab-initio</italic> simulations. The presence of multiple cation sites, with variable volume and coordination number (6&#x02013;9) and different polyhedral compressibilities, together with the observation of significant amounts of alumina in compositions of some natural tilleyite assemblages, suggests that post-tilleyite structure has the potential to accommodate cations with different sizes and valencies.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Mineralogy</kwd><kwd>Condensed-matter physics</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">https://doi.org/10.13039/501100003329</institution-id><institution>Ministerio de Econom&#x00026;amp;#x00ED;a y Competitividad (Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness)</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>MAT2015-71070-REDC</award-id><award-id>IJCI-2014-20513</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name><surname>Santamaria-Perez</surname><given-names>David</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruiz-Fuertes</surname><given-names>Javier</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">https://doi.org/10.13039/100010663</institution-id><institution>EC | EU Framework Programme for Research and Innovation H2020 | H2020 Priority Excellent Science | H2020 European Research Council (H2020 Excellent Science - European Research Council)</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>704998</award-id><award-id>695527</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name><surname>Chulia-Jordan</surname><given-names>Raquel</given-names></name><name><surname>Gregoryanz</surname><given-names>Eugene</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2019</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par2">With the possibility of efficient deep carbon ingassing during the last billion years of Earth&#x02019;s history<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref></sup>, the study of the nature of stable forms of carbon in Earth&#x02019;s mantle and their variation as a function of depth is an important area of investigation. At convergent boundaries, carbon enters into Earth&#x02019;s mantle via subduction in the form of carbonates<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref></sup>. Depending on the chemical environment and the thermodynamical conditions, some carbonates may survive in subducting slabs, diving deeper into the mantle<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref></sup>. Melting phase relations of recycled oceanic crust recently reported suggest that slabs should undergo melting and loss of carbonate components at 300&#x02013;700&#x02009;km depths<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref></sup>. However, the form carbon takes depends on the redox conditions in inner Earth, which is defined in terms of oxygen fugacity of the environment. The carbon oxidation state is still poorly constrained and is debated at present, but recent studies considered that carbonates may get reduced to diamond below ~250&#x02009;km depth<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup> due to a low oxygen fugacity<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup>. Therefore, the structure and properties of compositionally relevant oxidized carbon-bearing phases at shallower depths (upper mantle) are of great interest for the geophysical community. In this sense, silicate-carbonates are potential host structures for carbon in Earth&#x02019;s interior, particularly in the proximity of carbonate-rich subduction slabs.</p><p id="Par3">Only a few minerals that contain both silicate and carbonate groups exist, three of them belonging to the CaO-CO<sub>2</sub>-SiO<sub>2</sub> system: Ca<sub>7</sub>(SiO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>3</sub>(CO<sub>3</sub>) galuskinite<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup>, Ca<sub>5</sub>(SiO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>(CO<sub>3</sub>) spurrite<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref></sup>, and Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> tilleyite<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>. They form in the metamorphic zone between limestones (sharp contact with marble, mainly composed of CaCO<sub>3</sub> calcite) and igneous rocks (CaSiO<sub>3</sub> wollastonite and other silicate minerals), at low pressures and high temperatures<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref></sup>. Significant aqueous fluid fluxes in marbles and calc-silicate rocks may result in the production of these types of minerals at lower temperatures, depending also on fluid composition<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup>. Thermodynamical data and phase relations of minerals in this ternary system remain scarce<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref></sup>. Liu and Lin studied the phase stability of two of these calcium silicate carbonates, spurrite and tilleyite, using laser-heated diamond-anvil cells and found that these minerals decompose into their component silicates and carbonates above 4&#x02009;GPa and &#x0223c;1000&#x02009;&#x000b0;C<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref></sup>. On the other hand, experimental studies at low pressures suggest that spurrite and tilleyite have a field of stability between 600&#x000b0; and 1000&#x02009;&#x000b0;C<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref></sup>. It is then fundamental to invest in a more detailed knowledge of these compounds at pressures and temperatures of deep subduction regions, since these silicate-carbonate minerals might be constituents of &#x0201c;cold&#x0201d; slabs. In this regard, it is important to attain an accurate description of the crystal structures and physical properties of these materials at high pressures and temperatures. The compressibility and phase stability of spurrite up to 27&#x02009;GPa and 700&#x02009;K have been recently reported<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. No phase transformation was found, which suggests that the presence of carbonate [CO<sub>3</sub>] units gives stability to the tetrahedral [SiO<sub>4</sub>] orthosilicate group, holding up the formation of phases based on octahedral [SiO<sub>6</sub>] units. What occurs to tilleyite with a similar configuration remains unknown calling for further investigations.</p><p id="Par4">Tilleyite is a naturally-occurring calcium silicate-carbonate mineral that conforms well with the chemical formula Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>, but some minor substitution of other elements such as Al, Mg or F could occur<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref></sup>. It is therefore the most carbonated compound of the calcium silicate-carbonate family. The existence of this mineral was firstly reported by Larsen and Durham in 1933 from contact altered limestones at Crestmore quarries, California, USA<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>. The monoclinic crystal structure of tilleyite was firstly determined by Smith<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref></sup> and later refined by Louisnathan and Smith<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref></sup>, and Grice<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref></sup>. The structure contains the following atom-centered oxygen polyhedra as building blocks: [CO<sub>3</sub>] triangles, [SiO<sub>4</sub>] tetrahedra forming disilicate [Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>] units, and five irregular polyhedra with different coordination spheres for Ca atoms (20% are octahedrally coordinated, 60% are forming 7-fold-coordinated capped octahedra and 20% are forming distorted cubes). It is envisaged that the flexibility of the bridging Si&#x02013;O&#x02013;Si dihedral angle of the disilicate group upon compression could lead to an increase of the coordination number of the Ca atoms and the transition to a denser phase.</p><p id="Par5">Here we present, in contrast to spurrite counterpart, the formation of a novel silicate-carbonate phase after compressing tilleyite above 8&#x02009;GPa. The high-pressure polymorph is characterized <italic>in situ</italic> by X-ray diffraction (XRD) and Raman spectroscopy. DFT calculations confirm that the new phase is thermodynamically more stable at these conditions. We also found evidence for a second dense silicate-carbonate polymorph above 21&#x02009;GPa. The initial tilleyite structure is recovered after pressure is quenched.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2" sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Phase stability and determination of a high-pressure phase</title><p id="Par6">Powder and single-crystal XRD measurements on tilleyite were performed under compression. The initial sample can be described with a monoclinic <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub>/<italic>n</italic> space group and lattice parameters: <italic>a</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;7.582(4) &#x000c5;, <italic>b</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;10.265(4) &#x000c5;, <italic>c</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;15.030(6) &#x000c5; and <italic>&#x003b2;</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;103.99(2)&#x000b0; (V&#x02009;=&#x02009;1135.0(9) &#x000c5;<sup>3</sup>, Z&#x02009;=&#x02009;4), which are in excellent agreement with previously reported cell dimensions of other Crestmore specimens (once expressed in the same crystallographic setting). The structure is depicted in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a&#x02013;c</xref> and the atomic coordinates of the 22 independent atoms within the unit cell at ambient conditions are collected in Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref> of the Supplementary Information, SI (to be compared with literature data of Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>). The topological features of the structure are the same as previously determined, but a brief summary is needed to analyze subsequent structural transformations. In tilleyite, two [SiO<sub>4</sub>] tetrahedra share a common O atom to form a disilicate [Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>] group along the <italic>a</italic> axis and the [CO<sub>3</sub>] carbonate units are roughly oriented along the [001] direction. Ca polyhedra and disilicate units form corrugated walls parallel to (001) cross-linked by the [CO<sub>3</sub>] triangles. Voronoi-Dirichlet polyhedra of Ca atoms provide reliable information on the number of atoms that must be considered as first neighbors for bonding purposes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>. There are five Ca sites with three types of coordination: 1&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;[CaO<sub>6</sub>], 3&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;[CaO<sub>7</sub>] and 1&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;[CaO<sub>8</sub>]. Except the octahedron, the other Ca-centered polyhedra are very irregular and difficult to describe. Major distortions likely come from the shortening of edges shared between polyhedra, as expected from electrostatic interactions<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref></sup>. For instance, a result of the cooperative accommodation of the different building units is that the [Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>] groups flex to yield a dihedral angle of 156.86(14)&#x000b0;.<fig id="Fig1"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Structures of Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> tilleyite (top) and high-pressure post-tilleyite (bottom) projected along the three unitcell axes. Blue, light gray, light green and red spheres represent C, Si, Ca and O atoms, respectively. Cell edges are depicted as solid black lines. Red solid lines on post-tilleyite projections demarcate the location of tilleyite unitcell contents, for the sake of comparison between structures.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_44326_Fig1_HTML" id="d29e701"/></fig><table-wrap id="Tab1"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Experimental details of the Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> post-tilleyite single-crystal structure refinements at 10.8&#x02009;GPa.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td colspan="2">
<bold>Crystal data</bold>
</td></tr><tr><td>Chemical formula</td><td>Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub></td></tr><tr><td>Crystal system</td><td>Monoclinic</td></tr><tr><td>Space group</td><td><italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub></td></tr><tr><td>Unit cell parameters</td><td><italic>a</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;7.3402(11) &#x000c5;</td></tr><tr><td/><td><italic>b</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;9.7652(7) &#x000c5;</td></tr><tr><td/><td><italic>c</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;14.354(9) &#x000c5;</td></tr><tr><td/><td><italic>&#x003b2;</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;103.88(4)&#x000b0;</td></tr><tr><td>Cell volume</td><td>998.8(9) &#x000c5;<sup>3</sup></td></tr><tr><td>Z</td><td>4</td></tr><tr><td>Density</td><td>3.25&#x02009;g/cm<sup>3</sup></td></tr><tr><td colspan="2">
<bold>Crystal structure refinement</bold>
</td></tr><tr><td>Total number of reflections</td><td>6377</td></tr><tr><td>Unique reflections</td><td>5205</td></tr><tr><td>N&#x000b0;. refl. I&#x02009;&#x0003e;&#x02009;3&#x003c3;(I)</td><td>4355</td></tr><tr><td>R<sub>int</sub></td><td>0.0578</td></tr><tr><td>R1</td><td>0.0553</td></tr><tr><td>R1<sub>all</sub></td><td>0.0672</td></tr><tr><td>wR2</td><td>0.1355</td></tr><tr><td>N&#x000b0;. parameters</td><td>178</td></tr><tr><td>GooF</td><td>0.981</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><table-wrap id="Tab2"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Atomic coordinates and isotropic displacements (U<sub>iso</sub>) of Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> post-tilleyite phase at 10.8&#x02009;GPa.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Atom</th><th>x</th><th>y</th><th>z</th><th>U<sub>iso</sub></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Ca1</td><td>0.3197 (2)</td><td>0.11533 (14)</td><td>0.4325 (2)</td><td>0.0103 (2)</td></tr><tr><td>Ca2</td><td>0.1669 (2)</td><td>0.60264 (14)</td><td>0.5757 (2)</td><td>0.0104 (2)</td></tr><tr><td>Ca3</td><td>0.7990 (2)</td><td>0.35788 (14)</td><td>0.8650 (3)</td><td>0.0123 (3)</td></tr><tr><td>Ca4</td><td>0.32962 (19)</td><td>0.37492 (13)</td><td>0.8588 (2)</td><td>0.0105 (2)</td></tr><tr><td>Ca5</td><td>0.18118 (19)</td><td>0.22126 (13)</td><td>0.6343 (2)</td><td>0.0098 (2)</td></tr><tr><td>Ca6</td><td>0.9917 (2)</td><td>0.81712 (15)</td><td>0.7512 (3)</td><td>0.0120 (2)</td></tr><tr><td>Ca7</td><td>0.3427 (2)</td><td>0.01681 (14)</td><td>0.9344 (2)</td><td>0.0116 (2)</td></tr><tr><td>Ca8</td><td>0.33798 (19)</td><td>0.74761 (14)</td><td>0.3808 (2)</td><td>0.0104 (2)</td></tr><tr><td>Ca9</td><td>0.17152 (19)</td><td>0.47862 (14)</td><td>0.0473 (2)</td><td>0.0098 (2)</td></tr><tr><td>Ca10</td><td>0.5049 (2)</td><td>0.32289 (15)</td><td>0.2506 (2)</td><td>0.0116 (2)</td></tr><tr><td>Si1</td><td>0.8222 (3)</td><td>0.39301 (19)</td><td>0.4558 (3)</td><td>0.0080 (3)</td></tr><tr><td>Si2</td><td>0.1194 (3)</td><td>0.19132 (19)</td><td>0.0452 (3)</td><td>0.0083 (3)</td></tr><tr><td>Si3</td><td>0.6873 (3)</td><td>0.2176 (2)</td><td>0.0487 (3)</td><td>0.0083 (3)</td></tr><tr><td>Si4</td><td>0.3823 (3)</td><td>0.40791 (19)</td><td>0.4538 (3)</td><td>0.0080 (3)</td></tr><tr><td>C1</td><td>0.4829 (9)</td><td>0.6123 (6)</td><td>0.2392 (11)</td><td>0.0091 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>C2</td><td>0.0517 (9)</td><td>0.5120 (6)</td><td>0.7340 (11)</td><td>0.0100 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>C3</td><td>0.4380 (9)</td><td>0.0276 (6)</td><td>0.2744 (11)</td><td>0.0099 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>C4</td><td>0.0225 (10)</td><td>0.1234 (6)</td><td>0.7899 (12)</td><td>0.0106 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>O1</td><td>0.0383 (9)</td><td>0.4955 (6)</td><td>0.8220 (11)</td><td>0.0169 (11)</td></tr><tr><td>O2</td><td>0.9651 (7)</td><td>0.6079 (5)</td><td>0.6802 (9)</td><td>0.0112 (8)</td></tr><tr><td>O3</td><td>0.5793 (8)</td><td>0.3194 (6)</td><td>0.9685 (9)</td><td>0.0141 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>O4</td><td>0.2899 (7)</td><td>0.3394 (5)</td><td>0.3533 (9)</td><td>0.0113 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O5</td><td>0.1753 (9)</td><td>0.2761 (6)</td><td>0.9601 (11)</td><td>0.0207 (12)</td></tr><tr><td>O6</td><td>0.9762 (10)</td><td>0.0206 (7)</td><td>0.8306 (11)</td><td>0.0247 (14)</td></tr><tr><td>O7</td><td>0.6201 (7)</td><td>0.0628 (5)</td><td>0.0379 (9)</td><td>0.0111 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O8</td><td>0.8894 (7)</td><td>0.2128 (6)</td><td>0.0165 (9)</td><td>0.0119 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O9</td><td>0.8125 (8)</td><td>0.3297 (6)</td><td>0.3525 (10)</td><td>0.0141(10)</td></tr><tr><td>O10</td><td>0.6115 (7)</td><td>0.3952 (5)</td><td>0.4787 (9)</td><td>0.0116 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O11</td><td>0.1398 (7)</td><td>0.0303 (5)</td><td>0.0292 (9)</td><td>0.0113 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O12</td><td>0.9159 (7)</td><td>0.2865 (5)</td><td>0.5385 (9)</td><td>0.0115 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O13</td><td>0.3464 (7)</td><td>0.5647 (5)</td><td>0.4714 (9)</td><td>0.0116 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O14</td><td>0.5296 (7)</td><td>0.1194 (5)</td><td>0.3309 (9)</td><td>0.0114 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O15</td><td>0.8930 (7)</td><td>0.5467 (5)</td><td>0.4733 (9)</td><td>0.0117 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O16</td><td>0.4528 (8)</td><td>0.0172 (6)</td><td>0.1873 (9)</td><td>0.0145 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>O17</td><td>0.3460 (7)</td><td>0.3062 (5)</td><td>0.5369 (9)</td><td>0.0103 (8)</td></tr><tr><td>O18</td><td>0.4366 (8)</td><td>0.5356 (6)</td><td>0.1639 (9)</td><td>0.0151 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>O19</td><td>0.5385 (8)</td><td>0.5618 (6)</td><td>0.3222 (10)</td><td>0.0145 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>O20</td><td>0.4781 (8)</td><td>0.7431 (6)</td><td>0.2324 (10)</td><td>0.0158 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>O21</td><td>0.3238 (7)</td><td>0.9526 (5)</td><td>0.3059 (9)</td><td>0.0108 (8)</td></tr><tr><td>O22</td><td>0.7111 (8)</td><td>0.2953 (5)</td><td>0.1487 (10)</td><td>0.0139 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>O23</td><td>0.1668 (8)</td><td>0.4378 (5)</td><td>0.7001 (9)</td><td>0.0130 (9)</td></tr><tr><td>O24</td><td>0.2063 (8)</td><td>0.2685 (6)</td><td>0.1446 (10)</td><td>0.0140 (10)</td></tr><tr><td>O25</td><td>0.9075 (9)</td><td>0.2151 (7)</td><td>0.7500 (11)</td><td>0.0253 (14)</td></tr><tr><td>O26</td><td>0.1988 (9)</td><td>0.1394 (6)</td><td>0.7916 (12)</td><td>0.0217(13)</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><p id="Par7">Powder diffraction data present intensities that do not correspond to perfect randomly oriented powder, so only peak positions and not relative intensities could be used to the structural analysis. In other words, from powder diffraction data, we could only accurately infer the lattice parameters of the mineral upon compression (see an example of LeBail refinement in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref> of SI). Indexations and profile fittings of the powder XRD patterns up to 22&#x02009;GPa, the maximum pressure reached in this study, suggest that the structure can be described by a monoclinic space group and comparable unit cell dimensions in the whole pressure range. However, the evolution of the lattice parameters (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>), the monoclinic beta angle (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>), and unit-cell volume (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>) as a function of pressure evidence a clear discontinuity at 8&#x02013;9&#x02009;GPa. More specifically, according to our experiments (calculations), the <italic>a</italic> axis does not change noticeably, but <italic>b</italic> and <italic>c</italic> axes decrease at the transition about 0.2 (0.5) and 1.3 (1.5)%, respectively, and the <italic>&#x003b2;</italic> monoclinic angle suddenly decreases about 0.28 (0.12)&#x000b0;, giving as a result a unit cell contraction of about 1.5 (2.1)%. It is worth noting that the low symmetry and the large unit cell parameters preclude an unequivocal space group assignment, since numerous reflections overlap in powder XRD patterns. This problem is accentuated upon compression with the progressive broadening of the XRD reflections.<fig id="Fig2"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Pressure dependence of the lattice parameters of tilleyite and post-tilleyite Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> phases. Black squares, circles and triangles denote the <italic>a</italic>, <italic>b</italic> and <italic>c</italic> axes of both structure-types. Blue squares show the evolution of the monoclinic &#x003b2; angle with pressure. Solid and empty symbols correspond to the initial <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub>/<italic>n</italic> tilleyite and the high-pressure <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub> post-tilleyite phases. Lattice axes uncertainties are smaller than the size of the symbols. Error bars corresponding to the monoclinic &#x003b2; angle are indicated. Experimental fits are depicted as solid and dashed black and blue lines. Results from DFT calculations are represented with red lines.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_44326_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e1739"/></fig><fig id="Fig3"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Pressure dependence of the unit-cell volume of Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> tilleyite. Solid squares correspond to powder XRD data, and empty blue triangles and green circles correspond to single-crystal XRD data. Fits to all the experimental results for the low- and high-pressure phases are depicted as solid and dashed black lines, respectively. Results from DFT calculations are represented with red lines.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_44326_Fig3_HTML" id="d29e1763"/></fig></p><p id="Par8">Single-crystal XRD measurements allow us to fully characterize the progressive transformations of the tilleyite structure with increasing pressure and the nature of the high-pressure silicate-carbonate phase. Our results show that in tilleyite there is a Ca&#x02013;O distance that rapidly decreases upon compression, increasing the formal coordination number of one of the seven-fold coordinated Ca atoms to eight for pressures above 6&#x02009;GPa (see crystallographic data of tilleyite at 7.9&#x02009;GPa in Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref> of SI). Above 9&#x02009;GPa, the crystal structure can no longer be described by the tilleyite <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub>/<italic>n</italic> space group, but by the lower symmetry <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub> space group. The structure was solved with a dataset at 10.8&#x02009;GPa that has a reciprocal space completeness of 26.7% up to a resolution of 0.46&#x02009;&#x000c5;. The position of the Ca and Si atoms was determined by SHELXT<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref></sup>. Subsequent structural refinement and analysis of the difference-Fourier maps of the electron density function afforded localizing the rest of atoms of the unit cell. The final refinement of the structure was performed with SHELXL<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref></sup> and included all the atomic coordinates and the isotropic displacement parameters. Data pertinent to the intensity data collection are given in Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref> and the final positional parameters of post-tilleyite at 10.8&#x02009;GPa are collected in Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>.</p><p id="Par9">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d&#x02013;f</xref> show the projections of the high-pressure phase, hereafter named post-tilleyite, along the crystallographic axes. Although the transition comes with a volume collapse of &#x0223c;1.5%, the symmetry of the initial and final structures is related by a group-subgroup relationship and they can be easily compared (see Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a&#x02013;f</xref>). The coordination spheres around the C and Si atoms by O atoms have not changed, remaining in trigonal planar and tetrahedral configuration. However, in contrast to tilleyite, the [CO<sub>3</sub>] groups in post-tilleyite are no longer coplanar with each other. Half of them maintain their initial orientation whereas &#x000bc; are now roughly perpendicular to the <italic>c</italic> axis and &#x000bc; are roughly perpendicular to the <italic>a</italic> axis. A similar rotation of carbonate groups was observed in the high-pressure polymorph of calcite, CaCO<sub>3</sub>-III<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref></sup>. This fact supports previous descriptions of tilleyite in terms of silicate and carbonate separated layer modules, where the CaCO<sub>3</sub> component seems to follow a crystal behavior comparable to that of calcite itself in the same pressure range (CaCO<sub>3</sub>-III is reported to be stable between 2.5 and 15&#x02009;GPa).</p><p id="Par10">Post-tilleyite also contains two types of disilicate groups due to symmetry reduction, which causes that the Wyckoff positions 4e in the tilleyite <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub><italic>/n</italic> structure split into two symmetrically independent 2a positions. The dihedral angle of the [Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>] units change at the transition from 154.3&#x000b0; at 7.9&#x02009;GPa to 149.4&#x000b0; and 156.7&#x000b0; at 10.8&#x02009;GPa. These topological transformations entail considerable changes in the coordination number of Ca atoms. For instance, at 10.8&#x02009;GPa, analyses of Voronoi-Dirichlet polyhedra reveal that Ca&#x02013;O distances between 2.16 and 2.88&#x02009;&#x000c5; make up the Ca first-coordination spheres in post-tilleyite, defining variable Ca coordination polyhedra in different sites. The Ca coordination number varies from 6 to 9 (1&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;[CaO<sub>6</sub>], 3&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;[CaO<sub>7</sub>], 5&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;[CaO<sub>8</sub>], 1&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;[CaO<sub>9</sub>]). The existence of such a range of different polyhedral volumes within the same structure is very unusual and interesting from the geophysical point of view. Such a structure could likely host divalent cations with different radii without inducing significant elastic strains. This is particularly relevant within the complex scenario of Earth&#x02019;s mantle, where natural compositions likely include Mg<sup>2+</sup>, Fe<sup>2+</sup>, and other cations coexisting with Ca<sup>2+</sup>. Thus, post-tilleyite offers a versatile structural possibility in comparison with aragonite, the most stable structure for Ca-rich carbonates in the upper and intermediate mantle, which has large polyhedral voids to host small cations (Ca atoms in nine-fold coordination)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par11">To further understand the structural evolution of tilleyite under compression, we performed <italic>in situ</italic> Raman spectroscopy measurements up to 25&#x02009;GPa. Group theoretical analyses (point group C<sub>2h</sub>) predict 132 Raman active modes (&#x00393;<sub>R</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;66A<sub>g</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;66B<sub>g</sub>) and a complicated Raman spectrum<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. Raman scattering spectra at some representative pressures are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref> (All spectra in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref> of SI). The large number of modes of low-pressure Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> tilleyite precludes mode identification and only a rough assignment of fundamental vibrational modes was done. They can be distributed according to the following grouping: librational modes involving Ca<sup>2+</sup> and [SiO<sub>4</sub>] and [CO<sub>3</sub>] units below 400&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>; bending modes of [SiO<sub>4</sub>] and [CO<sub>3</sub>] units between 400 and 780&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>; internal stretching of the [SiO<sub>4</sub>] and [CO<sub>3</sub>] groups in the 800&#x02013;1500&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> range, and OH stretching region above 3000&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>.<fig id="Fig4"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Selected room-temperature Raman spectra of powder Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>. Pressures are indicated at the right-hand side. Intensity scales vary from spectral regions and it has been adapted for clarity as indicated in the top left side of each panel. Black is used for tilleyite, green for post-tilleyite, and blue for higher pressure phase. &#x003b4; symbols denote bending modes and &#x003bd; stretching modes, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_44326_Fig4_HTML" id="d29e1975"/></fig></p><p id="Par12">The most intense bands appear between 900 and 1100&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. The band at 905&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> corresponds to the Si-O stretching of the tetrahedral units<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup>. The intense triplet between 1083 and 1093&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> corresponds to the symmetric C-O stretching from the [CO<sub>3</sub>] units. The triplet structure is a consequence of the different environment surrounding the two distinct non-equivalent [CO<sub>3</sub>] units of tilleyite. In the lower frequency region, at 649&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>, the bending of the Si-O-Si inter-tetrahedral linkage appears<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>. The bands between 697 and 780&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> are assigned to the [CO<sub>3</sub>] bending mode. In the low frequency region, the broad band at around 300&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> is likely related to Ca-O connections, in analogy with the assignment done for wollastonite<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>. On the higher frequency region at around 1500&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> the antisymmetric C-O stretching mode appears. Moreover, at around 3500 and 3700&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>, we observe two broad bands corresponding to O-H stretching mode of water and intersticial OH<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. Due to the low intensity of these OH modes they were not always detected.</p><p id="Par13">In Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref> it can be seen the general upshift of the bands of tilleyite with increasing pressure (see also Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref> of SI). No significant broadening is observed as expected by the crystallinity of the solid and the hydrostaticity provided by the pressure transmitting medium. In the low frequency region there are changes in the relative intensities of the modes that could be explained by the continuous change towards a higher coordination number of the Ca atoms induced by pressure, as revealed in XRD experiments.</p><p id="Par14">Interestingly, between 8&#x02013;9&#x02009;GPa there is an abrupt splitting of the Si-O band and an even more remarkable one of the C-O bands, which perfectly agree with XRD results of the tilleyite to post-tilleyite transition. The orientational change of the [CO<sub>3</sub>] groups explains the splitting of the C-O stretching as its environment has changed. The splitting of the Si-O stretching into two contributions is perfectly explained by the existence of two types of unequivalent disilicate groups [Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>] in post-tilleyite while in tilleyite there was only one. In the bending mode regions between 600 and 800&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>, the Si-O bending splits into several contributions and some of them blueshift as a consequence of the observed decrease in the Si-O-Si bond angle<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>. On the other hand, the prints from the lattice modes drastically change as there appears an intense band at around 80&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. The splitting of all the contributions at the phase transition is illustrated in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref> of the SI. Moreover, there is a change in the O-H stretching region at the transition as a new contribution appears at around 3000&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. The presence of O-H stretching and bending bands provides evidence for the existence of [SiO<sub>3</sub>(OH)] groups in both, the low- and high-pressure phases. In addition to that aforementioned, the spectroscopic results presented in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref> show a significant band broadening between 19 and 25&#x02009;GPa, which is a consequence of the abrupt increase of deviatoric stresses in the sample due to the fact that argon is highly non-hydrostatic above that pressure. Pressure-induced amorphization is ruled out because post-tilleyite and tilleyite spectra were observed on pressure release.</p><p id="Par15">Theoretical DFT calculations confirm that post-tilleyite is a thermodynamically more stable structure at high-pressures. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> shows the energy as a function of volume curves for the initial tilleyite and high-pressure post-tilleyite calculated structures. It can be clearly seen that both curves cross each other at high pressure. As shown in the enthalpy as a function of pressure graph of Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> inset, the denser phase becomes more stable at 8&#x02009;GPa, in excellent agreement with the experimental data. Structural data from DFT calculations are also collected in Supplementary Information. Our simulations also provide frequencies and pressure coefficients of the IR- and Raman-active optical vibrations and, interestingly, show that some low-frequency modes corresponding to the tilleyite phase become softer with increasing pressure and eventually vanish at the phase transition pressure (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref> of SI). Furthermore, our theoretical data predict that post-tilleyite will be dynamically unstable above 21&#x02009;GPa (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref> of SI).<fig id="Fig5"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Internal energy as a function of volume per unitcell for the initial <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub><italic>/n</italic> tilleyite and the <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub> post-tilleyite phases. The enthalpy variation <italic>versus</italic> pressure curve for both polymorphs is depicted in the inset (taking the <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub><italic>/n</italic> tilleyite structure as reference).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_44326_Fig5_HTML" id="d29e2122"/></fig></p><p id="Par16">Figures&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> and <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> illustrate the compression dependence of the lattice parameters and unit-cell volumes of both, tilleyite and post-tilleyite phases. The experimental and theoretical values are in good agreement and show a smooth and monotonous decrease under pressure. The strong anisotropy of tilleyite is described by the approximate linear axial compressibility values: &#x003b2;<sub>a</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;2.84(3)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>, &#x003b2;<sub>b</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;3.79(8)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup> and &#x003b2;<sub>c</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;3.48(9)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>&#x02009;GPa<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> for the <italic>a</italic>, <italic>b</italic>, and <italic>c</italic> axes, respectively. These experimental axial compressibilities agree well with theoretical results: &#x003b2;<sub>a</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;2.8(1)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>, &#x003b2;<sub>b</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;3.92(5)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup> and &#x003b2;<sub>c</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;4.00(6)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>&#x02009;GPa<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. Whereas the <italic>b</italic> and <italic>c</italic> lattice parameters show a quite similar relative contractions, the <italic>a</italic> axis is prominently harder (large incompressibility and rigidity of the [Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>] disilicate units), which means that the bulk compressibility will be dominated by that of the <italic>b</italic> and <italic>c</italic> axes. The least-squares fit of a second-order Birch&#x02212;Murnaghan equation of state (BM-EoS)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref></sup> to our experimental (theoretical) pressure-volume data of the initial phase give a zero-pressure unitcell volume, V<sub>0</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;1131(1) &#x000c5;<sup>3</sup> (1119.5(6) &#x000c5;<sup>3</sup>) and a bulk modulus, B<sub>0</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;80(2) GPa (75.3(4) GPa). These values reflect a slightly lower compressibility than those reported by Gao and coworkers: V<sub>0</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;1168.90(2) &#x000c5;<sup>3</sup>, B<sub>0</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;69.7(3) GPa, and B&#x02019;<sub>0</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;4.0(1) from DFT calculations using the PBE prescription<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref></sup>. Post-tilleyite is only slightly more incompressible with BM-EoS characteristic parameters: V<sub>0</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;1110(4) &#x000c5;<sup>3</sup> (1088.7(4) &#x000c5;<sup>3</sup>) and B<sub>0</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;83(3) GPa (82.1 (3) GPa), according to experimental (theoretical) results. Linear axial compressibilities indicate that the high-pressure phase is more isotropic: &#x003b2;<sub>a</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;2.3(2)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>&#x02009;GPa<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (2.64(3)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>&#x02009;GPa<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>), &#x003b2;<sub>b</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;2.5(2)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>&#x02009;GPa<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (2.31(5)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>&#x02009;GPa<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) and &#x003b2;<sub>c</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;2.2(1)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>&#x02009;GPa<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (2.00(4)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;3</sup>&#x02009;GPa<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) for the <italic>a</italic>, <italic>b</italic>, and <italic>c</italic> axes, respectively.</p><p id="Par17">The evolution of the DFT-calculated polyhedral unit volumes with compression is shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>. The compression of the unit cell is dominated by the compression of the softer calcium-centered polyhedral units. In the case of the low-pressure tilleyite phase, two types of polyhedra have a lower bulk modulus than the unit cell, a seven-fold [CaO<sub>7</sub>] capped-octahedron and the [CaO<sub>6</sub>] octahedron, with B<sub>0(P1)</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;54.6(9) and B<sub>0(P2)</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;66.2(6) GPa, respectively (Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">6</xref> of SI). After the transition, the remaining [CaO<sub>6</sub>] octahedron exhibits a similar bulk modulus B<sub>0(P3)</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;89.0(9) GPa to that of the unit cell, but two other polyhedral units are more compressible under compression: an 8-fold and the 9-fold coordinated Ca units with 62.7(3) and 83(1) GPa, respectively. Note that the diversity of environments of the Ca atoms is not only defined by the number of oxygen neighbours but also by the range of compressibilities of the different [CaO<sub>n</sub>] polyhedra, with bulk moduli as high as 139 (3) GPa.<fig id="Fig6"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>Representation of the evolution under compression of polyhedral unit volumes.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_44326_Fig6_HTML" id="d29e2349"/></fig></p><p id="Par18">Tilleyite was also studied at high-pressure high-temperature. The sample was progressively compressed and heated up to 7.2&#x02009;GPa and 402&#x02009;&#x000b0;C while characterized collecting <italic>in situ</italic> powder XRD data. The HP-HT patterns were indexed using the isolated single reflections and confirmed that the tilleyite structure remained stable in that P-T range (Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">7</xref> of SI). Due to the fact that the pressure is not constant during heating, we used a perturbational method to estimate the thermal expansivity at low pressures, as described in ref.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. This approximation has been successfully used to calculate the thermal expansivity under compression in other compounds<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref></sup>. A linear fit to our data yields a volumetric thermal expansion value of 3.5(4)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;5</sup>&#x02009;K<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (see Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5</xref> of SI). The thermal expansivity of tilleyite lies between those of CaCO<sub>3</sub> aragonite (6.53&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;5</sup>&#x02009;K<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) and CaCO<sub>3</sub> calcite (2.01&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;5</sup>&#x02009;K<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref></sup>, and it is only slightly smaller than those of calcium silicate &#x003b2;-Ca<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>4</sub> larnite (4.24(4)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;5</sup>&#x02009;K<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref></sup> at room pressure and Ca<sub>5</sub>(SiO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>(CO<sub>3</sub>) spurrite at &#x0223c;8&#x02009;GPa (4.1(3)&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;5</sup>&#x02009;K<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. CaSiO<sub>3</sub> wollastonite, another end-member calcium silicate, exhibits a smaller thermal expansion (5.7&#x02013;7&#x000b7;10<sup>&#x02212;6</sup>&#x02009;K<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref></sup>. This fact suggests therefore that the thermal expansivity of Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> tilleyite (2CaCO<sub>3</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;Ca<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>4&#x02009;+&#x02009;</sub>CaSiO<sub>3</sub> stoichiometric content) is a consequence of the structural homologies in the atomic arrangements with other members of the Ca-Si-C-O system.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec4" sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par19">The present study using a combination of powder and single-crystal XRD, Raman spectroscopy and DFT calculations clearly shows the existence of a novel silicate-carbonate polymorph under high P-T conditions. At 8&#x02009;GPa, tilleyite, a naturally-occurring silicate-carbonate mineral transforms into a denser phase which presents a large variety of environments for Ca atoms, from six-fold to nine-fold coordination. The different classes of irregular cation-centered oxygen polyhedra exhibit a wide range of bulk moduli, which suggest that such a structure could accommodate other divalent cation species with different radii; <italic>i</italic>.<italic>e</italic>. Mg<sup>2+</sup>, Fe<sup>2+</sup>, Mn<sup>2+</sup>, etc&#x02026;. On top of that, systematic studies on tilleyite reveal that traces of alumina and fluoride favor its formation, in agreement with compositions of natural mineral assemblages<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup>. Synthetic tilleyite has been grown from starting material with up to 8.2 and 4.7% of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> and CaF<sub>2</sub>, respectively. This means that partial substitution of Si by Al atoms is possible and alkali metals of different sizes can also be hosted in both tilleyite and post-tilleyite structures. Our Raman data also shows the replacement of some oxygen atoms by OH groups. Note that potential chemical substitutions and the low symmetry of the post-tilleyite structure are envisaged to further stabilize this phase at high temperature via an increase of the entropic term.</p><p id="Par20">The thermodynamic conditions for formation and preservation of Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> tilleyite are under debate, but it seems to be stable within the 450&#x000b0;&#x02009;<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref></sup>&#x02013;970&#x02009;&#x000b0;C<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup> temperature range at low pressures (&#x0003c;0.2&#x02009;GPa). At 4&#x02009;GPa, tilleyite is reported to break down at 1000&#x02009;&#x000b0;C into a mixture of calcium carbonate and silicate phases: aragonite, wollastonite and larnite<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref></sup>. Accurate phase relation constraints at pressures higher than 0.2&#x02009;GPa and temperatures lower than 1000&#x02009;&#x000b0;C are required to better understand the complex CaO-SiO<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub> phase diagram and define the geological formation of this mineral. This study reports valuable crystallographic data for the high-pressure polymorphic transition of tilleyite which contribute to the understanding of silicate-carbonate crystal chemistry.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec6"><title>Initial samples</title><p id="Par21">Naturally occurring tilleyite crystals from the Crestmore quarry in the Jurupa mountains (Riverside County, California, USA) were kindly provided by the Yale Peabody Museum (Specimen YPM MIN 041104). A few crystals were optically selected under the microscope and crushed with a mortar and pestle, giving a fine white powder without lustre. Qualitative chemical analyses were done on a Philips XL30 scanning electron microscope by the method of energy dispersive x-ray spectroscopy. Only traces (&#x0003c;1&#x02009;wt%) of Al and K were found apart the Ca, Si, C and O atoms present in the ideal Ca<sub>5</sub>(Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>)(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub> formulae. This is in good agreement with tilleyite chemistry reported in ref.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>. for a tilleyite specimen collected in the same area. Angle-dispersive x-ray diffraction measurements at ambient conditions confirm the tilleyite structure.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>High-pressure methods</title><p id="Par22">We performed high pressure (HP) experiments at both, room (RT) and high temperature (HT) conditions and the sample was characterized <italic>in situ</italic> by means of synchrotron angle-dispersive x-ray diffraction measurements. See details on pressure devices and sample configuration below.</p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>High-temperature methods</title><p id="Par23">For the HP resistive-heating studies, the DAC was contained within a custom-built vacuum vessel designed for HP&#x02013;HT experiments<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref></sup>. The DACs were heated using Watlow 240&#x02009;V (rated at 4.65&#x02009;W&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) coiled heaters wrapped around the outside of the DACs. The temperature was measured using a K-type thermocouple attached to one of the diamond anvils, close to the gasket. The accuracy of the thermocouple on the temperature range covered by the experiments is 0.4%<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref></sup>. NaCl powder was included in the sample chamber to act as pressure transmitting medium and pressure marker<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref></sup>.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Powder XRD methods</title><p id="Par24">HP-RT XRD experiments to 21&#x02009;GPa were carried out in a gas-membrane-driven diamond-anvil cell (DAC) equipped with diamonds of 350&#x02009;&#x000b5;m of culet diameter. The tilleyite sample was placed together with two ruby chips at the center of a 100&#x02009;&#x000b5;m diameter 40&#x02009;&#x000b5;m thick pressure chamber drilled in a preindented rhenium gasket. High-purity Ne gas was also loaded in the DAC at room temperature using the Sanchez Technologies gas loading apparatus. Ne is fluid up to 4.7&#x02009;GPa and acted as a quasi-hydrostatic medium in the pressure range of the study<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref></sup>. Pressure was determined using the ruby fluorescence method<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref></sup>, which provided pressure accuracies of 0.1&#x02009;GPa below 14&#x02009;GPa and 0.2&#x02009;GPa up to 23&#x02009;GPa. The equation of state of Ne was used as a second pressure gauge<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref></sup> above 5&#x02009;GPa. <italic>In situ</italic> angle-dispersive powder X-ray diffraction measurements were carried out at MSPD beamline at ALBA-CELLS synchrotron using a x-ray wavelength of 0.534&#x02009;&#x000c5; (Rh K edge)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref></sup>. This beamline provides a X-ray beam focused down to ~20&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;20 &#x000b5;m<sup>2</sup>, and the diffracted signal was collected with a Rayonix CCD detector. The detector parameters were calibrated with LaB<sub>6</sub> powder standard, and integration to conventional 2<italic>&#x003b8;</italic>-intensity data was carried out with the Dioptas software<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref></sup>. The indexing and refinement of the powder patterns were performed using the Chekcell<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref></sup>, Unitcell<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref></sup> and Powdercell<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref></sup> program packages.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Single crystal XRD (SXRD) methods</title><p id="Par25">Experiments up to 21.1&#x02009;GPa were performed with a Boehler-Almax diamond anvil cell (DAC) (4&#x003b8;~70&#x000b0;) in which a 10-&#x000b5;m-thick sample was introduced inside a 150&#x02009;&#x000b5;m diameter hole of a stainless-steel gasket preindented to 40&#x02009;&#x000b5;m. The pressure calibrant was a ruby chip and the pressure transmitting media were Ne and a 4:1 methanol:ethanol mixture. These experiments were done at the MSPD beamline at ALBA-CELLS synchrotron using a x-ray wavelength of 0.3185&#x02009;&#x000c5; (Ne as PTM) and at the P02.2 Extreme conditions beamline at PETRA III synchrotron, DESY, using a x-ray wavelength of 0.28973&#x02009;&#x000c5; (methanol:ethanol mixture as PTM). The maximum pressure in single-crystal runs was 21&#x02009;GPa at ALBA-CELLS and 10.8&#x02009;GPa at PETRA III. It has to be stressed out that few measurements resulted in succesful structural solution and satisfactory refinement relies (data measured at PETRA III). The diffraction images were collected by 0.5&#x000b0; &#x003c9; scanning. The image format was converted for further processing with the CRYSALIS<sup><italic>Pro</italic></sup> software<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref></sup> for indexing reflections and intensity data reduction. The structures were refined with SHELXL<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref></sup>, operated using the WinGX interface<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref></sup>.</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Raman spectroscopy methods</title><p id="Par26">Raman experiments were performed to 25.2&#x02009;GPa using a symmetric screw-driven diamond-anvil cell equipped with ultra low-fluorescence diamonds of 200 &#x003bc;m culet diameter. A rhenium gasket was used to hold the sample, with a chamber of about 75 &#x003bc;m diameter and 30 &#x003bc;m thick. A Tilleyite powder sample was loaded in the chamber together with a ruby chip whose fluorescence is used as pressure calibrant. Argon gas was loaded into diamond anvil cells at a pressure of 0.2&#x02009;GPa to be used as pressure transmitting medium. High-quality Raman spectra were acquired using a custom-built micro-focused Raman system, using a 514&#x02009;nm laser as the excitation line. Raman scattering radiation was collected in back-scattering configuration. The device is equipped with a 20x Mitutoyo long working distance objective and focused onto the slit of a Princeton monochromator with a grating of 1800 gr/mm and a CCD detector.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref></sup> Spectra were measured with a spectral resolution of about 1&#x02013;2&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> and calibrated with a standard neon emission lamp. The typical sampling area was about 2 &#x003bc;m in diameter.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Computational methods</title><p id="Par27">The present study was performed through total energy ab initio simulations with the Vienna ab initio simulation package (VASP) plane-wave pseudopotential program<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref></sup>. We have employed the Born-Oppenheimer approximation and the electrons were quantum-mechanical treated by solving the Khon-Sham equations of density functional theory (DFT)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref></sup>. The exchange-correlation energy was described with the generalized gradient approximation (GGA), according to the Perdew-Burke-Ernzerhof for solids (PBEsol)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR58">58</xref></sup> prescription. The projector augmented wave (PAW)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">59</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR60">60</xref></sup> was used to take into account the electron-ion interactions, and the plane waves basis set was extended up to a cutoff energy of 530&#x02009;eV in order to obtain accurate results. The Brillouin zone integrations were carried out by means of a grid of Monkhorst-Pack<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR61">61</xref></sup> (4&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;2) k-special points that provided well converged results due to the large size of the primitive cell, that contains 88 atoms, with a great number of degrees of freedom. For a set of different volumes, we achieved a total relaxation of all these free degrees to obtain the optimized structural parameters. The total energy was converged to 0.001&#x02009;eV, the Hellman-Feynman forces on the atoms were lower than 0.004&#x02009;eV/&#x000c5;, and hydrostatic conditions were obtained, it means that the stress tensor was diagonal with an accuracy of 0.1&#x02009;GPa. After these simulations for the set of volume-fixed cells, we got the volumes, total energies and pressures, as well as the cell parameters and the fractional atomic coordinates of the atoms. This allowed using an equation of state, EOS, to fit the data and to obtain the bulk modulus and its derivatives. This method was applied with very good results to the study of phase stability of many semiconductors compounds under high pressure<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR62">62</xref></sup>.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary information</title><sec id="Sec13"><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1"><media xlink:href="41598_2019_44326_MOESM1_ESM.pdf"><caption><p>Supplementary information</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher&#x02019;s note:</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Supplementary information</title><p><bold>Supplementary information</bold> accompanies this paper at 10.1038/s41598-019-44326-9.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>We are thankful for the financial support received from the Spanish Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness through national projects PGC2018-097520-A-100, MAT2016-75586-C4-3-P and MAT2015-71070-REDC (MALTA Consolider). D.S.-P., J.R.-F., and T.M. acknowledge financial support of the Spanish MINECO for the RyC-2014-15643 Ram&#x000f3;n y Cajal Grant, the IJCI-2014-20513 Juan de la Cierva Fellowship and a FPI Fellowship, respectively. M.P.-A. acknowledges the support of the support of the European Research Council (ERC) Grant Hecate held by Prof. Graeme Ackland with Reference No. 695527. R. Ch.-J. acknowledges the European Union Horizon 2020 Program for the Marie Sklodowska-Curie grant Nr. 704998. The Generalitat Valenciana is also acknowledged for financial support (project BEST-2018/203). Authors thank PETRA III and ALBA-CELLS synchrotrons for providing beamtime (PETRA-III experiment I-20180464, and ALBA experiments 2016091819 and 2017082293). Authors thank Dr. Nicolescu and the Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History for providing the mineral samples. British Crown Owned Copyright 2018/AWE. Published with permission of the Controller of Her Britannic Majesty&#x02019;s Stationery Office.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>D.S.P. proposed the research and did the project planning. D.S.P., J.R.F., T.M., D.Z., V.G.C., S.M. and C.P. performed the X-ray diffraction measurements in three different synchrotron beamtimes at PETRA III and ALBA-CELLS. Diffraction data were later analyzed by D.S.P., J.R.F. and R. Ch.J. The Raman spectroscopy measurements and analysis were carried out by D.S.P., M.P.A. and E.G. The <italic>ab initio</italic> calculations were done by P. R.H. and A.M. The writing of the manuscript was done by D.S.P. and all the authors contributed to revising it.</p></notes><notes notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing Interests</title><p id="Par28">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dasgupta</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Ingassing, storage, and outgassing of terrestrial carbon through geologic time</article-title><source>Rev. Mineral. Geochem.</source><year>2013</year><volume>75</volume><fpage>183</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2138/rmg.2013.75.7</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dasgupta</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirchmann</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The deep carbon cycle and melting in Earth&#x02019;s interior</article-title><source>Earth Planet. Sci. Lett.</source><year>2010</year><volume>298</volume><fpage>1</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.epsl.2010.06.039</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Poli</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Franzolin</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Fumagalli</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Crottini</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The transport of carbon and hydrogen in subducted oceanic crust: An experimental study to 5 GPa</article-title><source>Earth Planet. Sci. Lett.</source><year>2009</year><volume>278</volume><fpage>350</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.epsl.2008.12.022</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Connolly</surname><given-names>JAD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Computation of phase equilibria by linear programming: A tool for geodynamic modelling and its application to subduction zone decarbonation</article-title><source>Earth Planet. Sci. Lett.</source><year>2005</year><volume>236</volume><fpage>524</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.epsl.2005.04.033</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Thomson</surname><given-names>AR</given-names></name><name><surname>Walter</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Kohn</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name><name><surname>Brooker</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Slab melting as a barrier to deep carbon subduction</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2016</year><volume>529</volume><fpage>76</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nature16174</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26738593</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rohrbach</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Schmidt</surname><given-names>MW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Redox freezing and melting in the Earth&#x02019;s deep mantle resulting from carbon-iron redox coupling</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2011</year><volume>339</volume><fpage>456</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stagno</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name><surname>Ojwang</surname><given-names>DO</given-names></name><name><surname>McCammon</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name><name><surname>Frost</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The oxidation state of the mantle and the extraction of carbon from Earth&#x02019;s interior</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2013</year><volume>493</volume><fpage>84</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nature11679</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23282365</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Frost</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name><name><surname>McCammon</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The redox state of the Earth&#x02019;s mantle</article-title><source>Ann. Rev. Earth Planet. Sci.</source><year>2008</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>389</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1146/annurev.earth.36.031207.124322</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lazic</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Galuskinite, Ca<sub>7</sub>(SiO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>3</sub>(CO<sub>3</sub>), a new skarn mineral from the Birkhin gabbro massif, Eastern Siberia, Russia</article-title><source>Mineral. Mag.</source><year>2011</year><volume>75</volume><fpage>2631</fpage><lpage>2648</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1180/minmag.2011.075.5.2631</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Spurr</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name><surname>Garrey</surname><given-names>GH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Ore-deposits of the Velarde&#x000f1;a district, Mexico</article-title><source>Econ. Geol.</source><year>1908</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>688</fpage><lpage>725</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2113/gsecongeo.3.8.688</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Larsen</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name><name><surname>Dunham</surname><given-names>KC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Tilleyite, a new mineral from the contact zone at Crestmore, California</article-title><source>Amer. Mineral.</source><year>1933</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>469</fpage><lpage>473</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Harker</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The synthesis and stability of tilleyite, Ca<sub>5</sub>Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Amer. J. Sci.</source><year>1959</year><volume>257</volume><fpage>656</fpage><lpage>667</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2475/ajs.257.9.656</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rubenach</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Cuff</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The occurrence of coarse-grained massive tilleyite in the Redcap Creek magmatic skarn, North Queensland</article-title><source>Mineral. Magaz.</source><year>1985</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>71</fpage><lpage>75</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1180/minmag.1985.049.350.09</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tracy</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Frost</surname><given-names>BR</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Phase equilibria and thermobarometry of calcareous, ultramafic and mafic rocks, and iron formations</article-title><source>Rev. Mineral.</source><year>2019</year><volume>26</volume><fpage>207</fpage><lpage>289</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Treiman</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name><name><surname>Essene</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Phase equilibria in the system CaO-SiO<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Amer. J. Sci.</source><year>1983</year><volume>283-A</volume><fpage>97</fpage><lpage>120</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>L-G</given-names></name><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>C-C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>High-pressure phase transformations of carbonates in the system CaO-MgO-SiO<sub>2</sub>-CO<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Earth Planet. Sci. Lett.</source><year>1995</year><volume>134</volume><fpage>297</fpage><lpage>305</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0012-821X(95)00130-5</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Henmi</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Henmi</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Synthesis of spurrite and tilleyite at low CO<sub>2</sub> partial pressure</article-title><source>Mineral. J.</source><year>1978</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>106</fpage><lpage>110</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2465/minerj.9.106</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Santamaria-Perez</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Structural behavior of natural silicate-carbonate spurrite mineral, Ca<sub>5</sub>(SiO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>(CO<sub>3</sub>), under high-pressure high-temperature conditions</article-title><source>Inorg. Chem.</source><year>2018</year><volume>57</volume><fpage>98</fpage><lpage>104</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.inorgchem.7b02101</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29227639</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anthony, J. W., Bideaux, R. A., Bladh, K. W. &#x00026; Nichols, M. C. Eds, Handbook of Mineralogy, Mineralogical Society of America, Chantilly, VA 20151&#x02013;1110, USA, <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.handbookofmineralogy.org/">http://www.handbookofmineralogy.org/</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>JV</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The crystal structure of tilleyite</article-title><source>Acta Cryst.</source><year>1953</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>9</fpage><lpage>18</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S0365110X53000028</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Louisnathan</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>JV</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Crystal structure of tilleyite: Refinement and coordination</article-title><source>Zeits. Kristallogr.</source><year>1970</year><volume>132</volume><fpage>288</fpage><lpage>306</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1524/zkri.1970.132.1-6.288</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Grice</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The structure of spurrite, tileyite and scawtite, and relationships to other silicate-carbonate minerals</article-title><source>Can. Mineral.</source><year>2005</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>1489</fpage><lpage>1500</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2113/gscanmin.43.5.1489</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Blatov</surname><given-names>VA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Voronoi-Dirichlet polyhedral in crystal chemistry: theory and applications</article-title><source>Crystal. Rev.</source><year>2004</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>249</fpage><lpage>318</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/08893110412331323170</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sheldrick</surname><given-names>GM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>SHELXT - Integrated space-group and crystal-structure determination</article-title><source>Acta Cryst. A</source><year>2015</year><volume>71</volume><fpage>3</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S2053273314026370</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sheldrick</surname><given-names>GM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Crystal structure refinement with SHELXL</article-title><source>Acta Cryst. C</source><year>2015</year><volume>71</volume><fpage>3</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S2053229614024218</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Merlini</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Hanfland</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Crichton</surname><given-names>WA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>CaCO<sub>3</sub>-III and CaCO<sub>3</sub>-IV, high-pressure polymorphs of calcite: Possible host structures for carbon in the Earth&#x02019;s mantle</article-title><source>Earth Planet. Sci. Lett.</source><year>2012</year><volume>333&#x02013;334</volume><fpage>265</fpage><lpage>271</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.epsl.2012.04.036</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>De Villiers</surname><given-names>JPR</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Crystal structures of aragonite, strontianite, and witherite</article-title><source>Amer. Mineral.</source><year>1971</year><volume>56</volume><fpage>159</fpage><lpage>167</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Frost</surname><given-names>RL</given-names></name><name><surname>Lopez</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Scholz</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>de Oliveira</surname><given-names>FAN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Scanning electron microscopy with energy dispersive spectroscopy and Raman and infrared spectroscopy study of tilleyite Ca<sub>5</sub>Si<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>(CO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>-Y</article-title><source>Spectrochim. Acta A</source><year>2015</year><volume>149</volume><fpage>333</fpage><lpage>337</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.saa.2015.04.015</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Santamaria-Perez</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Metastable structural transformations and pressure-induced amorphization in natural (Mg,Fe)<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>4</sub> olivine under static compression: A Raman spectroscopic study</article-title><source>Amer. Mineral.</source><year>2016</year><volume>101</volume><fpage>1642</fpage><lpage>1650</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2138/am-2016-5389CCBY</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Iguchi</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Kashio</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Goto</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Nishina</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Fuwa</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Raman spectroscopic study on the structure of silicate slags</article-title><source>Can. Metall. Q.</source><year>1981</year><volume>20</volume><fpage>51</fpage><lpage>56</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1179/cmq.1981.20.1.51</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kubicky</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name><name><surname>Hemley</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Hofmeister</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Raman and infrared study of pressure-induced structural changes in MgSiO<sub>3</sub>, CaMgSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>6</sub> and CaSiO<sub>3</sub> glasses</article-title><source>Am. Mineral.</source><year>1992</year><volume>77</volume><fpage>258</fpage><lpage>269</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Serghiou</surname><given-names>GC</given-names></name><name><surname>Hammack</surname><given-names>WS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Pressure-induced amorphization of wollastonite CaSiO<sub>3</sub> at room temperature</article-title><source>J. Chem. Phys.</source><year>1993</year><volume>88</volume><fpage>9831</fpage><lpage>9834</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Birch</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Finite elastic strain of cubic crystals</article-title><source>Phys. Rev.</source><year>1947</year><volume>71</volume><fpage>809</fpage><lpage>824</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRev.71.809</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The crystal chemistry and the compressibility of silicate-carbonate minerals: Spurrite, galuskinite and tilleyite</article-title><source>Geosci. Frontiers</source><year>2015</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>771</fpage><lpage>777</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.gsf.2015.02.001</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Santamaria-Perez</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Structural evolution of the CO<sub>2</sub>-filled pure silica LTA zeolite under high-pressure high-temperature conditions</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><year>2017</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>4502</fpage><lpage>4510</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.7b01158</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Marque&#x000f1;o</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>An ultrahigh CO<sub>2</sub>-loaded silicalite zeolite: Structural stability and physical properties at high pressures and temperatures</article-title><source>Inorg. Chem.</source><year>2018</year><volume>57</volume><fpage>6447</fpage><lpage>6455</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.inorgchem.8b00523</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29737842</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>P-V-T equation of state and high-pressure behavior of CaCO<sub>3</sub> aragonite</article-title><source>Amer. Mineral.</source><year>2015</year><volume>100</volume><fpage>2323</fpage><lpage>2329</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2138/am-2015-5246</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Some thermodynamic properties of larnite (&#x003b2;-Ca<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>4</sub>) constrained by T/P experiment and/or theoretical simulation</article-title><source>Amer. Mineral.</source><year>2016</year><volume>101</volume><fpage>277</fpage><lpage>288</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2138/am-2016-5425</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Weston</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name><name><surname>Rogers</surname><given-names>PS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Anisotropic thermal expansion characteristics of wollastonite</article-title><source>Mineral. Mag.</source><year>1976</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>649</fpage><lpage>651</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1180/minmag.1976.040.314.16</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cazorla</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Thallium under extreme compression</article-title><source>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter</source><year>2016</year><volume>28</volume><fpage>445401</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27605357</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dorogokupets</surname><given-names>PI</given-names></name><name><surname>Dewaele</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Equations of state of MgO, Au, Pt, NaCl-B1, and NaCl-B2: Internally consistent high-temperature pressure scales</article-title><source>High Press. Res.</source><year>2007</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>431</fpage><lpage>446</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/08957950701659700</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Santamaria-Perez</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Mukherjee</surname><given-names>GD</given-names></name><name><surname>Schwager</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Boehler</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>High-pressure melting curve of helium and neon: Deviations from corresponding states theory</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2010</year><volume>85</volume><fpage>214101</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.81.214101</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Klotz</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Chervin</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name><name><surname>Munsch</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Le Marchand</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hydrostatic limits of 11 pressure transmitting media</article-title><source>J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys.</source><year>2009</year><volume>42</volume><fpage>075413</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/0022-3727/42/7/075413</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>KK</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Bell</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Calibration of the Ruby Pressure Gauge to 800-Kbar under Quasi-Hydrostatic Conditions</article-title><source>J. Geophys. Res.-Solid Earth Planets</source><year>1986</year><volume>91</volume><fpage>4673</fpage><lpage>4676</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1029/JB091iB05p04673</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hemley</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Zha</surname><given-names>CS</given-names></name><name><surname>Jephcoat</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name><name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>HK</given-names></name><name><surname>Finger</surname><given-names>LW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>X-Ray Diffraction and Equation of State of Solid Neon to 110 GPa</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>1989</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>11820</fpage><lpage>11827</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.39.11820</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fauth</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Peral</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Popescu</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Knapp</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The new material science powder diffraction beamline at ALBA synchrotron</article-title><source>Powd. Diffract.</source><year>2013</year><volume>28</volume><fpage>5360</fpage><lpage>5370</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR47"><label>47.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Prescher</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Prakapenka</surname><given-names>VB</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>DIOPTAS: A Program for Reduction of Two-Dimensional X-Ray Diffraction Data and Data Exploration</article-title><source>High Press. Res.</source><year>2015</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>223</fpage><lpage>230</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/08957959.2015.1059835</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR48"><label>48.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laugier, J. &#x00026; Bochu, B. LMGP-Suite Suite of Programs for the interpretation of X-ray Experiments, ENSP/Laboratoire des Mat&#x000e9;riaux et du G&#x000e9;nie Physique, France, <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.inpg.fr/LMGP">http://www.inpg.fr/LMGP</ext-link> and <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.ccp14.ac.uk/tutorial/lmgp/">http://www.ccp14.ac.uk/tutorial/lmgp/</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR49"><label>49.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Holland</surname><given-names>TJB</given-names></name><name><surname>Redfern</surname><given-names>SAT</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Unit cell refinement from powder diffraction data: the use of regression diagnostics&#x0201d;. Mineral</article-title><source>Magaz.</source><year>1997</year><volume>61</volume><fpage>65</fpage><lpage>77</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR50"><label>50.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nolze</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Kraus</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Powdercell 2.0 for Windows</article-title><source>Powd. Diffract.</source><year>1998</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>256</fpage><lpage>259</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR51"><label>51.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agilent, CRYSALIS<sup><italic>Pro</italic></sup> software system, version 1.171.36.28, Agilent Technologies UK Ltd., Oxford, UK (2013).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR52"><label>52.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Farrugia</surname><given-names>LJ</given-names></name></person-group><source>J. Appl. Cryst.</source><year>2012</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>849</fpage><lpage>854</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S0021889812029111</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR53"><label>53.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dalladay-Simpson, P., Howie, R.T. &#x00026; Gregoryanz, E. Evidence of a new phase of dense hydrogen above 325 gigapascals. <italic>Nature</italic><bold>529</bold>, 63 (2016).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR54"><label>54.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kresse</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Furthmuller</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Efficiency of <italic>ab-initio</italic> total energy calculations for metals and semiconductors using a plane-wave basis set</article-title><source>Comput. Mater. Sci.</source><year>1996</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>50</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0927-0256(96)00008-0</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR55"><label>55.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kresse</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Hafner</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title><italic>Ab-Initio</italic> molecular-dynamics simulation of the liquid-metal amorphous-semiconductor transition in germanium</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>1994</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>14251</fpage><lpage>14269</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.49.14251</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR56"><label>56.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kresse</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Hafner</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title><italic>Ab initio</italic> molecular-dynamics for liquid-metals</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>1993</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>558</fpage><lpage>561</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.47.558</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR57"><label>57.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hohenberg</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Kohn</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Inhomogeneous Electron Gas</article-title><source>Phys. Rev.</source><year>1964</year><volume>136</volume><fpage>864</fpage><lpage>871</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRev.136.B864</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR58"><label>58.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Perdew</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Restoring the density-gradient expansion for exchange in solids and surfaces</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><year>2008</year><volume>100</volume><fpage>136406</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.100.136406</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18517979</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR59"><label>59.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bl&#x000f6;chl</surname><given-names>PE</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Projector augmented-wave method</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>1994</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>17953</fpage><lpage>17979</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.50.17953</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR60"><label>60.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kresse</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Joubert</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>From ultrasoft pseudopotentials to the projector augmented-wave method</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>1999</year><volume>59</volume><fpage>1758</fpage><lpage>1775</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.59.1758</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR61"><label>61.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Monkhorst</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Pack</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Special points for Brillouin-zone integrations</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>1976</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>5188</fpage><lpage>5192</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.13.5188</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR62"><label>62.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mujica</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Rubio</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Munoz</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Needs</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>High-pressure phases of group-IV, III-V, and II-VI compounds</article-title><source>Rev. Mod. Phys.</source><year>2013</year><volume>75</volume><fpage>863</fpage><lpage>912</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/RevModPhys.75.863</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>