<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0780">This article focuses on the regular exposition of dozy-chaos mechanics or quantum-classical mechanics of elementary electron transfers in condensed matter, which are the simplest cases of molecular quantum transitions. For the theoretical description of molecular quantum transitions, quantum-classical mechanics arises in molecular and chemical physics instead of quantum mechanics as a consequence of a critical examination of the Franck-Condon principle, widely known and popular in optical molecular spectroscopy, which was introduced in optical spectroscopy as an external addition to quantum mechanics almost 100 years ago. Quantum-classical mechanics allows, for example, carrying out a theoretical examination of the shapes of optical bands in polymethine dyes and their aggregates, which can only be explained if the Franck-Condon principle is abandoned in principle. According to the arguments given in this article, the Franck-Condon principle remains to date an unsubstantiated hypothesis, despite its successful application to explain a substantial number of experimental facts. The dynamics of the molecular quantum transition, which is given by the Franck-Condon principle, does not stand up to criticism on the basis of general physical considerations (see Sections 
 <xref rid="sec2.1" ref-type="sec">2.1</xref> and 
 <xref rid="sec2.5" ref-type="sec">2.5</xref>). The main critical circumstance is the fact that up to the present, in the framework of quantum mechanics, there is no distinct quantitative solution to the problem of the dynamics of the molecular transient state, at least in some simplest cases, which would confirm the Franck-Condon principle and/or the Franck-Condon dynamics of the transient state. Moreover, the study of the dynamics of the molecular transient state has a physical meaning only when going beyond the Born-Oppenheimer adiabatic approximation, since in this approximation, the full-fledged dynamic role of the electronic subsystem is absent, and the role of the electronic subsystem is reduced solely to the formation of the adiabatic potential in which the nuclei move. However, as shown by the author in the example of a new theory of elementary electron transfers in condensed matter, going beyond the adiabatic approximation leads to a singularity in the rate constants of “quantum” transitions (see Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.4.3" ref-type="sec">2.4.3</xref>), which agrees with the general qualitative physical considerations in Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.1" ref-type="sec">2.1</xref>. At a qualitative level, a vivid physical demonstration of this singularity is given in Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.6" ref-type="sec">2.6</xref> in the example of a potential box with a moveable wall. Therefore, to correctly consider the dynamics of the molecular transient state, this singularity must be damped. In other words, we are forced to introduce into molecular quantum mechanics some additional assumption or postulate that this damping would provide, similar to how quantum mechanics was in due time forced to be supplemented from the outside by the Franck-Condon principle.
</p>
