<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0785">In the example of the problem of elementary electron transfers in condensed matter, the specified singularity is easiest to dampen if the infinitesimal imaginary additive in the energy denominator of the spectral representation of the total Green's function of the system is replaced by its finite value. In other words, for the first time the problem of the dynamics of a molecular transient state was solved quantitatively by the example of the problem of elementary electron transfers in condensed matter, that is, the solution to the problem was found as discussed in Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.1" ref-type="sec">2.1</xref>. A successful quantitative explanation, based on this new theory, of the basic set of experimental data on the shape of the optical bands in polymethine dyes and their aggregates showed that the absolute value of the new imaginary additive in the energy denominator of the total Green's function of the system significantly exceeds the magnitude of the quantum of nuclear vibrations. This additive could be interpreted as the energy width of the electron-vibrational virtual levels of the transient state, which provides a multiple exchange of motion and energy between different vibrational modes and the electron in the transient state. However, because of the aforementioned excessively large value of this additive, the exchange of motion and energy between different vibrational modes and the electron in the transient state proves to be so intense that it leads to chaos both in the motion of the medium nuclei and in the motion of the electron that undergoes an elementary transfer. Moreover, from the physical perspective, this can be interpreted in such a way that it is the electron, as very light and mobile, rather than the surrounding nuclei, that provokes chaos in a transient state. The electron provokes chaos to be able to easily control the movement of very heavy nuclei in a transient state. This involves the discovery of a new and universal property of an electron, namely, the property of creating chaos in the motion of nuclei in a transient state during a molecular quantum transition. Electrons acquire this universal property when they bind atomic nuclei to molecules. This is called dozy chaos, since it is not present either in the initial or final states and arises only during molecular quantum transitions. The presence of strong chaos (dozy chaos) in a transient state easily explains why the Franck-Condon principle is often so effective in applications. In strong dozy chaos, as previously shown using the example of elementary electron transfers, the rate constants of molecular quantum transitions cease to depend on the dynamics of the transient state (see Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.6" ref-type="sec">2.6</xref>, 
 <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4</xref>
 <italic>b</italic>, where the case of strong dozy chaos corresponds to the blue low-intensity Gaussian-like curve). They depend only on the initial and final adiabatic states of the molecular system, with which the Franck-Condon principle essentially only deals. Apparently, this is why dozy chaos has eluded the attention of researchers for so long.
</p>
