<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0800">Quantum-classical (dozy-chaos) mechanics of the elementary electron transfers in condensed matter, which was earlier used to quantitatively explain the optical band shapes in polymethine dyes and their aggregates (Section 
 <xref rid="sec1" ref-type="sec">1</xref>), allows for only non-local phonons and neglects local phonons. As a consequence, this leads to a relatively simple transient state with a continuous spectrum of electron-vibrational energies, that is, during molecular “quantum” transition — elementary electron-charge transfer, the quantum system — “electron + environment” — becomes a classical system. This provides (together with the dispersion of phonon frequencies [
 <xref rid="bib72" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>]) the continuous optical spectra of polymethine dyes and their aggregates, which were discussed in Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.1" ref-type="sec">2.1</xref>. Taking into account local phonons is a much more complicated problem than considering non-local phonons, and the solution will require considerable efforts from researchers in the future. This account will also lead to a complication of the transient state, in which, along with the chaotic classical dynamics of the electron-nuclear motion, quantum jumps in the vibrational energy of the nuclei at the final stage of the molecular “quantum” transition appear, that is, after the reorganization of the entire nuclear subsystem has already been completed (see Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.8" ref-type="sec">2.8</xref>). As a result of this account, in the theoretical optical spectra, along with continuous bands corresponding to non-local phonons, striped spectra appear corresponding to both non-local and local phonons. The dominance of any particular local modes in the molecular system should lead to well-defined discrete and narrow vibrational lines in the theoretical and experimental optical spectra (see Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.8" ref-type="sec">2.8</xref>).
</p>
