<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Tungsten trioxide has the same crystalline structure as rhenium oxide (ReO
 <sub>3</sub>) [
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-09-01555" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. This structure can be described as a three-dimensional network of WO
 <sub>6</sub> octahedra interconnected by their corners. Its various allotropic forms and sub-stoichiometric derivatives are known and listed in the literature. Indeed, the [WO
 <sub>6</sub>] octahedral site network can be slightly distorted in different ways with tungsten atoms located out of the center of the octahedron cage and/or twisted chains of octahedra. The various displacements of the cations (W
 <sup>6+</sup> ions) and anions (O
 <sup>2−</sup> anions) in the structure, and therefore the symmetry of WO
 <sub>3</sub>, can be modified with temperature [
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-09-01555" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Thus, depending on the temperature, the crystalline system of tungsten oxide can be tetragonal (P4/nmm), above 720 °C [
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-09-01555" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>], orthorhombic (Pnmb) from 720 to 320 °C [
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-09-01555" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], monoclinic (P2
 <sub>1</sub>/n) from 320 to 17 °C or triclinic (P-1) below 17 °C [
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-09-01555" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Hexagonal and cubic structures are also listed in the literature. The hexagonal WO
 <sub>3</sub> can be obtained by dehydration at 420 °C of hydrated tungsten trioxide (WO
 <sub>3</sub>.nH
 <sub>2</sub>O) [
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-09-01555" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. The formation of cubic WO
 <sub>3</sub> was observed at high temperature during the dehydration of aluminum tungsten phosphate (AlPW
 <sub>12</sub>O
 <sub>20</sub>) [
 <xref rid="B19-nanomaterials-09-01555" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. It is also known that tungsten oxide forms a set of sub-stoichiometric oxides with a general composition of W
 <sub>n</sub>O
 <sub>3n-x</sub> with x = 1, 2 or 3 [
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-09-01555" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. Oxygen sub-stoichiometry is known to potentially induce the occurrence of shear planes in the octahedron framework, leading to octahedra not only connected by their corners but also by their edges [
 <xref rid="B21-nanomaterials-09-01555" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. 
</p>
