<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>As for other crystalline carbonate materials such as calcite, Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub> has an inverse solubility, whereby the solubility of the solid phase decreases with increasing temperature.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref48">48</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref49">49</xref>
 </sup> The solubility limit of Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub> at 25 °C has been experimentally determined as 0.017 M.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref48">48</xref>
 </sup> Thus, the inverse solubility expected for Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub> and high concentration of Li
 <sup>+</sup> and carbonate in our solutions (both 0.5 M) should result in a very high supersaturation with respect to zabuyelite. In other carbonate systems, high supersaturation levels lead to the formation of amorphous precursor phases that transform into the final crystalline product.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref50">50</xref>
 </sup> In our experiments, we do not see direct evidence for a precursor phase. However, we repeatedly observe that the rosette crystal arrangement produced throughout our experiments have a hollow core. This is unusual as rosettes are typically proposed to form due to structural interactions between the different crystal arms, such as aragonite rosettes formed in the presence of nonionic polymers.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref51">51</xref>
 </sup> Similarly, in ice rosettes, whose crystals have a very similar shape to that of zabuyelite, the core is solid and connects the different crystal arms.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref>
 </sup> In addition, we observe hollow structures penetrating into the center of individual crystals in the sulfate experiments (
 <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>
 </xref>e). A similar structure has also been observed in ice formation and is typically attributed to higher supersaturations.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref52">52</xref>
 </sup> Recrystallization of less crystalline Ca-carbonate into a crystalline phase has been shown to form hollow structures in some experiments.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref53">53</xref>
 </sup> Thus, the presence of channels within our crystals and hollow centers of the rosettes indicates that zabuyelite may also precipitate via transformation from a precursor phase.
</p>
