<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In recent years, azobenzene-containing molecules (azos), which are reversibly responding to the light stimulus, have been widely applied in science and engineering to construct materials with various photosensitive characteristics [
 <xref rid="B1-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Among others, star-shaped azos, i.e., multi-photochromic compounds with azobenzene moieties attached to the central unit as arms, have received considerable attention in the research of the past decade. On one hand, such molecules combine mesomorphism and photoswitching [
 <xref rid="B6-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>], they can more effectively reply to the light stimulus (for example, during inscribing a surface relief grating) as compared to monomeric azos. On the other hand, they can be readily synthesized and purified, be either evaporated or cast from solution, build stable amorphous phases and exhibit more uniform physical properties. There is no dilution of the chromophores or any effects coming from entanglements unlike azo–photochromic polymers and composite polymer systems [
 <xref rid="B9-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. Star-shaped azos are also different from linear or cyclic azo 
 <italic>n</italic>-mers with the same number of azo-fragments (trimers, tetramers, etc.). First of all, this is manifested in different supramolecular structures the stars and the linear or cyclic [
 <xref rid="B11-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>] 
 <italic>n</italic>-mers can build. Moreover, the branching results in lower melting temperatures, and lower viscosity [
 <xref rid="B6-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-molecules-24-04387" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>], meaning that these properties are topology-dependent.
</p>
