<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>While the standard analysis of angular averaged scattering intensity shows excellent results for isotropic systems, like liquids and powders, and various crystallographic techniques are well suited to study the structure of crystals, AXCCA appears to be very useful to study the systems with weak orientational order. One of the prominent examples of such systems is a suspension of colloidal particles. The aqueous solution of charge-stabilized polyacrylate colloidal particles was studied at high pressure in reference [
 <xref rid="B86-materials-12-03464" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>]. X-ray diffraction patterns at ambient and high pressures (
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm234">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mi>p</mi>
     <mo>=</mo>
     <mn>1</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> bar and 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm235">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mi>p</mi>
     <mo>=</mo>
     <mn>2500</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> bar, respectively) in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f014">Figure 14</xref>a,b clearly show the development of the sixfold BO order in the system. The evolution of the angular averaged structure factor 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm236">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mi>S</mi>
     <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mi>Q</mi>
      <mo>)</mo>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> as a function of increasing pressure also indicates a transition from isotropic liquid-like structure of the colloidal suspension to the fcc structure 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f014">Figure 14</xref>c. These observations were supported by the increasing magnitude of the sixfold modulations of the CCF (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f014">Figure 14</xref>d). Surprisingly, AXCCA also revealed fourfold orientational order in the system under ambient pressure, which is not well resolved in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f014">Figure 14</xref>a. The authors attributed this fourfold symmetry to the metastable ordered state of the colloidal suspension at ambient pressure due to shear-induced melting.
</p>
