<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p content-type="flushleft">To summarize, both Raman spectroscopy experiments in diamond anvil cells and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations evidence the existence of a methane hydrate phase we named MH-IV, which is stable well beyond the probed stability limit of other hydrates (
 <xref rid="r5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). This phase can be pinpointed in the Raman spectra by the presence of 2 vibrational modes at frequencies between 900 and 1,100 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="i81">
   <msup>
    <mtext>cm</mtext>
    <mrow>
     <mo>−</mo>
     <mn>1</mn>
    </mrow>
   </msup>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>, which are absent in the MH-III phase, as well as a marked broadening of the CH
 <sub>4</sub> stretching modes. Simulations reveal that this phase consists of a skeleton isomorphic to ice I
 <italic>h</italic> and orientationally ordered methane molecules forming an intercalated sublattice, which mimics 1 of the 2 D
 <sub>2</sub>O sublattices as found in some high-pressure ice phases. The CH
 <sub>4</sub> molecules are arranged in rows along a ternary axis. Our proposed structure fully accounts for the X-ray diffractogram measured at 55 GPa in ref. 
 <xref rid="r15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref> and the lattice parameters proposed in ref. 
 <xref rid="r14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, where the existence of a high-pressure hydrate phase was conjectured. Simulations depict the transition pattern from MH-III to MH-IVs according to a complex transition sequence: First, in the 30 to 40 GPa range, H bonds become symmetric in MH-III, leading to MH-IIIs. Second, the transition from MH-IIIs to MH-IV implies a reorganization of the H-bonded water network into an ice I
 <italic>h</italic>-like phase, which requires 2 hydrogen bonds to move as well as a rotation of half of the methane molecules around 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="i82">
   <mrow>
    <mover accent="true">
     <mrow>
      <mi>c</mi>
     </mrow>
     <mo>→</mo>
    </mover>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>. This structure belongs to the Pmcn space group and presents symmetric H bonds beyond 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="i83">
   <mo>≃</mo>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>50 GPa, provided that quantum effects on the nuclear distributions are properly accounted for.
</p>
