<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The second issue is the modeling for the random influencing factors in the diamond turning process, especially the crystallographic orientation (single crystal material) and defects (polycrystal material) in the work material. For the single crystal work material, the influence of crystallographic orientation on the surface topography is always analyzed. For instance, Yuan et al. investigated the effect of the crystallographic orientation on the cutting force and surface quality in the diamond turning process, and selected single crystal aluminium and copper as the work material [
 <xref rid="B97-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">97</xref>]. A micro-plasticity model responsible for the anisotropy phenomenon in diamond turning is therefore developed. To et al. selected three different crystallographic orientations on the single crystal aluminium in diamond turning, and reported that there is a close dependency of surface topography with crystallographic orientation [
 <xref rid="B98-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">98</xref>]. Similarly, Chen et al. studied the effect of crystallographic orientation of potassium dihydrogen phosphate (KDP) on the finial surface finish, and pointed out that the variation of surface topography is consistent with the variation of crystallographic orientation [
 <xref rid="B99-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">99</xref>]. To further reveal the underlying mechanism responsible for the dependence of surface topography on the crystallographic orientation, the molecular dynamics (MD) method is usually employed. For instance, Komanduri et al. once conducted the MD simulation to analyze the influence of crystallographic orientation on surface formation of single crystal aluminium in nanometric cutting, and they disclosed the subsurface deformation, dislocations as well as the extent of anisotropy of workpiece material [
 <xref rid="B100-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">100</xref>,
 <xref rid="B101-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">101</xref>]. Li et al. explored the influence of pore and second phase particle on the surface finish in diamond turning of single crystal copper with MD simulation, and reported that the existence of pore promotes the slide of dislocation and leads to strong work hardening [
 <xref rid="B102-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">102</xref>]. Meanwhile, the influence of second phased particle is closely associated with its hardness relative to the work material. Liu et al. fabricated the small diamond tool with focused ion beam (FIB) technology, and further perform nano-cutting experiments on single crystal silicon using a specialized designed instrument with scanning electron microscopy (SEM) online observation [
 <xref rid="B103-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">103</xref>]. Their experimental results indicated that the cutting-induced amorphous layer on the machined surface is strongly dependent on the depth of cut and cutting edge radius (
 <italic>r</italic>
 <sub>n</sub>). As demonstrated, theoretical analysis and experimental observation have performed on the influencing factors of single crystal work material. However, up to now, no suitable surface topography model considering the influence of crystallographic orientation of the single crystal material has been established, which should be further explored in the future investigation. 
</p>
