<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Compared with the single crystal material, the polycrystal material is more extensively employed in the diamond turning process, for instance the aluminium alloy and polycrystal copper. In diamond turning, the depth of cut is usually less than the average grain size of polycrystalline material [
 <xref rid="B97-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">97</xref>]. Moriwaki performed cutting experiments on the machinability of copper and pointed out that the scratches parallel to cutting direction on the diamond turned surface is due to the imperfection on the cutting edge, i.e., tool edge waviness; while the irregular step structure is induced by the grain boundary [
 <xref rid="B104-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">104</xref>]. Furthermore, the step structure will be strengthened when the surface is machined under a larger depth of cut. Inamura et al. employed a quasi-static method to analyze the nano-cutting process of copper [
 <xref rid="B105-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">105</xref>]; and they claimed that the formation of surface topography for polycrystalline cooper depends on its crystal orientation. For the formation process of surface topography, they found that the plastic deformation firstly occurs along the grain boundary and then propagates into each grain. Brinksmeier et al. studied the step structure phenomenon and its height value in diamond turning of polycrystalline copper as shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="micromachines-10-00288-f009">Figure 9</xref>a, and pointed out that the step structure between two grains derives from the variation of elastic recovery [
 <xref rid="B106-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">106</xref>,
 <xref rid="B107-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">107</xref>]. They further pointed out that the grain structure of metal substrate is the ultimate limit to the achievable surface roughness. Liu et al. explored the formation mechanism of the step structure for polycrystalline copper, and claimed that the misalignment in the slip direction between the sub-grains and the original grains results in the step structure [
 <xref rid="B108-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">108</xref>]. To explain the step structure on the diamond turned surface of polycrystalline copper, a theoretical formula for the value of material spring back in diamond turning is developed in [
 <xref rid="B28-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>], and the formation of step structure on the machined surface is reported to heavily depend on the Young’s modulus of the neighbouring grain and their grain boundary. Specifically, as demonstrated in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="micromachines-10-00288-f009">Figure 9</xref>b for polycrystalline copper, the Young’s modulus of the two neighbouring grains are different and both are larger than its value on the grain boundary, which finally leads to the step structure as depicted in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="micromachines-10-00288-f009">Figure 9</xref>c. Furthermore, to reduce the influence of grain boundary of polycrystalline copper on the final surface finish, Zhang et al. employed the cold-deformation recrystallization annealing method, which has been proved to effectively improve the final surface roughness [
 <xref rid="B109-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">109</xref>].
</p>
