<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To reveal the underlying mechanism for the influence of hard particles, Xu et al. and Sharma et al. performed the molecular dynamics (MD) simulation process, and pointed out that when it encountered the diamond tool cutting edge, the hard particles embedded in the material matrix will be suppressed and subsequently protruded from the generated surface [
 <xref rid="B116-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">116</xref>,
 <xref rid="B117-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">117</xref>]. Particles removal or further suppressed into the material matrix are associated with their sizes and locations in the work material. In fact, on different cutting conditions, the dominant factors influencing the surface topography are different. For instance, He et al. once predicted the 2D surface topography of the diamond turned aluminium alloy at different feed rates and compared with the measured results, as shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="micromachines-10-00288-f011">Figure 11</xref>a,b [
 <xref rid="B28-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. Furthermore, the absolute prediction error (the average value for the difference between the prediction and measurement results) and the relative prediction error (the ratio of the absolute prediction error to the actual peak-valley surface roughness 
 <italic>R</italic>
 <sub>t</sub> of the surface) were also calculated, as presented in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="micromachines-10-00288-f011">Figure 11</xref>c. On a large feed rate condition (
 <italic>f</italic> = 8 μm/r), the dominant influencing factors on the surface formation are the duplication effect of tool edge profile, material spring back and plastic side flow. Instead, on a small feed rate condition (
 <italic>f</italic> = 6 μm/r), the influences of material defects, e.g., grain boundary, gradually dominate the formation of the surface topography. The critical impact of material defects on the formation of surface topography on the small feed rate condition (
 <italic>f</italic> ≤ 2 μm/r) also results in the sharp increase of the absolute and relative prediction errors, as demonstrated in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="micromachines-10-00288-f011">Figure 11</xref>c. 
</p>
