<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Moreover, in addition to the material property aspects, the ambient environment factors, the configurations of the diamond tool and some other process parameters, such as depth of cut and spindle speed, should also be considered. For instance, Mishra et al. made an experimental investigation and reported that the diamond tool overhang can lead to the excess tool tip vibration and tool wear in machining process, which further affects the final surface topography. The optimized range of the tool overhang, i.e., 12 mm to 16 mm, is recommended through the experimental observations [
 <xref rid="B118-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">118</xref>,
 <xref rid="B119-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">119</xref>]. Mir et al. studied the influence of rake angle in diamond turning of silicon with molecular dynamics method, and reported that a positive rake angle diamond tool contributes to the generation of cracks on the machined surface and therefore affects the final surface topography [
 <xref rid="B120-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">120</xref>]. Meanwhile, the selection of cutting fluids affects the lubrication condition [
 <xref rid="B121-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">121</xref>], tool wear rate [
 <xref rid="B122-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">122</xref>] and temperature distribution [
 <xref rid="B123-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">123</xref>,
 <xref rid="B124-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">124</xref>] on the contact interface between the diamond tool and workpiece surface, which further has impact on the final surface topography. For the process parameters, Cheung et al. and Zhang et al. once pointed out that the surface roughness decreases with the increase of spindle speed; while the variation trend under different depths of cut is irregular [
 <xref rid="B125-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">125</xref>,
 <xref rid="B126-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">126</xref>]. As demonstrated, there are only a few investigations concentrated on ambient environment factors and depth of cut, etc. Unfortunately, no suitable surface topography model with consideration of these influencing factors has been established up to now. 
</p>
