<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0675">The hypothesis of quanta was conflicting to classical mechanics, and in due time, it was entirely beyond the conventional physical concept, but implications of the discovery of quanta proved to be truly breathtaking. As a matter of fact we can say that quantum mechanics, originating in the hypothesis of quanta, underlies the modern science and technological progress. The quantum-classical mechanics under discussion, based on the hypothesis of dozy chaos, provides an understanding of a series of experimental results in chemistry (see Section 
 <xref rid="sec1" ref-type="sec">1</xref>), which for a long time could not be explained within the framework of the standard quantum mechanics of electron-nuclear motion. From general physical considerations it follows that dozy chaos is the cause not only of molecular quantum transitions, but also of the whole variety of chemical reactions, and as a consequence, it is the physical origin of the evolution of molecular matter, up to the emergence of living matter and the person himself [
 <xref rid="bib32" ref-type="bibr">32b</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib33" ref-type="bibr">33a, 33b</xref>]. Therefore, there is every reason to believe that the implications of the discovery of dozy chaos and quantum-classical mechanics in our life will be no less impressive in comparison with the implications of the discovery of quanta and quantum mechanics. From general considerations it follows, for example, that dozy chaos constitutes the physical basis for the effective functioning of the brain, which is the main “receptacle” of dozy chaos in the living organism [
 <xref rid="bib32" ref-type="bibr">32b</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib33" ref-type="bibr">33a, 33b</xref>]. Since the onset of cancer is usually associated with damage to the genes in cells, for example, by radiation, then the radiation of dozy chaos of the living brain in its pathological functioning, for example under stress, is one of the main physical causes of the natural onset and development of cancer [
 <xref rid="bib32" ref-type="bibr">32b</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib33" ref-type="bibr">33a, 33b</xref>].
</p>
