<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <list list-type="order">
  <list-item>
   <p>The η″ phase (the low-temperature phase of η-Fe
    <sub>2</sub>Al
    <sub>5</sub> with compositions on the Fe-rich side of the solubility range) exhibits commensurate long-period superlattice structures (space group 
    <italic>Pmcn</italic>) consisting of twin domains (orientation variants) alternately stacked along the long-periodicity axis parallel to the orthorhombic 
    <italic>c</italic>-axis.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Each of the twin domains possesses a motif structure belonging to a base-centered monoclinic-ordered structure (space group 
    <italic>C</italic>2/
    <italic>m</italic>), with a cell volume twice that of the parent orthorhombic unit cell of η-Fe
    <sub>2</sub>Al
    <sub>5</sub> (space group 
    <italic>Cmcm</italic>).
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>One-fourth of the 
    <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites corresponding to Al2- and Al3-sites in the η phase are respectively occupied by both Fe and Al atoms and exclusively by Al atoms in a regular manner, while this regularity is disturbed in the twin boundary region to give rise to structural/compositional modulation.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Because of the different chemical compositions in the motif structure and twin boundary region, the η″ phase with various compositions can be constructed only by changing the number (M) of the parent orthorhombic unit cells to be stacked along the orthorhombic 
    <italic>c</italic>-axis, without changing the atomic arrangements for the motif structure or the twin boundary region.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>The chemical formula of the η″ phase can be expressed as Fe
    <sub>3</sub>Al
    <sub>7+
     <italic>x</italic>
    </sub> under a simple assumption about the occupancies for Al/Fe atoms in the 
    <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites.
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
