<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>During last decades, Heusler alloys have received tremendous research interests and become of great importance for the development of new functional materials due to their various and special properties, such as half-metallicity [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>], semi-metallicity [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>], thermoelectricity [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>], spin-gapless semiconductivity [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>], ferromagnetism [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>] and topological insulativity [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. Their applications spread into different fields, mainly including spintronics and magnetoelectronics [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>]. Conventional Heusler materials comprise a large group of intermetallic compounds and they can be divided into two groups: half Heusler with stoichiometric compositions XYZ and full Heusler with X
 <sub>2</sub>YZ, where X and Y are transition metal elements and Z is a main group element. A lot of experimental effort has been dedicated to develop novel Heusler alloys [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>]. Especially with the rapid growth of microengineering and nanotechnology, different fabrication techniques and processes are widely available, like melt-spinning, arc-melting, magnetron sputtering, ball-milling and chemical coprecipitation. In the meantime, extensive theoretical calculations have also been devoted to study the properties of Heusler compounds and even design and predict new Heusler alloys [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>].
</p>
