<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The physical properties of Heusler compounds are directly related to their highly ordered structure. Typically, Heusler alloys crystallize in the face-centred cubic structure with two possible atomic orderings [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C50" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>]: Cu
 <sub>2</sub>MnAl-type and Hg
 <sub>2</sub>CuTi-type. On the other hand, several studies have demonstrated that a large number of Heusler compounds have the tetragonal structure as the ground state [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C51" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>]. Also, there could be various defects present in both structures, including disorder, antisite, swap and vacancy. Consequently, their properties would be strongly influenced by these structures, atom orderings and defects [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C54" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C56" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>–
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C61" ref-type="bibr">61</xref>]. In particular, for the development of magnetic-tunnel-junction memory material and ferromagnetic shape memory material, tetragonal structure Heusler with large magnetization is preferable. The group of Fe-based and Ni-based Heusler compounds are good candidates for this purpose, such as Fe
 <sub>2</sub>CrGa has different atomic configuration dependent on the preparation methods, and its magnetization can be significantly enhanced by either Fe-Ga or Cr-Ga disorder [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>]; Fe
 <sub>2</sub>MnGa has martensitic transformation induced by magnetic field, and it is accompanied by spontaneous magnetization [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C62" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>]; Fe
 <sub>2</sub>CrAl prepared by ball-milling method has partially disordered B2
 <sub>
  <italic>CD</italic>
 </sub> structure, and it shows both higher Curie temperature and magnetic moments [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>]; Ni
 <sub>2</sub>MnGa undergoes a phase transition from cubic structure at high temperature to tetragonal structure at low temperature [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C63" ref-type="bibr">63</xref>]; Mn
 <sub>2</sub>NiGa has the stable tetragonal phase compared to the cubic phase, and it is ferromagnetic in both phases with different magnetic moment [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>]. In combination of Fe and Ni together, several experimental studies have synthesized Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiZ (Z = Al, Ga, Si and Ge) [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C65" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C66" ref-type="bibr">66</xref>] along with some theoretical investigations on their electronic and magnetic properties under different structures [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C67" ref-type="bibr">67</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C68" ref-type="bibr">68</xref>]. Results show antisite disorder in Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiGe and Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiGa tends to enhance the stability of cubic structure [
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C69" ref-type="bibr">69</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSOS191007C70" ref-type="bibr">70</xref>], which is contradictory to the minimum total energy configuration in tetragonal phase when being chemically ordered. In particular, Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiSi shows different structures under different preparation processes, indicating the complicated atomic ordering in this compound. For the purpose to better understand the different structural configuration and its impact on the electronic and magnetic properties of full Heusler compounds Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiSi and Ni
 <sub>2</sub>FeSi, we employ first-principles calculation. Two different structures of cubic phase and tetragonal phase with two different atomic orderings of Cu
 <sub>2</sub>MnAl-type and Hg
 <sub>2</sub>CuTi-type have been investigated. Furthermore, uniform and tetragonal strain conditions have also been considered and discussed.
</p>
