<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Only a few minerals that contain both silicate and carbonate groups exist, three of them belonging to the CaO-CO
 <sub>2</sub>-SiO
 <sub>2</sub> system: Ca
 <sub>7</sub>(SiO
 <sub>4</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub>(CO
 <sub>3</sub>) galuskinite
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>, Ca
 <sub>5</sub>(SiO
 <sub>4</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub>(CO
 <sub>3</sub>) spurrite
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>
 </sup>, and Ca
 <sub>5</sub>(Si
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub>)(CO
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub> tilleyite
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>. They form in the metamorphic zone between limestones (sharp contact with marble, mainly composed of CaCO
 <sub>3</sub> calcite) and igneous rocks (CaSiO
 <sub>3</sub> wollastonite and other silicate minerals), at low pressures and high temperatures
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. Significant aqueous fluid fluxes in marbles and calc-silicate rocks may result in the production of these types of minerals at lower temperatures, depending also on fluid composition
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>. Thermodynamical data and phase relations of minerals in this ternary system remain scarce
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>. Liu and Lin studied the phase stability of two of these calcium silicate carbonates, spurrite and tilleyite, using laser-heated diamond-anvil cells and found that these minerals decompose into their component silicates and carbonates above 4 GPa and ∼1000 °C
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. On the other hand, experimental studies at low pressures suggest that spurrite and tilleyite have a field of stability between 600° and 1000 °C
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>. It is then fundamental to invest in a more detailed knowledge of these compounds at pressures and temperatures of deep subduction regions, since these silicate-carbonate minerals might be constituents of “cold” slabs. In this regard, it is important to attain an accurate description of the crystal structures and physical properties of these materials at high pressures and temperatures. The compressibility and phase stability of spurrite up to 27 GPa and 700 K have been recently reported
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. No phase transformation was found, which suggests that the presence of carbonate [CO
 <sub>3</sub>] units gives stability to the tetrahedral [SiO
 <sub>4</sub>] orthosilicate group, holding up the formation of phases based on octahedral [SiO
 <sub>6</sub>] units. What occurs to tilleyite with a similar configuration remains unknown calling for further investigations.
</p>
