<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Perovskite light-emitting diodes (PeLEDs) have drawn tremendous research interest in recent years due to the attractive properties of metal halide perovskite materials such as earth abundance, solution process capability, large carrier mobility, and excellent color purity
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. The versatile bandgap tuning of perovskite materials (ABX
 <sub>3</sub>) via composition tuning of A, B, and X sites makes them applicable in whole visible light range. The application of all inorganic cesium-based perovskite significantly enhances the material stability under electric field
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>. Very impressive progresses have been made in enhancing the efficiencies of perovskite LEDs in the past few years
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. External quantum efficiencies (EQEs) approaching 20% have been reported for both green and red PeLEDs, which ravel those from optimized organic phosphorescence light-emitting diodes (LEDs)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>. However, blue-emission PeLEDs, which are important for display and lighting applications, have efficiency much lower than green and red PeLEDs. The highest reported EQE for sky-blue PeLEDs is still &lt;10%
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. One convenient way to make blue-emission perovskite films is to incorporate chlorine (Cl) into Br-based perovskites, whereas one critical issue for the Cl:Br mixed or pure Cl-based perovskite films is their small photoluminescence quantum efficiency (PLQE) below 20%, which is much lower than the green- or red-emission perovskite films with a typical PLQE of 70
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. As only about a quarter of light could be extracted out of PeLED devices made on glass substrates due to the mismatched refractive index
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>, the highest EQE for the blue devices will be limited to &lt;5%, assuming perfect charge balance can be achieved in the devices. The exact reason for the low PLQEs in chlorinated perovskite films is not clear. One way used in previous studies to increase PLQE was adopting quantum dots or two-dimensional (2D) layered perovskites, in which strong quantum confinement could significantly improve the film PLQE to over 80%
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>. However, due to the inferior charge transport in these films, high EQE sky-blue PeLEDs are still rarely reported.
</p>
