<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par5">Most commonly, the displacement correlations in PMN are perceived to be manifested as polar nanoregions (PNR), several nanometers in size, which emerge below the so-called Burns temperature of ≈620 K
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup> and are widely regarded as a key feature associated with the relaxor behavior. A formal definition of PNRs is missing but typically this term refers to finite-size regions, dynamic or static, having nonzero spontaneous electrical polarization. A large fraction of structural research on PMN has involved X-ray and neutron-scattering measurements on single crystals, with a focus on the interpretation of the rich diffuse-scattering patterns in terms of displacement correlations
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>; this diffuse scattering appears below the Burns temperature and becomes increasingly pronounced as temperature is reduced. Various models of PNRs that could give rise to these patterns have been proposed, ranging from static nanodomains having well-defined shapes and boundaries
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup> to dynamic displacement patterns controlled by acoustic
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup> and/or optical phonon modes
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>. Some works suggested that the PNRs are distributed in a disordered paraelectric matrix
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>, whereas recent molecular-dynamics studies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup> have rejected this interpretation, claiming instead that PNRs are separated by domain walls. Similarly, while some computational studies associate the PNRs with chemically ordered regions (COR)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>, others question this relation
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>. The debate continues in part because no comprehensive structural model of PMN that would provide at least a snapshot of the multiscale correlated disorder, while also accounting for all the available experimental data, has been reported thus far.
</p>
