<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par23">Powder X-Ray Diffraction (PXRD) was performed on a Panalytical Xpert-pro diffractometer with Cu K
 <sub>α</sub> (λ = 1.54178 Å) operating in Bragg-Brentano geometry. For phase purity analysis, Raman spectroscopy was employed using a Horiba Jobin-Yvon LabRam Raman HR800 operating with a 532 nm laser. An aperture size of 100 µm and a 1% filter was used in order to prevent sample degradation. Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM) images were obtained using a Phillips XL30 ESEM instrument coupled with an Oxford Instruments X-act spectrometer for EDX measurements. The EDX was calibrated using the INCA EDX software with Cu as the calibration standard. Transmission electron microscopy micrographs were obtained using a FEI Tecnai G2 F30 S-twin equipped with a 300 kV field emission gun. Diffraction pattern simulations were performed using JEMS
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>. ICP-OES was conducted using an Agilent 5100 calibrated to a range of known-concentration (ppm) solutions of Mo and Te. The BET surface area of 1T′-MoTe
 <sub>2</sub> was determined with a Quadrasorb Evo ODS-30. X-ray photoelectron analysis (XPS): 1T′-MoTe
 <sub>2</sub> samples were carefully packed and sent to the National EPSRC XPS Users’ Service (NEXUS) at Newcastle University, UK and for measurements under inert atmosphere to the EPSRC National Facility for XPS (“Harwell XPS”). XPS spectra were acquired with a K-Alpha instrument (Thermo Scientific, East Grinstead, UK), using a micro-focused monochromatic AlKα source (X-ray energy 1486.6 eV, spot size 400 × 800 microns). The emission angle was zero degrees and the pass energy was 200 eV for surveys and 40 eV for high resolution. Charge neutralization was enabled. The resulting spectra were referenced to the adventitious C 1s peak (285.0 eV) and were analysed using the free-to-download CasaXPS software package. Infrared (IR) measurements were performed using a Bruker 66v Fourier transform instrument with a deuterated tryglicine sulfate (DTGS) detector in the far-infrared region, and a mercury cadmium telluride (MCT) detector in the mid-infrared region, with 2 cm
 <sup>−1</sup> spectral resolution. Samples were ground and pressed into KBr pellets with 1 wt% concentration (~3 mg in 300 mg KBr) and measured in transmission mode. Time-of-flight powder neutron diffraction (PND) measurements were performed on the General Materials (GEM) diffractometer at the ISIS Facility of the Rutherford Appleton Laboratory, UK
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>
 </sup>. Samples were loaded in 0.7 mm diameter quartz capillaries and data were collected at room temperature. XAFS measurements were performed at the Mo K-edge on the B18 beamline at the Diamond Light Source, Didcot, UK. Data was collected in transmission mode (to 
 <italic>k</italic>
 <sub>max</sub> = 18) using a QEXAFS setup with a fast scanning Si(111) double crystal monochromator and ion chamber detectors, with a Mo foil placed between I
 <sub>t</sub> and I
 <sub>ref</sub>. XAFS data processing was performed using IFEFFIT with the Horae package (Athena and Artemis)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. The amplitude reduction factor, S
 <sub>0</sub>
 <sup>2</sup> was derived from EXAFS data analysis of the Mo foil.
</p>
