<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) represent an emerging class of crystalline porous polymers with periodic two- or three-dimensional (2D or 3D) structure
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. Due to their permanent porosity, high stability, and designable functionality, COFs have gained considerable attention as promising applications in gas storage and separation
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>, catalysis
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>
 </sup>, sensing
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>, optoelectronics
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>, energy storage
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>, etc. For all these reported systems, most of the examples are focusing on 2D COFs, and their synthesis and characterization have been relatively well established
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>
 </sup>. By contrast, since Yaghi and co-workers reported the first example in 2007
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>, only a few 3D COFs have been announced over the past decade
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>
 </sup>, mainly due to their limited availability of molecular building blocks and synthetic challenge. However, it should be emphasized here, as these 3D architectures can allow hierarchical arrangement of nanopores and possess numerous open sites, some reported 3D COFs have shown interesting applications, for example, size-selective catalysis
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup>. Considering their unique structures and properties, the rational design and synthesis of 3D COFs with specific functions are highly demanded.
</p>
