<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Metal nanoparticles are one of the most widely used materials in innovative research and development studies within a variety of fields and have numerous potential applications, such as in antibiotics, optics, plasmonics, catalysts, and electronics. There have also been many studies aimed at the production of homogeneous nanocrystals, which exhibit narrow size and shape distributions, so as to determine the effect of size on the chemical and physical properties of these materials. Recently, there has been a breakthrough in the fabrication of monodisperse nanocrystals in the size range of 0.5 to 2.0 nm in diameter. These so-called subnanoclusters (SNCs) (
 <xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>1</italic>
 </xref>) can now be obtained via wet processes that are readily scalable for further application researches. The precise preparation of SNCs is realized using nanosynthesizers, such as dendritic phenylazomethine derivatives (
 <xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>2</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>3</italic>
 </xref>), in which a precise number of metal complexes is first accumulated at the imine parts within the dendrimer molecules. Subsequently, multinuclear complexed molecules were chemically reduced to form size-monodispersed metal clusters within the template molecule. This approach is extremely general and widely applicable to many of the metallic elements in the periodic table (
 <xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>4</italic>
 </xref>). SNCs exhibit distinctive discrete characteristics with the number of constituting atoms (atomicity), such as unexpectedly high catalytic activity on the electrochemical oxygen reduction reaction (
 <xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>5</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>8</italic>
 </xref>) and the aerobic oxidation of hydrocarbons (
 <xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>9</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>11</italic>
 </xref>), as well as a quantum size effect with notable shifts in bandgap energy (
 <xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>12</italic>
 </xref>). However, a detailed evaluation of physical and chemical properties of SNCs in literature is still in early stage.
</p>
