<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>An extensive characterization of cobalt phosphate using topological analysis and theoretical methods for experimental and theoretical electron‐density distribution was performed. The P−O bonds were identified as polar single bonds in which the BCP is considerably shifted to the phosphorus atom. The Co−O bonds can be described as closed‐shell interaction. The calculated MLWFs have a clear connection to the d‐orbital occupation, as well as the position of the charge‐depletion centers. In the solid state, the two independent cobalt atoms exhibit different numbers of charge depletion sites in the valence shell. Co
 <xref rid="chem201902303-bib-0005" ref-type="ref">5</xref> has, in addition to the charge depletions directed towards the negatively charged phosphate oxygen atoms, three additional vacant coordination sites. This suggests that the nucleophilic attack on Co
 <xref rid="chem201902303-bib-0005" ref-type="ref">5</xref> is much more likely. These depletions, congruent with the unoccupied or partially occupied d‐orbitals, were analyzed on the face of different solid‐state surfaces. It has been shown that the (011) face is the most suitable for catalytic oxidative dehydrogenation or dehydrogenation, showing Co
 <sup>[5by]</sup>⋅⋅⋅Co
 <xref rid="chem201902303-bib-0005" ref-type="ref">5</xref> cooperativity. There are sufficient acidic and basic sites for the chemisorption of butan‐2‐ol available. On this face Co
 <xref rid="chem201902303-bib-0005" ref-type="ref">5</xref> ions and phosphate ions are the most accessible; therefore, this surface is best equipped to activate both, the C−H and O−H bonds. Furthermore, the lobes of the MLWFs of both cooperative Co
 <xref rid="chem201902303-bib-0005" ref-type="ref">5</xref> atoms face each other to address both oxygen lone pairs of the substrate. The investigations show that the concerted but independent experimental and theoretical determination of charge‐density distribution is a valuable tool to rationalize catalytic active materials.
</p>
