<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par10">As an important class of functional nanomaterials, metallic nanoplates have been extensively synthesized and examined owing to their excellent activities in catalysis [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>], tunable optical properties [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>], potential utilization in microcircuits, among others [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. As is well known, the application performance of nanomaterials strongly depends on their structures and morphologies. Therefore, an in-depth understanding of the shape stability of these metallic nanoplates should be an issue of crucial importance to their synthesis and usage. From the thermodynamics point of view, the structure of a single nanoplate deviates from the energetic minimum and is supposed to develop into a sphere-like nanoparticle owing to the tendency of minimizing its surface energy. However, as metastable configurations, nanoplates are not rarely observed in experiments because of the participation of complex kinetic factors [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. Relatively higher temperature increases the possibility for the system to escape the kinetic trapping and to realize the state with lower energy. Especially for those nanoplates with thicknesses as thin as several atomic layers, the significantly high surface-to-volume ratios imply a large proportion of atoms with weak bonding (i.e., high mobility), which are sensitive to the ambient environment and hence are presumably easy to induce the shape change. Induced by the adjusted external conditions, the transformations of shape and structure have been observed to occur in the solid regime [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. Note that this kind of transformations is not uniquely determined by the thermodynamics to develop towards the more energetically favored spheres, while the reversed pathway from spherical particles to the anisotropic plates, similar to the Ostwald ripening, has also been discovered to be triggered by the thermal treatment [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>].
</p>
