<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Further structural assignment of 
 <bold>1‐σ</bold> in the solid state is supported by 
 <sup>31</sup>P CP MAS NMR spectroscopy, which indicates the presence of a single species with a signal at 
 <italic>δ</italic>
 <sub>iso</sub>=121.1 ppm, in the range expected for this coordination mode of 
 <bold>L</bold>.
 <xref rid="anie201909240-bib-0018" ref-type="ref">18</xref> In contrast, solution‐phase 
 <sup>31</sup>P{
 <sup>1</sup>H} NMR analysis of crystalline 
 <bold>1</bold> dissolved in suitable solvents
 <xref rid="anie201909240-bib-0019" ref-type="ref">19</xref> shows two distinct resonances. For example, in [D
 <sub>8</sub>]THF a sharp singlet at 130.7 ppm (or a triplet with 
 <sup>3</sup>
 <italic>J</italic>
 <sub>P‐H</sub>=13 Hz in the coupled 
 <sup>31</sup>P NMR spectrum) is assigned to 
 <bold>1‐σ</bold>, but is accompanied by a second, very broad resonance (
 <italic>τ</italic>
 <sub>1/2</sub>=1000 Hz) at −46.2 ppm. Attempts to selectively crystallise the species corresponding to this resonance have been unsuccessful, with XRD and 
 <sup>31</sup>P CP MAS measurements consistently showing the presence of only 
 <bold>1‐σ</bold> in the solid state. Nevertheless, the broadness and chemical shift of this signal are very similar to those observed previously for the complex [K([18]crown‐6)][Cp*Fe(η
 <sup>4</sup>‐TPP)]. In this compound the TPP ligand is rapidly equilibrating between different η
 <sup>4</sup> π‐coordination modes.
 <xref rid="anie201909240-bib-0016" ref-type="ref">16</xref> We therefore assign this signal to an isomeric structure of 
 <bold>1</bold> (
 <bold>1‐π</bold>) where the ligand 
 <bold>L</bold> coordinates in an η
 <sup>4</sup>‐fashion as shown in Scheme 
 <xref rid="anie201909240-fig-5001" ref-type="fig">1</xref>, and which exists in equilibrium with 
 <bold>1‐σ</bold> in solution. This conclusion is supported by DFT calculations. A minimum‐energy structure corresponding to 
 <bold>1‐π</bold> is only 0.9 kcal mol
 <sup>−1</sup> higher in energy than the optimized structure for 
 <bold>1‐σ</bold> (which reproduces well the structure observed by crystallography; see the Supporting Information). Furthermore, conversion of 
 <bold>1‐π</bold> to 
 <bold>1‐σ</bold> is calculated to proceed with a barrier of 27.0 kcal mol
 <sup>−1</sup>, consistent with an equilibrium at room temperature. 
 <sup>31</sup>P{
 <sup>1</sup>H} NMR integration indicates an approximately 2:1 ratio of 
 <bold>1‐σ</bold> to 
 <bold>1‐π</bold> at room temperature, which does not change significantly at lower temperature (−30 °C; at elevated temperatures other reactivity is observed, see the Supporting Information).
</p>
