<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The lattice parameters of AS1 depend linearly on the vacancy concentration 
 <italic>x</italic>, but two realms with different slopes are observed. For 
 <italic>x</italic> &lt; 1/3 the parameter 
 <italic>a</italic> increases linearly with 
 <italic>x</italic>, resembling experimental observation remarkably well. In the same realm 
 <italic>b</italic> decreases slightly, but neither the slope nor the absolute values agree with experimental observations. For higher vacancy concentrations (
 <italic>x</italic> &gt; 1/3), 
 <italic>a</italic> slightly decreases and deviates from the experimental observations. 
 <italic>b</italic> increases but still shows a clear offset from the reference values. The lattice parameters are almost unaffected by changing the orientation of the Al–Si dicluster chains because the parameters with the AS2 pattern (
 <italic>x</italic> &lt; 1/3) are almost identical with those of AS1. 
 <italic>c</italic> varies very little over the whole composition range and is hardly affected by the different Al/Si ordering patterns. Despite the good overlap of 
 <italic>a</italic> for 
 <italic>x</italic> &lt; 1/3, the overall picture indicates that the model does not account for all relevant structural aspects. This is not surprising because the calculations are based on fully ordered models with strict lattice periodicity along 
 <bold>b</bold> whereas the real structures are disordered. Investigations of the diffuse scattering revealed that important inter-vacancy vectors are, among others, [1.5 0.5 0] and [0.5 1.5 0] (Freimann &amp; Rahman, 2001
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb27"> ▸</xref>). The first also plays a crucial role in all supercells with 〈
 <italic>N</italic>
 <sub>V</sub>〉 &gt; 1, but [0.5 1.5 0] breaks the lattice periodicity along 
 <bold>b</bold>. Therefore, it is likely that the ordered model is an appropriate approximation of the disordered vacancy distribution along 
 <bold>a</bold>, but not along 
 <bold>b</bold> which explains the observed offset between 
 <italic>b</italic> from DFT calculations and experiments. It is unlikely that disorder in the real structure is limited to vacancies as Al/Si disordering can be expected as well. The lattice parameters of AS3 show that small changes of the Si distribution (Fig. 10
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig10"> ▸</xref>) result in a significant change of the lattice parameters. The discrepancy in the determined values of 
 <italic>a</italic> is thus likely to originate from Al/Si disorder. Therefore, the unified superspace model is considered to describe the general ordering pattern of vacancies and Al/Si, but in the real structure these patterns are not strictly followed. This is supported by the low energy differences between similar Al/Si ordering patterns (Section 3.1
 <xref ref-type="sec" rid="sec3.1"/>). More work is needed to better understand the disorder in the real structure for different degrees of ordering (Klar 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb39"> ▸</xref>).
</p>
