<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>LiBH
 <sub>4</sub> is as a potential hydrogen storage material due to its high hydrogen content. However, the dehydrogenation/hydrogenation high temperature and pressure prevent its use in a pure form. Thus, LiBH
 <sub>4</sub> has been mixed with a variety of chemicals, including LiAlH
 <sub>4</sub>, for the formation of binary composites [
 <xref rid="B97-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">97</xref>,
 <xref rid="B98-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">98</xref>,
 <xref rid="B99-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">99</xref>,
 <xref rid="B100-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">100</xref>]. Additionally, ternary composites of the type LiAlH
 <sub>4</sub>-LiBH
 <sub>4</sub>-MgF
 <sub>2</sub> have been proposed [
 <xref rid="B101-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">101</xref>]. In this regard, the possibilities of ternary composites are almost infinite. There are a lot of factors to consider, such as the selection of the composites, the relative composition, milling conditions, etc. Systematic studies are missing, noticeably by the difficulty and enormous of the task. The LiAlH
 <sub>4</sub> did not survive the milling process in many catalyzed mixtures, resulting in a mixture of LiBH
 <sub>4</sub>, LiH, and Al [
 <xref rid="B97-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">97</xref>]. Mao et al. proposed that LiAlH
 <sub>4</sub>-LiBH
 <sub>4</sub> doped with TiF
 <sub>3</sub> has a reduced dehydrogenation enthalpy as compared with pure LiBH
 <sub>4</sub> [
 <xref rid="B99-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">99</xref>]. The reported studies coincide in a two-step dehydrogenation pathway and a reduction of the dehydrogenation temperatures, especially if a catalyst, such as TiF
 <sub>3</sub>, is used [
 <xref rid="B99-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">99</xref>]. The first reaction is the decomposition of LiAlH
 <sub>4</sub> at temperatures around 100 °C. The second step is the decomposition of LiBH
 <sub>4</sub>. However, the presence of Al directs the formation of AlB
 <sub>2</sub> [
 <xref rid="B98-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">98</xref>]:
 <disp-formula>2LiBH
  <sub>4</sub> +Al ↔ 2LiH + AlB
  <sub>2</sub> + 3H
  <sub>2</sub>
  <label>(19)</label>
 </disp-formula>
</p>
