<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>As a final comparison, we consider related manganese(II) formate perovskites in which host–guest hydrogen bonding is less important. In dimethylammonium manganese formate, under ambient conditions, the manganese formate framework has the same rhombohedral structure as discussed above, with the dimethylammonium ions disordered about the threefold axis for want of a strongly bound hydrogen-bonding site [
 <xref rid="RSTA20180227C27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,
 <xref rid="RSTA20180227C33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>]. This suggests that host–guest hydrogen bonding is not needed to stabilize the rhombohedral phase. An even more dramatic example is provided by the material ‘[Mn(HCO
 <sub>2</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub>] · 
 <italic>n</italic>H
 <sub>2</sub>O’, which has no bulky 
 <bold>A</bold>-site cation at all. Under ambient conditions, it has the same rhombohedral structure as discussed above, with guest water molecules occupying the cubic interstices (
 <italic>a</italic> = 8.327 Å, 
 <italic>c</italic> = 22.890 Å) [
 <xref rid="RSTA20180227C34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. The original report suggested that this compound contains manganese(III) ions. However, the crystals were colourless and the Mn–O bond lengths were 2.190 Å; both of these observations suggest that the correct oxidation state is manganese(II) [
 <xref rid="RSTA20180227C35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>], with charge balance preserved by a guest hydronium ion, [Mn(HCO
 <sub>2</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub>] · H
 <sub>3</sub>O · 
 <italic>n</italic>H
 <sub>2</sub>O. (For comparison, the closely related compound 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="IM7">
   <mrow>
    <mo stretchy="false">[</mo>
    <mrow>
     <mi mathvariant="normal">Mn</mi>
    </mrow>
    <msub>
     <mrow>
      <mo stretchy="false">(</mo>
      <msub>
       <mrow>
        <mi mathvariant="normal">HCO</mi>
       </mrow>
       <mn>2</mn>
      </msub>
      <mo stretchy="false">)</mo>
     </mrow>
     <mn>3</mn>
    </msub>
    <mo stretchy="false">]</mo>
    <mo>⋅</mo>
    <mfrac>
     <mn>1</mn>
     <mn>2</mn>
    </mfrac>
    <msub>
     <mrow>
      <mi mathvariant="normal">CO</mi>
     </mrow>
     <mn>2</mn>
    </msub>
    <mo>⋅</mo>
    <mfrac>
     <mn>1</mn>
     <mn>4</mn>
    </mfrac>
    <mrow>
     <mi mathvariant="normal">HCOOH</mi>
    </mrow>
    <mo>⋅</mo>
    <mfrac>
     <mn>2</mn>
     <mn>3</mn>
    </mfrac>
    <msub>
     <mrow>
      <mi mathvariant="normal">H</mi>
     </mrow>
     <mn>2</mn>
    </msub>
    <mrow>
     <mi mathvariant="normal">O</mi>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>, which unambiguously contains manganese(III) ions, is dark red and has an Mn–O bond length of 2.001 Å [
 <xref rid="RSTA20180227C36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>].) If this oxidation state assignment is accepted, then this material demonstrates that the rhombohedral structure is stable even in the absence of a bulky organic 
 <bold>A</bold>-site cation.
</p>
