<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Recently, non-rare-earth transitional-metal Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> ions, which could serve as efficient luminescent activators with a strong absorption in the range of 250–600 nm and an intense red emission covering the region from 600 to 800 nm, were widely investigated for developing new red phosphors.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref30">30</xref>
 </sup> Generally, Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> ions can be stable in the host matrix with an octahedral environment.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">31</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref>
 </sup> Double perovskite structure is regarded as an outstanding host material for Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> activators on account of its different crystal structures, excellent optical properties, and good chemical stability.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref36">36</xref>
 </sup> Previously, our group has reported several red phosphors based on Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>-activated double perovskite compounds, including Ca
 <sub>2</sub>GdTaO
 <sub>6</sub>:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>, KLaMgWO
 <sub>6</sub>:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>, NaLaMgWO
 <sub>6</sub>:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>, BaLaMgSbO
 <sub>6</sub>:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>, Ca
 <sub>2</sub>GdSbO
 <sub>6</sub>:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>, and BaLaMgNbO
 <sub>6</sub>:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref37">37</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref41">41</xref>
 </sup> To the best of our knowledge, the luminescence properties of the Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>-doped Ba
 <sub>2</sub>GdTaO
 <sub>6</sub> (BGT) double perovskite have not been reported until now. The BGT compound would be a good host material for Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> ion doping because it has abundant [TaO
 <sub>6</sub>] octahedrons that are favorable for Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> ions to replace Ta
 <sup>5+</sup> ion sites.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref42">42</xref>
 </sup> Accordingly, in this work, we reported on the luminescence properties of BGT:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> phosphors, which were synthesized using the conventional high-temperature solid-state reaction method. The crystal structure, morphology, optical properties, decay curves, and internal quantum efficiency (IQE) of the BGT:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> phosphors were systematically investigated and discussed. Our results demonstrated that the as-prepared BGT:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> phosphors were efficient deep-red-emitting luminescent materials for indoor plants growth LEDs.
</p>
