<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>For the quantitative characterization of the mutual orientation of the nanoparticles with respect to the superlattice, the CCF 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm246">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mi>C</mi>
     <mrow>
      <mo>(</mo>
      <mrow>
       <msubsup>
        <mi>q</mi>
        <mrow>
         <mn>111</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
         <mi>A</mi>
         <mi>L</mi>
        </mrow>
       </msubsup>
       <mo>,</mo>
       <msubsup>
        <mi>q</mi>
        <mrow>
         <mn>112</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
         <mi>S</mi>
         <mi>L</mi>
        </mrow>
       </msubsup>
       <mo>,</mo>
       <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">Δ</mi>
      </mrow>
      <mo>)</mo>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> was evaluated to verify if the angular positions of the diffraction peaks from the atomic lattice in WAXS are correlated with the angular positions of the diffraction peaks from the superlattice in SAXS. The CCF averaged over all diffraction patterns, where both WAXS and SAXS signals are present, is shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f016">Figure 16</xref>c. Well-distinguishable peaks of the CCF clearly indicate that a certain orientation of the nanoparticles in the superlattice is preserved, not only within the domains but in all scanned regions of the sample. Further analysis of the CCF, which required simulations of the scattering patterns and evaluation of the model CCF shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f016">Figure 16</xref>d, revealed that the atomic lattice and the superlattice of the mesocrystal have five common directions, namely three 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm247">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mo stretchy="false">〈</mo>
     <mn>100</mn>
     <mo stretchy="false">〉</mo>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> directions, as well as the [110] and [−110] directions (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f016">Figure 16</xref>e). Moreover, the sensitivity of AXCCA to angular positions of the scattering peaks allows one to establish that the mesocrystal superlattice exhibits a tetragonal distortion with 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm248">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mi>c</mi>
     <mo>/</mo>
     <mi>a</mi>
     <mo>≈</mo>
     <mn>1.22</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> (
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm249">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mi>a</mi>
     <mo>=</mo>
     <mn>7.9</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> nm, 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm250">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mi>c</mi>
     <mo>=</mo>
     <mn>9.7</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> nm), which appears as splitting of the CCF peaks at about Δ = ±90° (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f016">Figure 16</xref>c,d). The width of the CCF peaks also contains important information about the orientational order in the system, namely that the above-mentioned mutual orientation of the nanoparticles and superlattice is preserved in all scanned positions with a mean deviation of ~2.5°.
</p>
