<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Particle shape and size of the quantum dots were estimated by using a transmission electron microscope (TEM, JEM-1230, JEOL Ltd., Japan) using an acceleration voltage of 80 kV. The film surface morphology was observed on a field emission scanning electron microscope (FESEM, Hitachi, S4800). An energy dispersive spectrometer (EDS, Genesis XM 4i Energy Dispersive X-ray Analysis System, FEI) was used to observe elemental distribution of cross-section in QD–polymer hybrid films, confirming the dispersion of QDs in the polymer matrix. Atomic force microscopy (AFM) images were taken for samples on a NT-MDT Solver PRO-M AFM operated at 200 kV. The crystal structures of CdSe-QDs were measured using an X-ray diffractometer (Bruker D8 ADVANCE X) with Cu radiation. UV–vis absorption and transmittance spectra were measured using a Perkin-Elmer Lambda UV–vis spectrophotometer using toluene as a background. The as-prepared quantum dots were diluted using toluene and placed in a quartz cell for measurement. The as-prepared quantum dots were diluted using toluene and placed in a quartz cell, and the prepared organic light-emitting film was placed on a solid stand. Photoluminescence (PL) spectra were recorded using a Hitachi F-7000 fluorescence spectrophotometer exciting at a wavelength of 440 nm to confirm the peak position of the fluorescence emission spectrum of the material. Thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) was measured on a thermogravimetric analyzer (SDT-Q600, TA) scanning from 25 to 800 °C. The analysis was performed at initial temperatures of 25 and 120 °C for 10 min to remove water at a heating rate of 20 °C/min. The CIE coordinates of a white LED device and QD-hybrid light-emitting film were determined on a lighting spectrometer (Model 14-1, Lighting Passport) using a UV light source excited at a wavelength of 365 nm. The fabricated white LEDs were employed to measure the color rendering index (CRI) and color temperature at different current densities from 10 to 50 mA. The luminous flux was measured by different current densities of 10–50 mA for the fabricated white LEDs and the original blue LED chip, respectively. The light extraction efficiency was calculated using the ratio of the above two luminous flux.</p>
