<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In view of the above disadvantages, recent investigations on the vibration in diamond turning are performed on the multi-direction and multi-frequency conditions. For instance, Zhang et al. proposed a five-degree-of-freedom dynamic model for the aerostatic bearing spindle to explore the mechanism of multi-direction vibration (in the 
 <italic>x</italic>-, 
 <italic>y</italic>- and 
 <italic>z</italic>-direction) and its influence on surface topography in diamond turning [
 <xref rid="B80-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">80</xref>,
 <xref rid="B81-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">81</xref>]. Their studies show that on the general effect of the axial and radial vibrations, a spiral and two-fold patterns surface profile generates on the machined surface. Based on the dynamic model, they further pointed out that the surface topography in the center area is mainly affected by the axial vibration of the spindle, while that outside region is primarily affected by the tilting motion of the spindle [
 <xref rid="B82-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">82</xref>]. In addition, Tian et al. assumed the relative vibration between diamond tool and workpiece in turning direction (infeed direction) and feeding direction to be a simple harmonic motion, and the fine correlations of surface topography between the simulation and experiment results proved the accuracy of the proposed model [
 <xref rid="B83-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">83</xref>]. Similarly, Huang et al. considered the vibrations in the feed and infeed directions, and established the surface topography model for flat, spherical and freeform surfaces [
 <xref rid="B84-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">84</xref>,
 <xref rid="B85-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">85</xref>]. Their investigations indicated that when considering the vibration in feed direction, the tool locus will be more complex and its influence on surface topography cannot be ignored, particularly for the spherical and freeform surfaces. Lin et al. considered the vibrations in three directions, i.e., 
 <italic>x</italic>-, 
 <italic>y</italic>- and 
 <italic>z</italic>-axis, and they claimed that the influence of vibration on surface topography decreases with the decrease of the spindle speed [
 <xref rid="B86-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>]. Furthermore, Qu et al. directly integrated the real-time vibration signals in the feed and infeed directions into the surface topography model in ultra-precision roll die turning and fine consistence is therefore observed [
 <xref rid="B87-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">87</xref>]. Meanwhile, it should be noted that the original phase of the vibration for [
 <xref rid="B83-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">83</xref>] to [
 <xref rid="B86-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">86</xref>] all assumed to be zero for convenience. 
</p>
