<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ack>
 <title>Acknowledgements</title>
 <p>N.D. and L.D. thank the German Research Foundation [Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG)] and the Federal Ministry of Education and Research [Bundesministerium für Bildung und Forschung (BMBF), Germany] for financial support: projects No. DU 954-11/1, No. DU 393-9/2, and No. DU 393-10/1 (DFG) and Grant No. 5K16WC1 (BMBF). Portions of this work were performed at GeoSoilEnviroCARS (The University of Chicago, Sector 13), Advanced Photon Source (APS), Argonne National Laboratory. GeoSoilEnviroCARS is supported by the National Science Foundation—Earth Sciences (EAR—1634415) and Department of Energy- GeoSciences (DE-FG02-94ER14466). This research used resources of the Advanced Photon Source, a U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) Office of Science User Facility operated for the DOE Office of Science by Argonne National Laboratory under Contract No. DE-AC02-06CH11357. A.C. acknowledges support by The Elite Network of Bavaria through the program Oxides. I.A.A., J.T., O.H., and S.I.S. are grateful to the support provided by the Swedish Research Council projects No 2015-04391, 2014-4750, and 637-2013-7296. Support from the Swedish Government Strategic Research Areas in Materials Science on Functional Materials at Linköping University (Faculty Grant SFO-Mat-LiU No 2009-00971) and the Swedish e-Science Research Centre (SeRC) is gratefully acknowledged. Theoretical analysis of structural properties was supported by the Ministry of Education and Science of the Russian Federation (Grant No. 14.Y26.31.0005). Simulations of the lattice vibrations were supported by the Ministry of Education and Science of the Russian Federation in the framework of Increase Competitiveness Program of NUST “MISIS” (No. K2-2017-080) implemented by a governmental decree dated 16 March 2013, No. 211. Calculations have been carried out at the Swedish National Infrastructure for Computing (SNIC) and at the computer cluster at NUST “MISIS”.</p>
</ack>
