<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Lithium is a well-known commodity due to its use in the pharmaceutical industry;
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
 </sup> however, its value has soared in recent years due to its use in rechargeable batteries. This increase in demand has resulted in a sharp rise in global consumption rate from 200 t per year in 1994 to over 40 000 in 2008.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>
 </sup> At present the majority of Li is extracted from pegmatite rocks, which contain the Li-feldspar spodumene (LiAl(SiO
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub>) and the Li-mica lepidolite (KLi
 <sub>2</sub>AlSi
 <sub>4</sub>O
 <sub>10</sub>F
 <sub>2</sub>). However, 66% of the world’s total Li is present in brines; thus, these sources have the highest capacity for long-term Li extraction.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
 </sup> Brines also have the additional benefit that extraction of Li is proposed to be between 30 and 50% less expensive than from mined mineral ores.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>
 </sup> Li can be extracted from brines via adsorption to inorganic solids, such as manganese
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref>
 </sup> and titanium oxides,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref>
 </sup> and using membrane electrolysis.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
 </sup> Alternatively, brines can be evaporated to precipitate Li directly from solution, typically as the Li-carbonate phase zabuyelite (Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub>).
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> Li extraction in the formation of zabuyelite has also been suggested as part of recycling procedures at the other end of the battery life cycle.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> The exact extraction method chosen for Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub> production depends on the composition of the aqueous solution, where the Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> content is the limiting factor in brines as this ion interferes with many of the extraction techniques currently used.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
