<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Despite its importance as a product in many different primary and secondary Li resources, there are only a limited number of studies on zabuyelite formation from solution. Typically, these reflect the nucleation and growth of Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub> phases in the presence of organic molecules
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup> and do not consider the effect of inorganic ions in brine on Li-carbonate formation. Brines of interest for Li extraction have a varied and complex solution chemistry with high concentrations of Na
 <sup>+</sup>, K
 <sup>+</sup>, Cl
 <sup>–</sup>, SO
 <sub>4</sub>
 <sup>2–</sup>, as well as Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> and Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> concentrations up to 4 wt %.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> The formation of ion pairs between the constituents of other oxyanion-bearing mineral phases, such as magnesite (MgCO
 <sub>3</sub>) and sulfate hemihydrate, has been shown to significantly change the ability of the mineral to form from aqueous solution.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> In addition, dissolved ions can form direct interactions with different surfaces on a growing crystal, influencing the stability of the surface and thus its ability to grow. For example, the presence of Li
 <sup>+</sup> in solution is known to bind to the {0001} surfaces of calcite (CaCO
 <sub>3</sub>) crystals, stabilizing this face
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>
 </sup> and changing the final crystal morphology.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>
 </sup> In contrast, the presence of different background ions, i.e., those that do not interact directly with the mineral constituents in solution or at the mineral surface, has been proposed to enhance or inhibit ion and surface dehydration,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> altering precipitation rates. Therefore, the solution components may contribute either positively or negatively to the formation of Li-carbonate from aqueous solutions.
</p>
