<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="Abs1">
 <p id="Par1">The practical implementation of supercapacitors is hindered by low utilization and poor structural stability of electrode materials. Herein, to surmount these critical challenges, a three-dimensional hierarchical α-Co(OH)
  <sub>2</sub>/α-Ni(OH)
  <sub>2</sub> heterojunction nanorods are built 
  <italic>in situ</italic> on Ni foam through a mild two-step growth reaction. The unique lamellar crystal structure and abundant intercalated anions of α-M(OH)
  <sub>2</sub> (M = Co or Ni) and the ideal electronic conductivity of α-Co(OH)
  <sub>2</sub> construct numerous cross-linked ion and electron transport paths in heterojunction nanorods. The deformation stresses exerted by α-Co(OH)
  <sub>2</sub> and α-Ni(OH)
  <sub>2</sub> on each other guarantee the excellent structural stability of this heterojunction nanorods. Using nickel foam with a three-dimensional network conductive framework as the template ensures the rapidly transfer of electrons between this heterojunction nanorods and current collector. Three-dimensional hierarchical structure of α-Co(OH)
  <sub>2</sub>/α-Ni(OH)
  <sub>2</sub> heterojunction nanorods provides a large liquid interface area. These result together in the high utilization rate and excellent structure stability of the α-Co(OH)
  <sub>2</sub>/α-Ni(OH)
  <sub>2</sub> heterojunction nanorods. And the capacitance retention rate is up to 93.4% at 1 A g
  <sup>−1</sup> from three-electrode system to two-electrode system. The α-Co(OH)
  <sub>2</sub>/α-Ni(OH)
  <sub>2</sub>//AC device also present a long cycle life (the capacitance retention rate is 123.6% at 5 A g
  <sup>−1</sup> for 10000 cycles), a high specific capacitance (207.2 F g
  <sup>−1</sup> at 1 A g
  <sup>−1</sup>), and high energy density and power density (72.6 Wh kg
  <sup>−1</sup> at 196.4 W kg
  <sup>−1</sup> and 40.9 Wh kg
  <sup>−1</sup> at 3491.8 W kg
  <sup>−1</sup>), exhibiting a fascinating potential for supercapacitor in large-scale applications.
 </p>
</abstract>
