<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is worth mentioning a peak appearance at 530.8 eV, already noticed by Mkhoyan et al. (
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0032" ref-type="ref">2006</xref>) and Garvie (
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0013" ref-type="ref">2010</xref>) at approximately 531 and 530 eV, respectively. This peak growth has been interpreted as a structure damage leading to O
 <sub>2</sub> cluster developments. The intensity normalization of differential ELNES spectra is done on the highest peak after the peak observed at 530.8 eV, that is, for an energy starting from 532 eV. Figure 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-fig-0006" ref-type="fig">6</xref> shows the normalized differential O K‐edge ELNES spectra of olivine//lamella for different zones characterized by different thicknesses since this parameter has a strong influence on the spectra. Whatever the thickness, the lamella is less affected by O
 <sub>2</sub> cluster developments than olivine, suggesting that the Si─O bonds within the lamella are stronger than in olivine. It can be noticed that there is no peak at 530.8 eV for the smallest thicknesses (
 <inline-formula>≈</inline-formula>30 nm), suggesting the impossibility to store O
 <sub>2</sub> clusters in such thin zones. To compare these experimental results with literature, the simulated O K‐edge ELNES spectrum of forsterite (the pure magnesia pole of olivine) has been subtracted to the simulated O K‐edge ELNES spectrum of stishovite (see Figure 2 in Winkler et al., 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0053" ref-type="ref">2013</xref> and Figure 4 in Kaneko et al., 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0022" ref-type="ref">1998</xref>, respectively) to obtain a simulated differential O K‐edge ELNES spectrum of « SiO
 <sub>4</sub> minus SiO
 <sub>6</sub> » with the same normalization process. The evolution of experimental differential spectra with the thickness is significant. From Figure 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-fig-0006" ref-type="fig">6</xref>, four peaks can be noticed, located near the same energies than the simulated differential spectrum ones, that is, 535, 537.5, 539.5, and 543 eV, respectively. The peak situated at 535 eV is negative, and the last peak (at 543 eV) is positive with a small intensity. The two other peaks are positive with medium intensities. Regardless of the studied zones thickness, approximately the same differential ELNES signatures are noted as the simulated ones. This confirms the hypothesis of the occurrence of silicon in octahedral sites in the lamella and hence the identification of Anh‐B.
</p>
