<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Monosilicides of transition metals that crystallize in a cubic noncentrosymmetric B20 structure (space group P2
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm2">
   <mrow>
    <msub>
     <mrow/>
     <mn>1</mn>
    </msub>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>3, #198) have many interesting magnetic, topological, and transport properties. In recent years, interest in the topological properties of solids has increased. Many monosilicides exhibit unusual properties both in real and in reciprocal space. For example, in MnSi and in isostructural MnGe, unusual magnetic properties related to the existence of the skyrmion phase were observed [
 <xref rid="B1-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Recently, it was discovered that the semimetallic CoSi and RhSi have nontrivial electronic structure topology [
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. While the low-energy electronic structure in Weyl semimetals contains an even number of doubly-degenerate band-touching points, carrying topological charge 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm3">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mo>±</mo>
     <mn>1</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>, in CoSi and RhSi the degree of degeneracy is higher, and topological charges are greater than unity. The high degree of degeneracy is caused by the symmetry of their crystal lattice [
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. In contrast to Weyl nodes, fermions corresponding to nodes with topological charge greater than unity do not exist in relativistic quantum-field theory because they are prohibited by Lorentz invariance. Thus, in Ref. [
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>], they are called “new fermions”.
</p>
