<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The study of the band structure of CoSi and its alloys with FeSi started with a semimetallic model featuring overlapping parabolic valence and conduction bands [
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. More recent band structure calculations in the framework of density functional theory demonstrated that their electronic structure is more complex. Band structure calculations of CoSi were done without taking into account the spin–orbit coupling (SOC) [
 <xref rid="B9-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>], as well as including SOC [
 <xref rid="B4-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. The band structure of the isostructural RhSi was studied too [
 <xref rid="B12-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. Symmetry analysis showed that the electronic structure of crystals with P2
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm4">
   <mrow>
    <msub>
     <mrow/>
     <mn>1</mn>
    </msub>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>3 space group (#198) contains a sixfold degenerate band-touching node at the 
 <italic>R</italic> point of the Brillouin zone (BZ) [
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations showed that the electronic structure of CoSi and RhSi indeed has nonzero topological charge and Fermi arcs, connecting projections of band-touching nodes at 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm5">
   <mrow>
    <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">Γ</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> and 
 <italic>R</italic> points on the surface Brillouin zone [
 <xref rid="B4-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. The band-touching nodes in bulk electronic spectrum and the Fermi arcs for CoSi were recently experimentally observed in angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES) experiments [
 <xref rid="B14-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. Although the degree of degeneracy is restricted by space-group symmetry, the energy position of these nodes and the peculiarity of the corresponding surface Fermi arcs should be determined by band structure calculations. Thus, it is interesting to compare their band structures and topological properties with other isostructural transition metal monosilicides and other compounds, such as CoGe, RhGe, and RhSn.
</p>
