<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Trends in the density of states (DOS) in monosilicides of Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ru, Rh, and Os with a B20 structure were analyzed in Ref. [
 <xref rid="B36-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>] using the plane-wave pseudopotential method. Ferromagnetic-to-paramagnetic phase transition under pressure in MnSi was studied theoretically using self-consistent linear muffin-tin orbital method within atomic-sphere approximation [
 <xref rid="B37-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>]. Band structure and magnetic property peculiarities were studied using the full-potential method in local density approximation (LDA) [
 <xref rid="B38-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>]. These works agree that the DFT ground state for MnSi is ferromagnetic, but calculations gave values of a magnetic moment equal to 1 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm14">
   <mrow>
    <msub>
     <mi>μ</mi>
     <mi>B</mi>
    </msub>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>, which is considerably larger than the experimental value of 0.4 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm15">
   <mrow>
    <msub>
     <mi>μ</mi>
     <mi>B</mi>
    </msub>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> [
 <xref rid="B38-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>]. The inclusion of on-site correlation of Mn d-electrons in the framework of the LDA+U approach allowed obtaining an experimental value of the magnetic moment for Hubbard parameter 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm16">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mi>U</mi>
     <mo>∼</mo>
     <mn>6</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> eV [
 <xref rid="B39-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
 <xref rid="B40-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>]. Due to the large period, description of a helical magnetic structure is difficult within an ab initio approach. Dzyaloshinskii–Moriya interaction appeared to be important in the description of long-period helical magnetic structures in MnSi [
 <xref rid="B41-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>]. Parameters of this interaction were obtained, and its influence on magnetic-phase transition in MnSi was discussed [
 <xref rid="B40-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,
 <xref rid="B42-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>]. Qualitatively, the band structure calculated in the DFT framework correlated with ARPES data near the Fermi level [
 <xref rid="B43-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>], although more refined self-consistent quasiparticle GW-calculations better describe an experimentally obtained electronic spectrum, away from the Fermi level [
 <xref rid="B43-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>].
</p>
