<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Another approach to the toxicity issue could be to use cesium lead halide perovskite QRs as the polarized emitter. These materials are very similar in synthesis and material properties to II‐VI and III‐V nanocrystals and display high QY and small FWHM of emission, making them well suited for LED applications. Several recent breakthroughs with these materials have occurred, and the field has experienced unprecedented development in just a few years' time.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0065" ref-type="ref">65</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0066" ref-type="ref">66</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0067" ref-type="ref">67</xref> While the current stability limitations and the presence of toxic Pb may again be a limiting factor for commercialization,
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0068" ref-type="ref">68</xref> recent results of high efficiency electroluminescent perovskite LEDs have generated significant interest in CsPbBr
 <sub>3</sub> as a down‐conversion emitter.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0065" ref-type="ref">65</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0066" ref-type="ref">66</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0067" ref-type="ref">67</xref> Nanocrystals of metal lead halides have been demonstrated with multiple routes to synthesis, including in situ and in polar solvents,
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0068" ref-type="ref">68</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0069" ref-type="ref">69</xref> and color tunability, including halide exchange and quantum size effects
 <sub>,</sub> to achieve linewidths as thin as 17 nm in FWHM. Emission from perovskite QRs has been found to display strong polarization anisotropy.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0068" ref-type="ref">68</xref> Perovskite nanowires synthesized via A‐group substitution suggests that a large family of anisotropic, inorganic perovskite nanocrystals with varying properties may be synthesized via careful selection of the reaction precursors.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0070" ref-type="ref">70</xref> Finally, in situ perovskite nanorod synthesis and alignment,
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0071" ref-type="ref">71</xref> and early stage LCD pixels have been reported, albeit with limited performance thus far. All this suggests that several innovative approaches are possible to achieving polarized emission from perovskites in LCDs.
</p>
