<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ack>
 <title>Acknowledgments</title>
 <p>We thank B. Yan and D. Zhang for assistance with the synchrotron XRD measurements. The XRD experiment was performed at the 13-BM-C experimental station of the GSECARS facility at the APS. 
  <bold>Funding:</bold> Q.X. acknowledges the strong support from Singapore Ministry of Education via Tier 2 grant (MOE2015-T2-1-047) and Tier 1 grants (RG 113/16 and RG 194/17). S.S. acknowledges support from National Natural Science Foundation of China (nos. 11504267 and 11604243), the Natural Science Foundation of Tianjin (no. 16JCQNJC01600), and Tianjin Municipal Education Commission Scientific Research project (2018KJ151). C.K.G. thanks the National Supercomputing Center (NSCC), Singapore and A*STAR Computational Resource Center (ACRC), Singapore for computing resources. A.G.d.Á. acknowledges the financial support of the Presidential Postdoctoral Fellowship program of the Nanyang Technological University. 13-BM-C operation is supported by COMPRES through the Partnership for Extreme Crystallography (PX
  <sup>2</sup>) project, under NSF cooperative agreement EAR 11-57758. 
  <bold>Author contributions:</bold> S.L., S.S., and Q.X. conceived the idea and designed the research. S.L. and S.S. performed the high-pressure setup and optical measurements. J.X. prepared the sample. C.K.G. carried out the first-principles calculation. S.S. did the synchrotron radiation XRD measurement. Y.F. and T.J.W. did the XRD refinement and structural analysis. S.L., S.S., A.G.d.Á., H.L., W.H., and Q.X. analyzed the data. A.G.d.Á. and T.T.H.D. intensively discussed on the data and manuscript. S.L., S.S., and Q.X. wrote the manuscript. All authors discussed and commented on the manuscript. S.L. and S.S. contributed equally to this work. 
  <bold>Competing interests:</bold> The authors declare that they have no competing interests. 
  <bold>Data and materials availability:</bold> All data needed to evaluate the conclusions in the paper are present in the paper and/or the Supplementary Materials. Additional data related to this paper may be requested from the authors.
 </p>
</ack>
