<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors were prepared from a stoichiometric mixture of MCO
 <sub>3</sub> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba), SiO
 <sub>2</sub>, Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub>, and Eu
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> under a reducing atmosphere (4% H
 <sub>2</sub>/Ar) at 900 °C for 12 h. N
 <sup>3–</sup>-doped Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4−δ</sub>N
 <sub>2/3δ</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors were prepared from a stoichiometric mixture of MCO
 <sub>3</sub> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba), α-Si
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>, Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub>, and Eu
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> under NH
 <sub>3</sub> atmosphere at 900 °C for 12 h. The Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> ion concentration was fixed at 1 mol %. X-ray diffraction analysis was carried out using a graphite monochromator (DMAX-2200PC, Rigaku). A step scan mode was selected in a 2θ range (10–110°) with a step size of 0.02° and counting time of 5 s for each step. The refinements of crystal structure were carried out by the Rietveld method using the FullProf program. The diffraction profiles were fitted using a pseudo-Voigt peak function and manually selected background points. FT-IR analyses were carried out using a Bruker VERTEX70 FT-IR spectrometer with an extension in the far-IR region. The extension consists of a multilayer mylar beam splitter, a room-temperature DLATGS detector with preamplifier, and polyethylene windows for the internal optical path. The binding energies of the elements were determined by an X-ray photoelectron spectrophotometer (ESCALAB 250) with a monochromatic Al Kα X-ray source (
 <italic>hν</italic> = 1486.6 eV) at Busan Center of Korea Basic Science Institute (KBSI). The determined binding energies were calibrated using the internal standard of adventitious carbon (C 1s at 284.6 eV). SIMS (CAMECA IMS-6f, France) was carried out to determine the elemental composition of the N
 <sup>3–</sup>-substituted phosphors. The SIMS standard was used with 
 <sup>14</sup>N isotope implanted into SiO
 <sub>2</sub> film as N
 <sup>+</sup> at 100 keV (a dose of 5 × 10
 <sup>14</sup> ions/cm
 <sup>2</sup>). To determine the relative sensitivity factor (RSF) of each element, the intensity of secondary ion was corrected by the SIMS results from the standard material. For a careful examination, the Cs
 <sup>+</sup> primary-ion beam was focused using an electron neutralizer for charge compensation (net impact energy = 15 keV; beam current = 20 nA). The PL spectra were obtained using a fluorometer (FS-2 model, Scinco) with a xenon lamp (150 W) under an operating voltage of 350 V. The diffuse reflectance spectra were obtained using a UV–visible spectrophotometer (UV-2600, Shimadzu) with a BaSO
 <sub>4</sub> reference.
</p>
