<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Vibrational transitions can be observed as infrared or Raman spectra. Although frequently, these two techniques are complementary, their physical origins are different [
 <xref rid="B302-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">302</xref>]. IR absorption spectra originate from photons in the infrared region that are absorbed by transitions between two vibrational levels of the molecule in the electronic ground state. Raman spectra have their origin in the electronic polarization that is caused by ultraviolet, visible, and near-IR light [
 <xref rid="B302-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">302</xref>]. The observed vibration modes depend on factors, such as the molecular symmetry, identity of atoms, and bond energies, i.e., the kinetic and potential energies of the system. The kinetic energy is determined by the masses of the individual atoms and their geometrical arrangement in the molecule. On the other hand, the potential energy arises from the interaction between the individual atoms and it is described in terms of the force constants [
 <xref rid="B302-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">302</xref>]. For the alanates, the common structures are the tetrahedral [AlH
 <sub>4</sub>]
 <sup>−</sup> and octahedral [AlH
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>3−</sup> units. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-02724-f027">Figure 27</xref> illustrates the four normal modes of vibration of a tetrahedral [AlH
 <sub>4</sub>]
 <sup>−</sup>. All four vibrations are Raman-active, whereas only ν
 <sub>3</sub> and ν
 <sub>4</sub> are infrared active [
 <xref rid="B302-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">302</xref>]. Octahedral molecules have six normal modes of vibration; of these, vibrations ν
 <sub>1</sub>, ν
 <sub>2</sub>, and ν
 <sub>5</sub> are Raman-active, whereas only ν
 <sub>3</sub> and ν
 <sub>4</sub> are infrared-active (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-02724-f028">Figure 28</xref>) [
 <xref rid="B302-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">302</xref>]. 
</p>
