<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The vibrational spectra of alanates are frequently classified as external and internal. The external vibrations are due to the vibration of the whole crystal structure. Meanwhile, the internal vibrations are due to the [AlH
 <sub>4</sub>]
 <sup>−</sup> ion, which has four active vibrational modes in Raman and only two in infrared [
 <xref rid="B303-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">303</xref>]. Some of these features are shared with other materials of similar structure, for example, the borohydrides [
 <xref rid="B304-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">304</xref>]. The infrared active modes of the [AlH
 <sub>4</sub>]
 <sup>−</sup> ion are the asymmetric stretching modes in the region 1600–2000 cm
 <sup>−1</sup> and the bending modes in the region 700–900 cm
 <sup>−1</sup> [
 <xref rid="B305-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">305</xref>]. Some representative data are collected in 
 <xref rid="materials-12-02724-t019" ref-type="table">Table 19</xref> and 
 <xref rid="materials-12-02724-t020" ref-type="table">Table 20</xref>. As a generally accepted trend of infrared vibrations in the alanates of group 1, the stretching modes, in wavenumbers, roughly decrease with increasing mass of the cation [
 <xref rid="B306-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">306</xref>]. Meanwhile, the bending modes are unaffected by the counter-ion [
 <xref rid="B305-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">305</xref>,
 <xref rid="B306-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">306</xref>]. Other correlations between the stretching and bending peaks (or regions) versus ionization energy, electronegativities, or bond distance have been proposed [
 <xref rid="B302-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">302</xref>]. Indeed, we tried to find correlations with these parameters. However, we obtained the best results by using the difference in the electronegativities between Al and the counter-cation or the counter-cation ion size. In 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-02724-f029">Figure 29</xref> we present a correlation between the most intense stretching and bending IR peak of MAlH
 <sub>4</sub> (M = group 1 metals, [AlH
 <sub>4</sub>]
 <sup>−</sup> tetrahedra) versus the difference in electronegativities of Al and the metal. The electronegativity scale was the Allred–Rochow [
 <xref rid="B307-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">307</xref>]. The IR data that were obtained by Adicks et al. in pure crystalline materials [
 <xref rid="B177-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">177</xref>] were complemented by data published in several experimental and theoretical reports compiled in this review [
 <xref rid="B167-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">167</xref>,
 <xref rid="B308-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">308</xref>,
 <xref rid="B309-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">309</xref>,
 <xref rid="B310-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">310</xref>,
 <xref rid="B311-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">311</xref>,
 <xref rid="B312-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">312</xref>,
 <xref rid="B313-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">313</xref>,
 <xref rid="B314-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">314</xref>,
 <xref rid="B315-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">315</xref>,
 <xref rid="B316-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">316</xref>,
 <xref rid="B317-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">317</xref>,
 <xref rid="B318-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">318</xref>,
 <xref rid="B319-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">319</xref>,
 <xref rid="B320-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">320</xref>]. The data reflects the significant dispersion of results. The NaAlH
 <sub>4</sub> data are the most common and particularly disperse, which is probably due to the diversity in the material history, such as milling, doping, or cycling [
 <xref rid="B318-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">318</xref>]. The quantity of available IR data on K, Rb, and Cs- alanates is rather scarce. Still, some tendencies were found; there is a bell-shape dispersion of the Al-H stretching frequency (most intense peak) versus the difference of electronegativity between Al and the group 1 metal. Meanwhile, there is an almost linear increase of the Al-H bending frequency (most intense peak). This can be related to the changes in the geometry of the alanates, along with the group.
</p>
