<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In recent years, novel crystal engineering strategies have been effectively developed to modify the characteristics of a variety of pharmaceutical products [
 <xref rid="B1-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Among pharmaceutical solid-state complexes, co-crystals have attracted increasing attention. Co-crystals are molecular complexes composed of two or more constituents which are bound in the unit cell through various noncovalent interactions such as hydrogen bonding, π-π stacking, and Van der Waals interactions [
 <xref rid="B3-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. The preparation of co-crystals for a given substance offers the advantage of altering the physical and pharmaceutical properties of the drug without modifying its molecular formula. Specifically, co-crystals with the same active pharmaceutical ingredient (API) and different complementary co-crystal formers (CCFs) may show strikingly diverse characteristics, which are directly related to the nature of the CCF component, such as its melting point, solubility, bioavailability, hygroscopicity, and chemical stability [
 <xref rid="B4-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Despite the importance of co-crystals, a systematic study of their structure and of the relation between the structure and the mechanical properties of the co-crystal still remains a rarity [
 <xref rid="B6-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. Consequently, the current development of pharmaceutical products relies, to a large extent, on empirical methods. Analysis and a deep understanding of the self-assembly rules and of the binding modes between the API and different CCFs may explain how the molecules interact with each other and how to select suitable CCFs to generate predictable structures. For this reason, crystal structure prediction constitutes the main focus of the vast majority of crystallographic articles.
</p>
