<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Steroids play a prominent role in life sciences or as pharmacophores. Progesterone (PROG) is a naturally and poorly water-soluble steroid drug that belongs to the category of progestins, which are used in birth control pills and menopausal hormone replacement therapies [
 <xref rid="B8-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. The formation of co-crystals can improve properties of pharmaceuticals [
 <xref rid="B9-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. Karamertzanis has investigated the α···π stacking interaction of different steroids with aromatic molecules and has indicated that the steroid-binding affinity depends on the steroid backbone and especially the A-ring structure [
 <xref rid="B10-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>] (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molecules-24-03936-f001">Figure 1</xref>). However, the solid-state complexation of PROG and aromatic molecules has never been systematically studied. In this work, PROG was selected as a co-crystallizing agent, not only due to its attractive backbone but also its terminal carbonyl groups, which provide the possibility for a more abundant network structure. Furthermore, PROG exists in two monotropically-related polymorphs: a thermodynamically stable form I, with a melting point at 129 °C, and a metastable form II, with a melting point at 122 °C [
 <xref rid="B11-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. The co-crystallization of PROG into a suitable co-former may contribute to improving its solid-state properties. However, co-crystallization may be influenced by many factors, including geometry, functional group position, and steric hindrance [
 <xref rid="B13-molecules-24-03936" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. Fortunately, the interplay of several interactions in the co-crystal structure provides some guidelines upon which to choose its co-formers based on crystal engineering principles.
</p>
