<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">Double perovskites (DP; 
 <italic>A</italic>
 <sub>2</sub>
 <italic>BB</italic>′ O
 <sub>6</sub>)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup> belong to a class of materials which exhibit many interesting properties and rich physics. Understandably, the choice of the transition metal ions at the 
 <italic>B</italic> and 
 <italic>B</italic>′ sites with different electron occupancies decide the material properties of the DPs. When both 
 <italic>B</italic> and 
 <italic>B</italic>′ are magnetic ions, the magnetic and electronic properties of the system are governed by 
 <italic>B</italic>-O-
 <italic>B</italic>′ interaction within a rock salt type structural definition as shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(a)</xref>. For example, the high temperature ferromagnetic (FM) order (
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>C</italic>
 </sub> &gt; 400 K) of the DP compounds, Sr
 <sub>2</sub>FeMoO
 <sub>6</sub> and Sr
 <sub>2</sub>FeReO
 <sub>6</sub> is explained by a generalized double exchange mechanism through electronic band filling of the (Mo/Re) 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub>↓-O-Fe 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub>↓ conduction band
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. However, if the 
 <italic>B</italic>-site ion is non-magnetic, the magnetic ground state would be defined by the edge-shared network of tetrahedra comprising the 
 <italic>B</italic>′ magnetic ions (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(b)</xref>). Such systems often exhibit geometric frustration in presence of antiferromagnetic nearest-neighbor correlations. Recently, detailed theoretical investigations have been carried out on similar DPs with the magnetic 
 <italic>B</italic>′ ions, having 
 <italic>nd</italic>
 <sup>1</sup> and 
 <italic>nd</italic>
 <sup>2</sup> (
 <italic>n</italic> = 4, 5) electronic configurations and significant spin orbit coupling (SOC)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>. Here, the nearest neighbor distance between the tetrahedrally arranged 4
 <italic>d</italic>/5
 <italic>d</italic> magnetic ions naturally becomes much larger compared to the cases when both 
 <italic>B</italic> and 
 <italic>B</italic>′ sites are filled up with the magnetic ions. This reduces the inter-atomic exchange between the magnetic ions which helps to protect the SOC driven states. This situation opens up many options, and consequently many double perovskites with 
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sup>1</sup> (e.g., Ba
 <sub>2</sub>YMoO
 <sub>6</sub>, Sr
 <sub>2</sub>CaReO
 <sub>6</sub>, Sr
 <sub>2</sub>MgReO
 <sub>6</sub>, Ba
 <sub>2</sub>NaOsO
 <sub>6</sub> etc.) as well as 
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sup>2</sup> electronic configurations (e.g., Ba
 <sub>2</sub>CaOsO
 <sub>6</sub>, Ba
 <sub>2</sub>YReO
 <sub>6</sub>, La
 <sub>2</sub>LiReO
 <sub>6</sub> etc.) have been studied, where numerous unusual magnetic ground states are revealed
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
