<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Another interesting possibility appears in DPs, when both 
 <italic>B</italic> and 
 <italic>B</italic>′ ions are magnetic, but the valence electrons of 
 <italic>B</italic> ion lack the orbital symmetry of the same of 
 <italic>B</italic>′ ion for effective 
 <italic>B</italic>-O-
 <italic>B</italic>′ super-exchange interaction. Such a situation will give rise to two noninteracting or weakly interacting magnetic sublattices. It will be interesting to gradually manipulate the extent of 
 <italic>B</italic>-O-
 <italic>B</italic>′ interaction by carefully changing the 
 <italic>B</italic>-O-
 <italic>B</italic>′ angle, and consequently follow the evolution of two sublattices getting engaged in single magnetic lattice (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(b)</xref> → Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(a)</xref>), following the famous Goodenough-Kanamori rule. Accordingly, we have designed a series of DPs, LaSr
 <sub>1−
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>Ca
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>NiReO
 <sub>6</sub>, having a combination of 3
 <italic>d</italic> and 5
 <italic>d</italic> transition metals Ni
 <sup>2+</sup> (3
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sup>8</sup>, 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub>
 <sup>6</sup>
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub>
 <sup>2</sup>) and Re
 <sup>5+</sup> (5
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sup>2</sup>, 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub>
 <sup>2</sup>) at the 
 <italic>B</italic> and 
 <italic>B</italic>′ sites, respectively. Due to large crystal field splitting, the empty 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub> orbitals of Re have much higher energy than the 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub> manifold and do not contribute in any interatomic exchange interaction. The filled 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub> orbital of Ni as well has less involvement in the exchange interaction. The only possible exchange interaction that can be active between the 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub> of Ni
 <sup>2+</sup> and the 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub> of Re
 <sup>5+</sup>, will be very weak if the 
 <italic>B</italic>-O-
 <italic>B</italic>′ angle is strictly 180°, as the overlap integral between the 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub> and the 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub> becomes zero. However, finite overlap between these orbitals can be introduced by tuning the bond angles and lattice parameters as a consequence of the doping of Sr
 <sup>2+</sup> ions by smaller sized Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> ions.
</p>
