<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>However, HARPES faces serious basic and technical obstacles. 
 <italic>Photoemission cross sections</italic> drop rapidly with excitation energy above photoionization thresholds (Trzhaskovskaya &amp; Yarzhemsky, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb73"> ▸</xref>), which is relevant not only for valence-band studies but also for core-level spectroscopy. Alongside this drop of signal intensity, the contribution of 
 <italic>electron–phonon scattering</italic> increases strongly and causes a quasi-elastic background that eventually dominates direct interband transitions. The phonon-scattering contribution is reduced at low sample temperatures. Quantitatively, the Debye–Waller factor and the atomic mass of the material specify the fraction of non-scattered electrons and therefore constitute criteria for the feasibility of HARPES for different elements (Papp 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2011
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb56"> ▸</xref>). At multi-keV energies, electron wavelengths are much smaller than interatomic distances, wherefore 
 <italic>X-ray photoelectron diffraction</italic> (XPD) plays a significant role. On the one hand, XPD can yield important structural information, as discussed in comprehensive work (for reviews, see, for example, Fadley, 2010
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb15"> ▸</xref>; Woodruff, 2010
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb80"> ▸</xref>; Osterwalder, 2011
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb53"> ▸</xref>; Matsui 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2014
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb44"> ▸</xref>). On the other hand, valence-band photoelectron diffraction hampers quantitative band mapping because strong diffraction signatures can modulate the band-structure patterns (Schönhense 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <italic>a</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb64"> ▸</xref>). With increasing photon energy, the 
 <italic>transfer of photon momentum to the photoelectron</italic> becomes significant. In the hard X-ray range, the resulting shift of the 
 <italic>k</italic>-patterns exceeds the size of a typical Brillouin zone (BZ), an important fact for the interpretation of HARPES data.
</p>
