<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The rare-earth-doped luminescent nanoparticles and microparticles have found many applications, and the rare-earth ions with emission in every color are revolutionizing applications from lighting devices to television displays.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>
 </sup> For instance, light-emitting diodes (LEDs) based on the use of rare-earth-doped phosphors have been widely recognized as a green lighting source in favor of energy saving and environment protection.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> In such a module, phosphors play crucial roles in determining the performance and quality of LEDs and the fast development of LED raises the demand of phosphors with uniform size distribution, high luminescence quantum efficiency, and high thermal stability.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> Typically, the phosphors are made up of host materials and activators, while their optical properties are extremely sensitive to their structures in mesoscale.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> The host materials include nitrogen/oxide,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>
 </sup> aluminate,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>
 </sup> silicate,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>
 </sup> borate,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> and fluorides.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>
 </sup> The activators are usually rare-earth ions that can absorb high-energy photons and emit low-energy photons. The ideal product of rare-earth-doped phosphors should have a uniform particle size distribution and homogeneous doping ions in each particle, while in common situation the products are unevenly distributed either in size or component (
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>
 </xref>). Previous studies show that the general process of the rare-earth-doped particle formation involves the mixing of the reactants, precipitation of the precursors, and high-temperature heat treatment of crystals.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref>
 </sup> The formation of primary particles in solution is usually the result of relative diffusion of solutes, and the main factor is the difference of diffusion concentration.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref>
 </sup> It is feasible to control and tune the characteristics of rare-earth-doped phosphors in lab-scale synthesis. However, it is very difficult to reproduce for scale-up due to the possible changes in reaction kinetics and thermodynamics.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref>
 </sup> To bridge the gap between the real products and ideal products of rare-earth-doped phosphors, tuning of the doping of rare-earth ions in nanoparticles and/or microparticles at mesoscale is therefore highly required.
</p>
