<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par12">Liquid crystal display (LCD) is gaining greater favor as the mainstream display technology in various contemporary society fields. With the improvement of living standards, people have higher and higher requirements on LCD display quality. Especially in terms of color gamut and brightness, LCDs are constantly being surpassed by other display technologies such as organic light-emitting diodes (OLEDs) and laser displays [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. In order to improve LCD performance, light-emitting diodes (LEDs) have gradually replaced the traditional cold cathode fluorescent lamp (CCFL) due to its small size, low energy consumption, and low heat generation. LEDs have become the new generation of LCD backlight unit (BLU) source [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. At present, the LED BLU uses a blue LED to excite the yellow phosphor to form a white backlight. However, the low efficiency of the phosphor, the wide spectrum, the large light decay, and the poor uniformity of the particles hinder the brightness improvement and CIE chromaticity range of the LCD; thus, there is still room for improvement. It is well known that white LEDs are mainly fabricated by coating a YAG yellow phosphor layer onto a gallium nitride (GaN) blue LED (wavelength 450–470 nm) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>]. However, its emission spectrum lacks red light, emits cool white light, is not natural enough, and has poor color rendering (CRI less than 75), which limits its application in high-end lighting and special fields. In order to obtain high CRI LEDs, a small amount of red phosphor and a small amount of green phosphor are added to the yellow phosphor to compensate and change the spectrum [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. However, this method of LED coated with phosphor is still insufficient in terms of luminous efficiency and chemical stability, and it is difficult to obtain large-scale popularization and application.
</p>
