<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par13">As a new type of fluorescent semiconductor nanocrystals, nano quantum dots (QDs) have many unique optical properties, such as high photoluminescence quantum yield, narrow emission spectrum, tunable emission spectrum, and high color purity [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. It has been demonstrated that in the efficient photon management, QD converter can be widely used in solar cells [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>], LEDs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>], and photodetectors [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Especially, QD photodetectors with selectable wavelengths and high responsivity and on/off ratio have been reported [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>]. Recently, QDs were also applied for water splitting due to its superior electrocatalytic and photocatalytic properties [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. QDs have become a suitable candidate material in the display field, which has great potential to replace the traditional phosphor powder and increase the LCD color gamut range [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>]. QD-based backlight technology is currently the mainstream application target in displays, which have a great deal of attention from both the scientific and industrial circles. QDs are generally composed of groups II–VI or III–V elements and have a crystal grain diameter of only about 2–10 nm [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. Due to the quantum confinement effect, the QD energy gap can change with the particle size. In the past few years, research on cadmium selenide (CdSe) and its core-shell QDs in display technology has been the most popular, mainly because its light emission wavelength falls within the visible range. The QD-LED device structure is similar to that of a polymer light-emitting diode (PLED), and its emission layer is spin-coated using a colloidal semiconductor QDs solution, thereby having the advantages of the simple preparation process, low cost, and flexibility for fabrication [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>].
</p>
