<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig2">
 <label>Fig. 2</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Electrochemical studies of nanocrystalline 1T′-MoTe
   <sub>2</sub>. 
   <bold>a</bold> Comparison of the current densities achieved by nanocrystalline 1T′-MoTe
   <sub>2</sub> before and after 100 cycles in 1 M H
   <sub>2</sub>SO
   <sub>4</sub>. Catalysts were prepared on a glassy carbon working electrode as described in the experimental section. Carbon felt and 3 M Ag/AgCl were used as the counter and reference electrodes, respectively. 
   <bold>b</bold> Chronoamperometry profiles of the catalyst in 1 M H
   <sub>2</sub>SO
   <sub>4</sub>. The applied potential was chosen by initially performing LSV and choosing the potential corresponding to j = −10 mA cm
   <sup>−2</sup>. Experiments were performed using a three electrode setup, with catalyst-deposited glassy carbon as the working electrode, 3 M Ag/AgCl as the reference and carbon felt as the counter electrode. 
   <bold>c</bold> Representative trace of the number of moles of hydrogen produced with time as a constant potential is applied. The applied potential was chosen from LSV and corresponded to j = −10 mA cm
   <sup>−2</sup>. Solid line indicates the experimentally determined value of hydrogen yield from gas chromatography for activated sample, while dashed line represents the theoretically calculated value without activation. 
   <bold>d</bold> Nyquist plots showing electrochemical impedance spectroscopy on nanocrystalline 1T′-MoTe
   <sub>2</sub> before and after 100 cycles at −300 mV (vs. NHE). Uncompensated resistances were calculated as 8.1 and 8.3 Ω for disordered 1T′-MoTe
   <sub>2</sub> before and after 100 cycles, respectively. This corresponds well with the iR compensation function on the potentiostat which gave values of 9.8 and 10.1 Ω. The inset shows equivalent circuit model
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_12831_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e672" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
