<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0625">As mentioned in Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.1" ref-type="sec">2.1</xref>, just as in quantum-classical mechanics, the transient state in the standard Franck-Condon picture is essentially classical: the classical motion of the nuclei is carried out to the turning point, or in other words, “towards the quantum transition.” In the standard theory, this qualitative Franck-Condon picture of the dynamics of the transient state does not have a formalized description. When we attempt to formalize this picture within the framework of quantum mechanics, we immediately obtain a singularity in the rates of molecular quantum transitions. This is because we use only quantum mechanics to describe molecular “quantum” transitions, whereas in the qualitative Franck-Condon picture, in addition to the quantum transition, we also have the classical motion of the nuclei “towards it.” Therefore, to eliminate the singularity, a certain paradigm of classicality must be introduced, in one way or another, into quantum mechanics. The simplest way to do this in the formal apparatus of quantum mechanics is to replace the infinitesimal imaginary additive in the energy denominator of the spectral representation of the total Green's function of the system by its finite value and thus come to quantum-classical mechanics. In the aforementioned reasoning, we did not have to resort, as we did earlier in the text of the article, to the argument that the mass of the nuclei is incomparably larger than the mass of the electrons (in this regard, see 
 <xref rid="fn10" ref-type="fn">footnote 10</xref> in Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.4.3" ref-type="sec">2.4.3</xref>). It was sufficient to refer to the internal inconsistency of the Franck-Condon picture, which is related with the fact that in theory, the qualitative Franck-Condon picture of the dynamics of the transient state does not have an adequate mathematical formulation.
 <xref rid="fn17" ref-type="fn">17</xref>
</p>
