<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0630">We previously discussed the internal inconsistency of the Franck-Condon principle related to the inability to formalize, within the framework of quantum mechanics, the qualitative quantum-classical picture of optical transitions in molecules, which the Franck-Condon principle offers. A similar internal inconsistency is inherent in the Franck-Condon principle when it is used in the standard theory of non-radiative elementary electron transfers in condensed media, namely, in Marcus' theory. In the qualitative picture of Marcus, it is assumed that the electron energy on the donor and on the acceptor in each individual donor-acceptor pair is equalized due to fluctuations in the classical motion of the nuclear subsystem (due to thermal fluctuations of the nuclear coordinates) before the quantum transition (transfer) of an electron occurs from the donor to the acceptor [
 <xref rid="bib91" ref-type="bibr">91</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib92" ref-type="bibr">92</xref>]. In other words, the quantum transition occurs at the “point” of intersection of the electronic terms of reagents and products,
 <xref rid="fn18" ref-type="fn">18</xref> which is achieved as a result of the classical reorganization of the nuclear subsystem, and each individual donor-acceptor pair immersed in the medium acts, as in the case of transitions in individual molecules, as a simple quantum-classical system. An attempt to formalize the qualitative picture of Marcus in the framework of quantum mechanics, which we essentially undertook at the initial stage of building quantum-classical (dozy-chaos) mechanics, leads to a singularity in the rates of transitions (transfers). Damping this singularity, that is, introducing chaos into the transient state of each individual donor-acceptor pair, we obtain the quantum-classical (dozy-chaos) mechanics of elementary electron transfers in condensed matter, which is formulated in Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.4" ref-type="sec">2.4</xref>. The result of the rate constant in Marcus' theory is obtained from the result of the rate constant in dozy-chaos mechanics when we turn to strong chaos [
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>] (
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M598" altimg="si9.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>γ</mi>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">≥</mo>
    <mi>E</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>; see also the limiting transition in Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.4.9" ref-type="sec">2.4.9</xref>). It follows that in the problem of elementary electron transfers, the Franck-Condon principle acts as an effective simulator of strong dozy chaos, just as in the problem of “quantum” transitions in molecules, and the Marcus model acts as an effective simulator of quantum-classical mechanics of electron transfers in strong dozy chaos.
</p>
