<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The term proton 
 <italic>transport</italic> is often used to refer to the long-scale diffusion of protons in a system. In aqueous solutions containing hydronium (H
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sup>+</sup>) and hydroxide (OH
 <sup>–</sup>) ions, proton transport proceeds 
 <italic>via</italic> the Grotthuss mechanism (reviewed in, for example, 
 <xref rid="cit1" ref-type="bibr">ref. 1</xref>), in which charge and mass transport are largely decoupled. A schematic representation of this mechanism for OH
 <sup>–</sup>(aq) is given in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">Fig. 1</xref>, where protons are transferred from water molecules to hydroxide ions. One sometimes uses a different perspective, namely that proton “holes”, 
 <italic>i.e.</italic>, missing protons, are transferred from the hydroxide ion to the water molecule.
 <xref rid="cit2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="cit3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref> The Grotthuss mechanism then becomes a series of proton hole transfer events. The transport mechanisms of protons and hydroxide ions in aqueous solution have been extensively studied,
 <xref rid="cit2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>–
 <xref rid="cit9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref> but only little is known about the proton transport mechanisms at solid–liquid interfaces. For instance, recent molecular dynamics (MD) studies
 <xref rid="cit10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="cit11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref> have shown that OH
 <sup>–</sup> diffuses both vehicularly (mass transport) and 
 <italic>via</italic> a Grotthuss-like mechanism in anion exchange membranes. Further, Muñoz-Santiburcio and Marx
 <xref rid="cit3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref> explored OH
 <sup>–</sup> diffusion in nanoconfined slit pores, and concluded that the transport mechanism depends on the degree of confinement. Achtyl 
 <italic>et al.</italic>
 <xref rid="cit12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref> showed that protons can diffuse through hydroxyl-terminated atomic defects in single-layer graphene.
</p>
