<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Proton diffusion at the metal-oxide–liquid-water interface is a challenging case for molecular simulation methods, since the underlying framework must be capable of describing with high accuracy an ionic crystal, a molecular liquid, the interface between them, as well as proton transfer events. Moreover, in order to minimize the influence of finite-size effects, which can be particularly pronounced for diffusion phenomena,
 <xref rid="cit43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref> a large system, both with respect to the area of the interface, as well as the thickness of the liquid phase, is needed. At the same time, although individual proton transfer events can be quite fast, long-scale proton diffusion is potentially much slower, thus requiring long trajectories. For these reasons, a computationally efficient method is needed. In this work, we use a reactive density-functional-theory-based high-dimensional neural network potential,
 <xref rid="cit44" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>,
 <xref rid="cit45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref> which provides a computationally inexpensive way of evaluating the total energy and atomic forces in a system maintaining first principles accuracy. Neural networks, one of the most widely used machine learning techniques, are in many ways ideal for simulating complicated processes like proton diffusion at solid–liquid interfaces, since they can be parameterized to reproduce density-functional-theory-calculated potential energy surfaces of arbitrary systems very accurately at a fraction of the computational cost:
 <xref rid="cit44" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>,
 <xref rid="cit45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref> in a previous work, we created and validated such a neural network potential for ZnO–liquid-water interfaces.
 <xref rid="cit34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref> The training and validation sets included ample numbers of structures for both the ZnO(101[combining macron]0) and ZnO(112[combining macron]0) surfaces in contact with liquid water. Additional validation of the neural network was performed by comparing, for example, proton transfer free energy landscapes as calculated by the neural network MD simulations to landscapes calculated directly from 
 <italic>ab initio</italic> MD simulations for small systems (see 
 <xref rid="cit34" ref-type="bibr">ref. 34</xref>, as well as the ESI
 <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">†</xref> to the present work). The comparison to 
 <italic>ab initio</italic> MD revealed satisfactory agreement between the NN and the DFT results, although the NN proton transfer barriers were somewhat underestimated compared to the DFT reference. Moreover, in 
 <xref rid="cit34" ref-type="bibr">ref. 34</xref> we highlighted that running a short 25 ps trajectory was not enough for equilibrating the proton transfer free energy landscapes, thus further justifying the need for an atomistic potential (in our case a neural network potential) that can be used to tackle large length and time scales.
</p>
