<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is unexpected that hydrostatic compression of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> is dimensionally reduced to be quasi-uniaxial. The most probable reason is that due to the 2D nature of the perovskite structure, the interlayer organic parts are much easier to deform than the inorganic layers. To verify the results, we constructed unit cell structures at 0 and 4 GPa by first-principles calculation, as shown in 
 <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5A</xref> (a video displaying the complete lattice structure evolution under pressure can be found in the Supplementary Materials). By comparing the two frames, one can hardly see noticeable changes in Pb─I inorganic counterpart (the gray and light purple spheres represent Pb and I atoms, respectively), while the organic part is greatly squeezed in the out-of-plane direction. The two paired PEA ligands, which extend from adjacent inorganic layers, are forced to move closer to each other. To reduce the volume, the carbon─carbon (C─C) bond between the benzene ring and C
 <sub>2</sub>H
 <sub>4</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>
 <sup>+</sup> is strongly bent, making the adjacent benzene rings become parallel. The organic layers, with this self-adaptive configuration, are, to some extent, similar to buffer layers formed of springs, which are inserted between the octaheral [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> layers, as illustrated in 
 <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5B</xref>. In this simplified model, when the (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> crystal is compressed, the “spring layer” will keep shrinking and absorbing most of the compression kinetic energy; when the crystal is decompressed, the spring layer will restore and release the absorbed volume. In this manner, the pressure-induced structure changes are reversible. Moreover, the calculated structure shows that the individual [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> octahedra are geometrically preserved under pressure, which is also supported by the previous XRD and first-principles calculation results about the isotropic change of the [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> octahedral layer. No matter compression or decompression, the [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> octahedral structure will be protected and prevented from distortion and rotation. This ordered compression of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub>, which protected by spring layer, is in stark contrast to 3D perovskites such as MAPbI
 <sub>3</sub> and FAPbI
 <sub>3</sub>, which experience disordered compression under pressure (
 <xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>20</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>21</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>26</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>27</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R43" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>43</italic>
 </xref>). In 3D perovskites, the [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> frame is continuously distributed in all space; therefore, the hydrostatic pressure will act on the Pb─I bonds with the organic molecules acting as anchor points to assist the distortion and rotation of the [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> octahedra.
</p>
