<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The unique anisotropic compression of 2D perovskite (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> causes its constant optical performance during bandgap modulation. It is well-understood that distortion and bending of chemical bonds seriously break the original crystal field and disorder the wave function overlap between atoms in semiconductors, suppressing the efficiency of band-edge transition (
 <xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>21</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>41</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>42</italic>
 </xref>). However, the quasi-uniaxial compression of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> perfectly preserves the octahedral geometry of [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> and thus maintains the stability and quality of Pb─I bonds. As a result, the efficiency of band-edge transition can be maintained to the highest degree during the compression. This can also explain the optical reversible and irreversible regions, which were determined by PL spectroscopy. The reversible and radiative region is likely to be within the self-adaptive range of the organic layers. After certain pressure (&gt;4 GPa), the organic layer inevitably reaches compression limit, the anisotropy decreases, and the octaheral [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> structure starts to distort and rotate. Under this scenario, the irreversible and nonradiative region takes place, just like what 3D perovskites experience at much lower pressure. Note that for different 2D perovskites, there could be organic ligands with different length and configuration, which can also affect the structural and electronic evolution under high pressure. Taking into account, the previous results in [(BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(MA)
 <sub>
  <italic>n</italic>−1
 </sub>Pb
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>I
 <sub>3
  <italic>n</italic>+1
 </sub>, 
 <italic>n</italic> = 1, 2, 3, 4] (
 <xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>28</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>30</italic>
 </xref>), we believe that longer ligands in (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> can help to reduce phase transition, and the benzene termination can simplify and stabilize the configuration of organic layers during compression. As a result, we do not observe any phase transition and octahedral distortion or rotation under moderate pressure range.
</p>
