<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5D</xref> shows the projected density of states (PDOS) on atoms and the band structure of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> at 0 and 4 GPa. The energy bandgap maintains direct at Γ point and shows a much bigger pressure-induced red shift than 3D perovskites. However, the nearly unchanged [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> size in the reversible region can hardly explain the large bandgap change, so there must be other reasons that could be related to the multiple quantum well structure. As shown in 
 <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5C</xref>, the compression of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> can be simplified to the compression of a single type I quantum well. We know that the thickness of the organic layer decreases much faster than the [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> octahedral layer under pressure, which means that the barrier layers of the quantum well will become thinner. The thinner barrier layers will decrease the barrier potential, allowing more leakage of the electron (hole) wave function that results from the weakening of the quantum confinement effect. The bandgap change under pressure can be attributed to two main factors: Δ
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>g</sub>(
 <italic>P</italic>) = Δ
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>PbI</sub>(
 <italic>P</italic>) + Δ
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>QC</sub>(
 <italic>P</italic>), where Δ
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>PbI</sub> and Δ
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>QC</sub> indicate the contributions from changes of the Pb─I bond and the quantum confinement effect, respectively. In this manner, the pressure-induced weakening of quantum confinement (Δ
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>QC</sub> &lt; 0) will cause the bandgap red shift of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub>. Using the structure and band structure parameters obtained from the XRD and first-principles calculation results, Δ
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>QC</sub> can be calculated (calculation details can be found in section S4). 
 <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">Figure 5E</xref> shows the energy position of the bound states at different barrier potentials (
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>1</sub> and 
 <italic>H</italic>
 <sub>1</sub> are in orange and cyan, respectively, and 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>2</sub> and 
 <italic>H</italic>
 <sub>2</sub> are in gray), and the barrier potential at each pressure can be given by the PDOS on Pb, I, and C atoms, as shown in 
 <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5F</xref> [barrier potential for electron (
 <italic>U</italic>
 <sub>e</sub>) and hole (
 <italic>U</italic>
 <sub>h</sub>) are in orange and cyan traces, respectively]. By tracking the energy change of bound states 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>1</sub> and 
 <italic>H</italic>
 <sub>1</sub>, the pressure-dependent Δ
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>QC</sub> can be obtained and shown as the black trace in 
 <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5F</xref>. The quantum confinement weakening becomes stronger and stronger with increasing pressure and lastly saturates at pressure around 3 to 4 GPa with Δ
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>QC</sub> ≈ −250 meV. As a result, the weakening of quantum confinement contributes significantly (250 of 320) to the bandgap red shift in the reversible region. Note that the dielectric confinement of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> can be modified by pressure. Since the organic barrier layer has a smaller dielectric constant (ϵ
 <sub>b</sub>) than the inorganic well (ϵ
 <sub>w</sub>), the electrical dipoles will be screened inside the well, and in this manner, the exciton binding energy is enhanced. Both ϵ
 <sub>b</sub> and ϵ
 <sub>w</sub> will change under high pressure (
 <xref rid="R45" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>45</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R46" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>46</italic>
 </xref>), and thus, the dielectric confinement will change accordingly. The precise changes of the overall dielectric confinement and the contribution from each counterpart as functions of pressure are issues worth further experimental and theoretical studies.
</p>
