<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>3D perovskite can be regarded as an extreme case of 2D perovskite with zero quantum confinement effect. However, the lattice compression under pressure still gives rise to bandgap red shifts (
 <xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>19</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>22</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>25</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>27</italic>
 </xref>), which is opposite to the blue shift in most of the conventional semiconductors (
 <xref rid="R47" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>47</italic>
 </xref>). For the irreversible region of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub>, the red shift continues after the saturation of the quantum confinement weakening, which should be taken over by the compression of the [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> octahedral structure, similar to 3D perovskite. A unique feature can be seen in the PDOS diagram that the I s orbital and Pb p orbital dominate the valence band minimum (VBM) and conduction band minimum (CBM), respectively. However, In III-V or II-VI semiconductors, band extrema are swapped, meaning that p-orbital and s-orbital states occupy VBM and CBM, respectively. Because of the linear configuration of p orbital, it will be affected by the interatomic distance variation more intensely than s orbital in symmetric configuration. Applying pressure will largely increase the binding force to p-orbital electrons and pull down its energy level from the vacuum level. For lead halide perovskite, pressure will bring down CBM (p orbital), thus narrowing the bandgap (as shown in 
 <xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5C</xref>). For conventional semiconductors, VBM (p orbital) will be reduced so that the bandgap broadens. This inverse order of p-s transition can also explain the unconventional red shift of PL observed for lead halide perovskites by decreasing temperature (
 <xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>8</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>33</italic>
 </xref>).
</p>
