<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>As the ideal distribution of Si atoms in mullite was not known, we assumed that the Al/Si ordering adopts the highest possible symmetry, 
 <italic>i.e.</italic> the orthorhombic symmetry of the block structures (Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>) is not reduced by the Al/Si ordering. The ideal superstructure then corresponds to the structure with the lowest energy. For M0, M33 and M50 the supercells are relatively small and therefore there are only a few Al/Si permutations. For these cases all Si distributions were investigated with FF and DFT calculations. Each supercell was assigned a number (FFID) corresponding to its stability according to the FF calculations. A comparison with an analogue ranking based on the DFT calculations allows one to evaluate the accuracy of the FF calculations. The ranking of M0 is identical with both approaches, 
 <italic>i.e.</italic> in this case the FF calculations correctly identify the most stable and least stable Al/Si ordering patterns. The FFID ranking of M33 deviates by about one position relative to the DFT ranking (Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref>). However, the first and last FFID correctly represent the most and least stable supercell, respectively. In the case of M50 the uncertainty of the ranking is about two positions and neither the first nor the last rank are correctly identified. The geometric optimization of the least stable structures with DFT in many cases results in a strong deformation leading to larger deviations from the bond lengths expected from X-ray diffraction studies. In contrast, the coordinates of the most stable structures are only slightly displaced from the expected coordinates. These results are taken as an indication that a qualitative assessment of the relative stability of a certain supercell is possible with the FF calculations, but for the determination of the ideal Al/Si ordering more accurate DFT calculations must be carried out.
</p>
