<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A qualitative comparison of the different Al/Si ordering schemes allows one to establish empirical rules to estimate the stability of a certain Si distribution. M0 #3, the least stable supercell, contains Al
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> units (Al–Al diclusters), in which the bridging oxygen is strongly underbonded (SUBO) according to Pauling’s bond valence rules (Pauling, 1929
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb55"> ▸</xref>; Loewenstein &amp; Lowenstein, 1954
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb46"> ▸</xref>). M0 #2 contains strongly overbonded oxygen (SOBO) atoms which are shared by two SiO
 <sub>4</sub> tetrahedra and one AlO
 <sub>6</sub> octahedron. These two structural elements are also present in the least stable supercells of M33 and M50. None of the M25 and M40 supercells investigated with DFT contains SOBOs and only one supercell of M25 contains Al–Al diclusters with SUBOs (FFID 9). In M25, M33 and M40 there are dicluster–vacancy columns, 
 <italic>i.e.</italic> diclusters alternate with vacancies parallel to 
 <bold>c</bold>, and in the ideal permutations these diclusters are consistently of the Si–Si type. In general, it is assumed that Si does not occupy tetrahedral sites of triclusters due to the anion charge on the threefold coordinated oxygen (Pauling, 1929
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb55"> ▸</xref>). Si is expected to especially avoid the 
 <italic>T*</italic> site of triclusters as the experimentally observed bond lengths are too long for typical Si—O distances (Angel 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1991
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb5"> ▸</xref>; Schneider 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2015
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb71"> ▸</xref>). M40 #1 and M50 #1 contain Si in triclusters indicating that this is a stable and favourable environment for Si. The identification of Si in triclusters and the presence of Si–Si diclusters between vacancies are consistent with the Al/Si ordering pattern suggested by Klar 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb39"> ▸</xref>). As M40 #2 and M50 #2 contain Si on the 
 <italic>T*</italic> site, the presence of this tricluster configuration is energetically not forbidden (Table S4).
</p>
