<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par11">Thirdly, the XRD peaks are significantly broadened for the HPT-induced metastable Al-Mg alloy and in addition the aged material shows these peaks in a plateau configuration which becomes more apparent at the higher scattering angles. This broadening is attributed not only to grain refinement but also to an instrumental broadening due to inherent imperfections in the camera and recording devices and compositional straining where solute atoms expand or compress the matrix lattice
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>. Regarding the large and non-Lorentzian shaped total peak profile due mainly to the distribution of chemical strain where a schematic illustration is shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>, the Williamson-Hall method breaks down to extract a small grain size broadening. Instead, a plateau-shape with a sharp fall-off profile was observed at Δ
 <italic>a</italic>/
 <italic>a</italic>
 <sub>0</sub> = 0 or 
 <italic>X</italic>
 <sub>Mg</sub> = 0 in the metastable solution after aging. However, a tail exists beyond the Al edge to larger scattering vectors or negative strain values which can be attributed to size-broadening. Fitting only the high-
 <italic>Q</italic> tail to a Lorentzian, a consistent grain size may be estimated from all four reflections. Thus, from a combination of many different peaks, it is reasonable to take the outline of the apparent line profile at the highest scattering vector indicating the smallest lattice parameter which is close to pure Al with a constrained state. Accordingly, the folding of the line fits well with a Lorentzian function
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup> and permits a convolution of a resultant line profile
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>
 </sup>. By performing this analysis, the line broadening of this specific high-
 <italic>Q</italic> tail of the line profile incorporates the instrumental and grain refinement components without any compositional gradient broadening.
</p>
