<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">An understanding of the principles and the technical parameters of many different SPD techniques has provided an opportunity to introduce superior mechanical properties and additional functionalities in nanostructured materials
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. Among the available SPD techniques, HPT is recognized as one of the most attractive methods since significant grain refinement is anticipated by comparison with other SPD procedures and often the technique is effective for hard-to-deform materials even at room temperature
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>. Utilizing this benefit, a new approach to mechanical bonding by HPT was examined recently for the synthesis of bulk hybrid nanostructured alloys by layering dissimilar nanostructured metals
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup> and ultimately leading to metal matrix nanocomposites by forming a reinforcement of a few nano-scale intermetallic phases
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>. In practice, this procedure applies the conventional HPT technique concurrently on two or more different kinds of bulk metals. The microstructures in the mechanically bonded metal systems by HPT processing generally develop into heterostructures
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup> involving heterogeneous and gradient microstructures from the sample surfaces to the depth. Thus, no clear information is available currently on any microstructural saturation and an ultimate metal state, thereby effectively limiting the mechanical properties when mechanically bonding dissimilar metals by HPT after very severe deformation. In this study, Al and Mg disks were mechanically bonded at room temperature by HPT for shear strains up to 4,000 through 100 torsional turns to assess the asymptotic microstructure by applying the simple yet powerful method of X-Ray diffraction (XRD) peak profile analysis.
</p>
