<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par23">Now we will schematically illustrate the origin of the revealed Weyl state in YbMnBi
 <sub>2</sub> in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> considering the gradual modification of the electronic and crystal structure of square net of Bi atoms. We start from the purely two-dimensional construct—the Bi net itself. Its electronic structure is shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5a</xref>. In this larger BZ there are no Dirac crossings and the dispersions are simple solutions of the tight-binding approach which takes into account only Bi 
 <italic>p</italic> states. Doubling of the unit cell because of the staggered coordination by Yb atoms results in Dirac crossings
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup> exactly at the Fermi level and the momentum locus of these points is given by the diamond-shaped Fermi contour. This unique electronic structure is shown in three-dimensional space in the lowest panel of Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5b</xref> and it is characterized by the 8-times-degenerate electronic states at X-point. It is remarkable that it is in the proximity of this point the degeneracy will be lifted completely in YbMnBi
 <sub>2</sub>. In the next column of panels (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5c</xref>) we show the case of Eu material with SOC and perfect AFM included. This example shows why Weyl state cannot be realized in EuMnBi
 <sub>2</sub>: spin–orbit and exchange interactions open the energy gaps at all Dirac points. Here it is also easy to see the mechanism of the formation of the lenses: the gap is not constant and is not centered at the Fermi level. Next set of panels (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5d</xref>) represents the case of YbMnBi
 <sub>2</sub> as it is seen from ARPES. The value of 
 <italic>k</italic>
 <sub>z</sub> corresponds to the plane containing Weyl points and the constant gap centered at the Fermi level is considered for simplicity. As mentioned earlier, the degeneracy is seen to be lifted leading to formation of four pairs of Weyl points. Note that the cut ΓX”runs through the Weyl point. If the gap would be centered at the Fermi level along the diamond-like contour (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5b</xref>), YbMnBi
 <sub>2</sub> would have been a canonical Weyl semimetal of type I. Presence of lenses and electron pockets near X-points which touch in a single point make it the Weyl semimetal of type II. Finally, we present a schematic plot of the electronic states responsible for the Fermi arc together with the bulk-originated states in the panels of Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5e</xref>. Again, for simplicity, we do not show all bands and the gap is chosen to be constant and centered at E
 <sub>F</sub>. The arc at the Fermi surface is given by the surface states shown by green color. They originate from the bulk states forming the one Weyl point and terminate in bulk states in the vicinity of another Weyl point. The presence of four arcs in the sketch and experimental maps is due to the superposition of two domains.
</p>
