<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0110">A completely different picture forms in connection with the works of Franck and Condon [
 <xref rid="bib54" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib56" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib57" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>], the basis of the so-called Franck-Condon principle. As previously mentioned, due to the significant difference in the masses of electrons and nuclei, the dynamics of molecular quantum transitions consists of two stages. In the first stage, under the influence of an external perturbation, a light electron nearly instantaneously passes into an excited electronic quantum state. In the second stage, a so-called reorganization of the nuclear subsystem of the molecule occurs, in which the spatial configuration of the heavy nuclei slowly adapts to the new electron-charge distribution. However, such a picture raises a serious objection. Namely, due to the significant inertia of the nuclei, they will not follow the movement of the electron, but simply return the electron to its original state just as rapidly [
 <xref rid="bib14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>, 33b]. In other words, proceeding from these general considerations, the probability (per unit time) of a molecular quantum transition must be zero. However, if the heavy nuclei suddenly begin to move after a light electron already in the excited state, then due to the substantial inertia of the nuclei, they cannot stop in the excited electronic state [
 <xref rid="bib14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>, 33b]. In other words, the probability (per unit time) of a molecular quantum transition must be infinite. Thus, these simple and general qualitative considerations demonstrate that there is a singularity in the rates of the molecular quantum transitions. At one time, these thoughts were either not discussed or considered, apparently because of the success of the Franck-Condon principle in its practical applications, which resulted in the development of modern molecular optical spectroscopy. Nevertheless, the question of the validity of the Franck-Condon principle remained unchanged in theory. In this regard, the Franck-Condon principle should not be treated as a physical principle, but as an efficient hypothesis that does not have a thorough theoretical justification.
</p>
