<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">Thermoelectrics (TE) materials can transfer energy from heat to electricity or vice versa due to their inherent Seebeck or Peltier effects. However, the TE device at present is still inefficient up to date mainly due to low TE performance or ZT valueof the materials, which is defined as ZT = 
 <italic>α2σT</italic>/κ,where 
 <italic>α</italic>, 
 <italic>σ</italic>, 
 <italic>T</italic>, and 
 <italic>κ</italic> are each the Seebeck coefficient, electrical conductivity, absolute temperature, and total thermal conductivity consisting of electronic (
 <italic>κ</italic>
 <sub>e</sub>) and lattice (
 <italic>κ</italic>
 <sub>L</sub>) components. Therefore, it is quite necessary to explore novel TE candidates. Ternary I-III-VI
 <sub>2</sub> (I = Cu, Ag; III = Al, Ga, In; VI = S, Se, Te) chalcogenides, such as CuGaTe
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup>, CuInTe
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>
 </sup>, AgInSe
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup> and AgGaTe
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>, have recently attracted much attention in thermoelectrics because of their unique crystal and band structures
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>, among which the cation vacancy and crystal structure are two important factors in engineering both the carrier concentration and phonon transport
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>
 </sup>. However, to our best knowledge, AgInTe
 <sub>2</sub> has not received due recognition. The possible reason is the presence of the defects V
 <sub>Te</sub> and In
 <sub>Ag</sub> in AgInTe
 <sub>2</sub>, which were identified through analyzing the electrical data of AgInTe
 <sub>2</sub> by Bellabarba etc
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>. These two defects, which are vital to the formation of two shallow donor levels at around 9 mV and 28 mV below the conduction band minimum (CBM)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>, directly degrade the electrical conductivity (10
 <sup>3</sup>~10
 <sup>6</sup> mΩcm at 300–700 K)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. As a consequence, the highest ZT value of AgInTe
 <sub>2</sub> is only 0.07 at 600 K
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. The temperature at which the highest ZT value was attained is just about half the melting point of AgInTe
 <sub>2</sub> (see the phase diagram in Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1</xref>). In this regard, it is important to eliminate the defects V
 <sub>Te</sub> and/or In
 <sub>Ag</sub> in order to improve the TE performance of AgInTe
 <sub>2</sub>.
</p>
