<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par20">The phase formation and crystallographic structure of the GMO thin films were analyzed by high resolution X-ray diffraction (HR-XRD) at room conditions, using a 
 <italic>X’Pert MRD Philips</italic> four-circle diffractometer, based in a Bragg–Brentano para-focusing optics configuration, operating with Cu Kα radiation 
 <bold>
  <italic>λ</italic>
 </bold> = 1.54056 Å at 30 mA and 40 kV, for performing conventional theta-2theta (Θ-2Θ
 <bold>
  <italic>)</italic>
 </bold> scans, pole figures and reciprocal space maps (rsm). Analysis of the diffractograms was performed through the basic Le Bail mode for assessment of crystallographic structure and parameters of the film. The surface morphology, cross-section and chemical composition of the thin film samples was checked using scanning electron microscopy (SEM) in a 
 <italic>Quanta 400 FEG ESEM/EDAX Genesis X4M</italic>, using 15.00 kV for secondary electrons mode and for backscattering mode. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) was performed using a 
 <italic>Kratos Axis Ultra HSA</italic> equipment with 15.00 kV source power, in order to analyze the surface composition and electronic state of elements. Atomic force microscopy was performed in contact mode using a 
 <italic>NT-MDT Ntegra Aura</italic> and respective 
 <italic>Nova_Px 3.4.0</italic> interface software. Commercial Pt coated doped silicon probes from 
 <italic>NT-MDT</italic>, with curvature radius of 10 nm, resonance frequency ~130 kHz and spring constant of 3 N/m, were used. The topographic images were edited via 
 <italic>WSxM 5.0 8.0</italic> software. The temperature dependence of the complex electric permittivity was measured in the 1 kHz - 1 MHz frequency range with an 
 <italic>HP4284A</italic> impedance analyzer, under an 
 <italic>ac</italic> electric field of amplitude 50 V/cm, in the 10–300 K temperature range. The thermally stimulated depolarization current (TSDC) was measured as a function of temperature, with a standard short-circuit method, using a 
 <italic>Keithley 617</italic> electrometer, with a resolution of 0.1 pA. The current intensity was measured during heating run in short-circuit conditions, for different heating rates. Different poling fields were applied during the preceding cooling process and a 30 min short-circuit was performed at the lowest temperature and before current measurements, in order to release spurious charges at the electrodes. The temperature dependence of the electric polarization was obtained by time integration of the TSDC current. The electric polarization was measured in the in-plane film orientation. As the electrodes are parallel to the substrate edges, which in turn are parallel to the axes of the STO cubic cell, and the GMO film has the in-plane crystallographic axes at 45° relatively to the STO axes, the electric polarization was measured along the [110] tetragonal direction. Both electric permittivity and TSDC were measured using interdigital electrodes (IDEs), fabricated on the prepared films by conventional photolithography process to define the resist pattern. The 
 <italic>AZ 1505 Microchemicals</italic> photoresist was first spread over the film with a spinner 
 <italic>Headway Research Inc PWM32-PS-R790</italic> and then dried by soft bake in a hotplate at 100 °C during 1 minute. After exposure using a 
 <italic>Heidelberg Direct Laser Writer uPG10</italic> and development with an appropriate solvent. The required IDEs pattern was used as a mask to remove the surplus material by ion milling in a 
 <italic>Nordiko3600</italic> system with a broad Argon beam of 40 mA (~130 μA/cm
 <sup>2</sup>) at a pressure of 0.2 mTorr.
</p>
