<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par23">To evaluate the contribution due to the misalignment between the sample and the cantilever (mount misalignment), we introduce 
 <italic>xyz</italic> coordinates for the cantilever, where the bending direction of the lever is in the 
 <italic>xy</italic> plane (Supplementary Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">6a</xref>). The signal of the cantilever is only sensitive to the torque along the 
 <italic>z</italic>-axis, because the bending of the lever is limited to the 
 <italic>xy</italic> plane due to its structure. Signal detected by the lever is 
 <italic>τ</italic>
 <sup>lever</sup>=
 <bold> τ</bold> ⋅ 
 <bold>e</bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>z</italic>
 </sub> = 
 <italic>τ</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>a</italic>
 </sub>
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>a</italic>
 </sub> + 
 <italic>τ</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>b</italic>
 </sub>
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>b</italic>
 </sub> + 
 <italic>τ</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>c</italic>
 </sub>
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>c</italic>
 </sub>, where 
 <bold>e</bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>z</italic>
 </sub> = (
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>a</italic>
 </sub>, 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>b</italic>
 </sub>, 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>c</italic>
 </sub>) is the normal unit vector for the bending (
 <italic>xy</italic>) plane. Thus, when the sample plane is perfectly aligned with the lever, i.e., 
 <bold>e</bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>z</italic>
 </sub> = (0, 0, 1), only in-plane torque 
 <italic>τ</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>c</italic>
 </sub> is measured. Of course, in reality, we have unavoidable mount misalignment of the sample with respect to the lever. However, the in-plane anisotropy can be accurately measured under the aligned field condition 
 <bold>H</bold> = (
 <italic>H</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>a</italic>
 </sub>, 
 <italic>H</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>b</italic>
 </sub>, 0), because  
 <bold>τ</bold> = (0, 0, 
 <italic>τ</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>c</italic>
 </sub>) even if mount misalignment is present. In practice, there also exists a small difference between the 
 <italic>xy</italic> plane of the lever and the 
 <italic>XY</italic> plane of the rotating stage, which cannot be determined accurately. However, we emphasise that this difference only results in a slight modification of 
 <bold>e</bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>z</italic>
 </sub> and does not alter our discussion when the magnetic field is correctly applied within the 
 <italic>ab</italic> plane.
</p>
