<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We now address the observation of an elevated BrQ presence at the membrane of the digestive vacuole. This membrane is clearly visible in soft X-ray tomographic images. In the BrQ-treated parasite the membrane is highlighted in X-ray fluorescence maps of Br, indicating the presence of BrQ molecules. The presence of background Br in parasites precludes analysis of BrQ molecule distribution in other parasitic membranes. Nonetheless, in a recent study by Woodland et al. (
 <xref rid="r32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>), chloroquine molecules covalently labeled for light fluorescence microscopy were detected also in other parasitic membranes, but not on red blood cell membranes, which is in accordance with our observations. We note that in their work little signal from the labeled molecule over hemozoin-rich area was detected, which is possibly due to signal absorption by the crystals. It is debatable whether the water-soluble drug would, by itself, tend to accumulate at the lipid membranes. However, the drug molecule has high affinity to complex with free heme in the aqueous medium of the digestive vacuole with the acidic pH. Indeed, the possibility of quinoline drug complexation with free heme has been proposed in the literature (
 <xref rid="r7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>
 <xref rid="r8" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r9" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r10" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r11" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r12" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r13" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r14" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r15" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>). The affinity to water of this complex is presumably higher than that of free heme but lower than that of BrQ alone. We therefore rationalize that this complex would be driven toward and accumulate at the lipid membrane of the digestive vacuole. Supporting this hypothesis is a report of chloroquine–hemin complex association with lipid membranes observed in vitro (
 <xref rid="r35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>
 <xref rid="r36" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>). A prolonged exposure of the digestive vacuole membrane to an increased presence of BrQ–heme complex might lead to intercalation of the heme or the complex with the membrane, leading to its local puncture and spread of the toxic heme into the interior of the parasite (
 <xref rid="r36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>, 
 <xref rid="r37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>).
</p>
