<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is interesting to reveal how to keep the balance in high energy materials with great safety. In addition, under the Hugoniot relation, which governs the detonation process, the energy, pressure, and volume of an explosive before and after a shock are involved. Prediction of the lattice structure is therefore, important to locate the detonation performances of EMs. As we know, energy release and stability maintenance of EMs should be both related to the response under external stimuli. Since the discovery of LLM-105 in the mid-1990, numerous studies have been attracting attention to thermal studies, equation of state (EOS) measurements, and sensitivity of LLM-105.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup> Xu et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
 </sup> measured the mechanical and thermal sensitivity of LLM-105. Zhang et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> investigated the morphology, particle size distribution, internal structure, sensitivity, and thermal decomposition properties of submicrometer-sized LLM-105 using scanning electron microscopy and X-ray diffraction. Gump et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> employed synchrotron angle-dispersive X-ray diffraction and diamond anvil cells to ascertain the isothermal equations of the state of LLM-105 at static high pressure and temperature. Williamson et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup> presented experiments combined with a range of diagnostic instrumentation to describe the impact response of LLM-105, demonstrating the low-level reaction in it, consisting of hotspot ignition, comparatively little light output, and substantial levels of gas production. Recently, Xu et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> have studied the structural stability of LLM-105 under different pressures and temperatures by X-ray diffraction, pressure-dependent Raman and infrared spectra, indicating that a structure phase transition occurs at approximately 30 GPa. Although many experiments have been performed, it is vague to comprehend the microscopic response mechanisms within the external stimulus.
</p>
