<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>However, the theoretical research studies mentioned are performed on the system with a small quantity of atoms. Virtually, many phenomena are always largely complicated and consist of thousands of atoms, such as shock response, thermal diffusion, hot points, and defects. Thus, the methods based on the empirical force field (FF) are usually employed to investigate the mechanisms. Generally, some general FFs were chosen to simulate the condensed phase of EMs, such as Amber
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>
 </sup> and Compass.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> However, to derive more dependable results for a particular material property, the tailor-made FFs are always applied to the simulations about the specific systems. Smith and Bharadwaj constructed a FF for HMX according to the DFT energies.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>
 </sup> Mathew and Sewell used MD with a tailor-made FF to investigate the surface-initiated melting of TATB.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref>
 </sup> With the combination of symmetry-adapted perturbation theory and DFT [SAPT(DFT)],
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref>
 </sup> a series of intermolecular interaction potential have been parameterized for RDX,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref>
 </sup> TATB,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref>
 </sup> and FOX-7.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>
 </sup> Furthermore, Song et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref30">30</xref>
 </sup> developed all-atom, nonempirical, and tailor-made FFs for α-RDX, which can be reliably applied into crystal and density predictions and the sensitivity and detonation estimations. Because of its good accuracy, it is successful in describing the phenomenon for the respective molecules. However, it is not found that molecule-tailored FFs for LLM-105 have been established.
</p>
