<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Pyrochlores used in the nuclear fuel cycle will be exposed to extreme conditions potentially affecting their long-term performance and reliability. Pyrochlores are potential waste form candidates for the immobilization of plutonium and other minor actinides from spent nuclear fuel
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup> because significant amounts of radioisotopes can be incorporated into the 
 <italic>A</italic>-site of the pyrochlore structure. To better understand the structural changes that can occur under irradiation, pyrochlores have been the subject of many experiments that focused on characterizing their response to electron
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>, ion
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>, and photon (pulsed laser)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup> irradiation in terms of radiation-induced defect generation, damage processes, microstructural evolution, and phase transformations. Many studies
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup> were specifically designed to investigate the effect of α-decay in various pyrochlore compositions using keV-GeV ion-beam irradiation; in this range, ion stopping is mediated predominantly by interactions with the target electrons, inducing excitations and ionizations along the ion path. These experiments have highlighted the importance of structure, bond-type, and electronic configuration on their radiation stability, particularly for the titanate (
 <italic>A</italic>
 <sub>2</sub>Ti
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub>) and zirconate (
 <italic>A</italic>
 <sub>2</sub>Zr
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub>) pyrochlores
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
