<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">While pyrochlore structures display a wide range of behaviors in response to ion-beam irradiation as a function of composition, it is generally found that titanate pyrochlores, such as Gd
 <sub>2</sub>Ti
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub>, are less resistant to electronic excitations compared to their zirconate counterparts, such as Gd
 <sub>2</sub>Zr
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub>. Analysis of the thermal spike following 119 MeV U irradiation
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup> shows that Gd
 <sub>2</sub>Ti
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> is readily amorphized, while Gd
 <sub>2</sub>Zr
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> is transformed into a radiation-resistant anion-deficient fluorite structure. For other zirconate pyrochlores (
 <italic>A</italic>
 <sub>2</sub>Zr
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub>), a more complex response was observed, in which both a pyrochlore-fluorite phase transformation and amorphization occur. 
 <italic>B</italic>-site mixed Gd
 <sub>2</sub>Ti
 <sub>2−
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>Zr
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> compounds showed a systematic increase in the resistance to ion-beam induced amorphization with increasing Zr content
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>. This result highlights the important effect of the 
 <italic>B</italic>-site cation on the response of pyrochlore materials to electronic excitations. Although zirconate pyrochlores are generally considered to be radiation-resistant, a systematic ion-beam study of 
 <italic>A</italic>
 <sub>2</sub>Zr
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> pyrochlores shows that the susceptibility to amorphization by electronic excitation increases with increasing cation radius ratio r
 <sub>A</sub>/r
 <sub>B</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
