<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The experimental method of grazing-incidence X-ray diffraction (GIXD) has achieved huge success in the characterization of thin films and surfaces (Robinson &amp; Tweet, 1992
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb26"> ▸</xref>). The possibility of choosing an incidence angle for the primary beam close to the critical angle of total external reflection provides a number of advantages for thin-film characterization: the penetration depth into the sample system can be adjusted and the scattered intensity from the sample is enhanced considerably (Als-Nielsen &amp; McMorrow, 2011
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb2"> ▸</xref>). Several possibilities for the collection of GIXD data from films have to be considered, which are related to the texture of the crystallites within the sample (see Fig. 1
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> ▸</xref>). For fibre texture of crystallites or samples with random in-plane orientation of the crystallites (often found in organic thin films deposited on isotropic surfaces), GIXD studies are typically performed on static samples, 
 <italic>i.e.</italic> without changing the azimuth of the sample. In these cases, the reciprocal information is distributed along rings [Fig. 1
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>)]. One measurement at a single sample orientation, representing a cut through reciprocal space, is thus sufficient to gain access to the diffraction data for full sample analysis. However, there are several situations where the distribution of reciprocal-lattice points is not constant along rings in reciprocal space. Such cases are present in samples with large individual crystals hosted at surfaces, thus resulting in poor statistics [Fig. 1
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>)], or epitaxially grown crystallites with a defined in-plane alignment (Haber 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2005
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb10"> ▸</xref>; Otto 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb23"> ▸</xref>) [Fig. 1
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>c</italic>)]. For both cases, the combination of a GIXD experiment with rotation of the sample is required to collect all necessary information for phase and/or texture analysis (Röthel 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2015
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb29"> ▸</xref>, 2017
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb28"> ▸</xref>). Moreover, sample rotation opens new possibilities for characterization methods that are inaccessible in a simple static experiment, like the determination of in-plane mosaicity.
</p>
