<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">The common HEAs reported in the literature are mostly based on elements like Al, Co, Cr, Cu, Fe, Ni, which have shown comparable or better properties than that of steels, Inconel etc
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>. To achieve higher strengths at high-temperature regime above 1100 °C-1200 °C, the use of refractory metals in HEAs was implemented by Senkov 
 <italic>et al</italic>. in 2010
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>. These refractory HEAs like MoNbTaW, TaNbHfZrTi etc are especially important for the development of high-temperature sustaining materials for aerospace applications
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>. Refractory metals and refractory HEAs have also shown their higher strengthening features at ambient temperatures, potential for use in electrical resistors, medical implants etc
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. In the literature some refractory HEAs with single phase bcc average structures have been reported in the as-cast or homogenized conditions
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. But, there are very few literature available for the long term phase stability at high-temperature, long-range or short-range ordering/ clustering (SRO/ SRC) on the nano-scale which can affect their applicability as high-temperature structural materials. However, in recent years a refractory HEA Ta
 <sub>0.25</sub>Nb
 <sub>0.25</sub>Hf
 <sub>0.25</sub>Zr
 <sub>0.25</sub> system has been experimentally studied for their local nano-structure evolution, SRCs and the effect of high-temperature annealing on mechanical properties by Maiti 
 <italic>et al.</italic>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. For this TaNbHfZr alloy, it was observed that with increasing annealing time there was formation of SRCs with evolving morphologies, which dictated the mechanical properties of this single-phase alloy. The average structure type, lattice parameters and local real structure, local chemical compositions with respect to high-temperature annealing has been well characterized. The effect of long term annealing heat treatment on the mechanical properties such as hardness, strength and ductility has also been experimentally measured. However, for all the experimental characterizations, lots of high-end expensive and time consuming, cumbersome and labour intensive techniques and equipment such as high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM), atom-probe tomography (APT), synchrotron source single-crystal X-ray diffraction, neutron powder diffraction etc were used
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
