<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The promising coupling between electric- and magnetic-order parameters and the potential to manipulate one by the application of the other have attracted much attention in the past few decades. Interest in the research on materials with such coupling has grown because of their wide range of application in multifunctional devices.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>
 </sup> The ultimate goal of this research is to obtain single-phase multiferroics with strong coupling between ferroelectric- and magnetic-order parameters at room temperature. There has been a considerable recent interest in developing lone pair-based magnetoelectrics because of their high value of electrical polarization. Examples of such composites include BiFeO
 <sub>3</sub>–LaFeO
 <sub>3</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref>
 </sup> BiFeO
 <sub>3</sub>–SrTiO
 <sub>3</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref>
 </sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref>
 </sup> BiFeO
 <sub>3</sub>PbTiO
 <sub>3</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
 </sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
 </sup> BiFeO
 <sub>3</sub>–BiCoO
 <sub>3</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> LaFeO
 <sub>3</sub>–PbTiO
 <sub>3</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> BiFeO
 <sub>3</sub>–BaTiO
 <sub>3</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup> BiCoO
 <sub>3</sub>–BaTiO
 <sub>3</sub>,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> etc. PbTiO
 <sub>3</sub> (PTO) is a perovskite ferroelectric material with a Curie temperature of 490 °C and a large tetragonal distortion with 
 <italic>c</italic>/
 <italic>a</italic> = 1.06
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>
 </sup> at room temperature. But it is nonmagnetic (NM) due to the absence of d electrons. The Ti atom can be substituted with some magnetic ions, as a result of which the new compound can be expected to produce both magnetic and ferroelectric behaviors. PTO-based magnetoelectrics could be much more interesting because of the existence of two types of mechanisms for ferroelectricity, i.e., lone pair electrons from Pb
 <sup>2+</sup> and d
 <sup>0</sup>-ness from Ti
 <sup>4+</sup>. So, here we examine the magnetoelectric properties of a PTO-based multiferroic series, i.e., PbTi
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>V
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> (
 <italic>x</italic> = 0, 0.25, 0.33, 0.50, 0.67, 0.75, 1), where the 6s electrons of Pb
 <sup>2+</sup> and the d
 <sup>0</sup>-ness of Ti
 <sup>4+</sup> stabilize the ferroelectricity and the V induces magnetism.
</p>
