<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>On the other hand, PbVO
 <sub>3</sub> (PVO), which is a member of this series (
 <italic>x</italic> = 1), has gained much interest in the last few years as a strong candidate for multiferroic oxide due to its large electric polarization. Although it is isostructural with PTO, it shows large tetragonal distortion (
 <italic>c</italic>/
 <italic>a</italic> = 1.229). Isolated layers of corner-shared VO
 <sub>5</sub> pyramids form a layer-type perovskite structure with a space group 
 <italic>P</italic>4
 <italic>mm</italic>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> PVO has been proposed to have an antiferromagnetic ordering and a ferroelectric polarization as large as 152 μC/cm
 <sup>2</sup> due to the presence of large structural distortions.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>
 </sup> To this point, however, the true magnetic structure and the multifunctional nature of this material are controversial to researchers. Shpanchenko et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> found no long-range magnetic ordering with their neutron powder diffraction measurements down to 1.5 K. Belik et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>
 </sup> proposed that PVO is a two-dimensional (2D) spin-half square-lattice strongly frustrated antiferromagnet due to the antiferromagnetic interactions of the next nearest neighbors. Using magnetic susceptibility and specific heat measurements as well as band structure calculations, Tsirlin
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> confirmed that the 
 <italic>S</italic> = 1/2 square lattice of vanadium 4+ ions in PVO is strongly frustrated due to the next-nearest-neighbor antiferromagnetic interactions and no long-range magnetic ordering was found down to 1.8 K. Due to the presence of defects or ferromagnetic (FM) impurities in the sample, it has been very difficult to clarify the intrinsic magnetic property in PVO. Oka et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>
 </sup> investigated the magnetic properties of PVO by preparing a multidomain single crystal without any magnetic impurity. The broad maximum centered around 180 K in the temperature-dependent magnetization curve indicates the presence of two-dimensional antiferromagnetism. Muon spin rotation measurement displayed the presence of a long-range order below 43 K. The epitaxial thin films of PVO have been grown
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref>
 </sup> using pulsed laser deposition, which brings a step forward to synthesis of multiferroic materials outside of high-temperature and high-pressure techniques to realize devices with multifunctionalities. In another study on PVO thin films by Kumar et al.,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref>
 </sup> a transition from a ferroelectric-only state to a ferroelectric and magnetic state was observed below 100–130 K using second-harmonic generation and X-ray linear dichroism. Experimental electron energy loss spectroscopy investigation on V–L edge shows that V in the PVO thin films is in the V
 <sup>4+</sup> state, resulting in a d
 <sup>1</sup> state.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
