<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>There are some reports about the transition-metal substitution at the V site of PVO. Tsuchiya et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref>
 </sup> synthesized PbFe
 <sub>0.5</sub>V
 <sub>0.5</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> under high pressure and found the crystal structure as a tetragonal perovskite with 
 <italic>c</italic>/
 <italic>a</italic> = 1.18. The magnetic study revealed that the compound is an antiferromagnet and the electrical polarization is estimated to be as large as 88 μC/cm
 <sup>2</sup>. Arévalo et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref>
 </sup> studied Ti and Cr substitutions at V site in PVO. A tetragonal-to-cubic transition was observed as the Cr substitution level reaches 0.4, whereas the Ti substitution preserves the 
 <italic>P</italic>4
 <italic>mm</italic> symmetry. The interesting result observed by Arévalo et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref>
 </sup> was the temperature-induced phase transition from tetragonal to cubic in PbTi
 <sub>0.8</sub>V
 <sub>0.2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> at 730 K. But PVO decomposes to Pb
 <sub>2</sub>V
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> at 570 K before reaching its transition temperature.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>
 </sup> In another V site, Ti-substituted PbMO
 <sub>3</sub> system (where M stands for V site substituted with Ti), Ricci
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref>
 </sup> predicted multiferroicity in PbTi
 <sub>0.875</sub>V
 <sub>0.125</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> with a ferromagnetic–ferroelectric ground state and an electrical polarization of 95 μC/cm
 <sup>2</sup>. Recently, Pan et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref>
 </sup> have experimentally studied the Pb(Ti,V)O
 <sub>3</sub> system where the V substitution level varies from 0.1 to 0.6. They have found that in the whole composition range, the 
 <italic>P</italic>4
 <italic>mm</italic> symmetry was preserved and the tetragonality was abnormally improved (so the spontaneous polarization) with the replacement of Ti with V. Interestingly, they have also observed an intrinsic giant volume contraction of ∼3.7% for Pb(Ti
 <sub>0.7</sub>V
 <sub>0.3</sub>)O
 <sub>3</sub> during the ferroelectric-to-paraelectric phase transition. These observed interesting findings in the substituted systems motivated us for the present study.
</p>
