<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Recently, tungsten telluride (WTe
 <sub>2</sub>), as a member of the TMDC family, has drawn tremendous research interest since the discovery of its large non-saturating positive magnetoresistance (MR) behavior, which was attributed to its perfect electron–hole compensation. Theoretical calculations and experiments have indicated that WTe
 <sub>2</sub> has a complicated electronic structure with more than two bands presenting at the Fermi level [
 <xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Meanwhile, it was believed to a wonderful candidate for the type-II Weyl semimetal [
 <xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>] and quantum spin Hall insulator material [
 <xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. Additionally, many other remarkable properties of WTe
 <sub>2</sub> have also been revealed, such as the temperature-driven Lifshitz transition [
 <xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>], pressure-induced superconductivity [
 <xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>], linear Nernst response [
 <xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>], etc. Interestingly, although all of the TMDCs have the same formula, the atomic structure of 1T’-phase WTe
 <sub>2</sub> is totally different from the other TMDCs. 1T’-WTe
 <sub>2</sub> exhibits a distorted structure relative to the 1T’ phase. Both Raman [
 <xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>–
 <xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>] and first-principles [
 <xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>–
 <xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>] calculations have been used to indicate that monolayer 1T’-WTe
 <sub>2</sub> has a highly in-plane anisotropic crystal structure, in addition to anisotropic electrical, thermal and optical properties [
 <xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>–
 <xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. However, most of the results are based on theoretical demonstrations of the anisotropic phenomenon, rather than further quantitative data for the characterization the natural anisotropy of 1T’-WTe
 <sub>2</sub>.
</p>
