<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The femur is a long bone that develops via endochondral ossification. In particular, the human femur first appears as mesenchymal condensation between Carnegie stage (CS) 16 and CS17. Chondrification occurs between CS17 and CS18 and subsequently proceeds to endochondral ossification between CS22 and CS23 [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref003" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Most previous studies have been focused on the differentiation processes after the appearance of a primary ossification center at the femoral diaphysis [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref004" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>–
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref006" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Gardner and Gray (1970) described that the invasion and destruction of calcified cartilage cells occurred in fetuses with a crown–rump length (CRL) of 37 mm and that endochondral ossification and endochondral trabecular formation were prominent in fetuses with a CRL of 57 mm [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref004" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. This process rapidly progresses toward each end of the femur. Recent evaluation of the role of chondrocytes in endochondral differentiation has supported the concept of transdifferentiation during endochondral ossification [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref007" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref008" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. Specifically, suspected cartilage fragmentation may be irregularly shaped residual matrix present during cartilage-to-osteoblast transdifferentiation. At 15–20 weeks of gestation, the diaphysis exhibits cancellous bone formation with scattered trabeculae [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref005" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Cartilage canals are minute tunnels containing blood vessels, which are the forerunners of the epiphyseal nutrient arteries and veins and their rami in bony epiphyses. These formations precede the formation of a secondary ossification center and are crucial for the establishment of the secondary ossification center observed after birth [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref009" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. Cartilage canal formation is observed initially in the proximal epiphysis of fetuses with a CRL of 57 mm and subsequently in the distal epiphysis of fetuses with a CRL of 61 mm [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref004" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>].
</p>
