<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par47">In Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>, we display configurations obtained for three different values of 
 <italic>U</italic>
 <sub>0</sub> keeping fixed 
 <italic>D</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>r</italic>
 </sub>. At small 
 <italic>U</italic>
 <sub>0</sub>, the cluster-crystal phase occurs and, for both ABP and AOUP, aligns along the wall direction, as shown in panels a), b), c) and d). Interestingly, we find two symmetric narrow stripes of clusters attached to the walls whose shapes are strongly deformed with respect to the bulk-clusters (see the insets in panels a) and b)): in the ABP case, we observe ellipsoidal-like clusters instead of the ring-like one, while in the AOUP the Gaussian clusters are compressed in the transversal direction with respect to the channel as if the wall affects the 
 <italic>x</italic>-variance of the particle distribution inside the wall-clusters. This narrow stripe of clusters slides along the walls changing direction with an average rate ~1/
 <italic>D</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>r</italic>
 </sub> = 
 <italic>τ</italic>, without breaking away from the walls. Clusters, hexagonally arranged, form in the bulk at very small 
 <italic>U</italic>
 <sub>0</sub>, behaving in the same way as unconfined clusters, with one of the hexagonal directions aligned with the walls, as confirmed by the study of the 
 <italic>x</italic>-density, 
 <italic>ρ</italic>(
 <italic>x</italic>), in panel g) which reveals separated peaks. This situation changes by increasing 
 <italic>U</italic>
 <sub>0</sub>. In the bulk, far from the walls, clusters become unstable: they disappear and reform continuously in time as in the unconfined case, but maintain a clear alignment. As shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4c,d</xref>, the inner clusters elongate along the 
 <italic>y</italic>-direction until they collapse in vertical stripes. In this case, the study of 
 <italic>ρ</italic>(
 <italic>x</italic>) cannot capture this dynamical effect: the central peaks are only less pronounced with respect to the lateral ones and overlap. A further increase of 
 <italic>U</italic>
 <sub>0</sub> destroys the stripes order in the inner region, creating a fluid-like homogenous bulk-phase, whose structure is confirmed by the study of the density in panel i) which is roughly homogenous until the occurrence of the first stripes. In the proximity of the walls two stripes clearly separated are stable: the one in front of the wall and the one at the interface with the fluid-region, clearly separated by an empty region. In practice, the wall stripe creates an effective extra wall at distance ~±(
 <italic>L</italic> − 
 <italic>R</italic>), where active particles accumulate.
</p>
