<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par31">Analytical scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM) analysis was done using a c
 <sub>s</sub>-abberation corrected TITAN
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup> 80–300 electron microscope (FEI company, Hillsboro, USA) at 300 kV acceleration voltage. A high-angle annular dark field detector (Fischione Model 3000, Fischione company, Export, USA) and a camera length of 115 mm were used to capture high-angle annular dark field (HAADF) scanning TEM micrographs. All further analysis was carried out in a selected area of the sample (see Supplementary Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref> top). The matrix, in which the particles are embedded, consists of SrO originating from the partial decomposition of the samples during the preparation. This effect is inevitable since the composition of SALON is not indefinitely stable versus the preparation with 30 keV (initial thinning)/5 keV (fine polishing) Ga
 <sup>+</sup> ion beams, and also versus the subsequent irradiation with 300 keV electrons in the transmission electron microscope. This is typical for materials that contain light elements such as oxygen, nitrogen, and especially lithium
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR60">60</xref>
 </sup>. STEM was combined with energy-dispersive X-ray analysis (EDX), using a Super-X EDX detector that is equipped with four SDD detectors (FEI company, Hillsboro, USA), to gather lateral element distribution maps of chosen elements. Quantification of the ratio of the elements N, Sr, Al, and O was performed with a Cliff-Lorimer approach under the assumption of a sample thickness of 100 nm, using the commercially available software Esprit, v1.9 (Bruker corporation, Billerica, USA). Element mappings of the elements N, Sr, Al, and O were derived by evaluating the lateral distribution of the peak intensity, i.e., the area underlying the K edges (N, O, Al), or L edge (Sr), respectively, with an automatic routine provided by the software.
</p>
