<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//Springer-Verlag//DTD A++ V2.4//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName A++V2.4.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.4?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName springer2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Scientific Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2045-2322</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group UK</publisher-name><publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6934717</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">56301</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-56301-5</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Lattice disorder effect on magnetic ordering of iron arsenides</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Sefat</surname><given-names>Athena S.</given-names></name><address><email>sefata@ornl.gov</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Xiaoping P.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Yaohua</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zou</surname><given-names>Qiang</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>Mimgming</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Gai</surname><given-names>Zheng</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ganesan</surname><given-names>Kalaiselvan</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Vohra</surname><given-names>Yogesh</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Li</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Parker</surname><given-names>David S.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0446 2659</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.135519.a</institution-id><institution>Materials Science &#x00026; Technology Division, </institution><institution>Oak Ridge National Laboratory, </institution></institution-wrap>Oak Ridge, TN 37831 USA </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0446 2659</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.135519.a</institution-id><institution>Neutron Scattering Division, </institution><institution>Oak Ridge National Laboratory, </institution></institution-wrap>Oak Ridge, TN 37831 USA </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0446 2659</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.135519.a</institution-id><institution>Center for Nanophase Materials Sciences, </institution><institution>Oak Ridge National Laboratory, </institution></institution-wrap>Oak Ridge, TN 37831 USA </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000000106344187</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.265892.2</institution-id><institution>Department of Physics, </institution><institution>University of Alabama at Birmingham, </institution></institution-wrap>Birmingham, AL 35294 USA </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>27</day><month>12</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>27</day><month>12</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>9</volume><elocation-id>20147</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>5</day><month>8</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>4</day><month>12</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2019</copyright-statement><license license-type="OpenAccess"><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this license, visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">This study investigates magnetic ordering temperature in nano- and mesoscale structural features in an iron arsenide. Although magnetic ground states in quantum materials can be theoretically predicted from known crystal structures and chemical compositions, the ordering temperature is harder to pinpoint due to potential local lattice variations that calculations may not account for. In this work we find surprisingly that a locally disordered material can exhibit a significantly larger N&#x000e9;el temperature (<italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>) than an ordered material of precisely the same chemical stoichiometry. Here, a EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> crystal, which is a &#x02018;122&#x02019; parent of iron arsenide superconductors, is found through synthesis to have ordering below <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;195&#x02009;K (for the locally disordered crystal) or <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;175&#x02009;K (for the ordered crystal). In the higher <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> crystals, there are shorter planar Fe-Fe bonds [2.7692(2) &#x000c5; vs. 2.7745(3) &#x000c5;], a randomized in-plane defect structure, and diffuse scattering along the [00&#x02009;L] crystallographic direction that manifests as a rather broad specific heat peak. For the lower <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> crystals, the <italic>a</italic>-lattice parameter is larger and the in-plane microscopic structure shows defect ordering along the antiphase boundaries, giving a larger <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> and a higher superconducting temperature (<italic>T</italic><sub>c</sub>) upon the application of pressure. First-principles calculations find a strong interaction between <italic>c</italic>-axis strain and interlayer magnetic coupling, but little impact of planar strain on the magnetic order. Neutron single-crystal diffraction shows that the low-temperature magnetic phase transition due to localized Eu moments is not lattice or disorder sensitive, unlike the higher-temperature Fe sublattice ordering. This study demonstrates a higher magnetic ordering point arising from local disorder in 122.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Materials science</kwd><kwd>Condensed-matter physics</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>BES DOE</institution></funding-source></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2019</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par2">A bulk magnetic transition in a quantum material is thermally-driven by spin interactions dictated by nano- and mesoscale structures, such as lattice composition, crystal structure, disorder and defects, lattice strain, chemical impurities and dopants. The parents of the iron-based superconductors with <italic>A</italic>Fe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> (<italic>A</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;Ba, Sr, Ca, Eu) formula, known as &#x02018;122&#x02019;, are semi-metallic with all five Fe 3<italic>d</italic>-bands crossing the Fermi level<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref></sup>. These materials have a tetragonal structure at room temperature (<italic>a</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;<italic>b</italic>&#x02009;&#x02260;&#x02009;<italic>c</italic>), and at a N&#x000e9;el antiferromagnetic transition temperature (<italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>) there is a small tetragonal-to-orthorhombic structural distortion (<italic>T</italic><sub>s</sub>) where the unit cell rotates by ~45&#x000b0; within the <italic>ab</italic>-plane<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup>. Below <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> there is a sinusoidal modulation of Fe moments in the form of a spin-density wave (SDW)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup> described by a wave vector <bold><italic>q</italic></bold>&#x02009;=&#x02009;(&#x000bd; &#x000bd; 1) in the tetragonal structure, matching the nesting vector between the electron and hole pockets at the Fermi surface<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref></sup>. The Fe spin lattice is a &#x02018;stripe&#x02019; arrangement (spins are antiparallel along <italic>a-</italic> and <italic>c-</italic>axes, and parallel along <italic>b-</italic>axis)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par3">It has been found that strain can induce a nematic phase transition in 122&#x02009;s<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup> that is seen as an electronic in-plane anisotropy<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref></sup>, driven by orbital (unequal occupation of <italic>d</italic><sub>xz</sub> and <italic>d</italic><sub>yz</sub>) or spin directional order (not long range) that causes breaking of the in-plane C4 rotational symmetry and splits the <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> and <italic>T</italic><sub>s</sub> transitions. Moreover, higher <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> in BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> is linked to a more homogenous electronic structure<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup>, and there are local structure variations<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup>. Thermally annealing of BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> is found to shift and sharpen the heat capacity anomaly<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref></sup>. With disorder via electron irradiation in BaFe<sub>2</sub>(As<sub>1&#x02212;x</sub>P<sub>x</sub>)<sub>2</sub> the magneto-structural transition is suppressed and the superconducting dome tracks the shift of the antiferromagnetic phase<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref></sup>, while in Ba<sub>1-x</sub>K<sub>x</sub>Fe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> the antiferromagnetic and superconducting transition temperatures decrease<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref></sup>. For SrFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub>, in addition to a large variability of <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> values (195 to 220&#x02009;K)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>, superconducting signature (filamentary <italic>T</italic><sub>c</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;21&#x02009;K) can be found in strained crystals<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref></sup>. Furthermore, CaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> can be synthesized as entirely non-magnetic, or an antiferromagnet with a large <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>, achieved by staggered alleviation of local Fe&#x02212;As bonds with thermal annealing<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref></sup>. For this study, we hypothesize that the local lattice details, including disorder, of EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> may affect its <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> value. EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> is unique among the 122&#x02009;s for having both SDW order of Fe, and Eu local moment order below ~20&#x02009;K with <bold><italic>q</italic></bold>&#x02009;=&#x02009;(0 0&#x02009;L)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref></sup>. The Eu local moments are weakly coupled to the Fe sublattice and are strong enough for a large and indirect spin-lattice coupling that can lead to a structural detwinning by a small magnetic field<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref></sup> and can cause re-entrant non-bulk superconductivity<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par4">We have synthesized two stoichiometric EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> crystals with onset of Fe ordering at <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;195&#x02009;K or <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;175&#x02009;K, and use X-ray and neutron diffraction, microscopy and spectroscopy techniques, and theory, to understand the reasons that give these magnetic ordering temperatures. Surprisingly, the higher <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> crystal has a broader (usually associated with strain and disorder) specific heat peak, while the lower <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> crystal has a sharp peak. How does <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> relate to lattice and topological features, and does <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> value correlate with averaged lattice parameters? Would higher <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> mean more homogeneous electronic structure? What are the pressure results for diminishing antiferromagnetism and potentially deriving superconductivity in each of these crystals? Our results show that although <italic>T</italic><sub>N(Fe)</sub> and <italic>T</italic><sub>c</sub> values are greatly sensitive to the lattice details and local arrangements of defect structures, Eu ordering is unaffected at <italic>T</italic><sub>N(Eu)</sub>&#x02009;&#x02248;&#x02009;20&#x02009;K. This study demonstrates the apparent contradictory result that certain types of disorder can significantly increase the magnetic order, even in stoichiometric quantum material.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Experimental Procedure and Results</title><p id="Par5">Single crystals of EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> were grown out of a mixture of Eu and FeAs excess used as liquid flux<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref></sup>. Each of these mixtures was warmed to 1180&#x02009;&#x000b0;C, then cooled (2&#x02009;&#x000b0;C<italic>/</italic>h) followed by a decanting of the FeAs excess flux at 1090&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. Two different reaction loading ratios were used to obtain EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> single crystals with different <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>. A loading ratio of Eu:FeAs&#x02009;=&#x02009;1:5 gives an onset transition temperature of <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;195&#x02009;K (referred to as &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;), while Eu:FeAs&#x02009;=&#x02009;1:4 gives crystals with <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;175&#x02009;K (&#x02018;crystal b&#x02019;). The chemical composition of these crystals was measured with a Hitachi S3400 scanning electron microscope operating at 20&#x02009;kV. Three spots (each &#x0223c;80 &#x003bc;m area) were checked and averaged on each crystal; energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS) and site-refinement of single-crystal X-ray diffraction analyses indicate that both crystals are stoichiometric and are EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub>. The phase purity of the crystals was checked by collecting data on an X&#x02019;Pert PRO MPD X-ray powder diffractometer; structures were solely identified as tetragonal ThCr<sub>2</sub>Si<sub>2</sub> structure type (<italic>I</italic>4<italic>/mmm</italic>, <italic>Z</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;2).</p><p id="Par6">Specific heat data were collected on EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> single crystals, using a Quantum Design Physical Property Measurement System (PPMS); the C(T) results are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>. Each EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> crystal exhibits two transitions: an ordering of the Fe lattice at higher temperature, followed by lower temperature ordering (&#x02248;20&#x02009;K) due to Eu moments. The EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; exhibits the higher onset ordering temperature of <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;195&#x02009;K with a broader peak, compared to &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; giving a sharp lambda transition below <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;175&#x02009;K. The specific heat result of &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; looks similar to that reported in a pressed polycrystalline sample (with respect to peak width, height, and transition temperature)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref></sup>.<fig id="Fig1"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Data on EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; and &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019;. (<bold>a</bold>) Specific heat, C(T), results with transitions associated with Eu (<italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;21&#x02009;K) and Fe ordering (<italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;195&#x02009;K or 175&#x02009;K). (<bold>b</bold>) Precession images showing the [HK0] and [H0L] reciprocal lattice planes reconstructed from single crystal X-ray diffraction patterns measured at room temperature. Smearing in diffraction spots are more prevalent in &#x02018;crystal a,&#x02019; noted in [H0L] plane.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_56301_Fig1_HTML" id="d29e830"/></fig></p><p id="Par7">To analyze crystal structures, single crystal X-ray diffraction data were collected at room temperature on a Rigaku XtaLAB PRO diffractometer (Mo Source, K<sub>&#x003b1;</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0.71073&#x02009;&#x000c5;) equipped with a DECTRIS Pilatus 200&#x02009;K area detector. Data collection and reduction used the CrysAlisPro program<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>. Crystal structure refinements were performed using the SHELX-2014 program<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref> (insets) shows the pictures of crystals for the data collection, stuck on top of needles. Crystals &#x02018;a&#x02019; and &#x02018;b&#x02019; appeared similar visually, with sheet morphologies; [001] direction is perpendicular to the plane of the plate. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref> gives the precession images of [HK0] and [H0L] reciprocal lattice planes, showing lattice strain effects associated with smeared diffraction spots in the L direction for &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;; this crystal has a relatively broad C(T) peak (<italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;195&#x02009;K) from the Fe ordering. A broader peak of specific heat is usually associated with lattice strain and disorder. Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref> shows the lattice parameters and refinement results of the X-ray structure measured at room temperature. The EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> sample with higher <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> (&#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;) gives a lower overall <italic>a</italic>-lattice parameter and a shorter planar Fe&#x02212;Fe distance of 2.7692(2) &#x000c5;, indicating a contraction of 0.0053(4) &#x000c5; for the in-plane Fe&#x02212;Fe bond when compared to that of 2.7745(3) &#x000c5; for the lower <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> (&#x02018;crystal b&#x02019;).<table-wrap id="Tab1"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Single-crystal X-ray diffraction refinement on the two crystals of EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub>: &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; (<italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;195&#x02009;K), &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; (<italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;175&#x02009;K).</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> sample ID</th><th>&#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;</th><th>&#x02018;crystal b&#x02019;</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><italic>a</italic> (&#x000c5;)</td><td>3.9162 (3)</td><td>3.9238 (4)</td></tr><tr><td><italic>c</italic> (&#x000c5;)</td><td>12.104 (3)</td><td>12.105 (2)</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3"><bold>As at (0, 0</bold>, <bold><italic>z</italic></bold><bold>); 4e</bold></td></tr><tr><td><italic>z</italic></td><td>0.36256 (13)</td><td>0.36255 (11)</td></tr><tr><td><italic>U</italic><sub>iso</sub></td><td>0.0104 (6)</td><td>0.0109 (6)</td></tr><tr><td>arsenic height, &#x000c5;</td><td>1.3624 (10)</td><td>1.3624 (8)</td></tr><tr><td>site occupancy</td><td>0.96 (9)</td><td>0.97 (8)</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3"><bold>Fe at (&#x000bd;, 0, &#x000bc;); 4</bold><bold><italic>d</italic></bold></td></tr><tr><td><italic>U</italic><sub>iso</sub></td><td>0.0106 (6)</td><td>0.0107 (6)</td></tr><tr><td>Fe&#x02012;Fe distance, &#x000c5;</td><td>2.7692 (2)</td><td>2.7745 (3)</td></tr><tr><td>site occupancy</td><td>0.97 (9)</td><td>0.97 (8)</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></p><p id="Par8">Neutron diffraction measurements were carried out using the TOPAZ single crystal diffractometer at the ORNL Spallation Neutron Source (SNS), which uses the wavelength-resolved Laue technique with an extensive array of neutron time-of-flight area detectors for 3-dimentional <italic>Q</italic> space mapping of Bragg and diffuse scattering patterns originating from magnetic and nuclear phase transitions<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref></sup>. Pieces of &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; and &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; had dimensions of 3.25&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;2.50&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;0.20&#x02009;mm<sup>3</sup> and 2.75&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;2.63&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;0.30&#x02009;mm<sup>3</sup>, respectively, and were attached on a MiTegen loop using super glue for data collection at room temperature and 95&#x02009;K. Each of the samples was oriented with high precision for volumetric sampling of Bragg peaks in specific directions with the CrystalPlan program<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref></sup>. At room temperature, the (0 2 0)<sub>Tetragonal</sub> peak profiles for the two EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> crystals are shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>, demonstrating the peak false-color maps and their corresponding peak intensity profiles along the crystallographic <italic>c</italic>-direction. The peak from &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; is broad and shows extensive diffuse lines along the L direction, which is consistent with that observed in X-ray diffraction, and gives broader and higher <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> in C(T).<fig id="Fig2"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Tetragonal (0 2 0) peak profiles for the two EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> crystals at room temperature for (<bold>a</bold>) &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; and (<bold>b</bold>) &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019;, showing the peak false color maps, and their corresponding peak intensity profiles along the crystallographic <italic>c</italic> direction. Note the difference in scales on both axes. The peak from &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; is substantially broadened showing extended diffuse lines.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_56301_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e1109"/></fig></p><p id="Par9">As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref>, the streaks for the (2 0 0) peak along L direction for &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; is much more pronounced (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref>) than that of &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2b</xref>), which could be induced by strain, stacking fault or disorder in the bulk single crystal sample. Since the refined average <italic>c</italic> lattice parameter remains essentially unchanged for both crystals (Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>), the much more pronounced streaks for &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; are likely from microstrain caused by randomly distributed defects in &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;, which is evident from scanning tunneling microscopy/spectroscopy (STM/S) measurement (see Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> below). The split of the peaks along <italic>c</italic> also indicates twinning and multidomain structures of &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;. In particular, we note from Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> (bottom panels) that the full-width at half maximum (FWHM) for the (2 0 0) peak along L direction is some 0.13&#x02013;0.27 reciprocal lattice units larger than that of &#x02018;crystal b.&#x02019; If one assumes that in the ordered &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; the finite (i.e. non-zero) FWHM is largely due to measurement resolution limits, the FWHM for &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; would correspond to a ~2&#x02013;5% local variation in the lattice constant <italic>c</italic>.<fig id="Fig3"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>(<bold>a</bold>) The structure model of EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> and the surface reconstruction models of arsenic 2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;1 and europium &#x0221a;2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;&#x0221a;2 terminations. The black boxes outline the unit cells. (<bold>b</bold>,<bold>c</bold>) Topographic images of 2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;1 surface reconstruction from &#x02018;crystals a&#x02019; (&#x02212;500 mV, 100 pA) and &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; (&#x02212;1 V, 100 pA), respectively. (<bold>d</bold>,<bold>e</bold>) Topographic images of &#x0221a;2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;&#x0221a;2 surface reconstruction from &#x02018;crystals a&#x02019; (&#x02212;60 mV, 400 pA) and &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; (&#x02212;20 mV, 800 pA), respectively. Insets show the atomic resolved images in 3&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;3 nm<sup>2</sup> size and black boxes are the unit cells of &#x0221a;2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;&#x0221a;2 surface reconstruction. (<bold>f</bold>,<bold>g</bold>) Comparison of average LDOS from &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; (red) and &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; (blue), for surface reconstructions at 4.2&#x02009;K.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_56301_Fig3_HTML" id="d29e1179"/></fig></p><p id="Par10">For these crystals, neutron diffraction results were additionally carried out at 95&#x02009;K, to confirm the Fe magnetic peak below <italic>T</italic><sub><italic>N</italic></sub> in accordance with the propagation vector <bold><italic>q</italic></bold>&#x02009;=&#x02009;(1 0 1)<sub>Orthorhombic</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;(&#x000bd; &#x000bd; 1)<sub>Tetragonal</sub> and the stripe arrangement of the Fe spin lattice<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup> (see Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1a</xref> in Supplementary). Additionally, variable temperature scans of the Eu magnetic peak at (0 3 0) for both crystals were performed below 30&#x02009;K using the elastic diffuse scattering spectrometer CORELLI at SNS<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup> and showed the same temperature dependence of Eu magnetic peak as (0 3 0) with <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;21&#x02009;K (see Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1b</xref>). In contrast, the N&#x000e9;el transition temperature for Fe is clearly lattice and disorder sensitive. The high-temperature phase transition is due to the ordering of the transition metal Fe moments, whereas the low-temperature phase transition is due to the ordering of the localized Eu moments<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref></sup>. The divergent behavior of the Fe and Eu sublattices from &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; to &#x02018;b&#x02019; &#x02013; the former sublattice sensitive to lattice disorder, the latter insensitive &#x02013; is of interest here. One plausible hypothesis is that the Eu 4&#x02009;<italic>f</italic> moments are much more localized, near the Eu nucleus, than the Fe moments that are more itinerant. This would suggest that the Eu 4&#x02009;<italic>f</italic> moments are less subject to nano-strain than the Fe 3<italic>d</italic> moments, and the relatively isolated location of Eu between the layers (as opposed to the tightly bound FeAs layers) would enhance this possibility. Supporting this assertion is the relative insensitivity of Eu ordering temperature to pressure (see Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S4</xref>), again unlike the Fe sublattice ordering. Indeed the Eu magnetic order survives to higher pressure than the Fe order, despite occurring at much lower temperatures.</p><p id="Par11">To further investigate the local origin of the bulk <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> differences between the two EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> crystals, surface topography and electronic structures were investigated using STM/S on <italic>in-situ</italic> low-temperature cleaved surfaces. The two sets of EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; and &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; were cleaved in an ultra-high vacuum at ~ 78&#x02009;K and then immediately transferred to the STM/S head precooled to 4.2&#x02009;K without breaking vacuum. The STM/S experiments were carried out using a scanning tunneling microscope with base pressure better than 2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;10<sup>&#x02212;10</sup>&#x02009;Torr, with mechanically cut Pt-Ir tip. All Pt-Ir tips were conditioned on clean Au (1 1 1) and checked using the topography, surface state, and work function before each measurement. The STM/S were controlled by the SPECS Nanonis control system. Topographic images were acquired in constant current mode with bias voltage applied to samples, and tip grounded. All the spectroscopies were obtained using the lock-in technique with a modulation of 1&#x02009;mV at 973&#x02009;Hz on bias voltage, dI/dV. Current-imaging-tunneling-spectroscopy were collected over a grid of pixels at bias ranges around Fermi level using the same lock-in amplifier parameters. The survey on multiple large areas of both samples shows the coexistence surface reconstructions on &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; and &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019;, as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>. Using a similar method as STM report on Co-doped BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref></sup>, the 2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;1 and &#x0221a;2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;&#x0221a;2 reconstructed surfaces can be assigned to arsenic termination and europium termination, respectively, as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a</xref>. While the 2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;1 surfaces of both crystals (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3b,c</xref>) are very similar, the &#x0221a;2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;&#x0221a;2 surfaces of the two crystals (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d,e</xref>) are very different. The atomic resolved images in the insets of Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d,e</xref> from the well-ordered &#x0221a;2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;&#x0221a;2 reconstructed areas of the two crystals are similar, but the arrangements of the defects on the surfaces are rather different. In &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;, surface defects (one of the defects is marked with a black arrow in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d</xref>) are essentially randomly distributed on the surface, but in &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019;, large amount of defects prefer to form into chains (one of the chains is marked with a white arrow in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3e</xref>). By analyzing atomically resolved images around these areas, we found the chains are aligned on the antiphase boundaries. Because the surface reconstruction is 2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;1 or &#x0221a;2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;&#x0221a;2, those domains can shift by 1 to form antiphase boundaries. Although antiphase boundaries also exist on the &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; surface (one of the antiphase boundaries is marked with a green arrow in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d</xref>), defects in &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; do not segregate along the boundaries. The electronic properties revealed by the STS from the surfaces are consistent with the morphological observation (see also Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S2</xref>). In Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3f</xref>, the average electronic local density of states (LDOS) of 2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;1 surfaces (As termination) over large areas are almost identical for both crystals, but the LDOS from the two &#x0221a;2&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;&#x0221a;2 surfaces (Eu termination) in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3g</xref> have significant differences. This shows that the different arrangements of the surface defects in the two crystals change the electronic structure dramatically. Given the preparation of these surfaces by cleaving the crystals in ultra-high vacuum at low temperatures, this difference is in electronic structure that is generally reflective of the effects of the defects in the bulk crystals.</p><p id="Par12">For both EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> crystals, high-pressure electrical-resistance measurements were performed using a diamond anvil cell (see Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S3</xref> and <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S4</xref>), to explore the differences of pressure effects on the two crystals that have different <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>, under the same experimental setup. Although the feature due to Eu ordering is not changed for either crystals up to ~4&#x02009;GPa, Fe ordering is greatly sensitive to pressure and the rate of <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> suppression for both crystals is similar. For &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; with smaller <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;175&#x02009;K, the drop in resistivity is noticed at lower pressure of 2.5&#x02009;GPa, compared to &#x02018;crystal a,&#x02019; with a drop in resistivity at 3.2&#x02009;GPa. EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> with sharper, but lower <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>, is prone to a higher superconducting dome (<bold>S4</bold>); highest <italic>T</italic><sub>c</sub> value for &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; is 36&#x02009;K, and for &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; is 41&#x02009;K.</p></sec><sec id="Sec3"><title>First Principles Calculations</title><p id="Par13">In the effort to understand the sample-to-sample variation in N&#x000e9;el temperatures, we have conducted first principles theory calculations of the effect of nano-scale strain on the magnetic order, specifically on two questions. The first question is straightforward: is the observed variation in <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> related to the slight difference in planar lattice constants in crystals &#x02018;a&#x02019; and &#x02018;b&#x02019;? We assess based on calculations of the &#x02018;ordering energy,&#x02019; specifically the difference in energy between the stripe ground-state and the checkerboard (all neighboring moments are anti-aligned) excited state. The second question, with more complex interpretation, is whether <italic>c</italic>-axis strain is relevant to the observed <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> variation. The motivation for studying this question is the evident &#x02018;shoulder&#x02019; in the neutron diffraction results presented in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref>, which could result from <italic>c</italic>-axis nano-scale strain, and thereby an effective <italic>distribution</italic> of local <italic>c</italic>-axis lattice parameters. Note that the bulk lattice constants for crystals &#x02018;a&#x02019; and &#x02018;b&#x02019; are identical (to within 0.001&#x02009;&#x000c5;), so that we are studying, in effect, the local nanoscale energetics rather than constructing an involved model of the bulk N&#x000e9;el point variation for a sample with a distribution of local lattice constants.</p><p id="Par14">First principles calculations were performed using the linearized augmented plane wave (LAPW) density functional theory code WIEN2K<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref></sup>. As in our previous work<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup> we have used the local density approximation (LDA), with arsenic height and lattice parameters taken directly from our experimental XRD refinements (Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>), except as stated below. An RK<sub>max</sub> value of 8.0 &#x02013; the product of the smallest sphere radius and largest planewave expansion wavevector &#x02013; was used. To avoid the generally confounding complexities of 4&#x02009;<italic>f</italic> physics (here we are focused on the Fe magnetic behavior) we have followed our previous theoretical work<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref></sup> and performed the all-electron calculations with the isoelectronic substitution of Sr for the divalent Eu, but retained our lattice parameters and internal coordinates for EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub>. The effect of these choices is to allow a direct evaluation of the Fe sublattice magnetic properties without the need to apply a correlated (i.e. LDA&#x02009;+&#x02009;U) approach to deal with the Eu 4&#x02009;<italic>f</italic> electrons, which play little or no role in the Fe magnetism. Sphere radii of 2.5 Bohr were used for Sr, and between 2.26 and 2.30 for Fe (depending on volume), and between 2.15 and 2.22 for As. Identical sphere radii were used for the calculations at given volume, relevant for assessing the interlayer coupling.</p><p id="Par15">With regards to the first question of whether changes in the magnetic ordering energy, or energetic difference between the stripe ground state and checkerboard excited state, result from the small difference in planar lattice parameters, we find only a small change (0.4%) in this energy, from 51.6&#x02009;meV/Fe for &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;, to 51.8&#x02009;meV/Fe for &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019;. This means that the observed ~ 10% N&#x000e9;el temperature variation does not result from changes in this ordering energy. At the same time, one should note that the observed 0.2% change in lattice parameter from &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; to &#x02018;b&#x02019; corresponds to an effective chemical pressure of several tenths of a GPA, and pressure is a well-known means of <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> suppression. While it remains possible that this effective planar strain is relevant here, arguing against this is the fact that the smaller lattice parameter &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; has the larger N&#x000e9;el point, whereas the application of pressure, thereby yielding smaller lattice constants, generally lowers the <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>.</p><p id="Par16">Concerning the second question, the neutron scan of &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; along the [00&#x02009;L] direction shows clear evidence of disorder, with a rather broadened peak around the (0 0 0) point and a substantial &#x02018;shoulder&#x02019; feature extending nearly to the [001] point (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref>). While there are many possible sources of such disorder, ranging from vacancies and anti-site defects to small grain sizes, here we explore the idea that <italic>c</italic>-axis strain in &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; is ultimately responsible for the rather broad neutron diffraction peaks. The hypothesis here is that nanoscale <italic>c</italic>-axis strain could significantly change the interlayer magnetic coupling, since this coupling is known from previous work<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref></sup> to depend rather substantially on pressure, or equivalently compression or expansion of the cell from the equilibrium value. The interlayer coupling is of course necessary to attain a finite ordering temperature, given the Mermin-Wagner finding that truly low-dimensional systems do not order at finite temperature. Since, as in many materials, the interlayer coupling here is relatively weak, it is plausible that nanoscale <italic>c</italic>-axis strain could change the coupling, which generally falls off quickly with increased distance.</p><p id="Par17">We have therefore conducted calculations of this interlayer magnetic coupling. Here we report the energy difference, per unit cell, between the ground-state stripe magnetic order (which is antiferromagnetically coupled along the <italic>c</italic>-axis) and a state with ferromagnetic <italic>c</italic>-axis coupling. We have done this at the experimental lattice parameter of 12.104&#x02009;&#x000c5;, and in addition for <italic>c</italic> values 5% larger and smaller than this value. For the experimental <italic>c</italic>-lattice parameter, we find an interlayer coupling energy difference of 7.1 mRyd/u.c., which increases slightly to 7.7 mRyd for the +5% <italic>c</italic> value, but decreases sharply to some 4.5 mRyd for the &#x02212;5% <italic>c</italic> value. These values are in qualitative agreement with the previous work on BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref></sup>, where it was found that the application of pressure decreases the interlayer coupling. We mention also that the calculated magnetic moments decrease substantially for the smaller cell, and correspondingly increase for the larger cell. In the antiferromagnetically coupled layer state, for the smallest cell these moments are 1.25 &#x003bc;<sub>B</sub> per Fe, for the experimental cell the value is 1.63 &#x003bc;<sub>B</sub>, and for the largest cell is 1.92 &#x003bc;<sub>B</sub>. Neutron diffraction results give an Fe moment of ~1 &#x003bc;<sub>B</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup>, consistent with the general overstatement of magnetic order by first principles approaches in these materials.</p><p id="Par18">These data suggest that interlayer strain can affect the magnetism in a substantial manner. In this scenario, the broadened specific heat peak in &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019; would result from a <italic>distribution</italic> of local lattice parameters, and thereby a distribution of local interlayer exchange couplings, resulting in a spread of ordering points. However, one difficulty with this argument is that such a distribution would have a larger effect on the temperature width of the transition than the mean transition temperature, since the bulk <italic>c</italic>-axis lattice parameters in crystals &#x02018;a&#x02019; and &#x02018;b&#x02019; are identical (leaving aside such questions as the temperature dependence of the magnetic correlation length in such a disordered scenario). Furthermore the fact that the strained calculations show larger <italic>decreases</italic> in magnetic order (measured as the interlayer coupling) with compressive strain than <italic>increases</italic> with tensile strain suggests that the effect of a distribution of <italic>c</italic>-axis lattice parameters around the bulk value would be a <italic>decrease</italic> in N&#x000e9;el point, not an increase. If the reverse were true &#x02013; that the increases in magnetic order with one form of strain were larger than the decreases with the opposite strain &#x02013; one would in fact have a possible explanation for the <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> enhancement. However, the calculations do not suggest this ladder possibility, and thus we must consider, as unsupported the hypothesis, that strain-related interlayer-magnetic exchange differences create the observed <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> increase in &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;.</p><p id="Par19">Since the straightforward explanations of the <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> increase, based on disorder-induced structure modification, do not explain this rather unusual behavior, it is necessary to consider other possibilities. For example, in materials near a magnetic instability, it has recently been posited<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref></sup> that charge doping can induce a magnetic transition based on Stoner physics, and one could plausibly imagine a similar enhancement in magnetic character of an already magnetic material. However, the generally stoichiometric character of both samples studied here argues against such a possibility. An additional possibility is provided by the theoretical work of Gastiasoro <italic>et al</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref></sup>, which finds (for superconductivity, and extended to magnetic order) density-of-states increase from either resonant states or Anderson localization leading to enhancements in ordering points. We here suggest a different possibility: spin fluctuations are known to be exceptionally strong in the iron arsenides, and in fact are a leading candidate for the interaction causing superconductivity. It is commonly believed<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref></sup> that these fluctuations also play an important role in reducing the N&#x000e9;el point of these materials from a much higher &#x02018;bare&#x02019; value. It is also known from several recent theory works<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref></sup> that disorder can play a substantial role in weakening spin fluctuations and inducing magnetism, and this role is especially prominent<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref></sup> in the case of stripe magnetic order, as is observed in the iron-arsenides. Putting such arguments together, we suggest that the disorder evident in our specific heat and neutron data is weakening the spin fluctuations and thereby enhancing the magnetic order.</p><p id="Par20">One means of testing this theory would be to employ the quasi-particle interference techniques recently applied to LiFeAs<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref></sup>. While in that work it was the superconductivity (and its coupling to a bosonic excitation) that was studied, we anticipate that a measure suitably adapted to the case of the antiferromagnetic order here could also yield insight. If reduced spin fluctuations are in fact at work here, the momentum and energy dependent differential conductance g(<bold>k</bold>, &#x003c9;) should show signatures of reduced scattering in the higher <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub>. In particular, generally sharper (as a function of momentum and energy) peaks are expected in the conductance in this material, when measured at the same temperature as the lower N&#x000e9;el point crystal. Future experimental studies would be highly beneficial are to assess this possibility.</p></sec><sec id="Sec4" sec-type="conclusion"><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par21">We find that disorder-related lattice variability drives significantly different Fe N&#x000e9;el ordering temperatures in the stoichiometric EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> crystals, with the highly unusual result that the <italic>more</italic> locally disordered crystal exhibits the <italic>higher</italic> N&#x000e9;el point. The diffuse scattering that is seen along the [00&#x02009;L] direction in X-ray and neutron diffraction measurements for the higher <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> crystal may well be the origin of the broadened specific heat peak and the suppressed superconducting dome. The surface topography and electronic structure studies show that there is a clear difference in electronic and defect structures between the two <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> crystals, with defect states dominating and elevating the LDOS for the higher <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> &#x02018;crystal a&#x02019;. Although the two crystals have a similar number of defects, their segregation around the antiphase boundaries in &#x02018;crystal b&#x02019; largely decreases the number of random individual defects, which may cause a higher-<italic>T</italic><sub><italic>c</italic></sub> superconductor with pressure. This study thereby demonstrates the modification of <italic>T</italic><sub>N</sub> in an iron arsenide by controlled disorder, thus explaining the observation of substantial ordering temperature variations for these stoichiometric quantum materials in the literature.</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary information</title><sec id="Sec5"><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1"><media xlink:href="41598_2019_56301_MOESM1_ESM.docx"><caption><p>Supplementary Information</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher&#x02019;s note</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Supplementary information</title><p>is available for this paper at 10.1038/s41598-019-56301-5.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>The research is primarily supported by the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE), Office of Science, Basic Energy Sciences (BES), Materials Science and Engineering Division. Neutron scattering experiments at Oak Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL) were supported by the Scientific User Facilities Division, Office of BES, DOE.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>Sefat: Measured bulk properties, wrote paper. Wang: Performed single crystal X-ray diffraction. Liu: Performed single crystal neutron diffraction. Zou, Fu, Gai: Performed STM/S Kalaiselvan, Vohra: Performed high pressure resistivity measurements Li: synthesized crystals Parker: theory calculations.</p></notes><notes notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par23">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sefat</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Chemistry and electronic structure of iron-based superconductors</article-title><source>MRS Bull.</source><year>2011</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>614</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1557/mrs.2011.175</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fisher</surname><given-names>IR</given-names></name><name><surname>Degiorgi</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>ZX</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>In-plane electronic anisotropy of underdoped &#x02018;122&#x02019; Fe-arsenide superconductors revealed by measurements of detwinned single crystals</article-title><source>Rep. Prog. Phys.</source><year>2011</year><volume>74</volume><fpage>124506</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/0034-4885/74/12/124506</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Niedziela</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name><surname>McGuire</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name><surname>Egami</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Local structural variation as source of magnetic moment reduction in BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2012</year><volume>86</volume><fpage>174113</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.86.174113</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Observation of Fermi-surface-dependent nodeless superconducting gaps in Ba<sub>0.6</sub>K<sub>0.4</sub>Fe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Europhys. Lett.</source><year>2008</year><volume>83</volume><fpage>47001</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1209/0295-5075/83/47001</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Neutron-diffraction measurements of magnetic order and a structural transition in the parent BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> compound of FeAs-based high-temperature superconductors</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><year>2008</year><volume>101</volume><fpage>257003</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.101.257003</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 19113744?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19113744</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Spin and lattice structures of single-crystalline SrFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2008</year><volume>78</volume><fpage>140504</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.78.140504</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Goldman</surname><given-names>AI</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Lattice and magnetic instabilities in CaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub>: A single-crystal neutron diffraction study</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2008</year><volume>78</volume><fpage>100506</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.78.100506</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Brueckel, Magnetic structure of EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> determined by single-crystal neutron diffraction</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2009</year><volume>80</volume><fpage>174424</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.80.174424</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>W-L</given-names></name><name><surname>Sefat</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Richard</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Blumberg</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Stress-induced nematicity in Eu Fe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> studied by Raman spectroscopy</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2016</year><volume>94</volume><fpage>014513</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014513</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chu</surname><given-names>J-H</given-names></name><name><surname>Kuo</surname><given-names>H-H</given-names></name><name><surname>Analytis</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name><name><surname>Fisher</surname><given-names>IR</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Divergent nematic susceptibility in an iron arsenide superconductor</article-title><source>Science</source><year>2012</year><volume>337</volume><fpage>710</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.1221713</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 22879513?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22879513</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rotter</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Spin-density-wave anomaly at 140 K in the ternary iron arsenide BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2008</year><volume>78</volume><fpage>020503</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.78.020503</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sefat</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Superconductivity at 22 K in Co-doped BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> crystals</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><year>2008</year><volume>101</volume><fpage>117004</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.101.117004</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 18851319?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18851319</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Saparov</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Sefat</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Annealing effects on the properties of BFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> (B = Ca, Sr, Ba) superconducting parents</article-title><source>Dalton Trans.</source><year>2014</year><volume>43</volume><fpage>14971</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C4DT01068J</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 24901039?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24901039</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Improving superconductivity in BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub>-based crystals by cobalt clustering and electronic uniformity</article-title><source>Sci. Rep.</source><year>2017</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>949</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-00984-1</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 28424488?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28424488</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rotundu</surname><given-names>CR</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Heat capacity study of BaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub>: Effects of annealing</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2010</year><volume>82</volume><fpage>144525</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.82.144525</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mizukami</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Impact of disorder on the superconducting phase diagram in BaFe<sub>2</sub>(As<sub>1&#x02212;<italic>x</italic></sub>P<sub><italic>x</italic></sub>)<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn.</source><year>2017</year><volume>86</volume><fpage>083706</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7566/JPSJ.86.083706</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Prozorov</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Interplay between superconductivity and itinerant magnetism in underdoped Ba<sub>1&#x02212;<italic>x</italic></sub>K<sub><italic>x</italic></sub>Fe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> (<italic>x&#x02009;</italic>=&#x02009;0.2) probed by the response to controlled point-like disorder, Quant</article-title><source>Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>737</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>G-F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Superconductivity in Hole-Doped (Sr<sub>1&#x02212;x</sub>K<sub>x</sub>)Fe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Chin. Phys. Lett.</source><year>2008</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>3403</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/0256-307X/25/9/083</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Saha</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><name><surname>Butch</surname><given-names>NP</given-names></name><name><surname>Kirshenbaum</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Paglione</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Zavalij</surname><given-names>PY</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Superconducting and ferromagnetic phases induced by lattice distortions in stoichiometric SrFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> single crystals</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><year>2009</year><volume>103</volume><fpage>037005</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.103.037005</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 19659311?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19659311</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Saparov</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Complex structures of different CaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> samples</article-title><source>Sci. Rep.</source><year>2014</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>4120</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/srep04120</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 24844399?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24844399</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gofryk</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Fermi-surface reconstruction and complex phase equilibria in CaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><year>2014</year><volume>112</volume><fpage>186401</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.112.186401</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 24856707?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24856707</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Antiferromagnetic transition in EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub>: A possible parent compound for superconductors,</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2008</year><volume>78</volume><fpage>052501</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.78.052501</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Koo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Magnetic and structural phase transitions of EuFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> studied via neutron and resonant X-ray scattering</article-title><source>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn.</source><year>2010</year><volume>79</volume><fpage>114708</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1143/JPSJ.79.114708</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Herrero-Mart&#x000ed;n</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Magnetic structure of EuFe2As2 as determined by resonant x-ray scattering</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2009</year><volume>80</volume><fpage>134411</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.80.134411</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jeevan</surname><given-names>HS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Electrical resistivity and specific heat of single-crystalline EuFe2As2: A magnetic homologue of SrFe2As2</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2008</year><volume>78</volume><fpage>052502</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.78.052502</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zapf</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Persistent detwinning of iron-pnictide EuFe2As2 crystals by small external magnetic fields</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><year>2014</year><volume>113</volume><fpage>227001</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.113.227001</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25494081?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25494081</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Louca</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Llobet</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>J-Q</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Evidence of local disorder in the overdoped regime of Ba(Fe1&#x02009;&#x02212;&#x02009;xCox)2As2</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2011</year><volume>84</volume><fpage>024502</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.84.024502</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Paramanik</surname><given-names>UB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Reentrant superconductivity in Eu(Fe1-xIrx)2As2</article-title><source>J. Phys.: Condes. Matter</source><year>2013</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>265701</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Saparov</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Mitchell</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name><surname>Sefat</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Properties of binary transition-metal arsenides (Tas)</article-title><source>Supercond. Sci. Technol.</source><year>2012</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>084016</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/0953-2048/25/8/084016</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sefat</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Bulk synthesis of iron-based superconductors, Curr. Opin</article-title><source>Solid State &#x00026; Mater. Sci.</source><year>2013</year><volume>17</volume><fpage>59</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.cossms.2013.04.001</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">CrysAlisPro 1.171.39.9g, Data Collection and Processing Software for Agilent X-ray Diffractometers, Rigaku Oxford Diffraction (2017).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sheldrick</surname><given-names>GM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Crystal structure refinement with SHELXL, Acta Cryst</article-title><source>C</source><year>2015</year><volume>71</volume><fpage>3</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schultz</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Integration of neutron time-of-flight single-crystal Bragg peaks in reciprocal space</article-title><source>J. Appl. Crystallogr.</source><year>2014</year><volume>47</volume><fpage>915</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S1600576714006372</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Michels-Clark</surname><given-names>TM</given-names></name><name><surname>Savici</surname><given-names>AT</given-names></name><name><surname>Lynch</surname><given-names>VE</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>XP</given-names></name><name><surname>Hoffmann</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Expanding Lorentz and spectrum corrections to large volumes of reciprocal space for single-crystal time-of-flight neutron diffraction</article-title><source>J. Appl. Crystallogr.</source><year>2016</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>497</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S1600576716001369</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 27047306?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27047306</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Whitfield</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Osborn</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Rosenkranz</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Implementation of cross correlation for energy discrimination on the time-of-flight spectrometer CORELLI</article-title><source>J. Appl. Crystallogr.</source><year>2018</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>315</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S160057671800403X</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 29657565?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29657565</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zou</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Effect of surface morphology and magnetic impurities on the electronic structure in cobalt-doped BaFe2As2 superconductors</article-title><source>Nano Letters</source><year>2017</year><volume>17</volume><fpage>1642</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b04825</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 28140593?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28140593</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blaha, P. <italic>et al</italic>. WIEN2k, An augmented plane wve + local orbitals program for calculating crystal properties (Karlheinz Schwarz, Techn. Universit&#x000e4;t Wien, Austria), ISBN 3-9501031-1-2 (2018).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Moon</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Dual character of magnetism in EuFe2As2: Optical spectroscopic and density-functional calculation study</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2010</year><volume>81</volume><fpage>205114</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.81.205114</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Johannes</surname><given-names>MD</given-names></name><name><surname>Mazin</surname><given-names>II</given-names></name><name><surname>Parker</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of doping and pressure on magnetism and lattice structure of iron-based superconductors</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2010</year><volume>82</volume><fpage>024527</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.82.024527</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pandey</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Parker</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Borderline magnetism: How adding Mg to paramagnetic CeCo3 makes a 450-K ferromagnet with large magnetic anisotropy</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Appl.</source><year>2018</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>034038</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevApplied.10.034038</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gastiasoro</surname><given-names>MN</given-names></name><name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Enhancing superconductivity by disorder</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2018</year><volume>98</volume><fpage>184510</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.98.184510</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ortenzi</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Structural Origin of the Anomalous Temperature Dependence of the Local Magnetic Moments in the CaFe<sub>2</sub>As<sub>2</sub> Family of Materials</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><year>2015</year><volume>114</volume><fpage>047001</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.114.047001</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25679903?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25679903</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name><name><surname>Graser</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirschfeld</surname><given-names>PJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Disorder-Induced Freezing of Dynamical Spin Fluctuation in Underdoped Cuprates</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><year>2010</year><volume>105</volume><fpage>147002</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.105.147002</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 21230861?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21230861</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirschfeld</surname><given-names>PJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Kampf</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name><name><surname>Schmid</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Disorder-Induced Static Antiferromagnetism in Cuprate Superconductors</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><year>2007</year><volume>99</volume><fpage>147002</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.99.147002</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 17930705?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17930705</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Martiny</surname><given-names>JHJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Kreisel</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Theoretical study of impurity-induced magnetism in FeSe</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><year>2019</year><volume>99</volume><fpage>014509</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.99.014509</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Allan</surname><given-names>MP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Identifying the &#x02018;fingerprint&#x02019; of antiferromagnetic spin fluctuations in iron pnictide superconductors</article-title><source>Nat. Phys.</source><year>2015</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>177</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nphys3187</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>