<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par14">In Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>, the amorphous-liquid branch displays a smooth behavior resulting from cooling at various rates. Meanwhile, the crystalline branch shows the two states at 160 K and 229 K between which the warming-up process was performed plus the states resulting from a slow cooling-down from 229 K to 50 K. The insets of Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref> depict the warm-up states with green triangles and the cool-down states in black dots along the crystalline branch evidencing a hysteresis as observed in other alloys
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>
 </sup>. The annealing hysteresis is narrow in eutectic alloys because both metals melt simultaneously. The temperature above which the system did not remain crystalline while warming-up was 230 K. This temperature is lower than 260 K, the experimental melting temperature
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. On the other hand, the passage from liquid to supercooled liquid occurred gradually in the 240 K to 140 K range. Around 130–140 K the upper branch had an inflection point consistent with an arrest in volume changes in configuration space and the system became a long-lived metastable amorphous solid
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>
 </sup>. Properties of the liquid were in good agreement with experimental values, indicating that the SMA potential gives a realistic representation of the liquid alloy. The liquid heat capacity 
 <italic>C</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>p</italic>
 </sub> = 1019 J(kgK)
 <sup>−1</sup> was calculated from a fit to the enthalpy slope between 290–310 K, agreeing well with the experimental value of 977 J(kgK)
 <sup>−1</sup> at 298 K
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>. Additionally, the calculated equilibrium density of the liquid at 350 K was 0.89 g/cm
 <sup>3</sup>, comparing well with the experimental value
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup> of 0.86 g/cm
 <sup>3</sup>. No crystal structure measurements were found in the literature.
</p>
