<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par15">Analysis of the pair correlation function reveals clearly the different structural characteristics of the two types of solids, amorphous and crystalline, as illustrated in Figs 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> and 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>, respectively. The 
 <italic>g</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>K</italic>−
  <italic>K</italic>
 </sub>(
 <italic>r</italic>) and 
 <italic>g</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>Na</italic>−
  <italic>Na</italic>
 </sub>(
 <italic>r</italic>) were calculated with NVT MMC at 110 K and 1002.5 kg/m
 <sup>3</sup> for the crystalline solid and 992.57 kg/m
 <sup>3</sup> for the amorphous solid. A clear difference between these two solids is seen in the 
 <italic>g</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>K</italic>−
  <italic>K</italic>
 </sub>(
 <italic>r</italic>) 2nd through 4rd peaks, where the peaks in the crystalline solid match well with the bcc lattice, while the amorphous solid displays the characteristic structural loss with a double bumped-second peak. The crystal peaks are broadened because the potassium atoms occupy only 70% of the sample volume and the rest is occupied by sodium atoms. The 
 <italic>g</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>Na</italic>−
  <italic>Na</italic>
 </sub>(
 <italic>r</italic>) shows differences between crystal and amorphous, although not as clear as for the K-K pairs. In Figs 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> and 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>, the system snapshots of the two solid systems at 110 K show visually the difference between them. To help the visualization, the snapshots in these figures depict the computational box replicated three times in each Cartesian direction. The crystalline structure in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> shows the periodic array of the atoms and the segregated Na cluster (grey) immersed in the potassium matrix (violet). This Na cluster was shaped as a raft with 3–4 atomic layers of thickness, as desiring to form a lamellar structure with large surface area. By contrast, the solid system depicted in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> was amorphous throughout the occupied volume, had several segregated smaller Na clusters, and a significantly larger number of isolated Na atoms. Snapshots in Figs. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>, 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> were drawn with Ovito
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
