<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Anh‐B might form in places characterized by an enrichment of MgO or a depletion of SiO
 <sub>2</sub>. Yuan et al. (
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0054" ref-type="ref">2018</xref>) suggest that “MgO‐rich compounds might be produced through incongruent melting of both anhydrous and hydrous peridotites” or from the reduction of subducted carbonates. Ganguly and Frost (
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0012" ref-type="ref">2006</xref>) have proposed that an assemblage Anh‐B + stishovite might develop in cold slabs. To evaluate whether the presence of Anh‐B can be detected through a seismic signature, we have calculated its elastic and seismic properties. The elastic properties of Anh‐B can be compared to those of forsterite calculated at the same pressure, 15 GPa (Durinck et al., 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0008" ref-type="ref">2005</xref>). With a bulk modulus 5% larger and a shear modulus 20% larger, Anh‐B appears slightly stiffer than forsterite. Anh‐B is also more isotropic from the elastic point of view. Taking the orientation relationships between Anh‐B and olivine into account, one can compare their elastic constants. In olivine, the three longitudinal moduli are significantly different: C
 <sub>22</sub> is 37% softer than C
 <sub>11</sub> and C
 <sub>33</sub> is 27% softer than C
 <sub>11</sub>. In Anh‐B, C
 <sub>33</sub> (equivalent to C
 <sub>22</sub> in olivine) is only 13% softer than C
 <sub>22</sub> (equivalent to C
 <sub>11</sub> in olivine) and C
 <sub>11</sub> (equivalent to C
 <sub>33</sub> in olivine) is only 8% softer than C
 <sub>22</sub>. For both structures, the off‐diagonal moduli (C
 <sub>12</sub>, C
 <sub>13</sub> and C
 <sub>23</sub>) exhibit very similar values. Concerning the shear moduli, in olivine, C
 <sub>44</sub> is 10% softer than C
 <sub>55</sub> and 15% softer than C
 <sub>66</sub>. In Anh‐B, the situation is comparable, but with an opposite variation since C
 <sub>55</sub> (equivalent to C
 <sub>44</sub> in olivine) is 7% stiffer than C
 <sub>44</sub> and 6% stiffer than C
 <sub>66</sub>. This explains that Anh‐B displays only a moderate seismic anisotropy. Moreover, although it is less anisotropic, the seismic anisotropy pattern of the Anh‐B crystal is similar to the wadsleyite one (Mainprice, 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0029" ref-type="ref">2007</xref>). It seems thus difficult to observe a clear seismic signature of the presence of Anh‐B in MgO‐rich or SiO
 <sub>2</sub>‐depleted regions of the transition zone. If Anh‐B forms from olivine in cold slabs, as proposed by Ganguly and Frost (
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0012" ref-type="ref">2006</xref>), the strongest signal in terms of seismic anisotropy may result from the presence of stishovite, which is one of the most anisotropic phases in the mantle (especially for 
 <italic>S</italic> waves; see Mainprice et al., 
 <xref rid="ggge21980-bib-0030" ref-type="ref">2000</xref>). The volume fraction of stishovite is however expected to be very small and significant crystal preferred orientations would be necessary for it be detected. As discussed above, they could be inherited from those in olivine.
</p>
