<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This highly successful approach has, however, certain drawbacks. One of them is that it yields a cool shade of white light, and it is hard to tune the chromaticity of the emission; the other is that it cannot be employed to obtain transparent photoluminescent displays. The reason is the strong diffuse scattering that occurs inside the color-converting layer, which is a disordered packing of large irregular phosphor crystals (several micrometers of average size). The limitations imposed by this lack of transparency have motivated the search for ways to obtain optical-quality Ce-YAG.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
 </sup> Murai et al. have actually shown that it is possible to synthesize this material in the form of thin films with optical quality. However, the low extinction coefficient at short visible wavelengths hinders the consecution of a balanced white with thin films. Also, a wide variety of matrices have been doped with one or several kinds of RE cations, including glass ceramics, metal organic frameworks, layered hydroxides, and so forth, with the aim of achieving transparency and white emission simultaneously, but low efficiency is achieved in most cases.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> Another approach to prepare transparent phosphor layers is based on the use of RE nanocrystals or nanophosphors. Although transparent, nanophosphor films generally feature low brightness and low quantum yield (QY) because of the small absorption cross section of RE cations and the large surface-to-volume ratio of as-synthesized nanocrystals, which represent the main barriers for practical applications. To improve the emission of these materials, a judicious choice of the inorganic host material along with its crystal structure is central. Indeed, tungstate, molybdate, and vanadate compounds are of special interest in this regard as they enable the excitation of RE cations through energy transfer from the host that is more efficient than the direct excitation, which results in a higher brightness.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>
 </sup> However, a comparative study of the QY of such compounds is still missing.
</p>
