<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">A large interest in the polymers community resides in the synthesis and study of star polymers
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup> or dendrimers
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>, which have highly branched structures and thus endowed with several interesting characteristics such as globular, void-containing, shapes which make them suitable for the delivery of anticancer drugs and imaging agents. As a consequence of the presence of cavities and channels in their interior, the interaction between different dendrimers or star polymers in solution could be modeled by means of soft-core interactions, which do not prevent the overlap between particles. In particular, it may be described by Generalized Exponential Model (GEM) potentials whose properties have been reviewed by Likos
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. Following this, we adopt a coarse-grained model which replaces a suspension of complex polymers with overlapping spherical particles. Remarkably, under equilibrium conditions, these particles may bind together to form clusters and these, in turn, may organize periodically to form cluster crystals
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>. Because of the peculiarities of two-dimensional systems
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>, this would not be a true crystal phase with long-range positional order, but it displays a clear inhomogenous and periodic distribution of particles, much more clustered and ordered than the homogenous state found at high temperature. Such an interesting aggregation phase occurs also in the presence of other soft-core potentials besides the GEM ones, such as the ultra-soft core potentials used for low-temperature bosons
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>
 </sup> and vortices in superconductors
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
