<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">In recent years, the heterojunction composites have been widely studied in photocatalysis and solar cells
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. It is owing to the construction of heterojunction realizing the advantages complementary and synergistic effects of two different materials
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. Inspired by this innovation, the researchers also try to improve the comprehensive performance of electrode materials by building rich heterojunctions inside electrode materials and successfully prepared a series of heterojunction composites for supercapacitors (such as Ni
 <sub>3</sub>S
 <sub>2</sub>/Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>, NiS/Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>, NiCo
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>4</sub>/Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup> and CoS/Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup>), which combine the high ionic conductivity of Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> electrode attributing to its two-dimensional layered crystal structure and the excellent electronic conductivity of nickel sulfide owing to its compact crystal structure and high metallicity of sulfur atoms. These reports provide effective strategies for building novel electrode materials for supercapacitors. However, there arises another puzzle that the specific capacitance of electrode materials in two-electrode system is much lower than that in three-electrode system. This may be due to the fact that high ion and electron conductivity can only be achieved at heterojunctions and β-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> without abundant intercalated anions as steady state Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> exhibits no satisfactory ionic conductivity. Therefore, the preparation of electrode materials with both high utilization rate and excellent stability still needs to be further studied, which is also of great significance. Based on previous research, α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> with abundant intercalated anions between two-dimensional layered crystal structure exhibits much better ionic conductivity than β-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup>. α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> with the similar crystal structure of α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> also exhibits excellent ionic conductivity. Besides, α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> possesses ideal electronic conductivity
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup>. But the anions between layered crystal structures can easily escape, especially in alkaline aqueous environment, which causes the unstable crystal structure of α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> and α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> and the reduction in the interlamellar spacing
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>
 </sup>. Meanwhile, the deformation stress is produced by the change of interlamellar spacing. The construction of α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>/α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> heterojunctions can realize the complementarity of their advantages and further improve the utilization of electrode materials. In addition, their deformation stress may achieve synergistic effect and increase the structural stability of each other. So designing a mild strategy to construct the α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>/α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> heterojunction composite is expected to realize an electrode material with high utilization rate and stable structure.
</p>
