<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Several electron diffraction studies have reported on mullite with high-order satellite reflections (Nakajima &amp; Ribbe, 1981
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb51"> ▸</xref>; Ylä-Jääski &amp; Nissen, 1983
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb89"> ▸</xref>; Wang 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2007
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb82"> ▸</xref>). Structural models were not refined, but Klar 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb39"> ▸</xref>) have shown that different degrees of order exist and that with the same constraint scheme the occupational modulation functions of partially and highly ordered mullite can be described. To date, only refinements of disordered structures based on first-order satellite reflections using modulation functions with first-order harmonics have been published (Birkenstock 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2015
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb11"> ▸</xref>; Klar 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017
 <italic>b</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb38"> ▸</xref>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb39"> ▸</xref>). A superspace model refined against synchrotron single-crystal X-ray diffraction measurements (SA1 in Klar 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb39"> ▸</xref>) was chosen as experimental reference for comparison with the superspace model of M40 AS1 (PBEsol-D) determined with the method presented in Section 3.2
 <xref ref-type="sec" rid="sec3.2"/>. At first glance, the modulation functions from the refinement show a significantly weaker amplitude. This is to be expected as the calculations are based on a maximally ordered model and the refinement is based on a disordered structure with weak low-order satellite reflections. Therefore, the following modifications were applied: from the fitted modulation functions containing up to third-order harmonic terms only first-order harmonic terms were used and higher harmonics were cut off. The refinement modulation functions were amplified by a scale factor 
 <italic>s</italic> determined by minimizing the residual 
 <italic>R</italic> factor defined as
 <disp-formula id="fdu3">
  <graphic xlink:href="a-75-00260-efd3.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" position="float" orientation="portrait" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </disp-formula>
 <italic>x</italic>, 
 <italic>A</italic> and 
 <italic>B</italic> are the variables in 
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="a-75-00260-efi21.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> determined by the least-squares fitting for 
 <italic>x</italic>
 <sub>1</sub> and 
 <italic>x</italic>
 <sub>2</sub> of 
 <italic>T</italic>, O1 and O3, 
 <italic>x</italic>
 <sub>3</sub> of Al1 and O2 and the respective 
 <italic>A</italic> and 
 <italic>B</italic> amplitudes with 
 <italic>n</italic> = 1. Because of symmetry constraints only four coordinates, eight 
 <italic>A</italic> and five 
 <italic>B</italic> values must be determined. The atomic domains of Al3 and O4 were not considered in this procedure due to the low observables-to-parameters ratio and the fact that the four coordinate triplets are concentrated in a limited range in 
 <italic>t</italic> space. The minimum 
 <italic>R</italic> = 0.02 is found if 
 <italic>s</italic> = 4.4. In Fig. 13
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig13"> ▸</xref> the amplified modulation functions are shown together with the embedded coordinates and the calculated modulation functions from the fitting procedure.
</p>
