<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Herein, we discuss some nontypical chemical elements that are used in lead-free perovskites. The Pb atom was substituted by Yb in a simple hot-injection synthesis of CsYbI
 <sub>3</sub> NCs with high crystallinity and high uniform size distribution, reported in work [
 <xref rid="B55-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>]. Briefly, during the growth of nanocrystals, Yb (II) was introduced into the cubic ABX
 <sub>3</sub> perovskite lattice. The synthetic route for formation of the CsYbI
 <sub>3</sub> NCs is similar to that of lead halide perovskites, but with YbI
 <sub>2</sub> used as a metal halide precursor. The synthesized NCs demonstrated strong excitation-independent emission and high PLQY of 58%. In this work [
 <xref rid="B54-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>], a synthesis of all-inorganic Cs
 <sub>3</sub>Cu
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>5</sub> perovskite crystalline film via a spin-coating method was reported. The Cs
 <sub>3</sub>Cu
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>5</sub> thin film was formed from CsI and CuI precursors sequentially added into a mixed solvent of dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) and dimethylformamide (DMF). The perovskite film exhibited pronounced sensitivity to deep UV and UV light illumination with response rise/fall time speeds of 26.2/49.9 ms. Another chemical element that can be used for substitution of lead atom is gold. Two new hybrid organic–inorganic gold perovskite-like halides, (CH
 <sub>3</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>)AuX
 <sub>4</sub>⋅H
 <sub>2</sub>O (X = Br and Cl) were reported in work [
 <xref rid="B50-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>]. Non-stoichiometric 2:1 molar ratio of methylammonium halides (MACl or MABr) and Au (III) halides (AuBr
 <sub>3</sub> or AuCl
 <sub>3</sub>) in water/methanol 0.2 M solution system was used. The open flasks with mixture of precursors were kept at room temperature that allowed the evaporation of the solvent. After evaporation, dark red (CH
 <sub>3</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>)AuBr
 <sub>4</sub>⋅H
 <sub>2</sub>O crystals and yellow (CH
 <sub>3</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>)AuCl
 <sub>4</sub>⋅H
 <sub>2</sub>O crystals were obtained with lateral size up to 5 mm. These hydrated crystals formed in a new type structure featuring perovskite-derived 1D chains and 2D layers based on AuX
 <sub>6</sub> pseudo-octahedral building blocks. At room temperature, both crystals show a weak blue emission, which originates from the electronic transition between Au-6s and Au-5d.
</p>
