<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Bi (III) is another non-toxic candidate element for a solution to the toxicity problem of lead-based perovskite materials. Methylammonium bismuth iodide ((MA)
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>9</sub>) is one of most popular lead-free perovskite materials due to its air stability. Since the chemical composition of such a material is similar to organic–inorganic lead halide perovskites, the synthetic routes of film formation developed for lead-based perovskites, such as two-step deposition method, can be adopted for the Bi-based perovskites resulting in controllable morphology and high surface quality. Thus, in the work [
 <xref rid="B39-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>], the formation of (MA)
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>9</sub> films was demonstrated. Firstly, BiI
 <sub>3</sub> was deposited onto the meso-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> glass substrate followed by the toluene drop-casting and annealing, and secondly, the alcohol solution of MAI was spin coated and heated. For the hole transport layer, spiro-MeOTAD in chlorobenzene was deposited onto the prepared (MA)
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>9</sub> films. However, organic–inorganic perovskite films still contain the surface impurities, as pinholes. Wang’s group in their work [
 <xref rid="B40-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>] used diethyl ether as anti-solvent to improve the characteristics of (MA)
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>9</sub> based films such as compactness and reduce pinhole defects. The (MA)
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>9</sub> films treated by diethyl ether were compact with fewer pinholes and devices based on it exposited long-term air stability with 30% humidity for more than 200 days. The morphology of the perovskite film can also be improved by the post-synthetic treatment as was shown in work [
 <xref rid="B36-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>]. Stable (C
 <sub>6</sub>H
 <sub>5</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>)BiI
 <sub>4</sub> perovskite film was formed by spin coating followed by the gas pump treatment, which resulted in a dense and pinhole-free film with lateral dimension more than 20 cm
 <sup>2</sup>. This material shows good solubility in ethanol and heat stability confirmed by thermogravimetric analysis. Also due to the presence of a hydrophobic organic chain, it was shown that the (C
 <sub>6</sub>H
 <sub>5</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>)BiI
 <sub>4</sub> perovskite can withstand constant exposure of moisture for one year in ambient. Among the organic–inorganic bismuth-based perovskites, a (1,3-propanediammonium)
 <sub>2</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>10</sub>·2H
 <sub>2</sub>O with quantum-well morphology can be highlighted [
 <xref rid="B51-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>]. This material has sandwich structure with the inorganic Bi
 <sub>2</sub>I
 <sub>10</sub>
 <sup>4−</sup> clusters periodically arranged in the crystallographic “c” axis separated by 0.5 nm layers of organic cations. The crystal growth is induced by the slow evaporation of precursors BiI
 <sub>3</sub> and 1,3-propyl diammonium dihydrogen iodide.
</p>
