<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The use of an inorganic cation at the A site of perovskite results in the increased stability and intensity of emission. In the work [
 <xref rid="B38-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>], a synthesis of double-halide single crystal Cs
 <sub>3</sub>BiBr
 <sub>6</sub> perovskite was shown. The distinctive feature of double-halide perovskite materials is an isolated BiBr
 <sub>6</sub> polyhedron in the crystal lattice. Therefore, the ratio between two raw precursors BiBr
 <sub>3</sub> and CsBr plays key role in controlling the formation of the Cs
 <sub>3</sub>BiBr
 <sub>6</sub> single crystals. It was also shown that such Cs
 <sub>3</sub>BiBr
 <sub>6</sub> single crystals with band gap of 2.55 eV possess high thermal stability. To further improve PLQY of Cs
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>Br
 <sub>9</sub> perovskite NCs, a Eu
 <sup>3+</sup>-doping can be used via modified ligand-assisted reprecipitation (LARP) method as was shown in work [
 <xref rid="B53-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>]. The Cs
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>Br
 <sub>9</sub>:Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> NCs demonstrate multicolor emissions: Emission from the NC’ host Cs
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>Br
 <sub>9</sub> matrix and the Eu
 <sup>3+</sup> ion emissive transition. Compared to the Cs
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>Br
 <sub>9</sub> NCs, the Eu
 <sup>3+</sup>-doped NCs show PLQY more than 40% and moisture stability. Alkali metals such as rubidium (Rb) have a good influence on boosting the optical characteristics of perovskites. Thus, in work [
 <xref rid="B37-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>], Rb
 <sub>7</sub>Bi
 <sub>3</sub>Cl
 <sub>16</sub> single crystals with zero-dimensional cluster structure was reported. This structure represents two kinds of octahedra with different distortions. Such NCs were synthesized in a Teflon-lined stainless-steel autoclave, and they emit at 437 nm with a PLQY more than 28%. The moisture-stability of Rb
 <sub>7</sub>Bi
 <sub>3</sub>Cl
 <sub>16</sub> NCs was attributed to increased ratio of Rb atoms and the [BiCl
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>3−</sup> octahedra on the surface, which formed an inorganic protective BiOCl shell.
</p>
