<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Mass transport driven by the temperature gradient is well known in gases and liquids, as fluids can readily undergo mass transport via convection or Soret diffusion
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>
 </sup>. In contrast, in solids, the temperature gradient rarely builds up to a level high enough to drive thermomigration (one of Onsager’s famous off-diagonal linear responses) to cause a rapid shape change
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup>. However, for nanomaterials, thermomigration could become a powerful mechanism for growth or shape change. When the characteristic dimension decreases to the nanoscale, the surface/bulk ratio renders surface diffusion dominant over other diffusion mechanisms. In fact, surface transport is so fast that the material can plastically deform via purely diffusional mechanisms
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>. The characteristic length scale for surface diffusional mechanisms to dominate, 
 <italic>L</italic>
 <sub>s</sub>, is related to the homologous temperature (≡temperature 
 <italic>T</italic>/bulk melting temperature 
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sub>m</sub>) of the material. For example, at room temperature and a typical strain rate like 10
 <sup>−2</sup>/s, 
 <italic>L</italic>
 <sub>s</sub> = ~200 nm for Sn
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>, but ~10 nm for Ag
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. Below 
 <italic>L</italic>
 <sub>s</sub>, surface diffusion-mediated deformation can happen on the timescale of seconds to minutes
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>. Moreover, as the driving force, the temperature gradient in a nanostructure can reach a level much higher than that in the bulk counterpart, because the thermal resistance 
 <italic>R</italic> ∝ 
 <italic>L</italic>/
 <italic>A</italic>, where 
 <italic>L</italic> and 
 <italic>A</italic> are the length and cross-sectional area of a structure, respectively, and this is especially true for one-dimensional structures like nanowires, or nanoligaments
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>. For the reasons above, thermomigration can happen at the nanoscale to quickly reshape a nanostructure. While grain-boundary (GB) diffusion is similar to surface diffusion and often acts cooperatively to accommodate the thermomigration atomic current, by first transporting along and later depositing/stripping into GB as the sink/source
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>, here, we do want to make a distinction between surface and GB diffusions in that the latter process can be significantly more sluggish than the former depending on 
 <italic>T</italic>/
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sub>m</sub> due to the somewhat lower free volume inside GB than the free surface, so much so that the GB process can be the bottleneck when the two processes are coupled. Unlike a free surface, atoms in GB are sandwiched by two solid bodies, and are able to generate significant back stress normal to the GB when there is traffic jam inside GB
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>. This distinction turns out to be important for the thermomigration nanostructure with both free surfaces and GBs.
</p>
