<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="fig01" fig-type="featured" orientation="portrait" position="float">
 <label>Fig. 1.</label>
 <caption>
  <p>(
   <italic>A</italic>) Bromoquine molecule, BrQ, where Br takes the place of chlorine of the original drug chloroquine (see 
   <xref ref-type="sec" rid="s10">
    <italic>BrQ Synthesis and Methods</italic>
   </xref> for synthesis of BrQ). (
   <italic>B</italic>) Soft X-ray projection through parasite 1 along the same beam direction as in X-ray fluorescence maps shown in 
   <italic>D</italic> and 
   <italic>E</italic>. For parasite 1 the parasite membrane and the digestive vacuole (DV) are delineated by green and orange dots, respectively. Clusters of hemozoin (Hz) crystals are denoted by blue arrowheads. (
   <italic>C</italic>) Full segmentation of soft X-ray tomogram of the infected red blood cell (iRBC) labeled “
   <italic>C</italic>” with different compartments rendered in artificial colors. The 2 parasites that share the same red blood cell are colored green and blue and labeled parasite 1 and parasite 2, respectively. (
   <italic>D</italic>) X-ray fluorescence map of Fe in iRBC labeled “
   <italic>C</italic>” containing both parasites. Parasite 1 is delineated in accordance with the delineation in 
   <italic>C</italic>. (
   <italic>E</italic>) X-ray fluorescence map of Br in the same infected red blood cell with parasite 1 delineated in the same way as in 
   <italic>D.</italic> The similarity between the fluorescence maps of Fe and Br clearly demonstrates the affinity of BrQ molecules for attachment to the Hz crystals. The intensity scale factor 
   <italic>I</italic>
   <sub>
    <italic>Fe</italic>
   </sub>/
   <italic>I</italic>
   <sub>
    <italic>Br</italic>
   </sub> ∼ 272 (see main text) with an estimated uncertainty of 15%. The corresponding BrQ coverage is (7 ± 2)%.
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic id="gra1" xlink:href="pnas.1910123116fig01" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
