<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Fredrickson &amp; Fredrickson (2013
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb26"> ▸</xref>) studied the electronic structure of incommensurately modulated Co
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>4</sub>Si
 <sub>2</sub> taking a fivefold supercell and ‘the Al/Si ratios of the mixed sites were rounded to the nearest integer’ to achieve site occupancies that are either 0 or 1. The electronic structure was used to investigate the chemical bonds of the Co atoms. Kilduff &amp; Fredrickson (2016
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb36"> ▸</xref>) observed an incommensurate modulation in CaPd
 <sub>5+
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> compounds and extended the crystal chemical analysis with DFT calculations of a commensurate approximation with composition CaPd
 <sub>5</sub>. In the cases mentioned the simplest possible input structure was used, which is very advantageous with respect to computational cost. Gulec 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2016
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb31"> ▸</xref>) observed satellite reflections indicating an incommensurate modulation in Mo
 <sub>3</sub>Si, but all DFT calculations with up to 30 atoms in the unit cell (
 <italic>Z</italic> = 7 for Mo
 <sub>3.28</sub>Si) were based on randomly generated structure models. Zhao 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2014
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb90"> ▸</xref>) used an adaptive genetic algorithm to find stable crystal structures of ZrCo
 <sub>5+
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>. In one compound a structural modulation is clearly detected and mentioned, but not considered for further structural investigation. Izaola 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2007
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb34"> ▸</xref>) developed a unified superspace model for pyrrhotite (Fe
 <sub>1−
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>S) and compared the refined displacive modulation parameters with geometrically optimized superstructures determined with DFT calculations. Apart from the latter study from 2007, we do not know of any investigation that used the superspace formalism in combination with DFT calculations.
</p>
