<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" xml:lang="EN"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ACS//DTD ACS Journal DTD v1.02 20061031//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName ACSJournal-v102.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.02?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName acs2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">ACS Cent Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">ACS Cent Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">oc</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="coden">acscii</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>ACS Central Science</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">2374-7943</issn><issn pub-type="epub">2374-7951</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6822289</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">31681834</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject>Research Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Building a Consistent and Reproducible Database for Adsorption Evaluation in
Covalent&#x02013;Organic Frameworks</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><surname>Ongari</surname><given-names>Daniele</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath2"><name><surname>Yakutovich</surname><given-names>Aliaksandr V.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">&#x02021;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath3"><name><surname>Talirz</surname><given-names>Leopold</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">&#x02021;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" id="ath4"><name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>Berend</given-names></name><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="other">*</xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>&#x02020;</label>Laboratory of Molecular Simulation (LSMO), Institut
des Sciences et Ing&#x000e9;nierie Chimiques, <institution>&#x000c9;cole Polytechnique
F&#x000e9;d&#x000e9;rale de Lausanne (EPFL)</institution>, Rue de l&#x02019;Industrie 17,
Sion, CH-1951 Valais, <country>Switzerland</country></aff><aff id="aff2"><label>&#x02021;</label>Theory and Simulation of Materials (THEOS),
Facult&#x000e9; des Sciences et Techniques de l&#x02019;Ing&#x000e9;nieur,
<institution>&#x000c9;cole Polytechnique F&#x000e9;d&#x000e9;rale de
Lausanne</institution>, CH-1015 Lausanne, <country>Switzerland</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>E-mail: <email>berend.smit@epfl.ch</email>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>26</day><month>09</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><day>23</day><month>10</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>5</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>1663</fpage><lpage>1675</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>25</day><month>06</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019 American Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2019</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Chemical Society</copyright-holder><license><license-p>This is an open access article published under an ACS AuthorChoice <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/page/policy/authorchoice_termsofuse.html">License</ext-link>, which permits copying and redistribution of the article or any
adaptations for non-commercial purposes.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p content-type="toc-graphic"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0013" id="ab-tgr1"/></p><p>We present a workflow that traces the path from the bulk structure of a crystalline
material to assessing its performance in carbon capture from coal&#x02019;s
postcombustion flue gases. This workflow is applied to a database of 324
covalent&#x02013;organic frameworks (COFs) reported in the literature, to characterize
their CO<sub>2</sub> adsorption properties using the following steps: (1) optimization
of the crystal structure (atomic positions and unit cell) using density functional
theory, (2) fitting atomic point charges based on the electron density, (3)
characterizing the pore geometry of the structures before and after optimization, (4)
computing carbon dioxide and nitrogen isotherms using grand canonical Monte Carlo
simulations with an empirical interaction potential, and finally, (5) assessing the
CO<sub>2</sub> parasitic energy via process modeling. The full workflow has been
encoded in the Automated Interactive Infrastructure and Database for Computational
Science (AiiDA). Both the workflow and the automatically generated provenance graph of
our calculations are made available on the Materials Cloud, allowing peers to inspect
every input parameter and result along the workflow, download structures and files at
intermediate stages, and start their research right from where this work has left off.
In particular, our set of CURATED (Clean, Uniform, and Refined with Automatic Tracking
from Experimental Database) COFs, having optimized geometry and high-quality DFT-derived
point charges, are available for further investigations of gas adsorption properties. We
plan to update the database as new COFs are being reported.</p></abstract><abstract abstract-type="short"><p>An automated
and reproducible computational workflow is
proposed, to systematically optimize the geometry of covalent&#x02212;organic
frameworks and evaluate their performances for carbon capture and
storage.</p></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-old-9</meta-name><meta-value>oc9b00619</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-new-14</meta-name><meta-value>oc9b00619</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>ccc-price</meta-name><meta-value/></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p>Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) are a class of emerging materials composed of covalently
bonded organic residues.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref></sup> While classical covalent crystals like diamond,
graphene, or carbon nitride could also be considered as COFs, this nomenclature highlights
the concept of reticular design, where the precursor molecules, termed
<italic>ligands</italic> or <italic>linkers</italic>, are rationally combined into a
framework structure. The ancestors of COFs are metal organic frameworks (MOFs), where
ligands form coordinate bonds with metal centers. In COFs, however, ligands are directly
connected, forming the topology of the structure.</p><p>The first two-dimensional microporous COFs, named COF-1 and COF-5, were synthesized by
condensation reactions of phenyl diboronic acid in the group of Yaghi.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup>
Two years later, the same group employed a similar condensation reaction to obtain the first
three-dimensional COFs.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref></sup> To date, hundreds of different COFs have been
reported by different research groups.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref></sup> This new class of materials attracted the interest of the scientific
community for applications ranging from gas adsorption<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref></sup> to
catalysis<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref></sup> and photocatalysis,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref></sup> setting the stage
for a possible commercial use in the near future.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref></sup> In addition to the
synthesized COFs, new hypothetical COF structures have been designed <italic>in
silico</italic>(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>) and investigated to highlight possible promising frameworks
that experimental chemists could target in their synthesis. The total number of these
hypothetical structures exceeds 560&#x0202f;000.</p><p>Similarly to MOFs, we see a rapid increase in the number of novel COFs that are being
reported. Often these materials are synthesized with a particular application in mind, and
experimental data are often limited to this application; it is simply not practical to
experimentally test a novel material for all possible applications. For such studies a
computational screening to identify the most promising candidates is often the most
efficient first step. Essential in these computational studies is that all experimental
structures are curated in, what is referred to in the literature as,
&#x0201c;Computation-Ready Experimental&#x0201d; (CoRE) structures,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref></sup> The importance of this curation step
cannot be emphasized enough, and as we will argue in this work, in particular for COFs, the
lack of a systematic approach makes it impossible to reliably compare structures for
different applications.</p><p>The first public database to present the &#x0201c;CoRE&#x0201d; concept is the CoRE-MOF
database, which collects over 5000 structures.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref></sup> This database has been
used by many different groups for a large range of studies. The importance of such a
database is that all structures are reported in a uniform format (e.g., crystallographic
information files, CIFs, with <italic>P</italic>1 symmetry). Indeed, the possibility of
easily accessing and computationally analyzing these frameworks allows the screening of
thousands of different materials, comparison of their performance for specific applications,
and the finding of correlations between geometric properties and performances.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup> An important point is that the CoRE-MOF database not only involves a
conversion to a uniform format but also includes a minimal curation, that mainly involves
the removal of solvent molecules from the pores of the framework. Solvent molecules are
often present in the reported structure of MOFs, and they can be (partially) removed. The
idea of the CoRE-MOF database is to arrive at a solvent-free material which serves as a
reference for computational modeling. The difficulties of simply removing the solvent
molecules from the structure become clear if one realizes that for some MOFs the solvent
molecules are essential; without solvent the framework collapses. Another important issue is
that from the X-ray data one does not have sufficient information on the position of the H
atoms. These are then often added manually or using different software packages, where
different protocols would put them on slightly different positions. In addition, depending
of the quality of the X-ray data there can be uncertainty in the position of the atoms. The
net result of all these small difference is that these screening studies are of limited use
and a potential source of artifacts, due to the lack of uniformity between the investigated
structures.</p><p>Contrary to MOFs, the atomic coordinates of synthesized COFs are not deposited in commonly
available standardized databases. Therefore, it is already difficult to precisely estimate
how many have been reported so far, and an extensive literature review is necessary to
collect these structures: they must be extracted from experimental papers, checked, and
converted into a common format for storing atomic coordinates. Recently, Tong et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> published a collection of 280 structures, which were parsed from the
experimental literature, and that we used as a starting point to build the database of
frameworks of the present study.</p><p>It is interesting to note that only a very small fraction of these COFs have been reported
in the popular Cambridge Structural Database<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref></sup> (CSD). To be accepted into
the CSD, a structure has to be determined directly <italic>from X-ray and neutron
diffraction studies, and from powder studies using a constrained
refinement</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup> This is the case of the recently synthesized
single crystal COF-300, COF-303, LZU-79, and LZU-111.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup> In most of the
cases though, the poor long-range crystallinity makes it impossible to resolve the structure
directly. The fact that from an experimental point of view it is difficult to obtain
sufficiently reliable crystal structures requires experimental groups to increasingly rely
on computational techniques to make a model of the material. These proposed structures are
subsequently validated by comparison with experimental properties, such as NMR and/or the
&#x0201c;DFT pore-size distribution&#x0201d; fitted from gas isotherms.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup>
Part of this work was motivated by the notion that, for these types of computational
structure creations from scratch, there are no standards available. Depending on the
methodology, it is easy to optimize toward different metastable states; different approaches
may use different bond lengths, different positions of hydrogen atoms, etc. In addition,
these computations often involve geometry optimizations which are performed with very
different procedures (e.g., using different <italic>ab initio</italic> density functional
theory methods or empirical force fields) that are often poorly documented. A direct use of
these structures for molecular simulations therefore becomes a source of artifacts; these
seemingly small differences in the way a structure is determined can lead to significant
differences in the prediction of, for example, the thermodynamic properties of these
materials.</p><p>In this work, we make a first step toward a systematic approach, which allows for a
standardization. The challenge we aim to address is to develop a protocol that not only
allows such a standardization (i.e., all materials are optimized identically and using a
reproducible protocol) but also allows for systematic improvements and additions. Our
approach aims to address on one hand the needs of synthetic chemists with limited knowledge
of computational methods, but that would like to use state of the art methods in an
automated protocol to standardize the geometry of their just-synthesized crystal. On the
other hand we provide a tool to the computational community to collectively improve these
optimization protocols.</p><p>In this work, we consider a total of 324 COFs reported experimentally from 2005 to 2018 (we
refer to the Materials Cloud, see the Acknowledgements, for the
references to the original structures), cleaned from solvent molecules, and with no partial
occupations or disorder in the structures. We propose a systematic approach to organize and
store these frameworks in a curated database, to track eventual corrections to the
structures or additions to the database, and to link each entry back to its original source.
The atomic coordinates and the cell dimensions have been optimized using density functional
theory (DFT) to give a coherent geometry to all the frameworks. In addition, we have
analyzed the results from DFT calculations to spot and correct errors in the structure and
to achieve a robust and automated procedure to perform the DFT modeling and the
optimization. DFT-derived partial charges of the structures are computed and provided for
molecular simulations.</p><p>Whereas the optimization of a single structure can be seen as a routine DFT calculation,
the optimization of over 300 hundred structures, including both 2- and 3-dimensional
topologies, is particularly challenging. For a single structure, one can develop a recipe
that is tailor-made and optimized for a given material. For such a large number of
structures, the challenge is to build a workchain that is sufficiently general and robust
such that any COF structure can be optimized. Moreover, given the number of calculations,
one cannot afford to manually check all the outputs and ensure that all the calculations
proceeded correctly. Therefore, it is important for the workchain not only to print out just
the important values that the user needs to monitor but also to automatically act when a
known problem is encountered. Our aim is to shift the attention from the single calculation
to the inner logic of the workchain that, performing multiple calculations and tests, can
chose automatically the most efficient path that leads to the solution (in this case the
optimized geometry), and which can be extended to identify more problems and improve its
robustness.</p><p>The important additional complication is that our workchain requires the interaction of
multiple codes. Here, we show the advantage of employing a supervision tool that can
automatically execute these codes. For this purpose we used the Automated Interactive
Infrastructure and Database for Computational Science (AiiDA),<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref></sup> that
allows the representation of our simulation protocol (the &#x0201c;workchain&#x0201d;) in a
form of python script and its execution in an automated manner. It also gives a common
language for different groups to collaborate in extending and improving the routines we
designed.</p><p>A novel aspect of this work is not only the development of this workchain but also the full
integration between AiiDA and the Materials Cloud. The importance of this integration
becomes clear once groups start using our refined structures. For example, for 5% of the
structures our workflow did not succeed in obtaining a converged structure because of
inconsistencies or errors in the deposited crystal structure. These errors range from
missing hydrogen to incorrect labeling of atoms, wrong cell dimensions, etc. The access to
the Materials Cloud allows any user to inspect all corrections we have made on the original
structure, the outcome of the geometry optimization, and the computed partial charges to be
used for molecular simulations. In addition, the reader can find on the Materials Cloud the
detailed workchain, i.e., the logic and the input/output files for all programs that have
been used to compute and characterize the final structures. These workchains can be
downloaded, allowing any researcher to reproduce our results or extend our calculations
while maintaining their complete providence. We feel that it is important to create a
precedent on the level of transparency and reproducibility that can be obtained.</p><p>The other important point we aim to highlight is the potential for future extensions of the
entries in our COF database: the number of novel COFs that are published each year is still
increasing; novel structures can be added easily, allowing different groups to collectively
contribute to extending the number of structures with uniformly refined geometry.</p><p>Therefore, in this work we go beyond the &#x0201c;CoRE&#x0201d; approach, presenting the
&#x0201c;CURATED&#x0201d; COF database, where the focus is on the full tracking and
reproducibility of the operation that are needed to make the database (possibly) error-free,
consistent, uniform, and easily upgradable.</p><p>Finally, optimizing &#x0003e;300 structures also gives important insights in the state of the
art of COF synthesis and in the applicability of the different programs that were used in
our workchain. To show an example usage of the structure we obtained, with refined geometry
and partial charges, we screened the COFs in our database for their potential application in
capturing carbon dioxide from coal&#x02019;s postcombustion gases.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><title>Building of the Database</title><p>We aim to build a database of COFs structures reported from the literature and with refined
geometry. In the following, we will refer to these structures as <italic>CURATED</italic>
COFs, an acronym that stands for <italic>Clean, Uniform, and Refined with Automatic Tracking
from Experimental Database</italic>. The database includes one set of CURATED COF
structures that contains the original frameworks as reported in the literature, with uniform
orientations of the layers and minor corrections in the case of typos, chemical errors, or
solvent removal (&#x0201c;<italic>CURATED from literature</italic>&#x0201d;, 324 COFs), and
another set containing the structures that succeeded the DFT optimization
(&#x0201c;<italic>CURATED DFT-optimized</italic>&#x0201d;, 308 COFs). The whole design of
the CURATED COFs repository was conceived to easily correct for possible errors and to be
upgraded with more recently reported frameworks.</p><sec id="sec2.1"><title>Structure Labels</title><p>In the CURATED database, covalent organic frameworks are labeled using 7-character
strings (see <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>) that encode information
about their structure (charge state and dimensionality) as well as their provenance
(publication year, article ID, and structure ID).</p><fig id="fig1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Structure labels used throughout this work. The structure ID is a progressive counter
starting from zero and following the order of insertion into the database (not the
chronological order of publication). The charge state of a framework may be neutral
(N) or charged (C, needing floating counterions to balance its charge). The first four
integers are therefore an index for the reference paper, e.g., p0701, where
&#x0201c;p&#x0201d; stands for &#x0201c;paper&#x0201d;. Note that the counting for the IDs
starts form zero.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0001" id="gr1" position="float"/></fig><p>Therefore, simply looking at a structure&#x02019;s label one can realize in one glance
that, for example, COFs 07010N3, 07011N3, 07012N3, and 07013N3 are all 3D, do not contain
charge-balancing counterions, and were published in the same paper of 2007 (p0701).<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref></sup></p></sec><sec id="sec2.2"><title>Data Cleaning</title><p>In this work, we argue that an important requirement of our database is that the source
of the initial structures as well as all the modifications that these structures underwent
during the data cleaning process need to be fully tracked. Modifications are necessary to
ensure a uniform formatting of the structures and to remove errors in the structure that
were detected after a visual inspection or a suspect failure in the DFT optimization.</p><p>Our database contains 324 CURATED structures from the literature. Most of them come from
the previous collection done by Tong et al.; in particular, we focused on the second
version of their CoRE database.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref></sup> In the three versions of their database, Tong et al. collected
187,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref></sup> 280,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> and, only very recently, a third
version of the database containing 309 COF structures.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref></sup> Most of these
structures were manually parsed from the PDF documents in the Supporting Information of
the relative papers, and <italic>some COFs reported without atomic coordinate files are
constructed following the experimental information provided in the corresponding
synthetic studies</italic>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref></sup> As mentioned in the introduction, only
a few of the known COFs are deposited in the CSD database. Despite the care of the authors
in this necessary manual parsing, errors are unavoidable. Indeed, we had to apply ca. 20
corrections to the structures originally provided in the database of Tong et al. As our
parsing was also done manually, and is therefore equally prone to errors, we used the Git
version-control system to permanently keep track of these modifications.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref></sup> Our repository is built from the 280 structures reported in the second
version of Tong et al.&#x02019;s database.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup></p><p>It is important to realize that most of the errors were found by warnings in the
convergence of the DFT optimization and subsequently manually corrected. It was therefore
important to monitor this optimization step and double-check the input structure of
problematic runs. Problems in the initial structure are typically missing hydrogen atoms,
incorrect elements, highly unfavorable protonation states, overlapping atoms (originated
by the parsing of partial occupations), and incorrect unit-cell dimensions.</p><p>To extend the database, we added new structures from the literature research by querying
papers that contain the keywords &#x0201c;covalent&#x02013;organic framework&#x0201d; or
&#x0201c;COF&#x0201d; in the title. For most of the new structures, we had to manually parse
the coordinates and apply a few modifications: solvent removal, manual fix of partial
occupations, unit cell&#x02019;s realignment for 2D COFs, or correction of typos in the
original publication.</p><p>It is instructive to discuss a few examples of this detection and correction of typos. In
three cases the DFT calculation failed, and from visual inspection we observed unphysical
bond lengths. The problem was fixed by keeping the same fractional coordinates for the
atoms and rescaling the unit cell dimension to obtain physical C&#x02013;C bonds in benzene
rings (see COFs 18021N3, 18121N3, and 18122N3).<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref></sup> We see this as an example of a reasonable but ad-hoc fix,
which might be challenged in the future. In another case, a significant change in the unit
cell was found after optimization, and this was caused by a manual error in the parsing
from the SI: the COF with ID 120 in the database of Tong et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> was
incorrectly obtained by mixing the unit cell of HAT-NTBA-COF with the atomic coordinates
of HAT-NTBCA-COF.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref></sup> The mistake has been corrected in the present
database, and the two structures are now reported as 17061N2 and 17060N2,
respectively.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3"><title>Geometry and Cell Optimization</title><p>In this database, 85% of the COFs are layered structures. To have consistent
representation of all these layered COF structures, the unit cells were chosen to contain
two layers for all COFs, and these layers were placed perpendicular to the
<italic>z</italic> axis (c dimension). The stacking of two-dimensional COFs is important
for the evaluation of adsorption properties, and having only one layer would not allow the
geometry to find its energy minimum in a possible AB stacking during the optimization. Out
of 274 2D COFs, 253 single-layer structures were found and expanded assuming perfectly
eclipsed stacking. We would like to emphasize that one also could opt for 3 or more
layers, but this would make the optimization even more CPU-intensive.</p><p>For the DFT optimization, it is important to mention that the unit cells of several
structures in the database have more than 1000 atoms and volumes beyond 100&#x0202f;000
&#x000c5;<sup>3</sup>. Such large volumes and numbers of atoms pose a challenge for
performing density function theory in a high-throughput context, informing our choice for
the DFT code. Therefore, our choice of the CP2K package is motivated by its efficient DFT
implementation, that exploits the mixed Gaussian and plane waves (GPW) method based on
pseudopotentials, and the efficient orbital transformation (OT) method for the
optimization of the wave function. Since the OT method is not suited for structures with a
vanishing DFT gap, in the case of a final band gap smaller than 0.1 eV (a total of only 44
structures) the calculation was flagged, and different settings were used for the
workchain, applying diagonalization and smearing (see the <xref rid="sec5" ref-type="other">Methods</xref>
section for the details).</p><p>For the unit cell and geometry optimization we designed within AiiDA an advanced
workchain that ensures a more robust convergence by performing a
&#x0201c;three-stage&#x0201d; optimization. First, a preliminary cell optimization with a
fixed unit cell angle is run for a maximum of 20 steps. Then, 100 steps of flexible cell
<italic>ab initio</italic> molecular dynamics (AIMD) were performed to give a
&#x0201c;shake&#x0201d; to the structure and escape from metastable states. At the end, a
final cell optimization is performed without constraints on the unit cell&#x02019;s angles.
All the details on the parameters can be found in the reported workchain on the Materials
Cloud and are summarized in the <xref rid="sec5" ref-type="other">Methods</xref> section.</p><p>In the second step, the AIMD stage was found to be particularly necessary for the
optimization of 2-dimensional COFs. We report in the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619/suppl_file/oc9b00619_si_001.pdf">Supporting Information</ext-link> the comparison with a standard direct cell
optimization protocol, where we typically observe that, without the AIMD, the geometries
become stuck in a more symmetric state with higher energy, typically the perfectly
eclipsed AA configuration for 2D COFs.</p><p>In the way we designed and applied this workchain, it can almost be seen as a chemical
sanity check: if a structure does not pass this stage it most likely violates the
collective knowledge of quantum chemistry. This either implies DFT to have some severe
inaccuracies in modeling the crystal or, what we found in most of the cases, chemical
inconsistencies in the initial structure that need to be fixed manually before the
structure can be optimized.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.4"><title>Geometric Properties and Partial Charge Assignment</title><p>To characterize the structures before and after the cell optimization, a number of
geometric descriptors were evaluated, e.g., pore surface, pore volume, largest free
sphere, pore size distribution, etc.</p><p>DFT-derived partial charges (DDEC protocol; DDEC, density-derived electrostatic charge)
are computed for the optimized structures, utilizing the electron density that was already
computed in the previous optimization stage. These partial charges are already a valuable
result of our study as it allows for the modeling of the interactions with polar
adsorbates such as CO<sub>2</sub> or H<sub>2</sub>O.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.5"><title>Adsorption Calculations and Parasitic Energy</title><p>As an illustration of the use of these COFs, we screened the materials for their
performance to separate CO<sub>2</sub> from flue gases in a case study in which these
materials are use to capture carbon from a coal-fired power plant followed by geological
sequestration of the captured CO<sub>2</sub>. In our model, we mimic a
temperature&#x02013;pressure swing process to separate CO<sub>2</sub> from coal
postcombustion flue gases and its compression to 150 bar for underground storage. The aim
is to find the materials that give the lowest parasitic energy. This parasitic energy is
defined as the loss of electricity production caused by separation and compression of 1 kg
of CO<sub>2</sub>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref></sup> To evaluate this energy we need to predict the
pure component isotherms of CO<sub>2</sub> and N<sub>2</sub> in the COFs at 300 K, as
evaluated from grand canonical Monte Carlo (GCMC) simulations.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref30">30</xref></sup> We
have developed an AiiDA workchain to compute the minimal CO<sub>2</sub> parasitic energy
from the optimized structures, provided with DDEC charges. The full workflow is sketched
in <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>.</p><fig id="fig2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Block diagram of the workflow used in this work.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0002" id="gr2" position="float"/></fig></sec></sec><sec id="sec3"><title>Results and Discussion</title><sec id="sec3.1"><title>Analysis of Experimental Structures</title><p>The database of experimental COFs we are considering contains 324 structures, with 310
being neutral and the remaining 14 being charged: in this second case counterions are
necessary to maintain the neutrality of the system, and these charged molecules have been
kept in the pore as reported in the reference paper. The counterions found in these
structures are dimethylammonium, tetrafluoroborate, and single atom ions, e.g.,
Li<sup>+</sup>, NA<sup>+</sup>, F<sup>+</sup>, Cl<sup>+</sup>, Br<sup>+</sup>, and
I<sup>+</sup>. <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref> reports the variety of
elements in these crystals, distinguishing between 2D/3D and neutral/charged frameworks.
One can note that these COFs contain a number of transition metals, e.g., Co, Ni, Cu, and
Zn. However, unlike MOFs, these metals are not part of the connection nodes, but they are
embedded in ligands, typically in porphyrins and phthalocyanines.</p><fig id="fig3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Distribution of elements for the 324 COFs actually present in the database. COFs are
also distinguished into 3D or 2D, and neutral (N) or charged (C, that need floating
counterions).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0003" id="gr3" position="float"/></fig><p>An important point that we need to discuss is the stacking of 2D COFs, i.e., the
arrangement of neighboring layers, sticking together because of noncovalent interactions.
Reviewing the experimental literature about the synthesis and characterization of
COFs,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">31</xref></sup> we found that it is common to consider just two types of stacking: the
eclipsed AA stacking, where the different layers are perfectly superimposed, and the
staggered AB stacking, where there is an alternation of even and odd layers with an offset
in the <italic>xy</italic> plane. <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref> shows
as example these two configuration for COF-1 and COF-5.</p><fig id="fig4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>AA and AB stacking for (a) 05000N2 and (b) 05001N2, as reported in the experimental
reference,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup> are compared. Conventional names are COF-1 and COF-5,
respectively. In that report, the assessment of the presumed stacking was done by
generating for both COFs the AA configuration and reasonable AB configurations, and
comparing the computed XRD with the experimental PXRD.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0004" id="gr4" position="float"/></fig><p>Lukose et al. found that the minimum energy configuration for these COFs has a slightly
tilted stacking.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> Instead of the perfectly aligned AA and AB, COF-1
and COF-5 were found to have its minimum energy when the layers have an offset of ca. 1.4.
This misalignment was shown to be hard to distinguish from the experimental PXDR pattern,
and it is better to rely on computational methods. Recognizing the correct stacking is
indeed a crucial aspect for many applications,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref></sup> and particularly for gas adsorption,
where a shifted or staggered configuration results in a shrinking of the channel diameter,
possibly blocking the channels to the diffusion of gas molecules.</p><p>Analyzing the collected 2D COFs we noted that in only a few cases (21) two layers are
reported in the unit cell, and it is often not clear the method that was used for the
generation of that particular stacking configuration over all possible ones. For the
remaining 253 structures only one layer was reported, assuming AA stacking. Therefore, by
consistently considering two layers in the conventional unit cell for these 2D COFs, we
allow the geometry optimization to explore both the &#x0201c;serrated&#x0201d; configuration
(i.e., where odd layers are slightly shifted) and the &#x0201c;inclined&#x0201d;
configurations (i.e., where there is a constant offset of the layers, resulting in tilted
unit cells). Note that the serrated configuration cannot be obtained when only one layer
is considered.</p></sec><sec id="sec3.2"><title>Cell Optimization</title><p>We performed the cell optimization for the 310 COFs that do not contain counterions in
their pores (i.e., labeled as N, neutral). As we reported in the previous section, most of
the problems in the DFT optimization routine were solved after a careful inspection and
fixing of the initial structures. The problems that could be effectively attributed to the
DFT implementation are related to only two structures: 18081N2 and 18082N2. These two both
have cobalt, and they need electron smearing in the SCF: even testing different input
parameters (e.g, lower mixing alpha, spin state, etc.) did not lead to a successful
optimization. Considering that cobalt&#x02019;s pseudopotential is designed for 17 valence
electrons (the largest number of electrons in the set we used), this is known to be a
challenging element for the SCF diagonalization, and some effort is needed to design a
more effective protocol for this particular element. However, AiiDA allowed the full
tracking of the problem and reporting of the issue to the CP2K developers.</p><p>Given that more than 99% of the structures in the database converged, our three-stage DFT
optimization routine is suitable for high-throughput calculations. For comparison, in a
previous attempt of a systematic DFT-based geometry optimization of 2612 MOFs, only 879
(33.7%) successfully converged.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref></sup> In that case the unit cell dimension
was not optimized, and no check was included for the band gap.</p><p><xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref> shows the evolution of DFT energy over
our three-stage structure optimization workchain for two exemplary structures: 05000N2
(COF-1) and 05001N2 (COF-5).</p><fig id="fig5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Energy profile during the optimization workchain for COFs (a) 05000N2 and (b)
05001N2. Conventional names are COF-1 and COF-5, and the starting configurations of
the layers, as reported,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup> are staggered and eclipsed, respectively.
The three colored regions of the plot correspond to the first cell optimization with
constrained cell angles and 20 steps maximum (red), the NPT AIMD at 400 K/1 bar for 50
fs, i.e., 100 steps, (yellow), and the final cell optimization without constraints
(green). The energy is shifted to assign a 0 value to the minimum.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0005" id="gr5" position="float"/></fig><p>As one can note for the COF 05000N2 structure,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup> we already find the
minimum in the first stage, and there is no apparent need for stages two and three. For
COF 05001N2, however, the MD &#x0201c;shaking&#x0201d; of the structure results in it
finding a more stable minimum that is 13.7 meV/atom more stable. This final optimization
results from a shifting of the perfectly eclipsed layers in the reported structure,
coherently with the work of Lukose et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> In the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619/suppl_file/oc9b00619_si_001.pdf">Supporting Information</ext-link>, we show that, without the intermediate AIMD stage,
the structure becomes stuck in the first minimum, due to the high initial symmetry where
layers are perfectly eclipsed.</p><p>To evaluate for the entire COF database the relative importance of the two cell
optimization stages, we plotted in the histograms of <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref> the difference in energy in the first cell optimization (with
constrained angles) and the further drop in the energy for the final cell optimization,
showing also the contribution of dispersion interactions. This last is intended as the
change in the energy due to the DFT-D3(BJ) terms only.</p><fig id="fig6" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>Comparison of the difference in the energy in the (a) first and (b) third cell
optimization stages. These two stages are also referred in the text as
&#x0201c;preliminary&#x0201d; and &#x0201c;final&#x0201d;, respectively. Differences in
energies (blue) are sorted for the 308 COFs in the histogram, showing also the
relative contribution given by dispersion interactions (orange).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0006" id="gr6" position="float"/></fig><p>We observe that in most cases dispersion interactions play the major role in the final
cell optimization. In the first cell optimization, where the typical changes in energy are
larger by a factor of 10 (cf. the <italic>y</italic> axis scaling in <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>), we mainly observe from the optimization trajectories
a rearrangement of the atomic bonds and an increase of the distance between nonbonded
fragments when this is set too close in the starting geometry. If we further inspect the
statistics of <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>, we can observe that, for
the first cell optimization, in only one case there was an increase in the energy: this is
related to COF 12011N2 and results from a false step of the BFGS minimizer, which did not
have the time to relax back in the limit of 20 steps. For as many as 153 COFs (49.68%) the
cell optimization converged within the first 20 steps (i.e., at the
&#x0201c;preliminary&#x0201d; cell optimization stage), but only 19.61% of these had a
negligible energy drop (&#x0003c;1 meV) in the final cell optimization, meaning that still for
most of the cases the AIMD helped to find a lower minimum. More detailed statistics are
reported in <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref></xref>, distinguishing between two-
and three-dimensional COFs.</p><table-wrap id="tbl1" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>Statistics on the Optimization Process of the 308 COFs that Succeeded DFT
Optimization</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" border="0"><colgroup><col align="left"/><col align="left"/><col align="left"/><col align="left"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th style="border:none;" align="center">&#x000a0;</th><th style="border:none;" align="center">2D&#x000a0;COFs</th><th style="border:none;" align="center">3D&#x000a0;COFs</th><th style="border:none;" align="center">all&#x000a0;COFs</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">number of optimized structures</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">261</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">47</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">308</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">converged in preliminary cell opt.</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">50.96%</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">42.55%</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">49.68%</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">converged, but &#x00394;<italic>E</italic> final cell opt.
&#x0003e;&#x000a0;&#x02212;1.0&#x000a0;meV/atom</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">12.03%</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">70.00%</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">19.61%</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">avg. steps in preliminary cell opt.</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">16.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">16.5</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">16.3</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">avg. steps in final cell opt.</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">150.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">113.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="left">144.7</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>The difference in the structures before and after the geometry and cell optimization can
be appreciated from the change of the geometric properties, as plotted in <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>.</p><fig id="fig7" position="float"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>Parity plots that compare the geometric properties of COFs before and after the
optimization: (a) density, (b) accessible surface area, (c) largest free sphere, (d)
accessible probe occupiable volume, (e) accessible probe occupiable void fraction, and
(f) geometric void fraction. To determine the accessibility of the pore volume and
surface, a spherical probe with radius 1.86 &#x000c5; (i.e., the conventional kinetic
radius of nitrogen) was considered. The &#x0201c;geometric&#x0201d; void fraction is
considered as all of the portion of the pore volume that does not overlap with the
atoms.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref></sup> The colors distinguish between 2-dimensional (blue) and
3-dimensional (red) structures.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0007" id="gr7" position="float"/></fig><p>We can see that in many cases the DFT optimization leads to lower density, corresponding
to a shrinking of the unit cell of the COF. The most evident case is for COF 18120N3
(<xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref></xref>), where the density increases from
0.49 to 1.13 g/cm<sup>3</sup>, with a correspondent decrease of the geometric void
fraction from 0.72 to 0.39. After the optimization, this structure becomes nonporous
(i.e., null N<sub>2</sub>-accessible pore volume and surface). By inspecting the change in
the atomic positions and the unit cell lengths we can notice that the structure shrunk to
reach a more favorable configuration that optimizes the conformation of the ligands and
their van der Waals interactions. For this COF, the measured pore volume from the nitrogen
uptake is 0.36 cm<sup>3</sup>/g,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref></sup> i.e., well below the value computed
from the reported structure (accessible N<sub>2</sub> probe occupiable volume equal to
0.96 cm<sup>3</sup>/g). We can therefore expect that this structure can shrink after
desolvation. For this COF the rigid crystal assumption would not hold to model the
adsorption: the reported structure would lead to artificial results.</p><fig id="fig8" position="float"><label>Figure 8</label><caption><p>Structure of COF 18120N3 before (left) and after (right) the cell optimization.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0008" id="gr8" position="float"/></fig><p>For the two-dimensional COFs, we observe in most of the cases a shift in the layers
(i.e., the &#x0201c;inclined&#x0201d; configuration) that maximizes the noncovalent
interactions. This results in a general reduction of the largest free sphere, as shown in
<xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>. We observe that the energy
stabilization due to this shift is very low. Considering the 133 layered structures where
the geometry converged at the first cell optimization stage, the energy stabilization at
the end of the final cell optimization, i.e., due to the tilting, is on average
&#x02212;13.1 meV/atom. This is a relatively low energy, and one may therefore expect that,
at finite temperature, there is no unique stacking of these materials. While our protocol
successfully identifies a close-by local minimum for both 2D and 3D structures, for 2D
materials, a complete screening of all possible stacking configurations and the averaging
over those accessible at finite temperature need to be further explored.</p></sec><sec id="sec3.3"><title>CO<sub>2</sub> Separation Performances</title><p>The systematically optimized structures with high-quality charges, that have been
obtained for 308 COFs (CURATED DFT-optimized set), allow us to model the interaction with
polar molecules, e.g., considering Coulombic attractions, and evaluate the performance of
these materials for gas adsorption. As an example, we investigate the use of COFs for the
removal of carbon dioxide from coal&#x02019;s postcombustion flue gases.</p><p>To highlight the importance of high-quality input structures (i.e., DFT-optimized and
with DDEC charges) for the evaluation of CO<sub>2</sub> adsorption, we computed also the
empirical Qeq charges for the nonoptimized structures: this is a cheaper protocol that is
usually exploited for high-throughput screenings. In <xref rid="fig9" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig9" ref-type="fig">9</xref></xref>, we compare the CO<sub>2</sub> Henry coefficient and adsorption
energy at infinite dilution (i.e., computed from the Widom insertion method) for the two
protocols, where the absolute change in the void fraction is shown by the color of the
markers. It is striking to see the impact of both the optimization and the use of accurate
partial charges. One can observe at best a weak correlation between the two protocols. The
implication of these results is that using the COF-structures as reported combined with a
simple charge assignment scheme will potentially result in many false positives and
neglecting good-performing materials. This observation is one of the main motivations of
this work and illustrates the need to extend our CURATED approach to other databases. More
details of the contributions that charges and geometry have to the CO<sub>2</sub>
interactions are included in the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619/suppl_file/oc9b00619_si_001.pdf">Supporting Information</ext-link>.</p><fig id="fig9" position="float"><label>Figure 9</label><caption><p>Comparison of the CO<sub>2</sub> Henry coefficient and the adsorption energy at
infinite dilution for nonoptimized COFs with Qeq partial charges and DFT-optimized
COFs with DDEC charges. Dashed lines show the condition of equal values for both axes.
The color of the markers indicates the absolute change of the geometric void fraction
after the optimization. Points that lie close to the axes (i.e., null Henry
Coefficient and adsorption energy) indicate nonpermeable structures, where all the
pores are inaccessible. Blocking spheres have been used in all the calculations to
exclude inaccessible pores, as described in the <xref rid="sec5" ref-type="other">Methods</xref>
section.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0009" id="gr9" position="float"/></fig><p>With our DFT-optimized set of CURATED COFs with DDEC charges, we are now in a position to
evaluate their performance for CO<sub>2</sub> capture and geological storage from a
coal-fired power plant. For consistency, we use the same protocol that our group employed
in previous studies to evaluate different classes of microporous
materials.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref></sup> In
this protocol we assume a pressure&#x02013;temperature swing adsorption process to separate
CO<sub>2</sub> from a CO<sub>2</sub>/N<sub>2</sub> mixture and subsequent compression of
purified CO<sub>2</sub> to 150 bar, the requirement for underground storage. The key
parameter to assess the performance of this process is the minimal parasitic energy, i.e.,
the energy that is required to separate and compress 1 kg of CO<sub>2</sub>. However,
other key parameters are also important for the evaluation: one should aim for high purity
of the final high-CO<sub>2</sub> concentration gas, and high working capacity of the
materials, to achieve the same productivity with less material or with fewer
adsorption/desorption cycles.</p><p>Of all the COFs we considered, 12 COFs are nonporous for CO<sub>2</sub> or N<sub>2</sub>
(according to the atomic radii definition from UFF, i.e., half of the Lennard-Jones sigma)
and need to be excluded from the calculation. In addition, eight structures have
inaccessible pores, which need to be blocked to prevent GCMC from growing particles in
these narrow pockets. In the present study, we assumed that the COFs are rigid and
therefore maintain their stacking upon adsorption. One can envision changes in the
stacking upon adsorption. It would be prohibitively expensive to include framework
flexibility in our screening structures, but it would be important to study these effects
if one further considers top performing structures.</p><p>In <xref rid="fig10" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig10" ref-type="fig">10</xref></xref>, we compared the simulated
CO<sub>2</sub> isotherms for the first seven entries of our CURATED DFT-optimized COF
database (i.e., the oldest synthesized) with experimental data.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref36">36</xref></sup></p><fig id="fig10" position="float"><label>Figure 10</label><caption><p>Comparison of simulated (lines) CO<sub>2</sub> isotherms with experimental ones
(triangles).<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref36">36</xref></sup> The isotherms were obtained at 300 and 298 K,
respectively. Note that the simulated uptake of COF 05000N2 is set to zero because,
from geometric analysis, no accessible volume was found for CO<sub>2</sub> nor
N<sub>2</sub>. The conventional names of these COFs are, in the same order as in the
legend, COF-1, COF-5, COF-10, COF-6, COF-8, COF-102, and COF-103.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0010" id="gr10" position="float"/></fig><p>A notable difference is found for COF 05000N2 (COF-1), which we found to be nonporous
under the rigid framework assumption: the small uptake that was measured is possibly the
consequence of the motion of the layers that creates interstices where the CO<sub>2</sub>
molecule can percolate and occupy the pores. Considering the uptake in the low-pressure
range, we note from the isotherms a systematic overestimation of the
CO<sub>2</sub>&#x02013;framework interactions, that reflects in higher Henry coefficients.
Also, in the 3D COFs 07010N3 and 07011N3 the apparently higher saturation found in
simulations may be related with the imperfect crystallinity of the sample or partial
desolvation. A more detailed comparison is provided in the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619/suppl_file/oc9b00619_si_001.pdf">Supporting Information</ext-link>. Considering that we carry out a high-throughput
approach, we conclude that the agreement with experiments is acceptable.</p><p>To compute the minimal parasitic energy of a material, we need as input the pure
component isotherms and the heats of adsorption for CO<sub>2</sub> and N<sub>2</sub>. The
adsorbing bed is assumed to have a void fraction of 0.3, due to the pelletization and
packing of the crystal. The volumetric working capacity measures the amount of
CO<sub>2</sub> that one cubic meter of bed can evacuate between adsorption and
desorption.</p><p>In <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">11</xref></xref> the minimal parasitic energy is
plotted as a function of the Henry coefficient, the volumetric working capacity, and the
final molar purity. In all three comparisons we see a strong correlation. However, for
materials with low parasitic energy, i.e., below 1 MJ/kg where the process is potentially
more energy efficient than ammine-based technologies, the correlation becomes less
evident. One can, for example, select among the materials with low parasitic energies
(that is an index for operative costs) the ones with higher working capacity, that would
correspond to the need of less adsorbent (and therefore lower capital costs).</p><fig id="fig11" position="float"><label>Figure 11</label><caption><p>For a set of 296 porous and DFT-optimized COFs the CO<sub>2</sub> parasitic energy is
plotted versus the Henry coefficient for CO<sub>2</sub>. The dotted line gives the
comparable parasitic energy of the amine-based capture process. In the lower plots the
parasitic energy is plotted versus the other two main outputs from the process
modeling: the CO<sub>2</sub> working capacity per cubic meter of adsorbent bed and the
final CO<sub>2</sub> molar purity of the mixture.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0011" id="gr11" position="float"/></fig><p>The envelope for the minimum parasitic energy versus the Henry coefficient that one can
draw in <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig11" ref-type="fig">11</xref></xref> can also be compared with the
results obtained for Lin et al. for a database of more than 300&#x0202f;000 hypothetical
zeolites and zeolitic imidazolate frameworks (ZIFs),<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref></sup> and later by
Huck et al., for MOFs and porous polymer networks (PPNs).<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref></sup> In the
present work, the lowest parasitic energies are obtained in the range of the Henry
coefficient between 10<sup>&#x02013;4</sup> and 10<sup>&#x02013;3</sup> mol/(kg Pa). These
results are coherent with the earlier findings on other materials. However, the Henry
coefficient for COFs rarely exceeds 10<sup>&#x02013;4</sup> mol/(kg Pa), and none were
found to exceed 10<sup>&#x02013;3</sup> mol/(kg Pa). Our effort consistently extends the
&#x0201c;materials genome&#x0201d; for carbon capture and sequestration, now including also
COFs. When compared with the best material found in the work of Huck et al.,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref></sup> we observe that the performances of these COFs are still below the best
performer MOF-74, for which we get 0.705 MJ per kg of CO<sub>2</sub>, with a purity of
0.943 and a volumetric working capacity of 64.87 kg of CO<sub>2</sub> per cubic meter of
bed. In total, 14 materials over 60 were indicated by Huck et al. to have a low parasitic
energy for coal flue gas (in the range 0.7&#x02013;0.85 MJ/kg), including 6 cation
exchanged zeolites, 5 MOFs, and 3 porous polymers. However, the consideration that COF
materials contain only light atoms, being potentially cheap, can be an important criterion
of choice, making this class of materials appealing for CO<sub>2</sub> separation.</p><p>Since we used AiiDA for the data-tracing of the full workflow, from the reported
structure to the performances evaluation, we can now easily inspect every intermediate
stage, backtracking the provenance of the final results. We illustrate this for three
COFs: 18041N3 having the lowest parasitic energy (0.819 MJ/kg), 13180N3 having the maximum
working capacity (30.42 kg/m<sup>3</sup>), and the test case 05001N2 (COF-5), which has a
relatively high parasitic energy of 2.681 MJ/kg and therefore is not promising for this
particular application. For these materials we can inspect in one glance (<xref rid="fig12" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig12" ref-type="fig">12</xref></xref>) the energy profile during the
optimization, the changes in the structures, the uptake sampling, and the details of the
process simulation. The reader can access a similar visualization from the Materials
Cloud, in the Discovery section (see Acknowledgments).</p><fig id="fig12" position="float"><label>Figure 12</label><caption><p>Results obtained from the full workflow are sketched for three COFs: 18041N3,
13180N3, and 05001N2. From the left to the right we can find the initial geometry, the
energy profile during the three-stage optimization, the final geometry and its main
geometric properties, the CO<sub>2</sub> and N<sub>2</sub> isotherms and heat of
adsorption, and finally the results from the process modeling. &#x0201c;SA&#x0201d;,
&#x0201c;PV&#x0201d;, and &#x0201c;LFS&#x0201d; labels indicate, respectively, the
nitrogen-accessible surface area, pore volume, and the largest free sphere&#x02019;s
diameter. &#x0201c;PE&#x0201d; and &#x0201c;WC&#x0201d; stand for the minimal parasitic
energy and the CO<sub>2</sub> working capacity in the adsorbent, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_0012" id="gr12" position="float"/></fig><p>It is interesting to compare our results with the original articles, which report the
synthesis details for these COFs. For example, it is important to confirm that the
experimental structure can be desolvated. This is the case for 18041N3<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref37">37</xref></sup> but not for 13180N3,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref38">38</xref></sup> where the COF is reported to lose its
crystallinity and porosity after solvent removal. Therefore, to use this material for gas
adsorption, the fact that our optimization routine converges to a stable structure
suggests that this material can be stable without a solvent; this indicates that it would
be worthwhile to investigate different synthesis protocols that may allow for milder
conditions for the activation and possibly retain the crystallinity of the sample.</p></sec></sec><sec id="sec4"><title>Conclusions</title><p>We presented a systematic way to optimize the structures of covalent&#x02013;organic
frameworks (COFs) using density functional theory. In addition, we have assessed their
performance for CO<sub>2</sub> capture as estimated from classical simulations. The
optimization revealed some substantial changes, mainly in the layers rearrangement of these
materials, and finally provided a set of frameworks that have been obtained from a
consistent and reproducible protocol. The Automated Interactive Infrastructure and Database
for Computational Science (AiiDA) has been used to achieve the result, and this set of 308
CURATED DFT-optimized COFs is made available, with optimized structure and high-quality
partial charges, for further computational investigations. The acronym stands for
<italic>Clean, Uniform, and Refined with Automatic Tracking from Experimental
Database</italic>. We plan to extend our CURATED set of COFs periodically with the most
recently reported frameworks. It can serve as a reference for consulting and for molecular
simulations.</p><p>We show that the computed adsorption isotherms for CO<sub>2</sub> are in fair agreement
with experiments, allowing for a reliable ranking of these materials for carbon capture. The
modular design of our workchain allows for future testing of different force fields and
settings, to improve the overall match of simulation with experiments: we believe that this
will be possible with the parallel effort of building a consistent repository to collect
experimental adsorption measurements.</p><p>We plan to extend the same concept to other classes of materials, e.g., metal organic
frameworks (MOFs) and zeolites, aiming for an extensive database for adsorption properties,
useful not only for comparison but also for training machine learning models that can later
be used to prescreen new materials from quickly computed geometric properties. We will need
to face more complex challenges, e.g., dealing with the DFT modeling of transition metals,
or tuning the standard force fields to better describe the interaction with open metal sites
in MOFs. In this perspective, AiiDA can serve as a common language for the whole scientific
community to collaborate, systematically improving and recombining workchains that need to
model more and more complex systems.</p></sec><sec id="sec5"><title>Methods</title><sec id="sec5.1"><title>DFT Calculations</title><p>DFT calculations were performed using the Perdew&#x02013;Burke&#x02013;Ernzerhof (PBE)
exchange-correlation functional<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref></sup> with DFT-D3(BJ) dispersion
corrections.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref40">40</xref></sup> The Quickstep code of the CP2K package was
used,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref41">41</xref></sup> employing GTH pseudopotentials,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref42">42</xref></sup>
DZVP-MOLOPT-SR contracted Gaussian basis sets, and an auxiliary plane wave basis set. The
plane waves cutoff is set to 600 Ry cutoff, and these are mapped on a 4-level multigrid,
with relative cutoff of 50 Ry and progression factor of 3. The orbital transformation (OT)
method was used, and if a band gap &#x0003c;0.1 eV was found, the calculation was rerun from
scratch using Broyden diagonalization and Thomas&#x02013;Fermi smearing at 300 K.</p><p>For geometry optimization, we considered the atomic positions to be converged once the
maximum force on the atoms dropped below 1.0 millihartree/bohr (as well as a root-mean
squared value below 0.7). The threshold for the pressure is set to 100 bar for the cell
optimization. For the first stage (preliminary cell optimization) the BFGS minimizer is
used. For the second stage (AIMD), an NPT_F<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref43">43</xref></sup> simulation is performed
at 400 K and 1 bar, using the CSVR thermostat<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref44">44</xref></sup> and the barostat from
Martyna et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref45">45</xref></sup> As for the third stage (final cell optimization), the
Limited-memory BFGS (L-BFGS) minimizer is employed. Further details on the choice of the
convergence threshold and minimizer can be found in the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619/suppl_file/oc9b00619_si_001.pdf">Supporting Information</ext-link>.</p><p>The workchain is kept efficient by always restarting the wave functions from the
calculation of the previous stage, and using the Always Correct Predictor-Corrector
(ASPC)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref46">46</xref></sup> to have a more accurate first guess of coefficients of the
wave function at every cell optimization or MD step.</p></sec><sec id="sec5.2"><title>Partial Charges</title><p>Density-derived electrostatic charges (DDECs)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref47">47</xref></sup> are evaluated, using
the software Chargemol,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref48">48</xref></sup> and feeding the electron density of the
optimized structures as computed from CP2K. The version 6 of the protocol, i.e.,
DDEC-6,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref49">49</xref></sup> is used.</p><p>Qeq charges are computed with the same protocol we tested in our previous
work:<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref50">50</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref51">51</xref></sup> the
periodic-Qeq (PQeq) calculator egulp<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref52">52</xref></sup> was used with GMP parameters.
Out of 310 neutral COFs, only one did not converge the Qeq calculation (17131N2).</p></sec><sec id="sec5.3"><title>Geometry-Based Descriptors</title><p>Geometric properties are evaluated using the software Zeo++ (version 0.3).<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref53">53</xref></sup> The software&#x02019;s default definition of the atomic radii was used. The
accessibility of the internal pore volume and surface was assessed using a spherical probe
of 1.86 &#x000c5;, i.e., the conventionally used kinetic radius for nitrogen.</p><p>When computing the probe-occupiable accessible pore volume<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref></sup> and the
blocking spheres<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref54">54</xref></sup> to be used for the molecular simulation, we adopted
a different set of radii, consistently with the force field of the simulation. The
frameworks&#x02019; atomic diameters were set equal to Lennard-Jones sigma in UFF, and we
considered spherical probes with diameters of 3.05 and 3.31 &#x000c5; for CO<sub>2</sub>
(oxygen&#x02019;s sigma in TraPPE) and N<sub>2</sub> (nitrogen&#x02019;s sigma in TraPPE),
respectively.</p></sec><sec id="sec5.4"><title>Parasitic Energy Evaluation</title><p>CO<sub>2</sub> and N<sub>2</sub> isotherms are computed using the Raspa package,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref55">55</xref></sup> at 300 K, within the range 0.001&#x02013;30 bar. The TraPPE force field is
employed to model the gases,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref56">56</xref></sup> and the dispersion interactions with the
framework are computed using Lorentz&#x02013;Berthelot mixing rules, employing the UFF
parametrization<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref57">57</xref></sup> for the atoms of the COFs. The pressure points for
the sampling are selected using a novel protocol that we describe in the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619/suppl_file/oc9b00619_si_001.pdf">Supporting Information</ext-link>. The uptakes are computed from the lowest pressure,
running GCMC for 1000 cycles for initialization and 10&#x0202f;000 for production, and
restarting from the final configuration, for the next pressure calculation. The heat of
adsorption is computed during GCMC using the particle fluctuation method.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref58">58</xref></sup> Blocking spheres are considered, to prevent the insertion of gas molecules
in nonaccessible pores. COFs with null probe-occupiable accessible pore volume are
considered nonporous, and for these materials the isotherms were not computed.</p><p>Finally, we used the in-house code from the work of Huck et al.,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref59">59</xref></sup> to compute the optimal parameters
for the temperature&#x02013;pressure swing process, the parasitic energy, the working
capacity, and the final purity of the CO<sub>2</sub>-rich mixture.</p></sec></sec></body><back><notes id="notes1" notes-type="si"><title>Supporting Information Available</title><p>The Supporting Information is available free of charge on the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org">ACS Publications website</ext-link> at DOI: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619">10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619</ext-link>.<list id="silist" list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Comparison of the cell optimization protocol with other variants,
detailed description of the isotherm sampling protocol, detailed discussion on the
contribution of charges and optimization to the CO<sub>2</sub>&#x02013;framework
interactions, and a detailed comparison of experimental and simulated isotherms
(<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acscentsci.9b00619/suppl_file/oc9b00619_si_001.pdf">PDF</ext-link>)</p></list-item></list></p></notes><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="sifile1"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="oc9b00619_si_001.pdf"><caption><p>oc9b00619_si_001.pdf</p></caption></media></supplementary-material></sec><notes notes-type="COI-statement" id="NOTES-d7e1070-autogenerated"><p>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</p></notes><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>The research in this article was supported by the European Research Council (ERC) under the
European Union&#x02019;s Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme (grant agreement
666983, MaGic) and by the NCCR MARVEL, funded by the Swiss National Science Foundation. L.T.
acknowledges the support of the swissuniversities P-5 "Materials Cloud" project (ID:
182-008). Part of the calculations were enabled by the Swiss National Supercomputing Centre
(CSCS), under project ID s761. The authors are grateful to Prof. J. Hutter for the helpful
discussions, to the CP2K user forum, and to the AiiDA developers team for the support.
Materials Cloud Archive: Additional data are provided free of charge on the Materials Cloud
Archive at <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://archive.materialscloud.org/2019.0034/v1">https://archive.materialscloud.org/2019.0034/v1</uri>, including the AiiDA WorkChains
used in this work; the AiiDA provenance graph; and the CURATED COF structures in CIF format.
The archive record links to a DISCOVER section, where the structures and the main results of
this work can be browsed interactively, as well as to an EXPLORE section with the
interactive provenance browser (<uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.materialscloud.org/discover/curated-cofs">https://www.materialscloud.org/discover/curated-cofs</uri>).</p></ack><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit1"><name><surname>Diercks</surname><given-names>C. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yaghi</surname><given-names>O. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The atom, the molecule, and the covalent organic frame-
work</article-title>. <source>Science</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>355</volume>, <elocation-id>eaal1585</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.aal1585</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28254887</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit2"><name><surname>Cot&#x000e9;</surname><given-names>A. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Benin</surname><given-names>A. I.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ockwig</surname><given-names>N. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>O&#x02019;Keeffe</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Matzger</surname><given-names>A. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yaghi</surname><given-names>O. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Porous, crystalline, covalent organic frameworks</article-title>. <source>Science</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>310</volume>, <fpage>1166</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1170</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.1120411</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16293756</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit3"><name><surname>El-Kaderi</surname><given-names>H. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hunt</surname><given-names>J. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mendoza-Cortes</surname><given-names>J. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cote</surname><given-names>A. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>R. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>O&#x02019;Keeffe</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yaghi</surname><given-names>O. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Designed synthesis of 3D covalent organic frameworks</article-title>. <source>Science</source>
<year>2007</year>, <volume>316</volume>, <fpage>268</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>272</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.1139915</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17431178</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit4"><name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Covalent organic frameworks</article-title>. <source>Chem. Soc. Rev.</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>41</volume>, <fpage>6010</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6022</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c2cs35157a</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22821129</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit5"><name><surname>Lohse</surname><given-names>M. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bein</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Covalent organic frameworks: structures, synthesis, and appli-
cations</article-title>. <source>Adv. Funct. Mater.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>28</volume>, <fpage>1705553</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adfm.201705553</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit6"><name><surname>Olajire</surname><given-names>A. A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Recent advances in the synthesis of covalent organic frameworks for CO2
capture</article-title>. <source>J. CO2 Util.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>17</volume>, <fpage>137</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>161</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jcou.2016.12.003</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit7"><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Diercks</surname><given-names>C. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kornienko</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Nichols</surname><given-names>E. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Paris</surname><given-names>A. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yaghi</surname><given-names>O. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>C. J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Covalent organic frame- works comprising cobalt porphyrins for catalytic
CO2 reduction in water</article-title>. <source>Science</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>349</volume>, <fpage>1208</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1213</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.aac8343</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26292706</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit8"><name><surname>Stegbauer</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Schwinghammer</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lotsch</surname><given-names>B. V.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A hydrazone-based covalent organic framework for photocatalytic hydrogen
production</article-title>. <source>Chem. Sci.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>5</volume>, <fpage>2789</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2793</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C4SC00016A</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit9"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Covalent organic frameworks (COFs): perspectives of
indus-trialization</article-title>. <source>CrystEngComm</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>20</volume>, <fpage>1613</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1634</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C7CE02079A</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit10"><name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>R. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Simon</surname><given-names>C. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>In silico design of porous polymer networks: high-throughput screening for
methane storage materials</article-title>. <source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>136</volume>, <fpage>5006</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5022</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja4123939</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24611543</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit11"><name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>R. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Simon</surname><given-names>C. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Medasani</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Britt</surname><given-names>D. K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>In silico design of three-dimensional porous covalent organic frameworks
via known synthesis routes and commercially available species</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>118</volume>, <fpage>23790</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>23802</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jp507152j</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit12"><name><surname>Mercado</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>R.-S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yakutovich</surname><given-names>A. V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Talirz</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>In silico design of 2D and 3D covalent organic frameworks for methane
storage applications</article-title>. <source>Chem. Mater.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>5069</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5086</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.8b01425</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit13"><name><surname>Lan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tong</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Materials genomics methods for high-throughput construction of COFs and
targeted synthesis</article-title>. <source>Nat. Commun.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>9</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>10</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-018-07720-x</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29317637</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit14"><name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y. G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Camp</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sikora</surname><given-names>B. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bury</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Krungleviciute</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yildirim</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Farha</surname><given-names>O. K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sholl</surname><given-names>D. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Snurr</surname><given-names>R. Q.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Computation-ready, experimental metal-organic frameworks: a tool to enable
high-throughput screening of nanoporous crystals</article-title>. <source>Chem. Mater.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>26</volume>, <fpage>6185</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6192</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cm502594j</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit15"><name><surname>Moghadam</surname><given-names>P. Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wiggin</surname><given-names>S. B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tao</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Maloney</surname><given-names>A. G. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>P. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ward</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fairen-Jimenez</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Development of a Cambridge structural database sub- set: a collection of
metal-organic frameworks for past, present, and future</article-title>. <source>Chem. Mater.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>29</volume>, <fpage>2618</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2625</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.7b00441</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit16"><name><surname>Simon</surname><given-names>C. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gomez-Gualdron</surname><given-names>D. a.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Camp</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y. G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>R. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mercado</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Deem</surname><given-names>M. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gunter</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sholl</surname><given-names>D. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Snurr</surname><given-names>R. Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The materials genome in action: identifying the performance limits for
methane storage</article-title>. <source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>8</volume>, <fpage>1190</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1199</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C4EE03515A</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit17"><name><surname>Tong</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Computation-ready, experimental covalent organic framework for methane
delivery: screening and material design</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>122</volume>, <fpage>13009</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>13016</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.8b04742</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit18"><name><surname>Allen</surname><given-names>F. H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The Cambridge structural database: a quarter of a million crystal
structures and rising</article-title>. <source>Acta Crystallogr., Sect. B: Struct. Sci.</source>
<year>2002</year>, <volume>58</volume>, <fpage>380</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>388</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S0108768102003890</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><mixed-citation publication-type="weblink" id="cit19"><article-title>The Cambridge Crystallographic
Data Centre</article-title>. <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://ccdc.cam.ac.uk/Community/depositastructure/">ccdc.cam.ac.uk/Community/depositastructure/</uri> (accessed April, 2019).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit20"><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kapustin</surname><given-names>E. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>S. X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Niu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L.-H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>W. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yaghi</surname><given-names>O. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Single-crystal x-ray diffraction structures of covalent organic
frameworks</article-title>. <source>Science</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>361</volume>, <fpage>48</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>52</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.aat7679</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29976818</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit21"><name><surname>Pizzi</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cepellotti</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sabatini</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Marzari</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kozinsky</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>AiiDA: automated interactive infrastructure and database for computational
science</article-title>. <source>Comput. Mater. Sci.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>111</volume>, <fpage>218</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>230</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.commatsci.2015.09.013</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref22"><mixed-citation publication-type="weblink" id="cit22"><article-title>GitHub&#x02014;core-cof/CoRE-COF-Database</article-title>. <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://github.com/core-cof/CoRE-COF-Database">github.com/core-cof/CoRE-COF-Database</uri> (accessed November, 2018).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref23"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit23"><name><surname>Tong</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Exploring the structure-property relationships of covalent organic
frameworks for noble gas separations</article-title>. <source>Chem. Eng. Sci.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>168</volume>, <fpage>456</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>464</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ces.2017.05.004</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref24"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit24"><name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tong</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Screening and design of covalent organic framework membranes for CO2/CH4
separation</article-title>. <source>ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng.</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>1220</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.8b04858</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref25"><mixed-citation publication-type="undeclared" id="cit25"><article-title>danieleongari/CURATED-COFs</article-title>. <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3352138">http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3352138</uri>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref26"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit26"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ge</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xing</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A 3D covalent organic framework with exceptionally high iodine capture
capability</article-title>. <source>Chem. - Eur. J.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>24</volume>, <fpage>585</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>589</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/chem.201705405</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29178592</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref27"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit27"><name><surname>Guan</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yusran</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Valtchev</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qiu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Fast, ambient temperature and pressure ionothermal synthesis of
three-dimensional covalent organic frameworks</article-title>. <source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>140</volume>, <fpage>4494</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4498</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jacs.8b01320</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29553727</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref28"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit28"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>S.-q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>R.-r.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhan</surname><given-names>T.-g.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>Q.-y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Construction of 2D covalent organic frameworks by taking advantage of the
variable orientation of imine bonds</article-title>. <source>Chem. Commun.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>53</volume>, <fpage>2431</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2434</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C6CC09906H</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref29"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit29"><name><surname>Huck</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>L.-C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Berger</surname><given-names>A. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shahrak</surname><given-names>M. N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>R. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bhown</surname><given-names>A. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Reuter</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Evaluating different classes of porous materials for carbon
capture</article-title>. <source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>4132</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4146</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C4EE02636E</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref30"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit30"><name><surname>Frenkel</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Understanding molecular simulation: from algorithms to
applications</article-title>. <source>Physics Today</source>
<year>1997</year>, <volume>50</volume>, <fpage>66</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.881812</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref31"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit31"><name><surname>C&#x000f4;t&#x000e9;</surname><given-names>A. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>El-Kaderi</surname><given-names>H. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Furukawa</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hunt</surname><given-names>J. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yaghi</surname><given-names>O. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Reticular synthesis of microporous and mesoporous 2D covalent organic
frameworks</article-title>. <source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source>
<year>2007</year>, <volume>129</volume>, <fpage>12914</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>12915</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja0751781</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17918943</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref32"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit32"><name><surname>Lukose</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kuc</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Heine</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The structure of layered covalent-organic frameworks</article-title>. <source>Chem. - Eur. J.</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>17</volume>, <fpage>2388</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2392</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/chem.201001290</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21259346</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref33"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit33"><name><surname>Nazarian</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Camp</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>Y. G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Snurr</surname><given-names>R. Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sholl</surname><given-names>D. S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Large-scale refinement of metal-organic framework structures using density
Functional Theory</article-title>. <source>Chem. Mater.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>29</volume>, <fpage>2521</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2528</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.6b04226</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref34"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit34"><name><surname>Ongari</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Boyd</surname><given-names>P. G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Barthel</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Witman</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Accurate characterization of the pore volume in microporous crystalline
materials</article-title>. <source>Langmuir</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>33</volume>, <fpage>14529</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>14538</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.7b01682</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28636815</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref35"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit35"><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>L.-C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Berger</surname><given-names>A. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>R. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Swisher</surname><given-names>J. a.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jariwala</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rycroft</surname><given-names>C. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bhown</surname><given-names>A. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Deem</surname><given-names>M. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>In silico screening of carbon-capture materials</article-title>. <source>Nat. Mater.</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>633</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>641</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nmat3336</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22635045</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref36"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit36"><name><surname>Furukawa</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yaghi</surname><given-names>O. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Storage of hydrogen, methane, and carbon dioxide in highly porous covalent
organic frameworks for clean energy applications</article-title>. <source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source>
<year>2009</year>, <volume>131</volume>, <fpage>8875</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>8883</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja9015765</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19496589</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref37"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit37"><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Guan</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yusran</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qiu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Valtchev</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Postsynthetic functionalization of three-dimensional covalent organic
frameworks for selective extraction of lanthanide ions</article-title>. <source>Angew. Chem., Int. Ed.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>57</volume>, <fpage>6042</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6048</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201712246</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref38"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit38"><name><surname>Beaudoin</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Maris</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wuest</surname><given-names>J. D.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Constructing monocrystalline covalent organic networks by
polymerization</article-title>. <source>Nat. Chem.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>5</volume>, <fpage>830</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>834</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nchem.1730</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24056338</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref39"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit39"><name><surname>Perdew</surname><given-names>J. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Burke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ernzerhof</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Generalized gradient approximation made simple</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source>
<year>1996</year>, <volume>77</volume>, <fpage>3865</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3868</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.77.3865</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10062328</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref40"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit40"><name><surname>Grimme</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ehrlich</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Goerigk</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Effect of the damping function in dispersion corrected density functional
theory</article-title>. <source>J. Comput. Chem.</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>32</volume>, <fpage>1456</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1465</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcc.21759</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21370243</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref41"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit41"><name><surname>VandeVondele</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Krack</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mohamed</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Parrinello</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chassaing</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hutter</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Quickstep: fast and accurate density functional calculations using a mixed
Gaussian and plane waves approach</article-title>. <source>Comput. Phys. Commun.</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>167</volume>, <fpage>103</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>128</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.cpc.2004.12.014</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref42"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit42"><name><surname>Goedecker</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Teter</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Separable dual-space Gaussian pseudopotentials</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. B: Condens. Matter Mater. Phys.</source>
<year>1996</year>, <volume>54</volume>, <fpage>1703</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1710</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.54.1703</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref43"><mixed-citation publication-type="weblink" id="cit43"><article-title>CP2K user
manual</article-title>. <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://manual.cp2k.org/cp2k-5_1-branch/CP2K_INPUT/MOTION/MD.html">manual.cp2k.org/cp2k-5_1-branch/CP2K_INPUT/MOTION/MD.html</uri> (accessed April,
2019).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref44"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit44"><name><surname>Bussi</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Donadio</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Parrinello</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Canonical sampling through velocity rescaling</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2007</year>, <volume>126</volume>, <elocation-id>014101</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.2408420</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17212484</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref45"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit45"><name><surname>Martyna</surname><given-names>G. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tobias</surname><given-names>D. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Klein</surname><given-names>M. L.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Constant-pressure molecular-dynamics algorithms</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>1994</year>, <volume>101</volume>, <fpage>4177</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4189</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.467468</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref46"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit46"><name><surname>Kolafa</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Time-reversible always stable predictor-corrector method for molecular
dynamics of polarizable molecules</article-title>. <source>J. Comput. Chem.</source>
<year>2004</year>, <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>335</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>342</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcc.10385</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14696069</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref47"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit47"><name><surname>Manz</surname><given-names>T. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sholl</surname><given-names>D. S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Chemically meaningful atomic charges that reproduce the electrostatic
potential in periodic and nonperiodic materials</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Theory Comput.</source>
<year>2010</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>2455</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2468</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ct100125x</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26613499</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref48"><mixed-citation publication-type="weblink" id="cit48"><article-title>chargemol, release
09_26_2017</article-title>. <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/ddec/">sourceforge.net/projects/ddec/</uri> (accessed August, 2018).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref49"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit49"><name><surname>Manz</surname><given-names>T. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Limas</surname><given-names>N. G.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Introducing DDEC6 atomic population analysis: part 1. charge partitioning
theory and methodology</article-title>. <source>RSC Adv.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>47771</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>47801</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C6RA04656H</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref50"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit50"><name><surname>Rappe</surname><given-names>A. K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Goddard</surname><given-names>W. A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Charge equilibration for molecular dynamics simulations</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem.</source>
<year>1991</year>, <volume>95</volume>, <fpage>3358</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3363</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/j100161a070</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref51"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit51"><name><surname>Ongari</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Boyd</surname><given-names>P. G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kadioglu</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mace</surname><given-names>A. K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Keskin</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smit</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Evaluating charge equilibration methods to generate electrostatic fields in
nanoporous materials</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Theory Comput.</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>15</volume>, <fpage>382</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>401</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jctc.8b00669</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30419163</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref52"><mixed-citation publication-type="undeclared" id="cit52"><article-title>danieleongari/egulp</article-title>. <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3352156">http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3352156</uri>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref53"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit53"><name><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>T. F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rycroft</surname><given-names>C. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kazi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Meza</surname><given-names>J. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Algorithms and tools for high-throughput geometry-based analysis of
crystalline porous materials</article-title>. <source>Microporous Mesoporous Mater.</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>149</volume>, <fpage>134</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>141</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.micromeso.2011.08.020</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref54"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit54"><name><surname>Haranczyk</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sethian</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Automatic structure analysis in high-throughput characterization of porous
materials</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Theory Comput.</source>
<year>2010</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>3472</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3480</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ct100433z</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26617098</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref55"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit55"><name><surname>Dubbeldam</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Calero</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ellis</surname><given-names>D. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Snurr</surname><given-names>R. Q.</given-names></name>
<article-title>RASPA: molecular simulation software for adsorption and diffusion in
flexible nanoporous materials</article-title>. <source>Mol. Simul.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>42</volume>, <fpage>81</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>101</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/08927022.2015.1010082</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref56"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit56"><name><surname>Potoff</surname><given-names>J. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Siepmann</surname><given-names>J. I.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Vapor-liquid equilibria of mixtures containing alkanes, carbon dioxide, and
nitrogen</article-title>. <source>AIChE J.</source>
<year>2001</year>, <volume>47</volume>, <fpage>1676</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1682</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aic.690470719</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref57"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit57"><name><surname>Rappe</surname><given-names>A. K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Casewit</surname><given-names>C. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Colwell</surname><given-names>K. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Goddard</surname><given-names>W. a.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Skiff</surname><given-names>W. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>UFF, a full periodic table force field for molecular mechanics and
molecular dynamics simulations</article-title>. <source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source>
<year>1992</year>, <volume>114</volume>, <fpage>10024</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>10035</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja00051a040</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref58"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit58"><name><surname>Dubbeldam</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Torres-Knoop</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Walton</surname><given-names>K. S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>On the inner workings of monte carlo codes</article-title>. <source>Mol. Simul.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>39</volume>, <fpage>1253</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1292</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/08927022.2013.819102</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref59"><mixed-citation publication-type="weblink" id="cit59"><article-title>danieleongari/calc_pe</article-title>. <uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3352154">http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3352154</uri>.</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>