<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The basic and simplified laser configuration consists of the following elements (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03845-f005">Figure 5</xref>a): (i) An active medium, where the stimulated emission process occurs; (ii) a pump source to produce the population inversion in active media; and (iii) a resonator, which is needed to stimulate the positive feedback mechanism that causes the majority of the atoms to contribute to the coherent output in active medium. The active medium should possess high gain coefficient, which makes possible stimulated emission amplification inside the material (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03845-f005">Figure 5</xref>b). Briefly, the incoming photon from pump source excites the atom in active medium, and then it undergoes radiative relaxation through either spontaneous emission (SE) or stimulated emission of a coherent photon. The latter interacts with the incident photon from pump source which, in turn, causes the creation of doubled number of coherent photons. For the normal population of atoms, the SE prevails over the stimulated emission. To obtain the amplification, a population inversion is needed, which can be achieved by pumping the active medium. For that purpose, different sources are implemented so far. All variety of pump sources can be divided into two classes: Optical and electrical pumping. After excitation by pump, source atoms start to emit the photons in all directions and the photons that propagate along the active medium axis can stimulate other excited atoms to emit coherent photons. The “alignment” of emitted photons is achieved by different configurations of the resonators, for instance: (i) Distributed Bragg reflector (DBR), (ii) Fabry–Perot (F-P), (iii) random scattering (or random lasing, RL), and (iv) whispery gallery mode (WGM). The types of resonator’s geometry are depicted in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03845-f005">Figure 5</xref>c.
</p>
