<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">Recently, Na-birnessite (Na-bir) has attracted plenty of interests due to its unique structure containing crystal water in the Na layer
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. Normally, Na-bir is a layered-structure composed of edge-sharing MnO
 <sub>6</sub> octahedra, where Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> cations act as redox centers. A charge deficit in the slab arises from the presence of Mn
 <sup>3+</sup> cations in the interlayers and/or a manganese vacancy in the octahedral center. This deficit is normally compensated by the presence of interlayer hydrolyzable cations
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. Here, the crystal water in the Na layer differentiates Na-bir from other layered-structure oxides. Dehydration of Na-bir would increase the number of vacancies in the transition metal layers because of the layer-to-interlayer migration of Mn
 <sup>3+</sup> cations, resulting in the formation of triple corner-sharing Mn. The migration of Mn
 <sup>3+</sup> cations into the interlayer also releases the steric strain associated with the Jahn–Teller distortion of the MnO
 <sub>6</sub> octahedra
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. These features stimulated couple of previous studies into the crystallographical and chemical properties of Na-bir, although its pristine structure and structural dynamics during oxidation/reduction remain unclear, especially regarding how those aforementioned features affect or dominate the redox processes and the associated phase transformation. Specifically, by elucidating how the layered structure is rearranged and identifying the cation sites that can be activated during oxidation/reduction, we aim to overcome the performance limitation of layered cathode materials through the reversible transformation between the layered and spinel phases. Hence, in this paper, we investigate how the structural dynamics of Na-bir during charge/discharge are affected by reducing the content of crystal water. The results here show that partial dehydration renders the Na-bir structure flexible, thereby enabling the reversible phase transformation between the layered and spinel-like structure.
</p>
