<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par23">In summary, the α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>/α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> heterojunction nanorods arrays on Ni foam is successfully synthesized by a facile and mild nanotechnology in large-scaled industrialization. The α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>/α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> heterojunction structure with two-dimensional crystal intercalation structure expands the complementary advantages of ion transport and electron transport between the two materials. Meanwhile, the heterojunction material also integrates the fluid-collecting device with high electron transport and utilizes the own advantages of nanomaterials, so that the heterojunction material can achieve a high utilization rate with a capacitance retention rate of 93.4% at 1 A g
 <sup>−1</sup> for single electrode (based two-electrode system and three-electrode system) and long cycle life (the capacitance retention rate is 123.6% at 5 A g
 <sup>−1</sup> for 10000 cycles). In addition, a good rate performance (70.2% of capacitance retention from 1 to 20 A g
 <sup>−1</sup>), a high energy density (72.6 Wh kg
 <sup>−1</sup> at 196.4 W kg
 <sup>−1</sup> and 40.9 Wh kg
 <sup>−1</sup> at 3491.8 W kg
 <sup>−1</sup>) and cycling stability can be came down to the following ways: (1) The complementary advantages between abundant ion supply of α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> and ideal conductance of α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> further enhance ions and electron transport rate. (2) The materials reveal plicate morphology with a large surface and a large intercalated structure from each material, which deepen utilization of active sites. (3) Ni foam as conductive substrates combine the steadily heterojunction structure constructs a continuous conductive frame, which further guarantees the rapid electron transport. (4) The α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> is compactly fixed to the surface of α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>, the mutual deformation stress ensures that the layered structure of the two materials can be stable to each other. The α-Co(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>/α-Ni(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> heterojunction nanorods arrays on Ni foam open up a fascinating prospect for designing supercapacitor with excellent performance using a simple and mild method in larger-scale preparation.
</p>
