<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The recombination of free exciton is the source of narrow emission and small Stokes shift about (001) 2D lead halide perovskites. Stimulated by light, electrons transit from the ground state to the excited state, leaving holes in the ground state, and then the recombination of free exciton releases energy in the form of fluorescence, as shown in 
 <bold>Figure</bold>
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0006" ref-type="fig">
  <bold>6</bold>
 </xref>a.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0106" ref-type="ref">106</xref> The merits of tunable color in the visible range and high PLQY of 2D perovskites are demonstrated. The luminescence with different wavelengths is realized through the regulation of metals (Pb and Sn) and halogens (Cl, Br, I) of L
 <sub>2</sub>[ABX
 <sub>3</sub>]
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>−1</sub>BX
 <sub>4</sub> (
 <italic>n</italic> = 1 and 2) perovskites as depicted in Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0006" ref-type="fig">6</xref>b.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0052" ref-type="ref">52</xref> By replacing bromine with iodine of lead‐based perovskites, the emission peak moves to the direction of lower energy from 3.08 to 2.41 eV for 
 <italic>n</italic> = 1, and from 2.82 to 2.16 eV for 
 <italic>n</italic> = 2. By replacing Pb with Sn, the emission peak shifts to much lower energy of 1.97 (
 <italic>n</italic> = 1) and 1.80 eV (
 <italic>n</italic> = 2). 2D metal halide perovskites (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbX
 <sub>4</sub> with high PLQY and adjusted band edge emission were reported by Dou et al.,[qv: 17c] as demonstrated in Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0006" ref-type="fig">6</xref>c. Zhang's group reported tunable emission of ultrathin monolayer (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbX
 <sub>4</sub> 2D perovskites with halogen substitution.[qv: 15d] It can be seen from Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0006" ref-type="fig">6</xref>d that the emission peak of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> is located at 524.0 nm with a full width at half maximum (FWHM) of 14.7 nm. When the proportion of Br increases, the emission peak gradually shifts to blue, until (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbBr
 <sub>4</sub> forms with a highest PLQY of 46.5% at 409.1 nm and a narrow FWHM of 10.6 nm. Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0006" ref-type="fig">6</xref>e shows the color change of (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbX
 <sub>4</sub> from violet to blue and finally green, under a 365 nm light excitation.
</p>
