<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Today, there is huge interest in the synthesis of new materials used as the basis for the creation of photocatalysts, anode materials for lithium-ion batteries, microelectronic devices, etc. [
 <xref rid="B1-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Among the variety of methods for obtaining new materials, of particular interest are methods that allow obtaining nanostructured materials, the interest in which is due to their structural properties, as well as a large area of active surface [
 <xref rid="B3-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. However, despite the enormous number of research works on methods of obtaining nanostructures, interest in studying their properties, the impact of various factors on the alteration in their structural and dimensional characteristics, as well as the effect of structure and phase composition on the practical application of these nanomaterials has not yet dried up, but only increases every day. The impetus for this is the lack of full information about the behavior of materials and the change in phase composition on a nanoscale [
 <xref rid="B5-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. This fact pushes all new groups of researchers to search for new materials, as well as the study of their structural features and the search for practical applications [
 <xref rid="B9-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>].
</p>
