<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>One of the promising candidates in modern alternative energy as the basis of solid fuel elements are perovskite-like systems based on RFeO
 <sub>3</sub> ferrite (R = Ce, Y, Ba, Sr) [
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. The increased interest in this class of structures is due to their distorted crystal structure with the possibility of filling vacancies with equivalent iron ions [
 <xref rid="B19-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>], which has an essential impact on the structural, optical, magnetic, and dielectric properties [
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B22-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>,
 <xref rid="B23-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]. However, the presence of magnetic domains in the structure of ferrite systems allows using them as magneto optical sensors, catalysts, and devices for long-term data storage [
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B25-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. As is known, nanoscale structures, in contrast to macrostructures, have a large active surface area, higher chemical and corrosion resistance, and unique magnetic and electrical properties, which led to their active use in modern energy and microelectronics [
 <xref rid="B26-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,
 <xref rid="B27-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]. Among the wide variety of oxide perovskites and perovskite-like structures, special attention is paid to ferrites, in which cerium is used as a rare-earth element [
 <xref rid="B28-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>,
 <xref rid="B29-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>,
 <xref rid="B30-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>], due to its crystalline structure and conductive characteristics. As a rule, such structures are obtained by solid-phase synthesis [
 <xref rid="B31-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,
 <xref rid="B32-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>], hydrolysis [
 <xref rid="B33-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,
 <xref rid="B34-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>], mechanochemical treatment, followed by heat treatment [
 <xref rid="B35-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,
 <xref rid="B36-nanomaterials-09-01079" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>], the results of which are micro or macro particles with non-uniform composition. Cerium ferrite is characterized by high corrosion and structural stability, which makes it environmentally safe and suitable for use in almost all branches of solid fuel energy.
</p>
