<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <italic>Fabrication of Perovskite‐Based PD</italic>: The perovskite‐based PD was composed of SnO
 <sub>2</sub>:F (FTO) conductive glass, compact TiO
 <sub>2</sub>, mesoporous TiO
 <sub>2</sub>, MAPbI
 <sub>3</sub> light absorption layer, MAPbI
 <sub>3</sub> crystalline capping layer, hole transport layer (HTL), and gold electrode in sequence. First, FTO conductive glass was cleaned by detergent, followed by ultrasonic wave with acetone and ethanol. Then, a compact TiO
 <sub>2</sub> layer (25 nm in thickness) was coated onto the cleaned FTO substrate by 500 cycles of atomic layer deposition at a temperature of 200 °C (Picosun Sunaler‐100). TiCl
 <sub>4</sub> and N
 <sub>2</sub> were respectively utilized as the Ti source and purging gas. TiO
 <sub>2</sub> paste (Dyesol‐18NRT) was diluted by ethanol with a weight ratio of 2:7 and the mixture was spin‐coated onto the compact TiO
 <sub>2</sub> layer at 5500 rpm. The coated TiO
 <sub>2</sub> layer was sintered at 500 °C for 30 min during which a mesoporous TiO
 <sub>2</sub> layer was formed with a thickness of 300 nm. Pbl
 <sub>2</sub> in 
 <italic>N</italic>,
 <italic>N</italic>‐dimethylformamide solution (462 mg mL
 <sup>−1</sup>) was infiltrated into the mesoporous TiO
 <sub>2</sub> layer by spin coating at 6500 rpm, followed by drying at 70 °C. The dried TiO
 <sub>2</sub> layer was then dipped into an MAPbI
 <sub>3</sub> solution (9 mg mL
 <sup>−1</sup> in 2‐propanol) for 30 s and sintered at 70 °C for 30 min. The concentration of the CH
 <sub>3</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>I in the solution was adjusted to control the crystal size of the MAPbI
 <sub>3</sub> capping layer. The HTL was deposited by spin‐coating at 3000 rpm for 30 s with Spiro‐OMeTAD solution. This solution was obtained by dissolving 73.5 mg Spiro‐OMeTAD powders in 1 mL chlorobenzene with 28.8 µL tBP and 17.5 µL Li‐TFSI in acetonitrile (520 mg L
 <sup>−1</sup>). Lastly, the gold electrode layer was deposited by e‐beam evaporation.
</p>
