<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Single-point diamond turning technology is extensively employed in the advanced manufacturing process, such as the fabrication of optics components and the critical parts in the aerospace technology and clean energy [
 <xref rid="B1-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. This technology employs the ultra-sharp diamond tool mounted on the ultra-precision lathe, which is capable of achieving the nanometric surface finish and sub-micron form accuracy at the mean time [
 <xref rid="B5-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. The fluid film bearings and high-accurate numerical controller are applied on the lathes to control the relative movements between the diamond tool and the workpiece [
 <xref rid="B9-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Furthermore, the ambient temperature and the surrounding environment have been strictly controlled to acquire the fine surface finish [
 <xref rid="B12-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. The above controlling process technologies are applied since they can all affect the final surface topography of the diamond turned components, i.e., the surface topography is the comprehensive result of the above influencing factors. Meanwhile, surface topography also has a direct impact on the functional performance, like the optical functions [
 <xref rid="B14-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. Therefore, it is of great significance to establish an accurate surface topography model for the diamond turned components. 
</p>
