<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>While total scattering is not the primary mission of this instrument, the shortest usable wavelengths provide quality data for PDF analysis. The extended 
 <italic>Q</italic> range (in particular, the range of the 0.8 Å center wavelength setting) and increased measurement counts offered by POWGEN’s instrument upgrade have expanded opportunities for studies of disordered crystalline materials. Fig. 10
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig10"> ▸</xref> displays POWGEN PDF data collected for a 6.4 g sample of BaTiO
 <sub>3</sub> for 2.5 h at room temperature with a 0.8 Å center wavelength and high-intensity guide setting. Data were transformed into real space using a 
 <italic>Q</italic>
 <sub>min</sub> of 1 Å
 <sup>−1</sup> and a 
 <italic>Q</italic>
 <sub>max</sub> of 32 Å
 <sup>−1</sup>. This canonical ferroelectric material is well known at room temperature to possess local ordering that is rhombohedral in nature, while the long-range PDF and average structures are consistent with tetragonal symmetry (Senn 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2016
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb35"> ▸</xref>; Page 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2010
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb30"> ▸</xref>; Neilson &amp; McQueen, 2015
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb26"> ▸</xref>). The data have been fitted in the least-squares-based refinement program 
 <italic>PDFgui</italic> (Farrow 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2007
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb14"> ▸</xref>) over 1–100 Å in real space. The quality of refinement matches or exceeds that available at other modern neutron total scattering beamlines. Factors influencing the quality of neutron TOF PDF data were recently reviewed (Olds 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb29"> ▸</xref>). POWGEN’s overall high resolution results in observable intensities exceeding 200 Å
 <sup>−1</sup> in real space, while the influence of its near linear Δ
 <italic>d</italic>/
 <italic>d</italic> (equivalent to Δ
 <italic>Q</italic>/
 <italic>Q</italic>) resolution behavior displayed in Fig. 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>, as a function of 
 <italic>d</italic> spacing, is modeled straightforwardly with a Gaussian damping envelope available in the fitting software.
</p>
