<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <p>The focus of this paper is centered on the thermal reduction of KMnO
  <sub>4</sub> at controlled temperatures of 400 and 800 °C. The materials under study were characterized by atomic absorption spectroscopy, thermogravimetric analysis, average oxidation state of manganese, nitrogen adsorption–desorption, and impedance spectroscopy. The structural formulas, found as a result of these analyses, were 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm1">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <msubsup>
       <mi>K</mi>
       <mrow>
        <mn>0.29</mn>
       </mrow>
       <mo>+</mo>
      </msubsup>
      <mrow>
       <mo>(</mo>
       <mrow>
        <mi>M</mi>
        <msubsup>
         <mi>n</mi>
         <mrow>
          <mn>0.84</mn>
         </mrow>
         <mrow>
          <mn>4</mn>
          <mo>+</mo>
         </mrow>
        </msubsup>
        <mi>M</mi>
        <msubsup>
         <mi>n</mi>
         <mrow>
          <mn>0.16</mn>
         </mrow>
         <mrow>
          <mn>3</mn>
          <mo>+</mo>
         </mrow>
        </msubsup>
       </mrow>
       <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
      <msub>
       <mi>O</mi>
       <mrow>
        <mn>2.07</mn>
       </mrow>
      </msub>
      <mo>·</mo>
      <mn>0.61</mn>
      <msub>
       <mi>H</mi>
       <mn>2</mn>
      </msub>
      <mi>O</mi>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula> and 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm2">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <msubsup>
       <mi>K</mi>
       <mrow>
        <mn>0.48</mn>
       </mrow>
       <mo>+</mo>
      </msubsup>
      <mrow>
       <mo>(</mo>
       <mrow>
        <mi>M</mi>
        <msubsup>
         <mi>n</mi>
         <mrow>
          <mn>0.64</mn>
         </mrow>
         <mrow>
          <mn>4</mn>
          <mo>+</mo>
         </mrow>
        </msubsup>
        <mi>M</mi>
        <msubsup>
         <mi>n</mi>
         <mrow>
          <mn>0.36</mn>
         </mrow>
         <mrow>
          <mn>3</mn>
          <mo>+</mo>
         </mrow>
        </msubsup>
       </mrow>
       <mo>)</mo>
      </mrow>
      <msub>
       <mi>O</mi>
       <mrow>
        <mn>2.06</mn>
       </mrow>
      </msub>
      <mo>·</mo>
      <mn>0.50</mn>
      <msub>
       <mi>H</mi>
       <mn>2</mn>
      </msub>
      <mi>O</mi>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula>. The N
  <sub>2</sub> adsorption–desorption isotherms show the microporous and mesoporous nature of the structure. Structural analysis showed that synthesis temperature affects the crystal size and symmetry, varying their electrical properties. Impedance spectroscopy (IS) was used to measure the electrical properties of these materials. The measurements attained, as a result of IS, show that these materials have both electronic and ionic conductivity. The conductivity values obtained at 10 Hz were 4.1250 × 10
  <sup>−6</sup> and 1.6870 × 10
  <sup>−4</sup> Ω
  <sup>−1</sup>cm
  <sup>−1</sup> for Mn4 at 298 and 423 K respectively. For Mn8, the conductivity values at this frequency were 3.7074 × 10
  <sup>−7</sup> (298) and 3.9866 × 10
  <sup>−5</sup> Ω
  <sup>−1</sup>cm
  <sup>−1</sup> (423 K). The electrical behavior was associated with electron hopping at high frequencies, and protonic conduction and ionic movement of the K
  <sup>+</sup> species, in the interlayer region at low frequencies.
 </p>
</abstract>
