<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">SrTiO
 <sub>3</sub> (STO) is the workhorse oxide semiconductors. Since the discovery of the high-mobility electron gas (EG) at the LaAlO
 <sub>3</sub>/STO heterointerface
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup>, much effort has been undertaken to explore and understand the emergent phenomena at this heterointerface
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>
 </sup>. Many intriguing properties that are not present in conventional semiconductor heterostructures, such as interface magnetism
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>, interface superconductivity
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>, and even the coexistence of magnetism and superconductivity at the interface
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>, have been observed. Applications in field-effect transistors (FETs)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup> and integrated circuit devices
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup> have also been demonstrated. One most remarkable result in previous studies is that the EG can only be formed on TiO
 <sub>2</sub>-terminated STO (T-STO), and the heterointerface with SrO-terminated STO (S-STO) is highly insulating
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. This extreme asymmetry originates from the polar arrangement of atomic layers in LaAlO
 <sub>3</sub>, and can be understood in an elegant polar discontinuity and electronic reconstruction picture
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. Inspired by this EG, more EGs have been formed between STO and a few different polar oxides
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. Following a similar idea, very recently a hole gas was achieved in a sandwiched STO/LaAlO
 <sub>3</sub>/STO heterostructure
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>. In fact, nowadays interface engineering with polar oxides has become a very popular designing concept in controlling strongly correlated electrons in transition metal oxides.
</p>
