<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <p>The crystal structure of 1-(pyren-1-yl)but-2-yn-1-one (
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm1">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mn mathvariant="bold">1</mn>
      <mi mathvariant="bold">a</mi>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula>, a polynuclear aromatic hydrocarbon displaying enhanced luminescence in the solid state, has been re-determined at several pressures ranging from atmospheric up to 3 GPa using a Diamond Anvil Cell (DAC). These experiments were augmented by periodic DFT calculations at pressures up to 4.4 GPa. UV-Vis fluorescence of 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm2">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mn mathvariant="bold">1</mn>
      <mi mathvariant="bold">a</mi>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula> at non-ambient pressures has also been investigated. The crystal structure consists of infinite 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm3">
    <mrow>
     <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">π</mi>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula>-stacks of anti-parallel 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm4">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mn mathvariant="bold">1</mn>
      <mi mathvariant="bold">a</mi>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula> molecules with discernible dimers, which may exemplify aggregates formed by pyrene derivatives in solution and thin films, and is predominantly stabilized by dispersion. The average inter-planar distance between individual molecules within 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm5">
    <mrow>
     <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">π</mi>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula>-stacks decreases with pressure in the investigated range. This results in piezochromic properties of 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm6">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mn mathvariant="bold">1</mn>
      <mi mathvariant="bold">a</mi>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula>: a red-shift of sample color, as well as a bathochromic shift of fluorescence with pressure (by ca. 100 nm at 3.5 GPa). Two-component fluorescence spectra support the hypothesis that at least two types of excimers are involved in the electronic excitation processes in crystalline 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm7">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mn mathvariant="bold">1</mn>
      <mi mathvariant="bold">a</mi>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula>.
 </p>
</abstract>
