<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.1 20151215//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.1?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">J Appl Crystallogr</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">J Appl Crystallogr</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">J. Appl. Cryst.</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Journal of Applied Crystallography</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0021-8898</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1600-5767</issn><publisher><publisher-name>International Union of Crystallography</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6782082</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">pd5109</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S1600576719011725</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="coden">JACGAR</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pii">S1600576719011725</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research Papers</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>The site-symmetry induced representations of layer groups on the Bilbao Crystallographic Server</article-title><alt-title>Site-symmetry induced representations</alt-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>de la Flor</surname><given-names>Gemma</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="a">a</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="b">b</xref><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor">*</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Orobengoa</surname><given-names>Danel</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="b">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Evarestov</surname><given-names>Robert A.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="c">c</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Kitaev</surname><given-names>Yuri E.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="d">d</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Tasci</surname><given-names>Emre</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="e">e</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Aroyo</surname><given-names>Mois I.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="b">b</xref></contrib><aff id="a">
<label>a</label>Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Institute of Applied Geosciences, Karlsruhe, <country>Germany</country>
</aff><aff id="b">
<label>b</label>Departamento de F&#x000ed;sica de la Materia Condensada, Facultad de Ciencia y Tecnolog&#x000ed;a, Universidad del Pa&#x000ed;s Vasco (UPV/EHU), Bilbao, <country>Spain</country>
</aff><aff id="c">
<label>c</label>Institute of Chemistry, Saint Petersburg State University, Saint Petersburg, <country>Russian Federation</country>
</aff><aff id="d">
<label>d</label>Ioffe Institute, Saint Petersburg, <country>Russian Federation</country>
</aff><aff id="e">
<label>e</label>Department of Physics Engineering, Hacettepe University, Ankara, <country>Turkey</country>
</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor">Correspondence e-mail: <email>gemma.delaflor@kit.edu</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>01</day><month>10</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>04</day><month>10</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>04</day><month>10</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><!-- PMC Release delay is 0 months and 0 days and was based on the <pub-date pub-type="epub"/>. --><volume>52</volume><issue>Pt 5</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">j190500</issue-id><fpage>1214</fpage><lpage>1221</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>11</day><month>3</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>24</day><month>8</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; Gemma de la Flor et al. 2019</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2019</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution (CC-BY) Licence, which permits unrestricted
use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original authors and source are cited.</license-p><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref></license></permissions><self-uri xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1107/S1600576719011725">A full version of this article is available from Crystallography Journals Online.</self-uri><abstract abstract-type="toc"><p>The program <italic>LSITESYM</italic> of the Bilbao Crystallographic Server (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.cryst.ehu.es">http://www.cryst.ehu.es</ext-link>), which establishes symmetry relations between localized and extended states in crystals with layer symmetry, is presented. The utility of the program is discussed and illustrated with several examples.</p></abstract><abstract><p>The section of the Bilbao Crystallographic Server (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.cryst.ehu.es">http://www.cryst.ehu.es</ext-link>) dedicated to subperiodic groups includes a new tool called <italic>LSITESYM</italic> for the study of materials with layer and multilayer symmetry. This new program, based on the site-symmetry approach, establishes the symmetry relations between localized and extended crystal states using representations of layer groups. The efficiency and utility of the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic> is demonstrated by illustrative examples, which include the analysis of phonon symmetry in Aurivillius compounds and in van der Waals layered crystals MoS<sub>2</sub> and WS<sub>2</sub>.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>site-symmetry method</kwd><kwd><italic>LSITESYM</italic></kwd><kwd>Bilbao Crystallographic Server</kwd><kwd>layer groups</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source>Basque Government post-doctoral fellowship</funding-source><award-id>POS_2015_1_0025</award-id></award-group><award-group><funding-source>Ministerio de Ciencia y Tecnolog&#x000ed;a</funding-source><award-id>MAT2012-34740</award-id></award-group><award-group><funding-source>The Government of the Basque Country</funding-source><award-id>IT779-13</award-id></award-group><funding-statement>This work was funded by <funding-source>Basque Government post-doctoral fellowship</funding-source> grant <award-id>POS_2015_1_0025</award-id>. <funding-source>Ministerio de Ciencia y Tecnolog&#x000ed;a</funding-source> grant <award-id>MAT2012-34740</award-id>. <funding-source>The Government of the Basque Country</funding-source> grant <award-id>IT779-13</award-id>. </funding-statement></funding-group><counts><page-count count="8"/></counts></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="introduction" id="sec1"><label>1.</label><title>Introduction &#x000a0; </title><p>The interest in layered and multilayered materials such as graphene (Geim &#x00026; Novoselov, 2007<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb15"> &#x025b8;</xref>; Randviir <italic>et al.</italic>, 2014<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb30"> &#x025b8;</xref>) and van der Waals crystals, <italic>e.g.</italic> the transition metal dichalcogenide crystal family Me<italic>X</italic>
<sub>2</sub> with Me = Nb, Mo, Ta, W, Ti, V, Zr, Hf and <italic>X</italic> = S, Se, Te (Han <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb17"> &#x025b8;</xref>; Manzeli <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb26"> &#x025b8;</xref>; Choi <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb6"> &#x025b8;</xref>), is constantly growing owing to their interesting properties and possible technological applications. The symmetry of single monolayers can be described by the &#x02018;diperiodic&#x02019; or &#x02018;layer groups&#x02019; (Kopsk&#x000fd; &#x00026; Litvin, 2010<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb23"> &#x025b8;</xref>), which are three-dimensional crystallographic groups with two-dimensional translations. There are 80 layer groups which, together with the seven frieze groups (two-dimensional groups with one-dimensional translations) and the 75 rod groups (three-dimensional groups with one-dimensional translations), constitute the &#x02018;subperiodic groups&#x02019;. The crystallographic data for subperiodic groups are compiled in <italic>International Tables for Crystallography</italic>, Volume E, <italic>Sub&#x000ad;periodic Groups</italic> (hereafter referred to as <italic>ITE</italic>) and also offered online by the Bilbao Crystallographic Server (Aroyo <italic>et al.</italic>, 2011<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb3"> &#x025b8;</xref>; Tasci <italic>et al.</italic>, 2012<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb34"> &#x025b8;</xref>) (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.cryst.ehu.es">http://www.cryst.ehu.es</ext-link>).</p><p>While space groups and their representations describe the symmetry of the bulk electron and phonon states, the layer groups are essential for the description of the electronic structure and the surface states of crystals. Depending on the interaction between the layer and the bulk, materials with layer symmetry can be classified into five different types: (i) pure layered systems like free-standing films, with graphene monolayers as a notable example of such films; (ii) single layers in layered crystals which, owing to a weak van der Waals interlayer interaction, can be separated from the bulk; (iii) artificial nanolayers grown on substrates or between two bulk materials where the interaction between the nanolayer and surrounding bulk materials is neglected; (iv) layers (or slabs) which model atomically clean crystal surfaces where the slab interaction with the rest of the semi-infinite crystal is neglected; (v) interfaces between different crystals, including domain walls approximated by atomically clean crystal surfaces.</p><p>The site-symmetry approach (Evarestov &#x00026; Smirnov, 1987<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb9"> &#x025b8;</xref>, 1993<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb10"> &#x025b8;</xref>; Hatch <italic>et al.</italic>, 1988<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb16"> &#x025b8;</xref>; Stokes <italic>et al.</italic>, 1991<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb33"> &#x025b8;</xref>; Kovalev, 1993<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb21"> &#x025b8;</xref>) is a powerful method which connects the local properties of atoms in crystals with the symmetry of states of the whole crystalline system, <italic>i.e.</italic> it establishes the symmetry relationships between the localized states in the crystal (vibrations of atoms and atomic orbitals) and crystal extended (phonon and electron) states over the entire Brillouin zone. The site-symmetry method is based on the procedure of induction of representations of the crystal space group from the irreducible representations (irreps) of the site-symmetry groups of the constituent units (atoms, clusters and layers) according to which the local excitations are transformed. In this way, the symmetry of phonon, electron, exciton, biexciton <italic>etc.</italic> states can be described by the crystal single- and double-valued representations induced by the irreps of the site-symmetry group. Tables of induced representations were deduced by Evarestov &#x00026; Smirnov (1987<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb9"> &#x025b8;</xref>, 1993<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb10"> &#x025b8;</xref>), Hatch <italic>et al.</italic> (1988<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb16"> &#x025b8;</xref>), Stokes <italic>et al.</italic> (1991<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb33"> &#x025b8;</xref>) and Kovalev (1993<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb21"> &#x025b8;</xref>), and later the programs <italic>SITESYM</italic> and <italic>DSITESYM</italic> (Elcoro <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb8"> &#x025b8;</xref>) available on the Bilbao Crystallographic Server were developed to calculate the site-symmetry induced representations of space and double groups, respectively.</p><p>Even though layer groups were described for the first time about a century ago (Weber, 1929<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb37"> &#x025b8;</xref>; Alexander &#x00026; Hermann, 1929<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb1"> &#x025b8;</xref>), it was not until the paper by Zallen <italic>et al.</italic> (1971<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb39"> &#x025b8;</xref>) that they were applied for the first time for the description of phonon states in layered As<sub>2</sub>S<sub>3</sub> and As<sub>2</sub>Se<sub>3</sub> crystals. Afterwards, they were also used for modelling atomically clean crystal surfaces (Ipatova &#x00026; Kitaev, 1985<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb18"> &#x025b8;</xref>). However, these studies did not involve the use of induced representations of layer groups. To the best of our knowledge, the first use of induced representations of layer groups was related to the study of the phonon symmetry of high-temperature superconductors (Evarestov <italic>et al.</italic>, 1993<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb11"> &#x025b8;</xref>; Kitaev <italic>et al.</italic>, 1994<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb19"> &#x025b8;</xref>) and thereafter to describe the phonon, electron, exciton and biexciton states in artificially grown nanolayers (semiconductor quantum wells) (Tronc &#x00026; Kitaev, 2001<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb35"> &#x025b8;</xref>) and layered crystals (Kitaev <italic>et al.</italic>, 2007<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb20"> &#x025b8;</xref>). Quite recently, induced representations of layer groups have been applied in the analysis of the Brillouin-zone centre phonons in layered MoS<sub>2</sub> and WS<sub>2</sub> crystals (Evarestov <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb13"> &#x025b8;</xref>, 2018<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb14"> &#x025b8;</xref>).</p><p>Note that the induced representations of layer groups, in general, could be extracted by the existing tools of the Bilbao Crystallographic Server for induced representations of space groups, like <italic>SITESYM</italic>, but this procedure would be more complex and prone to errors due to the essential differences between space and layer groups (<italic>e.g.</italic> differences between the sets of Wyckoff positions and their labelling schemes, between the sets of representations <italic>etc.</italic>). The aim of this paper is to present the site-symmetry approach applied to layer symmetry groups for the study of materials with layer symmetry. On the basis of this method, the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic> has been developed and implemented on the Bilbao Crystallographic Server. In the following sections, the procedure of the program for the construction of the induced representations of layer groups is described in detail, and its utility is demonstrated by several examples.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><label>2.</label><title>Site-symmetry method &#x000a0; </title><sec id="sec2.1"><label>2.1.</label><title>General procedure &#x000a0; </title><p>The site-symmetry approach establishes the symmetry relations between the crystal extended states induced by localized states of some of the constituent structural units. The procedure for the determination of such a relationship is very useful, as it allows the prediction of the symmetry of the possible extended states starting from the crystal structural data. This task requires the derivation of the irreps of a space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> at any point in reciprocal space (which classify the extended states of the structure) induced by the irreps of the site-symmetry group of a Wyckoff position (according to which localized states are classified). In group-theoretical terms, the procedure relating localized and extended crystalline states can be described by induction of a representation of a space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> from the irreps of a finite subgroup <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi3.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, followed by its reduction into irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. In other words, the induction method permits the calculation of the symmetry of the compatible extended states transforming according to irreps of crystal space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> induced by a localized state described by an irrep of the local or site-symmetry group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi3.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> = <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. The induction procedure can be applied to any group&#x02013;subgroup pair <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi8.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, but in the site-symmetry approach, as its name suggests, a site-symmetry group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is taken as the subgroup of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. The calculation of the space-group irreps induced by the irreps of a site-symmetry group is not straightforward, because the site-symmetry group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (isomorphic with a point group) is a subgroup of infinite index of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. This implies that the representation of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> induced by an irrep of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> must be of infinite dimension and therefore difficult to calculate directly. This problem is solved by applying the &#x02018;Frobenius reciprocity theorem&#x02019; (Serre, 1977<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb40"> &#x025b8;</xref>), which states that the multiplicities of the irreps of a group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in the induced representation from an irrep of a subgroup <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi3.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> can be determined from the multiplicities of the irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi3.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in the representations subduced from <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> to <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi3.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. Therefore, the site-symmetry method is based on subduction and induction, two basic concepts of representation theory, and on the Frobenius reciprocity theorem.</p><p>The subduction procedure relates the representations of a group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> to those of its subgroups <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi22.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. Consider an irrep <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003b3;</sub>&#x000a0;= <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi23.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of a group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. The subduction of <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003b3;</sub> to the subgroup <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi25.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> results in a representation of the subgroup, known as the &#x02018;subduced representation&#x02019; <bold>D</bold>
<sup>Sub</sup>, formed by the matrices of those elements of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> that also belong to the subgroup <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, <italic>i.e.</italic>
<bold>D</bold>
<sup>Sub</sup> = <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi28.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> = <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi29.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. This subduced representation <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi30.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is in general reducible and is decomposable into irreps <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi31.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>:<disp-formula id="fd1"><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efd1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></disp-formula>The multiplicities <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi33.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of the irreps <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi31.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in the subduced representation <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi36.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> can be calculated by the reduction formula (known also as the &#x02018;magic&#x02019; formula):<disp-formula id="fd2"><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efd2.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></disp-formula>where &#x003c7;<sup>Sub</sup>(<italic>s</italic>) is the character of the subduced representation and &#x003c7;<sub>&#x003c3;</sub>(<italic>s</italic>) is the character of the irrep <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi31.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> for the same element <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi38.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>.</p><p>The induction procedure permits the construction of a representation of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> starting from a representation of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi22.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. If <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi31.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> = <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi42.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is an irrep of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, then the matrices of the induced representation <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi44.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> = (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi45.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> are constructed as follows:<disp-formula id="fd3"><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efd3.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></disp-formula>Here, <italic>t</italic>,&#x02005;<italic>r</italic> = 1, &#x02026;, <italic>m</italic> with <italic>m</italic> equal to the dimension of the irrep <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi31.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and <italic>k</italic>,&#x02005;<italic>j</italic> = 1, &#x02026;, <italic>n</italic> where <italic>n</italic> = <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi49.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is the index of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. The elements <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi52.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> are the coset representatives of the decomposition of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> with respect to <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>.</p><p>The characters of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi44.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> are given by<disp-formula id="fd4"><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efd4.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></disp-formula>where <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi56.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is the trace of the <italic>j</italic>th diagonal block of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi57.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and <italic>n</italic> is the index of the subgroup in the group (which can be finite or infinite). In general, the induced representations are reducible, and as such it is possible to decompose them into irreps <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi58.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>:<disp-formula id="fd5"><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efd5.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></disp-formula>where <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi60.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> are the multiplicities of the irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in the induced representations <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi44.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and can be calculated by the reduction formula [see equation (2<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="fd2"/>)].</p><p>The dimension of the induced representation can be read directly off the equation for its construction [equation (3<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="fd3"/>)]:<disp-formula id="fd6"><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efd6.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></disp-formula>This result points out the difficulties for the direct calculation of a representation of a space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> induced from an irrep of a finite subgroup <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. As the site-symmetry group is a subgroup of an infinite index, this suggests that the dimension of the induced irreps must be of infinite dimensions. By means of the site-symmetry approach it is possible to determine the multiplicities <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi60.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of an irrep of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in the induced representation without the necessity of constructing the infinite-dimensional representation. The method is based on the Frobenius reciprocity theorem, according to which the multiplicity of an irreducible irrep <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi58.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in a representation (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi70.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> induced by an irrep <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi31.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi22.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is equal to the multiplicity of the irrep <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi31.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in the representation (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi76.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) subduced by <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi58.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> to <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, <italic>i.e.</italic>
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi33.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> = <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi60.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. In other words, it is sufficient to calculate the multiplicities <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi33.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi31.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in the subduced representation (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi36.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) in order to obtain the frequencies <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi60.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi58.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in the induced representation (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi45.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>).</p></sec><sec id="sec2.2"><label>2.2.</label><title>Application of site-symmetry method to layer groups &#x000a0; </title><p>The group&#x02013;subgroup relations between layer and space groups <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi88.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> are essential to extend the site-symmetry method to layer groups. These relationships have been considered in detail in the literature [see <italic>e.g.</italic> Wood (1964<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb38"> &#x025b8;</xref>), <italic>ITE</italic> and references therein]. The type of space group of which a given layer group is a subgroup is not defined uniquely. The &#x02018;simplest&#x02019; space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> to which <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is related can be expressed as a semi-direct product of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> with the one-dimensional translation group <italic>T</italic>
<sub>3</sub> of additional translations <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi92.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, where <italic>T</italic>
<sub>3</sub> is a normal subgroup of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. Thus, the layer group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is isomorphic with the factor group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi95.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>.</p><p>The isomorphism between <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and the factor group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi95.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> results in close relationships between the Wyckoff positions and the irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. One can show that the set of Wyckoff positions of a layer group is contained in the set of Wyckoff positions of the related space group (<italic>cf.</italic> Evarestov &#x00026; Smirnov, 1993<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb10"> &#x025b8;</xref>). For example, consideration of the restrictions imposed by the loss of periodicity in the third (<italic>z</italic>) direction yields the following restrictions on the special-position coordinates of layer groups: only the special positions of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> whose <italic>z</italic> coordinate does not involve a fraction of the unit-cell parameter are possible special positions of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, <italic>i.e.</italic> special positions of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> with <italic>z</italic> coordinates <italic>z</italic>, &#x02212;<italic>z</italic> or 0. In that way, to each Wyckoff position of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> corresponds exactly one Wyckoff position of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, specified by exactly the same site-symmetry group and multiplicity, and by the same set of coordinate triplets of equivalent positions. Thus, the description of the Wyckoff positions of layer groups can follow the Wyckoff-position descriptions used in space groups. Note, however, that according to the conventions adopted in <italic>ITE</italic> the letter labelling of the Wyckoff positions of layer groups is done independently of that of space groups. As a result, the Wyckoff letters of the corresponding space- and layer-group Wyckoff positions might not coincide, in general.</p><p>The simple relationship between the irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is based on the isomorphism <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi107.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>: the irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> are also irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and every irrep of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is related to a specific irrep of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. In these irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> all elements of a given coset of the decomposition of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> with respect to <italic>T</italic>
<sub>3</sub> are mapped onto the same matrix, <italic>i.e.</italic> the irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> coincide with those irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> whose kernel is <italic>T</italic>
<sub>3</sub> (for details, see Evarestov &#x00026; Smirnov, 1993<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb10"> &#x025b8;</xref>). For example, the special <bold>k</bold> vectors of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> can also be deduced from the <bold>k</bold> vectors of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. The Brillouin zone of a layer group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> can be described as a projection of the Brillouin zone of the corresponding space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> onto the layer plane. Accordingly, the two-dimensional set of <bold>k</bold> vectors <bold>k</bold>(<italic>k</italic>
<sub>1</sub>,&#x02005;<italic>k</italic>
<sub>2</sub>) of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> can be obtained from the three-dimensional <bold>k</bold>(<italic>k</italic>
<sub>1</sub>,&#x02005;<italic>k</italic>
<sub>2</sub>,&#x02005;<italic>k</italic>
<sub>3</sub>) vectors of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> by ignoring the third component <italic>k</italic>
<sub>3</sub>.</p><p>The above considerations indicate that the induced representations of a layer group can be read off directly from the induced representations of the corresponding space group. On the basis of this observation, the procedure of the site-symmetry method for layer groups can be summarized as follows:</p><p>(i) Given the layer group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (specified by its number), the Wyckoff position and the <bold>k</bold> vector (<italic>k</italic>
<sub>1</sub>,&#x02005;<italic>k</italic>
<sub>2</sub>), the program identifies (<italic>a</italic>) the corresponding space-group number and Wyckoff letter, and (<italic>b</italic>) the space-group wave vector (<italic>k</italic>
<sub>1</sub>,&#x02005;<italic>k</italic>
<sub>2</sub>,&#x02005;<italic>k</italic>
<sub>3</sub>) with <italic>k</italic>
<sub>3</sub> = 0, related to the layer-group <bold>k</bold> vector (<italic>k</italic>
<sub>1</sub>,&#x02005;<italic>k</italic>
<sub>2</sub>).</p><p>(ii) The site-symmetry method for space groups is applied, <italic>i.e.</italic> the site-symmetry induced representations are calculated by the program <italic>SITESYM</italic>. [More detailed information on the algorithm of <italic>SITESYM</italic> can be found in the work of Elcoro <italic>et al.</italic> (2017<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb8"> &#x025b8;</xref>).]</p><p>(iii) The site-symmetry induced representations of space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> obtained by <italic>SITESYM</italic> are described with respect to the layer group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3"><label>2.3.</label><title>The program <italic>LSITESYM</italic> &#x000a0; </title><p>The computer program <italic>LSITESYM</italic> establishes symmetry relations between localized and extended states in crystals with layer symmetry. This algorithm calculates the multiplicities of the layer-group irreps in the representation induced by the irreps of a site-symmetry group (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> &#x0003c; <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>).</p><p>The necessary input steps of <italic>LSITESYM</italic> and its corresponding output will be illustrated by the study of the symmetry of the phonon states in the Aurivillius compounds [Bi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>]<sup>+2</sup>[<italic>A</italic>
<sub><italic>n</italic>&#x02212;1</sub>
<italic>B</italic>
<sub><italic>n</italic></sub>O<sub>3<italic>n</italic>+1</sub>]<sup>+2</sup> (known for their ferroelectric properties), a problem discussed in detail by Kitaev <italic>et al.</italic> (2007<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb20"> &#x025b8;</xref>). These compounds exhibit two types of layer symmetry: for even <italic>n</italic>, the layers are described by the layer group <italic>p</italic>4<italic>mm</italic> (No. 55), while for odd <italic>n</italic> there is one central layer with higher symmetry described by the layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> (No. 61). The output of the program will be illustrated by the specific calculations of the symmetry relationships between the phonon states at the point <bold>k</bold> = <italic>M</italic>(&#x000bd;,&#x02005;&#x000bd;) of the layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> and the localized states of atomic orbitals at the Wyckoff position 2<italic>c</italic> (0,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0) with site-symmetry group <italic>mmm.</italic>. The irreps of the layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> at the point <bold>k</bold> = <italic>M</italic>(&#x000bd;,&#x02005;&#x000bd;) with nonzero multiplicities, shown in the output of <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, describe the transformation properties of the extended phonon states induced by the irreps of the layer site-symmetry group <italic>mmm.</italic> of the Wyckoff position 2<italic>c</italic> (0,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0).</p><p>In the <monospace>INPUT</monospace> block of the program the user is expected to provide the layer group, an occupied Wyckoff position with its representative coordinate triplet and the <bold>k</bold> vector (specified by its coordinates and label) of the layer-group irreps <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003b3;</sub> whose induced-representation multiplicities are to be calculated. The information is entered in three steps: in the first one, the layer group is specified by its <italic>ITE</italic> sequential number; in the second step, the occupied Wyckoff positions are to be selected from a list produced by the program; and finally, the coordinates and the label of the <bold>k</bold> vector of the irreps <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003b3;</sub> have to be introduced.</p><p>The <monospace>OUTPUT</monospace> block starts with a header that reproduces the input data, followed by a display of tables with the results of the intermediate steps of the procedure:</p><sec id="sec2.3.1"><label>2.3.1.</label><title>List of operations of the layer site-symmetry group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> &#x000a0; </title><p>Each of the symmetry operations of the layer group that leaves the Wyckoff position representative point invariant is specified by its shorthand description (coordinate triplet) and matrix-column representation. Labels (<italic>g</italic>
<sub>1</sub>,&#x02026;, <italic>g<sub>n</sub></italic>), necessary for later referencing, are assigned to each element of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>.</p><p>The layer site-symmetry group <italic>mmm.</italic> of the position 2<italic>c</italic> (0,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0) of the layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> is formed by eight symmetry operations, as shown in the screenshot (Fig. 1<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> &#x025b8;</xref>) of the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic>.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3.2"><label>2.3.2.</label><title>Character table of the point group &#x000a0; </title><p>This table reproduces the character table of the irreps <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003c3;</sub> of the point group isomorphic with the site-symmetry group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. The notations of Mulliken (1933<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb29"> &#x025b8;</xref>) and Koster <italic>et al.</italic> (1963<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb24"> &#x025b8;</xref>) are applied to label the irreps [see also Bradley &#x00026; Cracknell (1972<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb4"> &#x025b8;</xref>)].</p><p>The site-symmetry group of the point (0,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0) is isomorphic with the point group <italic>mmm</italic> and has eight irreps. The character table is reproduced in Fig. 2<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> &#x025b8;</xref>.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3.3"><label>2.3.3.</label><title>Table of characters of the subduced representations &#x000a0; </title><p>The characters of the elements of the site-symmetry group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (obtained in the first step) for each of the irreps <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003b3;</sub> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of the selected wavevector are calculated internally by the program <italic>REPRES</italic> (<italic>cf.</italic> Aroyo <italic>et al.</italic>, 2006<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb2"> &#x025b8;</xref>). In this way, the characters of the subduced representations (<bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003b3;</sub> &#x02193; <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> are obtained. The notation of the layer-group irreps has been chosen to be the same as for the corresponding irreps of the related space group, and it follows that of Cracknell <italic>et al.</italic> (1979<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb7"> &#x025b8;</xref>).</p><p>The layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> has ten irreps for the <bold>k</bold> vector <italic>M</italic>. Fig. 3<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> &#x025b8;</xref> shows the characters of the corresponding subduced representations (*<italic>M</italic>
<sub><italic>i</italic></sub> &#x02193; <italic>mmm</italic>) of the site-symmetry group. In accordance with the notation of the space-group irreps, *<italic>M<sub>i</sub></italic> and <italic>M<sub>i</sub></italic> denote the full group and the little group irrep of the layer group, respectively.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3.4"><label>2.3.4.</label><title>Table of the decompositions of the subduced representations &#x000a0; </title><p>The multiplicities <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi33.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of the irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> in the subduced representations (<bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003b3;</sub> &#x02193; <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) are obtained by the application of the reduction formula [see equation (2<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="fd2"/>)]. In the example, the decompositions of the representations (*<italic>M<sub>i</sub></italic> &#x02193; <italic>mmm</italic>), <italic>i</italic> = 1, &#x02026;, 10, into irreps of <italic>mmm</italic> are shown in Fig. 4<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> &#x025b8;</xref>.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3.5"><label>2.3.5.</label><title>Table of induced representations &#x000a0; </title><p>According to the Frobenius reciprocity theorem, the multiplicities <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi60.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of the irreps <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003b3;</sub> of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> for a given <bold>k</bold> vector in the representations (<bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003c3;</sub> &#x02191; <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) (induced from the irreps <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003c3;</sub> of the site-symmetry group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) are obtained by transposing the table of the decompositions of the subduced representations (<bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003b3;</sub> &#x02193; <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>).</p><p>The table of representations of the layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> at the point <italic>M</italic> induced by the irreps of the site-symmetry group <italic>mmm</italic>. of the Wyckoff position 2<italic>c</italic> (0,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0) is shown in Fig. 5<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> &#x025b8;</xref>. The rows of the table correspond to the irreps <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003c3;</sub> of the site-symmetry group <italic>mmm</italic>. (<italic>cf.</italic> Fig. 2<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> &#x025b8;</xref>); the entries in each row indicate the multiplicities of the <italic>M</italic> irreps of <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> in the (infinite-dimensional) induced representation (<bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003c3;</sub> &#x02191; <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic>):<disp-formula id="fdu1"><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efd7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" position="float" orientation="portrait"/></disp-formula>The obtained results coincide exactly with the corresponding data of Table V in the work by Kitaev <italic>et al.</italic> (2007<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb20"> &#x025b8;</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="d5e1498"><title/><p>The URL of the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic> is <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.cryst.ehu.es/subperiodic/layer_sitesym.html">http://www.cryst.ehu.es/subperiodic/layer_sitesym.html</ext-link>.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec id="sec3"><label>3.</label><title>Transition metal dichalcogenide layer crystals &#x000a0; </title><p>We now illustrate the use of the <italic>LSITESYM</italic> program described in Section 2<xref ref-type="sec" rid="sec2"/>, taking as an example MoS<sub>2</sub> and WS<sub>2</sub> layered crystals which belong to the transition metal dichalco&#x000ad;genide crystal family. Although the structure of MoS<sub>2</sub> was determined about 100&#x02005;years ago and this layered crystal was used mainly as a dry lubricant, the new wave of interest in transition metal dichalcogenides began after the discovery of graphene. This interest, apart from the fundamental properties of monolayers, is connected with the observation of the direct band gap of 1.8&#x02005;eV at the <italic>K</italic> point in the MoS<sub>2</sub> monolayer, even though the bulk MoS<sub>2</sub> crystal is a semiconductor with an indirect band gap of 1.2&#x02005;eV. The transition to a direct band gap makes the MoS<sub>2</sub> monolayer an excellent candidate as a solar photovoltaic material owing to the drastic enhancement of photoluminescence in the monolayer compared with the bulk. Other crystals of the transition metal dichalcogenide family, like WS<sub>2</sub>, have similar electronic properties.</p><p>Comprehensive reviews and many references to studies of this material can be found in the work of Wang (2014<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb36"> &#x025b8;</xref>), Kolobov &#x00026; Tominaga (2016<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb22"> &#x025b8;</xref>) and Manzeli <italic>et al.</italic> (2017<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb26"> &#x025b8;</xref>).</p><p>The space group of the MoS<sub>2</sub> and WS<sub>2</sub> bulk crystals is <italic>P</italic>6<sub>3</sub>/<italic>mmc</italic> (No. 194). In the bulk crystal, the metal atoms occupy the 2<italic>c</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi142.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) position and the sulfur atoms occupy the 4<italic>f</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi143.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) position (Lee <italic>et al.</italic>, 2014<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb25"> &#x025b8;</xref>). The layer group of a single layer <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> = <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi145.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (No. 78) (Milo&#x00161;evi&#x00107; <italic>et al.</italic>, 2000<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb27"> &#x025b8;</xref>) is isomorphic with the factor group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi95.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, where <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is the space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi148.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (No. 187), <italic>i.e.</italic>
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is a subgroup of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. The crystal structure of a single layer is shown in Fig. 6<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> &#x025b8;</xref>. Atoms in the primitive unit cell of the layer occupy the following Wyckoff positions: Mo (W) 1<italic>c</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi151.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>), S 2<italic>e</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi143.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>). Note that the layer group of a single layer is also a subgroup of the space group of the bulk crystal.</p><p>The phonon symmetry in these crystals has been studied by Molina-S&#x000e1;nchez &#x00026; Wirtz (2011<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb28"> &#x025b8;</xref>), Ribeiro-Soares <italic>et al.</italic> (2014<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb31"> &#x025b8;</xref>) and Saito <italic>et al.</italic> (2016<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb32"> &#x025b8;</xref>). However, diperiodic groups were introduced explicitly only by Evarestov (2015<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb12"> &#x025b8;</xref>), Evarestov <italic>et al.</italic> (2017<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb13"> &#x025b8;</xref>) and Bocharov <italic>et al.</italic> (2019<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb5"> &#x025b8;</xref>). In the work of Ribeiro-Soares <italic>et al.</italic> (2014<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb31"> &#x025b8;</xref>), the symmetry of single layers was described in terms of the related space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi148.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (No. 187) and, in addition, the authors applied a non-standard irrep notation, which hinders the use and comparison of their results.</p><p>The results of <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, shown in Table 1<xref ref-type="table" rid="table1"> &#x025b8;</xref>, permit the analysis of the phonon symmetry of a single MoS<sub>2</sub> layer. Table&#x000a0;1<xref ref-type="table" rid="table1"> &#x025b8;</xref> is organized as follows. The <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> irreps describing the symmetry of phonons at the 2D Brillouin-zone symmetry points are induced by the irreps <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003c3;</sub> of the site-symmetry groups <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of the Wyckoff positions where the atoms given in column 1 are located. The localized atomic displacements <italic>x</italic>, <italic>y</italic> and <italic>z</italic> transforming according to the irreps <bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003c3;</sub> are indicated in brackets. The labels of layer group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi145.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> irreps at the <bold>k</bold> vector points of the two-dimensional Brillouin zone coincide with the labels of the irreps of the corresponding points of the three-dimensional Brillouin zone of the related space group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi148.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>.</p><p>From Table 1<xref ref-type="table" rid="table1"> &#x025b8;</xref> it is seen that the Mo atom vibrations along the <italic>z</italic> axis induce &#x00393;<sub>3</sub> modes, whereas vibrations in the <italic>xy</italic> plane induce &#x00393;<sub>5</sub> modes. Similarly, S atom vibrations along the <italic>z</italic> axis and in the <italic>xy</italic> plane induce &#x00393;<sub>1</sub> + &#x00393;<sub>3</sub> and &#x00393;<sub>5</sub> + &#x00393;<sub>6</sub> modes, respectively. The vibrational representation at the &#x00393; point can be written down, summing the contributions of all the atoms in the primitive unit cell. It is given by &#x00393; = &#x00393;<sub>ac</sub> + &#x00393;<sub>opt</sub> = (&#x00393;<sub>3</sub> + &#x00393;<sub>5</sub>) + (&#x00393;<sub>1</sub> + &#x00393;<sub>3</sub> + &#x00393;<sub>5</sub> + &#x00393;<sub>6</sub>), where the subscripts ac and opt indicate acoustic and optical layer modes, respectively. Further, one can establish a correspondence between layer and bulk crystal modes. Acoustic layer modes induce interlayer bulk modes, whereas optical layer modes induce intralayer bulk ones. The phonon symmetry in a bulk MoS<sub>2</sub> crystal obtained by the <italic>SITESYM</italic> program (Elcoro <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb8"> &#x025b8;</xref>) is given in Table 2<xref ref-type="table" rid="table2"> &#x025b8;</xref>. The notations in Table 2<xref ref-type="table" rid="table2"> &#x025b8;</xref> are the same as those in Table 1<xref ref-type="table" rid="table1"> &#x025b8;</xref>.</p><p>Knowing the symmetry of bulk and layer phonons, one can obtain the genesis of the bulk modes from the layer ones. This could be determined using the <italic>CORREL</italic> program of the Bilbao Crystallographic Server (Aroyo <italic>et al.</italic>, 2006<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb2"> &#x025b8;</xref>) for the group&#x02013;subgroup pair, namely <italic>P</italic>6<sub>3</sub>/<italic>mmc</italic> and <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi148.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. The factor group of the latter is isomorphic with the layer group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi145.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>. When applying this procedure it is necessary to choose correctly the transformation matrix relating the conventional settings of the group and the subgroup. For the <italic>P</italic>6<sub>3</sub>/<italic>mmc</italic> and <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi148.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> pair, the transformation matrix is reduced to an origin shift (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi161.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>).</p><p>On the basis of the Frobenius theorem, the correspondence between the layer irreps at the &#x00393; point and the bulk irreps is given in Table 3<xref ref-type="table" rid="table3"> &#x025b8;</xref>. It is seen that each layer mode generates a pair of bulk modes at the &#x00393; point, one odd and one even. The splitting is due to a weak van der Waals interaction between the layers. Therefore, the frequencies of the modes constituting a pair would be close.</p><p>Similarly, one can deduce the correspondence between layer and bulk modes at other Brillouin-zone points. For example, the correspondence between the layer (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi145.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) modes at the point <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi163.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and the bulk (<italic>P</italic>6<sub>3</sub>/<italic>mmc</italic>) modes at <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi164.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi165.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> are shown in Table 4<xref ref-type="table" rid="table4"> &#x025b8;</xref>.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions" id="sec4"><label>4.</label><title>Conclusions &#x000a0; </title><p>A new computer tool which calculates the site-symmetry induced representations of layer groups, called <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, has recently been implemented on the Bilbao Crystallographic Server. Like the rest of the programs on the server, this new tool is freely available and can be accessed via user-friendly web interfaces. The algorithm of <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, based on the site-symmetry method applied to layer groups, is an extension of the algorithm used in the program <italic>SITESYM</italic> for ordinary space groups. The group&#x02013;subgroup relation between layer and space groups <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi88.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> is fundamental for the development of the procedure for layer groups. On the basis of the isomorphism between the layer <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and the factor group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi95.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, it is possible to establish a simple connection between the Wyckoff positions, <bold>k</bold> vectors and irreps of <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> and <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>, which is essential to calculate the site-symmetry induced representations of layer groups.</p><p>The program <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, which is able to determine the symmetry relations between localized and extended states in crystals with layer symmetry, is also very useful in the description of phonon states and electronic structure. The capabilities of the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic> have been successfully demonstrated in several examples. Moreover, the utility of the program in combination with other tools of the Bilbao Crystallographic Server to obtain the relation between bulk and layer modes has also been shown.</p></sec></body><back><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="bb1"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alexander, E. &#x00026; Hermann, K. (1929). <italic>Z. Kristallogr.</italic>
<bold>70</bold>, 328&#x02013;345.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb2"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aroyo, M. I., Kirov, A., Capillas, C., Perez-Mato, J. M. &#x00026; Wondratschek, H. (2006). <italic>Acta Cryst.</italic> A<bold>62</bold>, 115&#x02013;128.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb3"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aroyo, M. I., Perez-Mato, J. M., Orobengoa, D., Tasci, E., de la Flor, G. &#x00026; Kirov, A. (2011). <italic>Bulg. Chem. Commun.</italic>
<bold>43</bold>, 183&#x02013;197.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb5"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bocharov, D., Piskunov, S., Zhukovskii, Y. F. &#x00026; Evarestov, R. A. (2019). <italic>Phys. Status Solidi RRL</italic>, <bold>13</bold>, 1800253.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb4"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bradley, C. J. &#x00026; Cracknell, A. P. (1972). <italic>The Mathematical Theory of Symmetry in Solids.</italic> Oxford: Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb6"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Choi, W., Choudhary, N., Han, G. H., Park, J., Akinwande, D. &#x00026; Lee, Y. H. (2017). <italic>Mater. Today</italic>, <bold>20</bold>(3), 116&#x02013;130.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb7"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cracknell, A. P., Davies, B. L., Miller, S. C. &#x00026; Love, W. F. (1979). <italic>Kronecker Product Tables</italic>, No. 1, <italic>General Introduction and Tables of Irreducible Representations of Space Groups.</italic> New York: IFI/Plenum.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb8"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elcoro, L., Bradlyn, B., Wang, Z., Vergniory, M. G., Cano, J., Felser, C., Bernevig, B. A., Orobengoa, D., de la Flor, G. &#x00026; Aroyo, M. I. (2017). <italic>J. Appl. Cryst.</italic>
<bold>50</bold>, 1457&#x02013;1477.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb12"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evarestov, R. A. (2015). <italic>Theoretical Modeling of Inorganic Nanostructures: Symmetry and Ab Initio Calculations of Nanolayers, Nanotubes and Nanowires.</italic> Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb13"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evarestov, R. A., Bandura, A. V., Porsev, V. V. &#x00026; Kovalenko, A. V. (2017). <italic>J. Comput. Chem.</italic>
<bold>38</bold>, 2581&#x02013;2593.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb11"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evarestov, R. A., Kitaev, Y. E., Limonov, M. F. &#x00026; Panfilov, A. G. (1993). <italic>Phys. Status Solidi B</italic>, <bold>179</bold>, 249&#x02013;297.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb14"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evarestov, R. A., Kovalenko, A. V., Bandura, A. V., Domnin, A. V. &#x00026; Lukyanov, S. I. (2018). <italic>Mater. Res. Expr.</italic>
<bold>5</bold>, 115028.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb9"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evarestov, R. A. &#x00026; Smirnov, V. P. (1987). <italic>Phys. Status Solidi B</italic>, <bold>142</bold>, 493&#x02013;499.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb10"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evarestov, R. A. &#x00026; Smirnov, V. P. (1993). <italic>Site Symmetry in Crystals. Theory and Applications</italic>, Springer Series in Solid State Sciences, Vol. 108, edited by M. Cardona. Heidelberg: Springer.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb15"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Geim, K. &#x00026; Novoselov, K. S. (2007). <italic>Nat. Mater.</italic>
<bold>6</bold>, 183&#x02013;191.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb17"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, G. H., Duong, D. L., Keum, D. H., Yun, S. J. &#x00026; Lee, Y. H. (2018). <italic>Chem. Rev.</italic>
<bold>118</bold>, 62976336.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb16"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hatch, D. M., Stokes, H. T. &#x00026; Putnam, R. M. (1988). <italic>Group Theoretical Methods in Physics</italic>, Lecture Notes in Physics, Vol. 313, edited by H. D. Doebner, J. D. Hennig &#x00026; T. D. Palev, pp. 326&#x02013;333. New York: Springer.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb23"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">
<italic>International Tables for Crystallography</italic> (2010). Vol. E, <italic>Subperiodic Groups</italic>, edited by V. Kopsk&#x000fd; &#x00026; D. B. Litvin, 2nd ed. Chichester: John Wiley &#x00026; Sons.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb18"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ipatova, I. P. &#x00026; Kitaev, Y. E. (1985). <italic>Prog. Surf. Sci.</italic>
<bold>18</bold>, 189&#x02013;246.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb20"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kitaev, Y. E., Aroyo, M. I. &#x00026; Perez-Mato, J. M. (2007). <italic>Phys. Rev. B</italic>, <bold>75</bold>, 064110.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb19"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kitaev, Y. E., Limonov, M. F., Panfilov, A. G., Evarestov, R. A. &#x00026; Mirgorodsky, A. P. (1994). <italic>Phys. Rev. B</italic>, <bold>49</bold>, 9933&#x02013;9943.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb22"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolobov, A. V. &#x00026; Tominaga, J. (2016). <italic>Two-Dimensional Transition Metal Dichalcogenides</italic>, Springer Series in Materials Science, Vol.&#x000a0;239. Cham: Springer International Publishing.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb24"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koster, G. F., Dimmock, J. O., Wheeler, R. G. &#x00026; Statz, H. (1963). <italic>Properties of the Thirty-Two Point Groups.</italic> Cambridge: MIT Press.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb21"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kovalev, O. V. (1993). <italic>Representations of the Crystallographic Space Groups: Irreducible Representations, Induced Representations and Co-representations</italic>, edited by H. T. Stokes &#x00026; D. M. Hatch. Philadelphia: Gordon and Breach.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb25"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, C., Hong, J., Lee, W. R., Kim, D. Y. &#x00026; Shim, J. H. (2014). <italic>J. Solid State Chem.</italic>
<bold>211</bold>, 113&#x02013;119.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb26"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manzeli, S., Ovchinnikov, D., Pasquier, D., Yazyev, O. V. &#x00026; Kis, A. (2017). <italic>Nat. Rev. Mater.</italic>
<bold>2</bold>, 17033.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb27"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milo&#x00161;evi&#x00107;, I., Vukovi&#x00107;, T., Damnjanovi&#x00107;, M. &#x00026; Nikoli&#x00107;, B. (2000). <italic>Eur. Phys. J. B</italic>, <bold>17</bold>, 707&#x02013;712.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb28"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Molina-S&#x000e1;nchez, A. &#x00026; Wirtz, L. (2011). <italic>Phys. Rev. B</italic>, <bold>84</bold>, 155413.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb29"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mulliken, R. S. (1933). <italic>Phys. Rev.</italic>
<bold>43</bold>, 279&#x02013;302.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb30"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Randviir, E. P., Brownson, D. A. &#x00026; Banks, C. E. (2014). <italic>Mater. Today</italic>, <bold>17</bold>, 426&#x02013;432.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb31"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ribeiro-Soares, J., Almeida, R. M., Barros, E. B., Araujo, P. T., Dresselhaus, M. S., Can&#x000e7;ado, L. G. &#x00026; Jorio, A. (2014). <italic>Phys. Rev. B</italic>, <bold>90</bold>, 115438.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb32"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saito, R., Tatsumi, Y., Huang, S., Ling, X. &#x00026; Dresselhaus, M. S. (2016). <italic>J. Phys. Condens. Matter</italic>, <bold>28</bold>, 353002.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb40"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serre, J.-P. (1977). <italic>Linear Representations of Finite Groups.</italic> New York: Springer Verlag.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb33"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stokes, H. T., Hatch, D. M. &#x00026; Wells, J. D. (1991). <italic>Phys. Rev. B</italic>, <bold>43</bold>, 11010&#x02013;11018.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb34"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tasci, E. S., de la Flor, G., Orobengoa, D., Capillas, C., Perez-Mato, J.&#x000a0;M. &#x00026; Aroyo, M. I. (2012). <italic>EPJ Web Conf.</italic>
<bold>22</bold>, 00009.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb35"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tronc, P. &#x00026; Kitaev, Y. E. (2001). <italic>Phys. Rev. B</italic>, <bold>63</bold>, 205326.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb36"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Z. M. (2014). Editor. <italic>MoS<sub>2</sub> Materials, Physics, and Devices</italic>, Lecture Notes in Nanoscale Science and Technology, Vol. 21. Cham: Springer International Publishing.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb37"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber, L. (1929). <italic>Z. Kristallogr.</italic>
<bold>70</bold>, 309&#x02013;327.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb38"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wood, E. (1964). <italic>Bell Syst. Tech. J.</italic>
<bold>43</bold>, 541&#x02013;559.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bb39"><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zallen, R., Slade, M. L. &#x00026; Ward, A. T. (1971). <italic>Phys. Rev. B</italic>, <bold>3</bold>, 4257&#x02013;4273.</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back><floats-group><fig id="fig1" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>A screenshot of the partial output of the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, showing the eight symmetry operations of the site-symmetry group <italic>mmm.</italic> of the Wyckoff position (WP) 2<italic>c</italic> (0,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0) of the layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> (No. 61). The symmetry operations are specified by their shorthand descriptions (coordinate triplets) and matrix-column representations.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-fig1"/></fig><fig id="fig2" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>A screenshot of the partial output of the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, showing the character table of the point group <italic>mmm</italic>, isomorphic with the site-symmetry group of the Wyckoff position 2<italic>c</italic> (0,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0) of the layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> (No. 61). The irreps are labelled according to the notation of Mulliken (1933<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb29"> &#x025b8;</xref>) and Koster <italic>et al.</italic> (1963<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb24"> &#x025b8;</xref>).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-fig2"/></fig><fig id="fig3" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>A screenshot of the partial output of the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, showing the characters of the subduced representations of the site-symmetry group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi7.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> of the Wyckoff position 2<italic>c</italic> (0,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0) of the layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> (No. 61) at the <bold>k</bold> point <italic>M</italic>. The columns are specified by the symmetry operations of the site-symmetry group <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi227.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
<italic>mmm</italic> (<italic>cf.</italic> Fig. 1<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> &#x025b8;</xref>).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-fig3"/></fig><fig id="fig4" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>A screenshot of the partial output of the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, showing the decompositions of the subduced representations (*<italic>M</italic>
<sub><italic>i</italic></sub> &#x02193; <italic>mmm</italic>), shown in Fig. 3<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> &#x025b8;</xref>, into irreps of <italic>mmm</italic> (<italic>cf.</italic> Fig. 2<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2"> &#x025b8;</xref>).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-fig4"/></fig><fig id="fig5" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>A screenshot of the partial output of the program <italic>LSITESYM</italic>, showing the representations of the layer group <italic>p</italic>4/<italic>mmm</italic> (No. 61) at the point <italic>M</italic> induced by the irreps of the site-symmetry group <italic>mmm</italic>. of the Wyckoff position 2<italic>c</italic> (0,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-fig5"/></fig><fig id="fig6" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>(<italic>a</italic>) The crystal structure of a single layer of MoS<sub>2</sub> (WS<sub>2</sub>), and (<italic>b</italic>) its projection along [001].</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-fig6"/></fig><table-wrap id="table1" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>Phonon symmetry in the single MoS<sub>2</sub> layer with <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi90.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> = <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi145.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (No. 78)</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead valign="bottom"><tr><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">Atom</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">Wyckoff position</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">
<bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003c3;</sub>
</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">&#x00393; (0, 0) <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi173.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">
<italic>K</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi174.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi175.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">
<italic>M</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi176.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) <italic>m</italic>2<italic>m</italic>
</th></tr></thead><tbody valign="top"><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">Mo</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1<italic>c</italic>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi177.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (<italic>z</italic>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">3</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">(<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi151.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi179.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (<italic>x</italic>, <italic>y</italic>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 2</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi180.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">S</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">2<italic>e</italic>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>A</italic>
<sub>1</sub> (<italic>z</italic>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">3, 4</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 3</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">(<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi143.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>E</italic> (<italic>x</italic>, <italic>y</italic>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">5, 6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 2, 5, 6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 2, 3, 4</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">3<italic>m.</italic>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><table-wrap id="table2" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Table 2</label><caption><title>Phonon symmetry in the MoS<sub>2</sub> bulk crystal <italic>P</italic>6<sub>3</sub>/<italic>mmc</italic> (No. 194)</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead valign="bottom"><tr><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">Atom</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">Wyckoff position</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">
<bold>D</bold>
<sub>&#x003c3;</sub>
</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">&#x00393; (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi182.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) 6/<italic>mmm</italic>
</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">
<italic>A</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi183.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) 6/<italic>mmm</italic>
</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">
<italic>K</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi184.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi180.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">
<italic>H</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi186.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi180.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">
<italic>M</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi188.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) <italic>mmm</italic>
</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">
<italic>L</italic> (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi189.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) <italic>mmm</italic>
</th></tr></thead><tbody valign="top"><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">Mo</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">2<italic>c</italic>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi190.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> (<italic>z</italic>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">2<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, 3<sup>+</sup>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">2<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, 3<sup>+</sup>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">(<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi142.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>E</italic>&#x02032; (<italic>x</italic>, <italic>y</italic>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">5<sup>+</sup>, 6<sup>&#x02212;</sup>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 4, 5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">2, 3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1<sup>+</sup>, 2<sup>+</sup>, 3<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, 4<sup>&#x02212;</sup>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 2</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi180.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">S</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">4<italic>f</italic>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>A</italic>
<sub>1</sub> (<italic>z</italic>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1<sup>+</sup>, 2<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, 3<sup>+</sup>, 4<sup>&#x02212;</sup>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">5, 6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1<sup>+</sup>, 2<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, 3<sup>+</sup>, 4<sup>&#x02212;</sup>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 1</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">(<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi143.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>E</italic> (<italic>x</italic>, <italic>y</italic>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">5<sup>+</sup>, 5<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, 6<sup>+</sup>, 6<sup>&#x02212;</sup>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">3, 3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 2, 3, 3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1<sup>+</sup>, 1<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, 2<sup>+</sup>, 2<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, 3<sup>+</sup>, 3<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, 4<sup>+</sup>, 4<sup>&#x02212;</sup>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">1, 1, 2, 2</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">3<italic>m.</italic>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x000a0;</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><table-wrap id="table3" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Table 3</label><caption><title>Correspondence between the layer (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi145.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) irreps at the point &#x00393;(0,&#x02005;0) and the bulk (<italic>P</italic>6<sub>3</sub>/<italic>mmc</italic>) irreps at &#x00393;(0,&#x02005;0,&#x02005;0) and <italic>A</italic>(&#x000bd;,&#x02005;&#x000bd;,&#x02005;0)</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead valign="bottom"><tr><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">Layer</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">&#x000a0;</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">Bulk</th></tr></thead><tbody valign="top"><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x00393;<sub>1</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi196.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi197.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <italic>A</italic>
<sub>1</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x00393;<sub>2</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi199.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi200.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <italic>A</italic>
<sub>2</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x00393;<sub>3</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi202.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi203.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <italic>A</italic>
<sub>1</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x00393;<sub>4</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi205.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi206.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <italic>A</italic>
<sub>2</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x00393;<sub>5</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi208.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi209.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <italic>A</italic>
<sub>3</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">&#x00393;<sub>6</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi211.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi212.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula> + <italic>A</italic>
<sub>3</sub>
</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><table-wrap id="table4" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Table 4</label><caption><title>Correspondence between the layer (<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi145.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) irreps at the point <italic>K</italic>(<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi214.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>,&#x02005;<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi214.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>) and the bulk (<italic>P</italic>6<sub>3</sub>/<italic>mmc</italic>) irreps at <italic>K</italic>(<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi214.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>,&#x02005;<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi214.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>,&#x02005;0) and <italic>H</italic>(<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi214.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>,&#x02005;<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi214.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>,&#x02005;&#x000bd;)</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead valign="bottom"><tr><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">Layer</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">&#x000a0;</th><th style="border-bottom:1px solid black;" rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="bottom">Bulk</th></tr></thead><tbody valign="top"><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>1</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>1</sub> + <italic>K</italic>
<sub>4</sub> + <italic>H</italic>
<sub>3</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>2</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>2</sub> + <italic>K</italic>
<sub>3</sub> + <italic>H</italic>
<sub>3</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>3</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>5</sub> + <italic>H</italic>
<sub>1</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>4</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>6</sub> + <italic>H</italic>
<sub>2</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>5</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>5</sub> + <italic>H</italic>
<sub>2</sub>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>6</sub>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<inline-formula><inline-graphic xlink:href="j-52-01214-efi195.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif"/></inline-formula>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1" align="left" valign="top">
<italic>K</italic>
<sub>6</sub> + <italic>H</italic>
<sub>1</sub>
</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></floats-group></article>