<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Energetic materials (EMs) such as explosives, oxidizers and propellants are of significant importance in aerospace, oil-well drilling and other military and civilian applications. In this field, understanding the sensitivity of single crystals under shock or impact has long been a challenge. In engineering, shock sensitivity can be identified by the shock initiation threshold pressure, 
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>90</sub>, which is obtained from the gap test and produces a detonation 50% of the time. 
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>90</sub> results are generally reproducible and reliable. However, because of the high complexity of the test, the measurements have been performed for only limited types of energetic single crystals [
 <xref rid="B1-nanomaterials-09-01251" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-nanomaterials-09-01251" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>] and the test is not easily applicable to newly synthesized EMs. On the other hand, the drop-weight impact test, which characterizes the impact sensitivity of EMs by height 
 <italic>h</italic>
 <sub>50%</sub>, is easy to implement. Therefore, there are abundant values of 
 <italic>h</italic>
 <sub>50%</sub> in the literature compared to 
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>90</sub> values. However, the 
 <italic>h</italic>
 <sub>50%</sub> value is generally not reproducible as the results significantly vary depending on the conditions under which the tests are performed. For example, for benzotrifuroxan (BTF), the reported 
 <italic>h</italic>
 <sub>50%</sub> values vary from 21 [
 <xref rid="B3-nanomaterials-09-01251" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>] to 50 [
 <xref rid="B4-nanomaterials-09-01251" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>] cm; for hexanitrohexaazaisowurtzitane/trinitrotoluene (CL-20/TNT) cocrystal, the values vary from 30 [
 <xref rid="B4-nanomaterials-09-01251" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>] to 99 [
 <xref rid="B5-nanomaterials-09-01251" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>] cm. Therefore, the 
 <italic>h</italic>
 <sub>50%</sub> values derived from the same experiments are comparable, while those from different equipment can only be used for a quantitative comparison of the mechanical sensitivity among various energetic single crystals.
</p>
