<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this study, for the first time, we investigated the effects of temperature, stress and grain size on the creep of nanocrystalline NiAl alloy (grain size ≤10 nm) through MD simulations. We have focused on the creep strain, crystal structure, dislocations and diffusions. The underlying creep mechanisms at different creep stages were explored. Specifically, we study the mechanism of creep properties at the micro–nano scale. For MD simulations, the time scale is relatively short and the system is not large enough, which are the normal limitations of molecular dynamics. Since the geometric scale and time scale of the molecular dynamics method are different from the actual experiment, the stress level and strain rate are much higher than the actual experiment [
 <xref rid="B8-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. Although creep is a time-dependent phenomenon that usually occurs on time scales beyond the MD range, creep behavior and microstructure evolution can be observed even at high strain rates in MD simulations. In this research, the creep curve of the material shows the same characteristics as the three stages of actual creep—the primary creep phase, steady-state creep phase and tertiary creep phase—and the deformation mechanism obtained by the MD method is consistent with the high-temperature creep mechanism. Previous studies into creep have also proved the rationality of the MD method, and the time scale and stress level used in their research are in the same order of magnitude as this study [
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-materials-12-02508" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>].
</p>
