<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Solar cells and LEDs have different requirements for the charge transfer process. The charge transfer process is mainly determined by the interplay between carrier mobility (μ) and exciton binding energy (
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>b</sub>), so they play a guiding role in the design of efficient optoelectronic devices.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0113" ref-type="ref">113</xref> Here, mobility refers to the velocity of charge carriers moving through conductive media under the electric field, and the binding energy of excitons is a representation of the strength of the binding force between an electron and a hole. Solar cells need fast charge separation, where both carrier radiative recombination and nonradiative recombination caused by defects need to be suppressed. In general, weak exciton binding and fast carrier mobility are required. To some extent, high mobility can reduce the contact time between the carrier and the trap, thus speeding up the escape rate from the shallow trap. However, in most cases, high mobility will actually speed up the trapping, so an appropriate mobility value is very important. LEDs ask for effective charge injection and radiative recombination, so nonradiative recombination resulting from defects should be avoided. For luminescent materials, strong exciton binding energy and low mobility increase the radiative recombination rate. However, in LED devices, low mobility can make charge injection unbalanced, and leads to charge accumulation, so that electrons accumulate at one side and holes at the other side of the device, resulting in lower device efficiency. A profound review about the design and construction of heterogeneous structures to improve the efficiency of charge transfer in semiconductor optoelectronic devices has been presented by Sargent's group.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0113" ref-type="ref">113</xref> It is indisputable that charge transfer, which plays a governing role in different optoelectronic devices, is a key to the device design and needs careful study.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0114" ref-type="ref">114</xref> In quasi‐2D perovskites with the existence of multiple phases, charge transfer is still controversial.
</p>
