<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In order to achieve an efficient charge transfer, the thin film preparation has to be improved. Recently, an orderly aligned orientation of (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(MA)
 <sub>3</sub>Pb
 <sub>4</sub>I
 <sub>13</sub> 2D perovskite was achieved through cation‐induced recrystallization process (CIRP).
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0036" ref-type="ref">36</xref> Compared with the random orientation without the CIRP treatment, the cations under design are evenly distributed, so the width of the quantum well is narrowed, which promotes the separation of charges and thus reduces the charge accumulation. This 2D perovskite is applied in a TiO
 <sub>2</sub>/Al
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub>/NiO/C framework for solar cells, showing a fine PCE of 8.2%. The XRD of the film of (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(MA)
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>−1</sub>Pb
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>I
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>+1</sub> (
 <italic>n</italic> = 1–4) shows that the texture of crystal changes gradually, and the proportion of [101] textured domains increases, as the thickness 
 <italic>n</italic> of lead iodide layer increases (
 <bold>Figure</bold>
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0008" ref-type="fig">
  <bold>8</bold>
 </xref>a). Different from the lead iodide layer in the monolayer (
 <italic>n</italic> = 1) compound, which is preferentially arranged parallel to the substrate, it is almost completely perpendicular in the 
 <italic>n</italic> = 4 compound.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0115" ref-type="ref">115</xref> The same controlled orientation of (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(MA)
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>−1</sub>Pb
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>I
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>+1</sub> film is used to assemble LEDs (Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0008" ref-type="fig">8</xref>b). Making inorganic layers perpendicular to the substrate, electrons and holes can be injected and transported to the deeper center of the film, rather than across the barrier of organic cations, compared with inorganic layers that are parallel to the substrate, thus improving the probability of radiative recombination.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0116" ref-type="ref">116</xref>
</p>
