<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par26">In this work, we found a general definition of interaction energy for 2-interacting fermions. First, we had examined two Dirac particles interacting with their central potential before we derived two-body Dirac equation in (2 + 1) space-time geometry. For solution of this equation, we separated center of mass and relative coordinates by using explicit form of the equation. Then, we obtained 1
 <sup>
  <italic>st</italic>
 </sup> order coupled radial differential equation set. Since the masses of an electron and a hole are very small (
 <italic>m</italic>
 <sub>1</sub> and 
 <italic>m</italic>
 <sub>2</sub>), we neglected 
 <inline-formula id="IEq38">
  <alternatives>
   <tex-math id="M125">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal} \usepackage{amsmath} \usepackage{wasysym} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{upgreek} \setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt} \begin{document}$${M}_{1}^{2}$$\end{document}</tex-math>
   <math id="M126">
    <msubsup>
     <mrow>
      <mi>M</mi>
     </mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mn>1</mn>
     </mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mn>2</mn>
     </mrow>
    </msubsup>
   </math>
   <inline-graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_45478_Article_IEq38.gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  </alternatives>
 </inline-formula> and 
 <inline-formula id="IEq39">
  <alternatives>
   <tex-math id="M127">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal} \usepackage{amsmath} \usepackage{wasysym} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{upgreek} \setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt} \begin{document}$${M}_{2}^{2}$$\end{document}</tex-math>
   <math id="M128">
    <msubsup>
     <mrow>
      <mi>M</mi>
     </mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mn>2</mn>
     </mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mn>2</mn>
     </mrow>
    </msubsup>
   </math>
   <inline-graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_45478_Article_IEq39.gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  </alternatives>
 </inline-formula> values in our equations. The solution of 2-interacting fermions in our model indicates that one can obtain general definition for an interaction energy including quantum numbers. We apply our model to an exciton and found its binding energy which is very close to results found in literature. Moreover, since we work in 2 + 1 dimensions, our results do not include any other effects for a monolayer medium. Finally, we calculated the decay time of an exciton (~ps) directly because the interaction energy in our calculations possesses imaginary part.
</p>
