<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par10">For these crystals, neutron diffraction results were additionally carried out at 95 K, to confirm the Fe magnetic peak below 
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>N</italic>
 </sub> in accordance with the propagation vector 
 <bold>
  <italic>q</italic>
 </bold> = (1 0 1)
 <sub>Orthorhombic</sub> = (½ ½ 1)
 <sub>Tetragonal</sub> and the stripe arrangement of the Fe spin lattice
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup> (see Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1a</xref> in Supplementary). Additionally, variable temperature scans of the Eu magnetic peak at (0 3 0) for both crystals were performed below 30 K using the elastic diffuse scattering spectrometer CORELLI at SNS
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup> and showed the same temperature dependence of Eu magnetic peak as (0 3 0) with 
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sub>N</sub> = 21 K (see Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1b</xref>). In contrast, the Néel transition temperature for Fe is clearly lattice and disorder sensitive. The high-temperature phase transition is due to the ordering of the transition metal Fe moments, whereas the low-temperature phase transition is due to the ordering of the localized Eu moments
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>. The divergent behavior of the Fe and Eu sublattices from ‘crystal a’ to ‘b’ – the former sublattice sensitive to lattice disorder, the latter insensitive – is of interest here. One plausible hypothesis is that the Eu 4 
 <italic>f</italic> moments are much more localized, near the Eu nucleus, than the Fe moments that are more itinerant. This would suggest that the Eu 4 
 <italic>f</italic> moments are less subject to nano-strain than the Fe 3
 <italic>d</italic> moments, and the relatively isolated location of Eu between the layers (as opposed to the tightly bound FeAs layers) would enhance this possibility. Supporting this assertion is the relative insensitivity of Eu ordering temperature to pressure (see Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S4</xref>), again unlike the Fe sublattice ordering. Indeed the Eu magnetic order survives to higher pressure than the Fe order, despite occurring at much lower temperatures.
</p>
