<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par11">To further investigate the local origin of the bulk 
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sub>N</sub> differences between the two EuFe
 <sub>2</sub>As
 <sub>2</sub> crystals, surface topography and electronic structures were investigated using STM/S on 
 <italic>in-situ</italic> low-temperature cleaved surfaces. The two sets of EuFe
 <sub>2</sub>As
 <sub>2</sub> ‘crystal a’ and ‘crystal b’ were cleaved in an ultra-high vacuum at ~ 78 K and then immediately transferred to the STM/S head precooled to 4.2 K without breaking vacuum. The STM/S experiments were carried out using a scanning tunneling microscope with base pressure better than 2 × 10
 <sup>−10</sup> Torr, with mechanically cut Pt-Ir tip. All Pt-Ir tips were conditioned on clean Au (1 1 1) and checked using the topography, surface state, and work function before each measurement. The STM/S were controlled by the SPECS Nanonis control system. Topographic images were acquired in constant current mode with bias voltage applied to samples, and tip grounded. All the spectroscopies were obtained using the lock-in technique with a modulation of 1 mV at 973 Hz on bias voltage, dI/dV. Current-imaging-tunneling-spectroscopy were collected over a grid of pixels at bias ranges around Fermi level using the same lock-in amplifier parameters. The survey on multiple large areas of both samples shows the coexistence surface reconstructions on ‘crystal a’ and ‘crystal b’, as shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>. Using a similar method as STM report on Co-doped BaFe
 <sub>2</sub>As
 <sub>2</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup>, the 2 × 1 and √2 × √2 reconstructed surfaces can be assigned to arsenic termination and europium termination, respectively, as shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a</xref>. While the 2 × 1 surfaces of both crystals (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3b,c</xref>) are very similar, the √2 × √2 surfaces of the two crystals (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d,e</xref>) are very different. The atomic resolved images in the insets of Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d,e</xref> from the well-ordered √2 × √2 reconstructed areas of the two crystals are similar, but the arrangements of the defects on the surfaces are rather different. In ‘crystal a’, surface defects (one of the defects is marked with a black arrow in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d</xref>) are essentially randomly distributed on the surface, but in ‘crystal b’, large amount of defects prefer to form into chains (one of the chains is marked with a white arrow in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3e</xref>). By analyzing atomically resolved images around these areas, we found the chains are aligned on the antiphase boundaries. Because the surface reconstruction is 2 × 1 or √2 × √2, those domains can shift by 1 to form antiphase boundaries. Although antiphase boundaries also exist on the ‘crystal a’ surface (one of the antiphase boundaries is marked with a green arrow in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d</xref>), defects in ‘crystal a’ do not segregate along the boundaries. The electronic properties revealed by the STS from the surfaces are consistent with the morphological observation (see also Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S2</xref>). In Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3f</xref>, the average electronic local density of states (LDOS) of 2 × 1 surfaces (As termination) over large areas are almost identical for both crystals, but the LDOS from the two √2 × √2 surfaces (Eu termination) in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3g</xref> have significant differences. This shows that the different arrangements of the surface defects in the two crystals change the electronic structure dramatically. Given the preparation of these surfaces by cleaving the crystals in ultra-high vacuum at low temperatures, this difference is in electronic structure that is generally reflective of the effects of the defects in the bulk crystals.
</p>
