<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To avoid the formation of microtwins, we performed differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) on a polycrystalline Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn sample prepared by arc-melting, as shown in 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acs.chemmater.9b02013/suppl_file/cm9b02013_si_001.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Figure S1b</ext-link>. Other than a sharp peak at 1306 K, which corresponds to the melting point of the compound, we observe another peak at 1013 K (inset in 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acs.chemmater.9b02013/suppl_file/cm9b02013_si_001.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Figure S1b</ext-link>), which is related to the structural transition from the high-temperature cubic phase to the low-temperature tetragonal phase. Considering the structural transformation at 1013 K, we have chosen the crystal growth range below this temperature. First, we set the furnace temperature to 1323 K, after which rapid cooling to 923 K occurred (below the structural transformation temperature), to avoid the growth of any cubic phase. The slow cooling from 923 to 723 K resulted in the formation of single crystals free of microtwins. Methods such as Bridgman crystal growth and optical floating zone require direct cooling from the melt; consequently, crystals of Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn from these methods are always microtwinned. Therefore, the only successful method to grow crystals of Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn, free of microtwins, is the flux-growth, wherein the growth process can be controlled far below the melting point. Stoichiometric Mn
 <sub>2</sub>PtSn is supposed to crystallize in the space group 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅
 <italic>m</italic>2, but this stoichiometric compound cannot be synthesized in a bulk single phase. However, removing some manganese atoms from the unit cell leads to the stabilization of the single-phase compound, Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn. It crystallizes in a different space group (
 <italic>I</italic>4̅2
 <italic>d</italic>), which is a superstructure of statistically vacancy-distributed Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn, obtained from Mn
 <sub>2</sub>PtSn (space group 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅
 <italic>m</italic>2); it will be discussed later in this article.
</p>
