<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In 
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>
 </xref>, we demonstrate how the structural evolution occurs from an inverse cubic Heusler structure to an inverse tetragonal Heusler structure, followed by the vacancies formation and their ordering, which transforms it into the superstructure form of another inverse tetragonal structure. The cubic structure of Mn
 <sub>2</sub>PtSn, supposedly, has the space group of 
 <italic>F</italic>4̅3
 <italic>m</italic>. As this cubic crystal structure leads to a tetragonal distortion, the new cell parameters of the tetragonal structure become 
 <inline-formula id="d30e414">
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="cm-2019-02013r_m001.gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> and 
 <italic>c</italic>
 <sub>t</sub> = 
 <italic>c</italic>
 <sub>c</sub>, changing the total volume of the unit cell to half; the subscripts correspond to the tetragonal and cubic structure, respectively. Upon introducing vacancies at the Mn-sites in Mn
 <sub>2</sub>PtSn and considering that the vacancies in the resulting compound Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn are statistically distributed (hypothetical situation), the crystal symmetry and lattice parameters would be the same as in Mn
 <sub>2</sub>PtSn, that is, 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅
 <italic>m</italic>2. However, if the vacancies are ordered, it transforms the space group from 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅
 <italic>m</italic>2 to 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅2
 <italic>d</italic> and consequently changes the lattice parameters. The new lattice parameters of Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn become 
 <inline-formula id="d30e460">
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="cm-2019-02013r_m002.gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> and 
 <italic>c</italic>
 <sub>T</sub> = 2
 <italic>c</italic>
 <sub>t</sub>, modifying the volume of the unit cell by 4 times; the subscripts correspond to the vacancy-ordered and vacancy-disordered structures, respectively. Thus, the relation between the volumes of the involved structures can be understood as 
 <italic>V</italic>
 <sub>T</sub> = 4
 <italic>V</italic>
 <sub>t</sub> = 2
 <italic>V</italic>
 <sub>c</sub>.
</p>
