<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In 
 <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>
 </xref>a, we show the crystal structure of Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn with space groups of 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅
 <italic>m</italic>2 (hypothetical, black line) and 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅2
 <italic>d</italic> (red line) as subcell and supercell, respectively, along the [001] zonal axis. The ‘
 <italic>a</italic>’ cell parameter of the supercell, 
 <italic>a</italic>
 <sub>T</sub>, is equal to the diagonal of the old subunit cell, which is 
 <inline-formula id="d30e529">
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="cm-2019-02013r_m003.gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula>. We employ single-crystal XRD study to understand the superstructure formation in Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn. 
 <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>
 </xref>c shows the corresponding experimental single-crystal XRD pattern obtained in the reciprocal space. The black square connecting the intensities of 220, 2̅20, 22̅0, and 
 <inline-formula id="d30e540">
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="cm-2019-02013r_m004.gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> represents the subcell, whereas the red square connecting the intensities of 200, 2̅00, 020, and 02̅0 represents the supercell. 
 <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figures 
  <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>
 </xref>b,d show the crystal structure and the experimental single-crystal XRD patterns, respectively, along the [100] zonal axis. From the single-crystal structure refinement, the best-fitted unit cell parameters are 
 <italic>a</italic> = 6.3651(4) Å and 
 <italic>c</italic> = 12.2205(11) Å. We provide the structural parameters obtained from the complete single-crystal refinement in 
 <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table 
  <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref>
 </xref>. In 
 <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">Table 
  <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">2</xref>
 </xref>, Wyckoff and atomic positions in the unit cell are presented along with the isotropic displacement parameters, while the anisotropic displacements of atoms are shown in Table S1 (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acs.chemmater.9b02013/suppl_file/cm9b02013_si_001.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Supporting Information</ext-link>). In 
 <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>
 </xref>e, we show the observed and calculated powder XRD patterns for Mn
 <sub>1.4</sub>PtSn, considering the ordered superstructure with the space group of 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅2
 <italic>d</italic>. The inset shows an expanded section of the pattern in the low angle range with 
 <italic>hkl</italic> labels for the highest superstructure reflections. In the inset, the blue curve represents the simulated XRD pattern for the disordered crystal structure with a space group
 <italic>I</italic>4̅
 <italic>m</italic>2. Upon comparing the simulated XRD patterns for both the space groups with the experimental XRD patterns, it can be clearly observed that the experimental patterns match accurately with the superstructure space group 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅2
 <italic>d</italic> and thus rules out the possibility of disordered crystal structure with the space group 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅
 <italic>m</italic>2.
</p>
