<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The article represents the outcome of the production of ferrite nanoparticles and the further evolution of structural and optical properties as a consequence of thermal annealing. The choice of synthesis conditions and temperature range is due to phase transformations according to state diagrams, as well as the possibility of obtaining CeO
 <sub>2</sub>-Fe
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> nanoparticles. As a result of the research, it was found that chemically synthesized nanoparticles are highly disordered polycrystalline structures of cerium oxide, with the presence of an amorphous phase of iron oxide in the structure. During thermal annealing of nanoparticles in an oxygen-containing medium, the formation of new phases containing iron oxides and the following ordering of the crystal structure and magnetic texture is observed. At an annealing temperature over 600 °C, the formation of an ordered magnetic phase of hematite is observed, which result in the appearance of magnetic properties of nanoparticles. The appearance of the hematite phase is a consequence of phase transformations of the oxide forms of iron from amorphous magnetite to hematite with the formation of the transition phase CeFeO
 <sub>3</sub>. In this case, with a growth in the annealing temperature, a decline in the regions of disorder and a decrease in the number of dislocation defects are observed, which is due to the crystallization processes and the emergence of new phases. In accordance with the data of Mössbauer spectroscopy, it was established that a rise in the annealing temperature result in an ordering of the magnetic texture and a decrease in the concentration of cationic and vacancy defects in the structure. It was established that a decrease in amorphous inclusions and a decrease in the oxygen content in the structure as a result of thermal annealing result in a decrease in the degradation rate of nanoparticles. The prospects of using the nanoparticles obtained as the basis of electrode materials for lithium-ion batteries are shown. It was revealed that the emergence of hematite in the phase structure results in a rise in the working life of lithium-ion batteries.
</p>
