<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par16">First-principles calculations for structural relaxations and atomic migrations of Na-bir were investigated by spin-polarized density functional theory (DFT) with the projector augmented-wave (PAW) method using Vienna ab initio simulation package (VASP)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>, 
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. The Perdew–Burke–Ernzerhof (PBE) of generalized-gradient approximation (GGA) was utilized for the exchange-correlation functional
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup>. The Hubbard 
 <italic>U</italic> correction was used for reflecting the strong correlation of 3
 <italic>d</italic> electrons, and the 
 <italic>U</italic> value of 3.9 eV for Mn ion were adopted from the previous study for Na layered oxide
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup>. From the convergence test, a plane-wave cut-off energy of 550 eV was used and 
 <italic>k</italic>-point mesh of 4 × 4 × 2 was sampled. The climbing-image nudged elastic band (ci-NEB) method
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>
 </sup> was utilized to calculate the migration barriers of Mn ions in Na-bir structures. We used Bader charge analysis to estimate the electronic charge transfer
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup>. The calculation model was established based on the structural characterization, such as Rietveld refinement, TGA, and ICP-AES. The hydrated Na-bir was modeled by Na
 <sub>0.25</sub>MnO
 <sub>2</sub>·0.5H
 <sub>2</sub>O of 
 <italic>R</italic>-3m space group consisting of three Na, 12 Mn, and 24 O ions with 6 water molecules, and the partially dehydrated structure was represented by Na
 <sub>0.25</sub>MnO
 <sub>2</sub>·0.08H
 <sub>2</sub>O of 
 <italic>R</italic>-3m space group consisting of three Na, 12 Mn, and 24 O ions with one water molecules. Relaxed 
 <italic>d</italic>-spacing between Mn layers without crystal water is 5.8539 Å, and the 
 <italic>d</italic>-spacing increases to 6.4506 Å when a crystal water remains between Mn layers.
</p>
