<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0680">The physical picture of molecular quantum transitions (MQT), which was previously discussed, does not at all exclude the presence of quantum jumps in general in the entire dynamics of MQT, in spite of the fact that these quantum jumps are absent in our theory of elementary electron-charge transfers [
 <xref rid="bib36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib96" ref-type="bibr">96</xref>]. In our theory, this absence is due to taking into account only the simplest dynamics of MQT, namely, the dynamics that is associated with the interaction of the electronic transition with non-local phonons of the environment; a more complex dynamics of the interaction of the electronic transition with local vibrations is neglected there.
 <xref rid="fn20" ref-type="fn">20</xref> Taking the latter into account will lead to the account in theory, along with the chaotic dynamics of the transient state of electron-vibrational transitions, as well as vibrational quantum jumps. When, together with the reorganization of the nuclear subsystem, the change in the electronic state during the electron transition to the final state is already completed, but in the molecular system there is still some small energy defect, determined by the energy conservation law, then there will be a rapid quantum jump in the vibrational energy of the nuclei, that being already in the final adiabatic electronic state (more precisely, in a state close to adiabatic, if we are talking about the optical excitation of the molecule), in order to eliminate this energy defect. In other words, the quantum jump or transition in the local vibrational mode in the entire process of a molecular “quantum” transition occurs at its final stage, namely, at the moment of transition of a molecule or molecular system from chaotic (dozy-chaos) dynamics to adiabatic (or nearly adiabatic) dynamics. In the experiment, this effect is manifested in the presence of striped spectra and discrete narrow lines in the electron-vibrational spectra that are well-known from the literature (see Refs. [
 <xref rid="bib62" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib63" ref-type="bibr">63</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>]).
</p>
