<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par22">Theoretical works have been performed to understand bonding characteristics of 
 <italic>Pnm2</italic>
 <sub>1</sub>-type arsenic based on the first-principles computational method
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>. Electronic states were calculated by the projector augmented-wave (PAW) method within the framework of density functional theory (DFT)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>
 </sup>. The generalized gradient approximation (GGA) functional proposed by Perdew, Burke and Ernzerhof
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>
 </sup> was employed for the exchange-correlation energy. The DFT-D method was employed for semiempirical correction of the van der Waals interaction
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. The momentum-space formalism was utilized, where the plane-wave cutoff energies are 11.0 and 70.0 Ry for the electronic pseudo-wave function and the pseudo-charge density, respectively
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup>. The energy was minimized with respect to the Kohn-Sham orbitals iteratively using a preconditioned conjugate-gradient method
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup>. Projector functions were generated for the 4 
 <italic>s</italic>, 4
 <italic>p</italic> and 4
 <italic>d</italic> states as the valence states for arsenic atoms. Periodic boundary conditions were applied to all Cartesian directions. Structural optimization was performed using the experimentally determined crystallographic data of the orthorhombic unit cell containing 16 atoms, which are listed in Extended Data Table 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>. The optimized unit cell constants (Å) were a = 10.1594, b = 3.6649 and c = 10.3882. Monkhorst-Pack grids of 2 × 6 × 2 
 <italic>k</italic> points were used for Brillouin zone sampling. We obtained the minimum-energy atomic configuration under 0.0 GPa using the quasi-Newton method. Calculated lattice constants and atomic coordinates are in good agreement with our experimental results. The atomic net charge of each atom and bond overlap populations between each atomic pair were calculated based on the population analysis method
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
