<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The high-quality bulk single crystal with well-defined surface termination provides an ideal platform for understanding the surface catalytic process. Although the details of the mechanism of the O═O bond formation remain unresolved, there is a consensus that the initial discharge of hydroxide ions at a catalytically active center is the initial step. For transition metals such as Co, Ni, and Fe, the crystal field formed by different types of coordination results in distinct spin states and 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub> filling. In octahedrally coordinated systems, the 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub> orbital has a large overlap with the oxygen-related adsorbates, making electron transfer between the active sites and adsorbates more favorable. This results the 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub> filling of surface active centers as an activity descriptor for OER and oxygen reduction reaction (
 <xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>12</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>41</italic>
 </xref>). For our Co
 <sub>3</sub>Sn
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>2</sub> single crystals, the Co atoms in the bulk are octahedrally coordinated and the 
 <italic>d</italic> orbitals are split into threefold degenerate 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2g</sub> states lying lower in energy and two-fold 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub> states at higher energy (
 <xref rid="F4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4D</xref> and fig. S15). The intermediate spin states of Co with a magnetic moment of 0.31 μ
 <sub>B</sub>/Co indicates that the 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub> orbitals are half-filled. However, for the surface Co atoms, the cleaving between S and Sn leads to loss of coordination and further breaking of the degeneracy of the 
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2g</sub> and 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub> orbitals, as illustrated in 
 <xref rid="F4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4D</xref> (
 <xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>42</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R43" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>43</italic>
 </xref>). The half-filled 
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sub>z
  <sup>2</sup>
 </sub> orbital points toward the 
 <italic>p</italic> orbital of the adsorbed hydroxide ions, resulting from the interaction with the bridging O
 <sup>2−</sup> via π-donation. This gives rise to the formation of σ-bonding between the Co atoms and the surface OH
 <sup>−</sup> adsorbates and favors electron transfer between them (
 <xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>12</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>14</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>27</italic>
 </xref>). In addition, loss of coordination for the surface Co octahedral leads to the formation of a highly distorted fivefold coordinated square pyramids. The newly open coordination sites make the uptake of OH
 <sup>−</sup> more favorable (
 <xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>15</italic>
 </xref>). Our theoretical investigations and previous angle-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy measurements confirm that the surface states derived by Co are topologically protected. Different from the spin degeneracy caused by fabricating elemental vacancies, defects, or doping, which are easily destroyed by breaking the surface symmetry, the unoccupied TSSs of Co provide robust active sites for oxygen evolution. On the basis of the reaction mechanism, the kinetics of OH
 <sup>−</sup> bonding via the surface Co atoms are determined by theoretical studies. As shown in fig. S16, OH
 <sup>−</sup> binds to Co atoms and is located above the center of the three Co atoms. The bonding distance is determined to be 2.00 Å, which is shorter than the original Co─Sn bonding distance of 2.67 Å. The isosurface plot of the transferred charge distribution for the slab of the Co octahedral and OH
 <sup>−</sup> adsorbate is shown in 
 <xref rid="F4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4E</xref>. It can be seen that the interfacial charge distributions on the Co atom are dumbbell-like, indicating a 3
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sub>z
  <sup>2</sup>
 </sub> orbital order (
 <xref rid="R43" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>43</italic>
 </xref>), while the charge distribution on Sn is strictly spherical. The total charge on Co
 <sup>δ+</sup> is calculated to be 8.75, while this value for OH
 <sup>−</sup> is 7.67, vividly confirming electron transfer through the Co─O bonding. We also observed the similar electron transfer behavior on other adsorbate such as hydrogen (fig. S17). As two of the most important reaction intermediates of many surface reactions such as hydrogen evolution, hydrogen reduction, oxygen reduction, and H
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>2</sub> electrochemical synthesis, our results indicate that one can efficiently control the surface reactions by carefully tailoring the robust surface states of topological phase catalysts.
</p>
