<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">Recent torque magnetometry measurements of the anisotropic susceptibility within the 
 <italic>ab</italic> planes of YBa
 <sub>2</sub>Cu
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>6+
  <italic>δ</italic>
 </sub> (YBCO) revealed that the in-plane anisotropy displays a significant increase with a distinct cusp at 
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sup>*</sup>, consistent with the possible existence of a nematic phase transition
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>. However, in YBCO, the fourfold (
 <italic>C</italic>
 <sub>4</sub>) rotational symmetry is already broken due to the orthorhombic crystal structure with one-dimensional (1D) CuO chains, and thus no further rotational symmetry breaking is expected. Moreover, in bilayer YBCO, the coupling of the CuO
 <sub>2</sub> planes in the unit cell may further affect the symmetry breaking
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. Therefore, the investigation of an underdoped single-layer system with tetragonal symmetry, such as hole-doped HgBa
 <sub>2</sub>CuO
 <sub>4+
  <italic>δ</italic>
 </sub> (Hg1201), is essential to clarify whether a nematic phase transition is an intrinsic and universal property of the high-
 <italic>T</italic>
 <sub>c</sub> cuprates. Figure 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref> displays the temperature-doping phase diagram of Hg1201. Similar to other hole-doped cuprates, the phase diagram contains CDW, superconducting and pseudogap regimes
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>. Short-range CDW order along [100]/[010], with wave vector close to 0.28 r.l.u., forms a dome-shaped boundary inside the pseudogap regime
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>. In zero magnetic field, CDW domains with typical size of a few nanometres appear.
</p>
