<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Here we show one example of the quality of the data that can be collected with POWGEN on hydrogenous material for structure solution and refinement. Citrate salts have many applications in industry. Recently, a family of compounds with the general formula Li
 <italic>M</italic>HC
 <sub>6</sub>H
 <sub>5</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> (
 <italic>M</italic> = Li, Na, K and Rb) were prepared and their structures were solved by powder X-ray diffraction (XRD) measurements (Cigler &amp; Kaduk, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb9"> ▸</xref>). However, since XRD is not sensitive to hydrogen, their positions were calculated using density functional theory (DFT). A powder sample of LiKHC
 <sub>6</sub>H
 <sub>5</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> with a mass of 1.22 g was loaded in a 6 mm vanadium can and measured for 2.6 h in the sample changer using a center wavelength of 2.665 Å at room temperature. The DFT structure was used as a starting point and refining the structure gave a fit with a weighted 
 <italic>R</italic> factor 
 <italic>R</italic>
 <sub>wp</sub> of 1.57. To test how sensitive the data are towards hydrogen, all the hydrogen atoms were removed from the refinement and a Fourier difference map was generated using 
 <italic>GSAS-II</italic> (Toby &amp; Von Dreele, 2013
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb39"> ▸</xref>). All six hydrogen positions are clearly identifiable from these data, as seen in Fig. 8
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig8"> ▸</xref>, which points to the feasibility of using NPD at POWGEN for locating hydrogen atoms in molecular compounds. Table 3
 <xref ref-type="table" rid="table3"> ▸</xref> lists the coordinates of the atoms calculated via DFT along with those obtained from neutron refinement. Currently, samples with nearly 50 at.% hydrogen have been successfully measured on the instrument. Preliminary measurements have indicated that, in addition to locating the hydrogen atoms in molecular compounds, the structure of water in mineral samples can be resolved.
</p>
