<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Δ
 <italic>S</italic> mostly corresponds to the change from molecular hydrogen gas to dissolved solid hydrogen [
 <xref rid="B328-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">328</xref>]. It amounts approximately to the standard entropy of hydrogen (130 J·K
 <sup>−1</sup>mol
 <sup>−1</sup>) and is, therefore, frequently taken as a constant for all metal-hydrogen systems [
 <xref rid="B328-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">328</xref>]. Δ
 <italic>H</italic> must be the dehydrogenation reaction enthalpy and each material must report it. However, the formation enthalpy is sometimes used instead, particularly if the material is a metal and its hydride. The enthalpies of formation and dehydrogenation have been related, directly or indirectly, to the bond energy, i.e., the stability of the compound [
 <xref rid="B328-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">328</xref>,
 <xref rid="B329-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">329</xref>]. The reported dehydrogenation enthalpies were used to construct the phase diagrams that are presented in this review. The representative values are condensed in 
 <xref rid="materials-12-02724-t021" ref-type="table">Table 21</xref>, altogether with formation enthalpies and the activation energies. The thermodynamic data is concentrated mainly in the alanates of group 1, a lot of data is missing on other alanates. The calculated and experimental data of formation enthalpy and dehydrogenation enthalpy show good correlation. However, an in-deep comment on the dispersion of the thermodynamic data is needed. Along with the several consulted papers, different experimental techniques and conditions were used to determine the thermodynamic data. The most used techniques are the differential scanning calorimetry (with variations, such as high-pressure, with or without hydrogen flow, different of values of flows, etc.), pressure-composition isotherms, and theoretical calculations (different levels of theory, programs, basis sets, etc.). Thus, the natural result is the dispersion of data. Perhaps, a standard method will be advisable. Meanwhile, the activation energies present the most disperse values, which is due to the additive and the history of the materials (mechanical milling, purification, recrystallization, cycling, etc.). Additionally, some of the original data are explicitly related to the released mol of H
 <sub>2</sub>, meanwhile, other data is not clearly reported of mol of which compound is related. 
</p>
