<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Formation of Ca and Mg-carbonate phases was predicted by the PHREEQC calculations and observed in the experiments. Unlike Na
 <sup>+</sup> and K
 <sup>+</sup>, Ca
 <sup>2+</sup>, and Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> effectively outcompete Li
 <sup>+</sup> for carbonate in solution. In the experiments with 0.033 M CaCl
 <sub>2</sub> (0.1 M ionic strength), zabuyelite was observed to form in addition to calcite. Although the DFT simulations indicate that divalent ions could significantly alter the surface stabilities, a very similar, elongated morphology of the zabuyelite crystals was observed in the presence of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup>. There is some indication that the Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> does interact with the crystal surface of zabuyelite as the {110} surface width decreases on these crystals. This agrees with the simulations, which suggest that divalent, monatomic cations will make this surface less stable than observed with only water and monovalent, monatomic cations. In addition, the presence of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> appears to affect the crystallinity of zabuyelite as the FWHM of the carbonate symmetrical stretching Raman band increased. This could be related to a small amount of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> in the zabuyelite structure. A complete solid solution is not expected as the two carbonate minerals crystallize with different crystal structures. There was no clear shift in the center of the Raman band for the carbonate symmetrical stretch and no Ca was observed in the EDX spectra of the zabuyelite crystals. Therefore, the amount of Ca incorporated is expected to be less than 1 wt %, the detection limit of the EDX. Up to 2 wt % of Li has been reported in calcite,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref63">63</xref>
 </sup> however, whether the reverse is possible is unclear as Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> is considerably larger than the Li
 <sup>+</sup> ion (0.99 Å versus 0.68 Å, respectively
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref64">64</xref>
 </sup>). Thus, it may be that there is insufficient space to incorporate larger ions in significant amounts without disrupting the crystal structure. This would fit with the experimental work with K
 <sup>+</sup>, another large cation (1.33 Å
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref64">64</xref>
 </sup>), for which no solid-solution compositions exist with Li
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub> even at elevated temperatures.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref65">65</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
