<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Calcite formation in the 0.033 M CaCl
 <sub>2</sub> experiments (0.1 M ionic strength) is clearly influenced by the presence of Li
 <sup>+</sup> in solution. Two different morphologies of calcite were observed: a rhombohedral-like shape, and larger, platy crystals in some cases with 3-fold rotational symmetry. The triangular shape at the center of the platy calcite crystal shown in 
 <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>
 </xref>b is very similar to what has been observed previously on {0001} calcite surfaces stabilized by the adsorption of Li
 <sup>+</sup>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref66">66</xref>
 </sup> Viewing the calcite crystal along the [0001] direction would also explain the potential twin observed below the crystal with 3-fold rotation, as this is one of the twin planes of calcite. Similar to the zabuyelite precipitation mechanism proposed above, twins on the calcite (0001) surface are predicted to be the only type of twins that can occur via 2D heterogeneous nucleation.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref67">67</xref>
 </sup> In contrast, in the Mg-bearing solutions, the Mg-carbonate dypingite dominates the precipitation of carbonate. However, zabuyelite growth in the presence of lower concentrations of MgCl
 <sub>2</sub> to those used here produces shorter crystals.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref68">68</xref>
 </sup> These crystals have a morphology that is close to that expected based on our simulations. Unlike calcite, dypingite crystals do not change their morphology when grown in different Li:Mg ratios and show a morphology consistent with that of the dypingite crystals in the absence of Li
 <sup>+</sup>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref69">69</xref>
 </sup> This indicates that Li
 <sup>+</sup> does not directly influence the growth morphology of the dypingite. Interestingly, previous experiments at the synthesis temperatures used, more commonly produce less hydrated phases including nesquehonite (MgCO
 <sub>3</sub>·3H
 <sub>2</sub>O) and hydromagnesite Mg
 <sub>5</sub>(CO
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>4</sub>·(OH)
 <sub>2</sub>·4H
 <sub>2</sub>O.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref70">70</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref71">71</xref>
 </sup> Given that Li
 <sup>+</sup> is proposed to aid the crystallization of other carbonates based on its strongly hydrated nature, these results imply that this effect is minimal on other strongly hydrated ions such as Mg
 <sup>2+</sup>. Alternatively, hydration is not the dominant barrier for anhydrous Mg-carbonate formation as proposed in a recent paper by Xu et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref72">72</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
