<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Although the crystal structures of the η′ and η″ phases are both superstructures based on the parent orthorhombic unit cell (space group 
 <italic>Cmcm</italic>) of the η phase, the ordered manner in which Al/Fe atoms arrange in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites is quite different from each other. Since the irregular atomic arrangement occurs in the twin boundary region, only the motif structure with the chemical formula of Fe
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>7</sub> is considered for the η″ phase. In the η′ phase, one-third of the Al3-equivalent sites are occupied exclusively by Al atoms while all the Al2-equivalent sites are vacant (bottom left of 
 <xref rid="F0010">Figure 10</xref>), giving rise to the tripled unit cell for the superlattice structure in the orthorhombic 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis direction and the stoichiometric composition of Fe
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>8</sub> [
 <xref rid="CIT0024">24</xref>]. Of the 18 Al2- and Al3-equivalent sites in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain, the 5th, 9th, 14th, and 18th sites (i.e. two-ninths of the 18 sites) are occupied in a regular manner exclusively by Al atoms. In the η″ phase, on the other hand, one-fourth of the Al2-equivalent sites are occupied by both Fe and Al atoms, while one-fourth of the Al3-equivalent sites are occupied exclusively by Al atoms (bottom right of 
 <xref rid="F0010">Figure 10</xref>), giving rise to the doubled superlattice structure and the stoichiometric composition of Fe
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>7</sub>. Of the 12 Al2- and Al3-equivalent sites in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain, the 1st, 5th, and 9th sites (i.e. every fourth of the 12 sites) are occupied by both Fe and Al atoms. This confirms that Fe atoms also occupy the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites when the Fe content increases in the low-temperature phases (from η′ to η″ phases), as observed in the high-temperature η phase by Becker and Leineweber [
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>]. Interestingly, once the Fe atoms start to occupy the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites, the Fe atoms prefer to occupy the Al2-equivalent sites while the Al atoms change to prefer to the Al2-equivalent sites together with Fe atoms.
</p>
