<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data">
 <p>Supplementary material for this article is available at 
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://advances.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/full/5/8/eaaw9867/DC1" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://advances.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/full/5/8/eaaw9867/DC1</ext-link>
 </p>
 <p>Calculation details</p>
 <p>Single-crystal XRD measurements</p>
 <p>Fig. S1. Band structure of Co
  <sub>3</sub>Sn
  <sub>2</sub>S
  <sub>2</sub> with different strength of SOC.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S2. Surface band structure of Co
  <sub>3</sub>Sn
  <sub>2</sub>S
  <sub>2</sub> with different strength of SOC.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S3. The surface states contributed by S atoms, and Sn atoms, respectively.</p>
 <p>Fig. S4. The surface states of Co
  <sub>3</sub>Sn
  <sub>2</sub>S
  <sub>2</sub> with S termination.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S5. Polarization curves of a Cu wire with silver paint and Co
  <sub>3</sub>Sn
  <sub>2</sub>S
  <sub>2</sub> crystal.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S6. Stability test of the crushed single-crystal catalyst on Ni foam.</p>
 <p>Fig. S7. SEM image of the crystal.</p>
 <p>Fig. S8. EDS spectra of the Co
  <sub>3</sub>Sn
  <sub>2</sub>S
  <sub>2</sub> single crystal.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S9. Powder XRD measurement of the crushed single crystal.</p>
 <p>Fig. S10. Crystal structure of Co
  <sub>3</sub>Sn
  <sub>2</sub>S
  <sub>2</sub> at 100 K.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S11. TEM image of the single crystal prepared using the FIB technique.</p>
 <p>Fig. S12. ZFC/FC curves for the single crystal.</p>
 <p>Fig. S13. XPS survey spectrum of the bulk single crystal.</p>
 <p>Fig. S14. High-resolution XPS spectra of Sn 3
  <italic>d</italic>.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S15. The Co atoms (red) in Co
  <sub>3</sub>Sn
  <sub>2</sub>S
  <sub>2</sub> are octahedrally coordinated.
 </p>
 <p>Fig. S16. The adsorption position of OH group on the crystal surface.</p>
 <p>Fig. S17. The adsorption position of H atom on the Co
  <sub>3</sub>Sn
  <sub>2</sub>S
  <sub>2</sub> single-crystal surface.
 </p>
 <p>Table S1. Crystallographic and refinement parameters of Co
  <sub>3</sub>Sn
  <sub>2</sub>S
  <sub>2</sub>.
 </p>
 <p>Table S2. Fractional atomic coordinates of the crystal.</p>
 <p>Table S3. Selected interatomic distances.</p>
 <p>Data S1. Crystallographic information file obtained at 100 K.</p>
 <p>Data S2. Crystallographic information file obtained at 300 K.</p>
 <p>References (
  <xref rid="R44" ref-type="bibr">
   <italic>44</italic>
  </xref>–
  <xref rid="R47" ref-type="bibr">
   <italic>47</italic>
  </xref>)
 </p>
</supplementary-material>
