<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) measurements were performed in air under open-circuit potential (OCP) conditions in a symmetrical configuration to extract the corresponding values of the electrolyte and electrode contributions. A dense electrolyte pellet of LSGM (La
 <sub>0.83</sub>Sr
 <sub>0.17</sub>Ga
 <sub>0.8</sub>Mg
 <sub>0.2</sub>O
 <sub>3−δ</sub>) was used and was prepared in our laboratory. An ink of the cathode material was created with the Sr
 <sub>0.9</sub>Ba
 <sub>0.1</sub>Co
 <sub>0.95</sub>Ru
 <sub>0.05</sub>O
 <sub>3−δ</sub> powders. First, the material was ball-milled in ethanol to break the agglomerates and then the dried powders were mixed with a binder (V-006 from Heraeus, Madrid, Spain). The ink was symmetrically painted over the electrolyte onto both surfaces in Sr
 <sub>0.9</sub>Ba
 <sub>0.1</sub>Co
 <sub>0.95</sub>Ru
 <sub>0.05</sub>O
 <sub>3−δ</sub>/LSGM/Sr
 <sub>0.9</sub>Ba
 <sub>0.1</sub>Co
 <sub>0.95</sub>Ru
 <sub>0.05</sub>O
 <sub>3−δ</sub> configuration. The cells were calcined at 1000 °C for 2 h to obtain a good adherence between the cathodes and the electrolytes according to a procedure previously optimized in our laboratories for doped-SrCoO
 <sub>3</sub> cathode powders. Subsequently, two Pt electrodes were painted onto the cathode surfaces and calcined at 800 °C for 1 h to ensure equipotential conditions. EIS was then performed in potentiostatic mode, decreasing the temperature from 900 to 600 °C, with an excitation voltage of 50 mV in the range of 1 kHz to 100 MHz. All the cell impedances were normalized by the superficial area so that they have the units of Ω cm
 <sup>2</sup>. The electrode endurance was evaluated under a constant cathodic current density of 200 mA·cm
 <sup>−2</sup> at 850 and 800 °C for 20 h. The current passage was interrupted to collect the electrochemical impedance spectra in open circuit. The data obtained were analyzed with the Zview software (version 3.5) (Scribner Associates). The EIS spectra were collected using an AUTOLAB PGSTAT 302 (NorECs Norwegian Electro Ceramics AS, Oslo, Norway) from ECO CHEMIE.
</p>
