<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>At lower temperatures, some LC compounds form the stacked hexatic phase (Hex-B), which differs from the Sm-A phase by the presence of the sixfold long-range in-layer BO order (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f003">Figure 3</xref>c). At the same time, the positional order remains short-range, however the positional correlation length increases compared to its value in the Sm-A phase. Due to the interaction between the molecules, the intermolecular bonds have approximately the same orientation in the neighboring layers, but the shear modulus between the layers remains zero. As a result, in reciprocal space the BO order in the Hex-B phase manifests itself by a sixfold modulation of the scattering intensity at 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm119">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <msub>
      <mi>q</mi>
      <mn>0</mn>
     </msub>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> along the azimuthal direction, which at lower temperatures leads to splitting of the scattering ring into six distinct peaks [
 <xref rid="B20-materials-12-03464" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B61-materials-12-03464" ref-type="bibr">61</xref>] (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-03464-f003">Figure 3</xref>d). It was shown that due to the interaction between the positional order and BO order thermal fluctuations, the radial cross-section through the centers of the hexatic peaks changes to the square root of the Lorentzian function close to the Sm-A–Hex-B phase transition [
 <xref rid="B17-materials-12-03464" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B62-materials-12-03464" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>], while far away from the transition temperature it is well described by the simple Lorentzian function (Equation (15)). The same interaction also slightly shifts the position of the scattering peaks along 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm120">
   <mrow>
    <mi>q</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> over the value proportional to the mean squared modulus of the hexatic BO order parameter 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm121">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <msup>
      <mrow>
       <mrow>
        <mo stretchy="false">〈</mo>
        <mo>|</mo>
        <mrow>
         <msub>
          <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">Ψ</mi>
          <mn>6</mn>
         </msub>
        </mrow>
        <mo>|</mo>
       </mrow>
      </mrow>
      <mn>2</mn>
     </msup>
     <mo stretchy="false">〉</mo>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> [
 <xref rid="B62-materials-12-03464" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>].
</p>
