<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Because of its high chemical stability and high photocatalytic activity, nano-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> has great development prospects in the fields of environmental protection [
 <xref rid="B1-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>], such as in photocatalytic disinfection, antibacterial use [
 <xref rid="B2-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>], wastewater treatment [
 <xref rid="B4-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>], air purification [
 <xref rid="B5-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>], and so on. Especially in the face of the current difficulty of eliminating volatile organic compound (VOC) pollution in the air, TiO
 <sub>2</sub> photocatalysis technology has shown unique advantages [
 <xref rid="B6-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. However, the preparation cost of nano-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> is high, and the process is difficult to control, meaning that nano-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> has poor dispersion and a wide particle-size distribution. Moreover, the photocatalytic performance restricts its development and application: firstly, the band gap of 3.2 eV limits it to using only ultraviolet light below 387.5 nm in wavelength [
 <xref rid="B8-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. Secondly, the electron and hole produced by the light excitation of TiO
 <sub>2</sub> recombine very easily [
 <xref rid="B9-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. Therefore, developing preparation technology of TiO
 <sub>2</sub> with good dispersion and a uniform particle size and exploring a way to broaden the light response range and inhibit the electron and hole recombination of TiO
 <sub>2</sub> are the key problems which need to be solved urgently in order to develop the commercialization and advanced application of nano-TiO
 <sub>2</sub>.
</p>
