<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The most common synthesis method of nano-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> is the sol-gel method [
 <xref rid="B11-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. However, the raw material titanium alkoxide is relatively expensive, and the whole process not only produces a large number of organic compounds but also needs to use a large number of organic solvents, resulting in organic waste pollution, causing problems for the mass production of nano-TiO
 <sub>2</sub>. The preparation of nano-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> by the precipitation method has the advantages of a cheap raw material, a simple process and a non-toxic organic solvent, which is convenient for industrial production. However, the traditional precipitation method generally uses an intermittent stirred tank with low mass transfer and microscopic mixing performance as the reactor. The nucleation and growth process occur before the homogeneous mixing of the titanium precursor and precipitant in the intermittent stirred tank, and there is a high level of non-uniformity in this process. It is difficult to move the completely grown particles from the intermittent stirred tank in time, resulting in those particles possibly being used as a crystal nucleus to grow further. As a result, the particle sizes are uneven and seriously agglomerate. High-gravity technology has been proven to be an excellent technology for the preparation of high-quality nanometer powder. The rotating packed bed (RPB) [
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>] is the typical reactor of high-gravity technology, which uses a motor to drive the packing to rotate at a high speed, resulting in a huge centrifugal force field. In the RPB, the raw material liquid is immediately cut and dispersed by the packing to form a very small liquid microelement, and a uniform microscopic mixing effect is obtained [
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. The nucleation and growth of the particles occur in a uniform supersaturation environment, and so the particles sizes are similar. The particles in a strong centrifugal force field will be immediately thrown out of the packing and separated from the raw materials and will not grow further, meaning that the particles are able to maintain good dispersion. A large number of studies have confirmed that RPB is an excellent reactor for the preparation of nanoparticles by the precipitation method, such as ZrO
 <sub>2</sub> [
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], Fe
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub> [
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], Mg(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> [
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>], and some composite materials [
 <xref rid="B19-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>], etc. However, there are few reports into the preparation of nano-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> by RPB.
</p>
