<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this paper, TiO
 <sub>2</sub> and Fe
 <sup>3+</sup> ions with in-situ doped TiO
 <sub>2</sub> (Fe-TiO
 <sub>2</sub>) nanoparticles were prepared by the direct precipitation method with an impinging stream-rotating packed bed (IS-RPB) [
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,
 <xref rid="B26-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,
 <xref rid="B27-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>] as a reactor and used for the photodegradation of gaseous toluene as a typical pollutant in air. The main purpose of this work is to make use of the efficient mass transfer capacity and strong microscopic mixing characteristics of IS-RPB to obtain nano-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> with high dispersion and small particle size and to prepare Fe-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> by uniformly doping Fe
 <sup>3+</sup> in TiO
 <sub>2</sub>. The doping of Fe
 <sup>3+</sup> shows the ability to enhance the response of TiO
 <sub>2</sub> to visible light and reduce the rebinding of electrons and holes, which is beneficial to improving the photocatalytic performance. The morphology, structure and optical response of TiO
 <sub>2</sub> and Fe-TiO
 <sub>2</sub> were analyzed by various characterization methods. The photocatalytic activity of the photocatalyst was studied by the degradation of gaseous toluene as the typical VOC. Toluene was taken as the target VOC mainly because it is one of the most common pollutants both indoors or outdoors [
 <xref rid="B28-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>,
 <xref rid="B29-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. Furthermore, there have been many studies on the photocatalytic degradation of toluene, and thus there is a sufficient theoretical basis and practical feasibility [
 <xref rid="B30-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>,
 <xref rid="B31-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,
 <xref rid="B32-nanomaterials-09-01173" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>].
</p>
