<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par24">All electrochemical measurements were performed using a Biologic SP-150 potentiostat with a single cell, three electrode setup in 1 M H
 <sub>2</sub>SO
 <sub>4</sub> (unless otherwise stated). Catalyst powders were drop-cast onto a glassy carbon working electrode following the method of Gao et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup> This involved sonicating an ink consisting of 10 mg catalyst, 80 µL Nafion and 1 mL (3:1) water: ethanol for an hour. Thirty microlitre of the suspension was then drop cast on to the surface of the glassy carbon electrode (surface area 0.071 cm
 <sup>2</sup>). Carbon felt and 3 M Ag/AgCl were used as the counter and reference electrodes, respectively. Identical experiments were repeated with a saturated Hg/Hg
 <sub>2</sub>SO4 reference electrode in order to rule out any silver leakage as the source of improved performance. The electrode potentials were converted to the NHE scale using 
 <italic>E</italic>(NHE) = 
 <italic>E</italic>(Ag/AgCl) + 0.209 V or 
 <italic>E</italic>(NHE) = 
 <italic>E</italic>(Hg/Hg
 <sub>2</sub>SO
 <sub>4</sub>) + 0.658 V; and the ohmic resistances were compensated. Polarisation datasets were obtained using cyclic voltammetry at a scan rate of 100 mV s
 <sup>−1</sup>. Tafel plots were obtained by linear sweep voltammetry with constant stirring at scan rates of 2 mV s
 <sup>−1</sup>. Nyquist plots were obtained with frequencies ranging between 200 kHz and 1 mHz. The electrochemically-active surface area (ECSA) was obtained by sweeping the applied potential over a small potential range in the non-Faradaic region (in this case between 0.05 V and 0.25 V (vs. NHE)) at various scan rates (20, 40, 60, 80, 100, 120, 160, 200, 250, and 300 mV s
 <sup>−1</sup>). Capacitive currents at 0.15 V (vs. NHE) were then plotted against scan rate, with the gradient being the double layer capacitance, C
 <sub>dl</sub>. Due to their proportional relationship, ECSA can be estimated from the calculated 
 <italic>C</italic>
 <sub>dl</sub> values
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup>. Gas chromatography (GC) was performed using an Agilent GC 7890 A with a thermal conductivity detector. The GC system was calibrated using certified standards of hydrogen at various volume % in argon (CK Gas Product Limited (UK)) before use. For chronoamperometry, a potential of −320 mV (vs. NHE) was applied which corresponded to the overpotential required for 
 <italic>j</italic> = –10 mA cm
 <sup>−2</sup>. Faradaic efficiency measurements were obtained in a single airtight cell after being degassed under argon. A two electrode setup consisting of a platinum counter electrode and the catalyst-deposited glassy carbon working electrode was used for electrolysis. Galvanostatic electrolysis was then performed with a current density of 3.4 mA cm
 <sup>−2</sup> being applied. Twenty-five microlitre samples of the headspace were directly injected into the GC at various intervals. The Faradaic efficiency was then calculated as the ratio of expected H
 <sub>2</sub>% in the headspace (as calculated from the charge passed) to the H
 <sub>2</sub>% detected by GC measurements.
</p>
