<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In 2016, Q. Xiong et al. published a review [
 <xref rid="B9-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>] on synthesis and applications of metal halide perovskite nanomaterials. In this review, authors focused on precise and detailed description of the synthetic routes for nanocrystals, nanowires, and nanoplates formation, including hot-injection, ligand-assistant reprecipitation, and chemical vapor deposition methods with focus on the crystal formation mechanism. In 2018, M.V. Kovalenko, L. Manna, et al. in their review [
 <xref rid="B10-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>] highlighted the challenges and opportunities of colloidal lead-halide perovskite nanocrystals as a perspective materials to replace the conventional semiconductor quantum dots. Indeed, lead-halide perovskite NCs are believed to become as novel single-photon sources and highly efficient active down-converting media in lightning applications. The authors emphasized the existence of some ambiguities in the crystal structure, related energy structure, and contribution of different crystal phases and/or chemical composition to the NC emission. Along with the investigation of the perovskite nanocrystals, a lot of work was done in the research field devoted to 2D perovskite materials. In 2017, W. A. Tisdale et al. published a review on perovskite nanoplatelets [
 <xref rid="B11-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>], where they showed the 2D materials advantages over the bulk materials, and discussed in detail perovskite nanoplatelets synthesis, photophysics, and stability. Next, in 2018, Letian Dou et al. published a review [
 <xref rid="B12-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>] on 2D perovskite materials with extensive overview of their applications. It worth to be noted that yet another set of reviews were published in 2019 in Chemical Reviews [
 <xref rid="B13-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-materials-12-03845" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>], with the topics covered there including metal halide perovskite nanocrystals, layered halide perovskites, perovskite interfaces, and halide perovskite photovoltaics.
</p>
