<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">The study of a relativistic interaction, i.e., the spin-orbit coupling (SOC), has been one of the central themes in the context of spintronics, branch of electronics aiming at utilizing the electron’s spin degree of freedom for device applications
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup>. Many intriguing SOC-related phenomena were observed, such as spin relaxation
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>
 </sup>, optical spin orientation
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>, spin Hall effects
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>, persistent spin structures
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>
 </sup>, hidden spin polarization in centrosymmetric systems
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>, and the spin galvanic effects
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>. In particular, Dresselhaus
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup> and Rashba
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup> demonstrated that SOC splits spin-up and spin-down bands in nonmagnetic systems lacking inversion symmetry, inducing an effective magnetic field that depends on the crystal momentum 
 <bold>k</bold>. Although the Dresselhaus and Rashba effects lead to different spin polarizations of the energy bands, they result in a similar band dispersion: the original spin degenerate bands split so that spin-up and spin-down bands shift towards opposite directions in k-space, as shown in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>. Even though the Rashba effect is generally associated to heterostructures and surfaces, as due to 2D structural inversion asymmetry, a giant Rashba effect has been recently observed in bulk polar/ferroelectric systems
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>. Sometimes, Dresselhaus and Rashba terms coexist
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>, giving rise to interesting physics and applications. For example, if the magnitudes of Dresselhaus and Rashba terms are equal, the spin–orbit field is unidirectional, resulting in a momentum-independent spin configuration (i.e., the so-called “persistent spin texture”), which could support an extraordinarily long spin lifetime of carriers
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>. To further develop the field of spin–orbitronics (a branch of spintronics)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>, it is of great interest to explore SOC-related phenomena beyond the well-known Dresselhaus-Rashba effects. Indeed, a first contribution in this direction has been recently provided by a careful analysis of bulk and site symmetries of crystalline materials, that allowed for a unified description of spin-splitting effects and, more importantly, to unveil hidden spin-polarization phenomena in centrosymmetric systems
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>, recently observed in several layered compounds
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
