<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Alanates are like other hydrogen storage materials, in the sense that no material fulfills all of the requirements of hydrogen capacity, dehydrogenation temperatures, or reversibility. The DOE (Department of Energy, USA [
 <xref rid="B15-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]) had proposed along several decades the figures of merit for hydrogen storage materials and systems, specifying the type of applications (portable, light-duty vehicles, etc.). In general, high hydrogen storage capacity (6.5 wt.% [
 <xref rid="B15-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]) and reversibility would prevail as the two fundamental characteristics of hydrogen storage materials. The exigencies of the DOE are very rigorous, particularly for light-duty vehicles applications [
 <xref rid="B15-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], and they include (not limited to) the quantity of stored/released hydrogen (mass and volume of a complete system, 6.5 wt.% and 5 vol.%), reversibility, kinetics (optimum time to charge a hydrogen tank, 3–5 min), minimum number of cycles of hydrogen charge/discharge (1500), operational temperature (−40 to 85 °C), operational pressure (delivery pressure 5–12 bar), cost of the system (266 USD/kg H
 <sub>2</sub>), safety, etc. Other factors to be careful with are the thermodynamics (related to the dehydrogenation temperature, but also to the quantity of heat added/removed to/from the system), the onboard efficiency (90%), etc. Moreover, in the future, factors such as recyclability, sustainability, or alanate production from recycled materials [
 <xref rid="B16-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>] must also be included as critical factors. However, niche applications for different applications [
 <xref rid="B18-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>] could be developed while using different hydrogen storage materials, including the alanates. These niche applications must meet the particular characteristics of the hydrogen production type and the needs of the final user [
 <xref rid="B18-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,
 <xref rid="B19-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. Nonetheless, the alanate family would allow for the development of new materials. The present work covers the general synthesis procedures, structure, thermodynamics, and hydrogen storage capacity of the known alanates (whenever available). Additionally, double cation alanates or anion substituted materials are also presented and discussed. In the last part of the work, we present a compilation of IR (Infrared) spectroscopy, Raman spectroscopy, and thermodynamics data, along with some general tendencies.
</p>
