<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0655">Consider the basics of quantum mechanics from another point of view. Molecules and atoms are similar to each other. Their similarity lies in the fact that the structural elements of both microsystems are nuclei and electrons. The main difference between these microsystems is the number of nuclei: atoms are electron-nuclear microsystems that have only one single nucleus, while molecules are electron-nuclear microsystems that generally have a large number of nuclei (at least two). It is this well-known and trivial fact that ultimately serves as the divide between quantum and quantum-classical mechanics. Quantum mechanics was created at one time to describe the electronic structure of atoms and quantum transitions of electrons between different states of this structure. In stationary states of atoms, due to the massive and single nucleus, the electronic structure is formed as a result of the movement of electrons in the electric field of this single nucleus. In stationary states of molecules, compared with atoms, due to the presence of several massive nuclei, the dynamic roles of electrons and nuclei change places. Here, not the only heavy nucleus, being “turned off” from the full-fledged dynamics of the entire atomic system, is the “main” source of the electric field that forms the electronic structure of the microsystem. In molecules, such a “main” source of the electric field is the subsystem of light valence electrons, which creates an adiabatic potential that forms the nuclear structure of the microsystem and in which the nuclei make their oscillatory movements. In other words, in the adiabatic approximation, these electrons themselves are “turned off” from the full-fledged dynamics of the entire molecular system. It is this fact of “switching off” in the adiabatic approximation of the valence electron subsystem from full-fledged dynamics that is the condition for the applicability of quantum mechanics to molecular systems. Going beyond the adiabatic approximation leads to the need to consider the full-fledged dynamics of not only nuclei, but also valence electrons. However, due to the incomparability of their masses, in the framework of quantum mechanics this joint dynamics, as shown by the author on the example of elementary electron transfers in condensed matter, becomes singular. In other words, in molecular physics, quantum mechanics works only within the framework of the adiabatic approximation and ceases to work when it goes beyond its framework. The same statement applies to chemical physics, which studies the dynamics of elementary chemical reactions, or in the simplest case, the dynamics of elementary electron transfers in condensed matter, which we consider in this article.</p>
