<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>As shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-09-01241-f001">Figure 1</xref>, 20% of emitted light is extracted outside of OLED devices; however, 80% of emitted light is trapped inside OLED devices and dissipated, which is caused by the difference of the refractive index of each layer comprised in OLED devices [
 <xref rid="B5-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. Various ways were tried to extract the trapped light from the OLED devices [
 <xref rid="B5-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. Several methods have been proposed to enhance the light extraction from OLEDs, including mesh structures on the glass substrate [
 <xref rid="B8-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>], silica micro spheres [
 <xref rid="B9-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>], scattering layers [
 <xref rid="B10-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>], embedded low-index grids [
 <xref rid="B11-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>], photonic crystals [
 <xref rid="B12-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>], micro pyramids [
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>], and micro lens arrays [
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. However, these methods could be used for limited applications such as illumination products without pixels. Most methods for enhancing the efficiency of OLED are implemented on the outer side of the glass substrate, where the distance between the light source and the emitting structures is relatively long, due to the thickness of the glass substrate. In display products with many pixels, these methods cause image blurring, which is a mixture of light from adjacent pixels and poor image quality by a diffusion effect. Other approaches have been studied to enhance the light extraction of OLEDs, adopting nano sized structures to OLEDs. By the scattering effect of the nano structures, such as gratings [
 <xref rid="B19-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>], metallic nanoparticles [
 <xref rid="B21-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B22-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>,
 <xref rid="B23-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B25-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>], and buckled substrates [
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B26-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,
 <xref rid="B27-nanomaterials-09-01241" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>], the light trapped in glass substrate can escape. However, nano structures have limited application in OLEDs due to the complicated process, requiring high cost. Additionally, their size limitation impedes their implementation in practical OLED products. Hence, the nanoparticles fabricated by easy methods or by methods compatible with conventional manufacturing processes suitable for large areas are more beneficial for practical OLEDs devices.
</p>
