<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this work, Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors before and after N
 <sup>3–</sup> doping were systematically prepared and analyzed. SIMS measurement revealed that the average contents of N
 <sup>3–</sup> ion for LCSON, LSSON, and LBSON were 0.003, 0.009, and 0.032, respectively, probably implying that Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4−δ</sub>N
 <sub>2/3δ</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors with larger ion size can easily accommodate more N
 <sup>3–</sup> ions in the crystal lattice sites. Furthermore, the N
 <sup>3–</sup> sited in the host lattices was corroborated by IR and XPS analyses, i.e., the chemical shift of Si–O stretching mode from 825 to 817 cm
 <sup>–1</sup> after N
 <sup>3–</sup> doping (for LSSON) and the chemical shift of Si 2p binding energy from 101.5 to 100.7 eV and the presence of the N 1s binding energy at 393.4 eV after N
 <sup>3–</sup> doping (for LSSON). From the PL spectra in Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors before and after N
 <sup>3–</sup> doping, it was verified that the enhanced emission intensity of the phosphors is most likely due to N
 <sup>3–</sup> doping. The change of the emission band maxima was also investigated in these phosphors. In Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors, the maximum wavelengths of the emission bands were red-shifted in the order Ca &lt; Ba &lt; Sr, which is not consistent with the trend of crystal field splitting: Ba &lt; Sr &lt; Ca. This discrepancy between the shift of emission band maxima and trend based on the crystal field splitting was clearly explained by electron–electron repulsions among polyhedra, LiO
 <sub>4</sub>–MO
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>, SiO
 <sub>4</sub>–MO
 <sub>
  <italic>n</italic>
 </sub>, and MO
 <sub>
  <italic>n</italic>
 </sub>–M’O
 <sub>
  <italic>n</italic>
 </sub> associated with structural difference in host lattices. Therefore, the energy levels associated with the 4f
 <sup>6</sup>5d → 4f
 <sup>7</sup> transition of Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> are definitely established in the following order: Li
 <sub>2</sub>CaSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> &gt; Li
 <sub>2</sub>BaSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> &gt; Li
 <sub>2</sub>SrSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>. Furthermore, using Williamson–Hall (W–H) method, the determined structural strains of Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors revealed that the increased compressive strain after N
 <sup>3–</sup> doping plays an important role in the enhanced PL intensity of these phosphors. White LEDs fabricated by a combination of three N
 <sup>3–</sup>-doped phosphors and a 365 nm emitting InGaN chip exhibited the (0.333, 0.373) color coordinate and a high color-rendering index (
 <italic>R</italic>
 <sub>a</sub> = 83). These phosphor materials may provide a platform for development of new efficient phosphors in solid-state lighting field.
</p>
