<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Recently, with the development of science and technology, the methods of studying montmorillonite are not limited to experimental research. Computer molecular simulation can be used for theoretical research and experimental determination, which has been widely used in research of montmorillonite [
 <xref rid="B11-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. Compared with the traditional experimental research methods, the advantages of computer molecular simulation are obvious, which can not only simulate the molecular structure of the substance itself, but also simulate the dynamic change of the molecule when the substance reacts. It can visually describe the mechanism of reaction between substances at the molecular and atomic scales, and then verify the rationality of the experiment or predict the experimental results [
 <xref rid="B13-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. Skipper et al. first simulated the interlayer water structure of Na-montmorillonite and Mg-montmorillonite by using Monte Carlo (MC) and molecular dynamics methods (MD) in 1991, and proposed a complete MC simulation method for a clay–ion–water system in 1995, including the construction of the model, the selection of potential functions, and the processing of non-bonded interaction, which laid the foundation for the future molecular simulation study of montmorillonite [
 <xref rid="B14-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Marry et al. studied the Na-montmorillonite and Cs-montmorillonite by MC and MD simulation methods, and compared their structural and kinetic characteristics with experimental data; their findings showed that the layer spacing calculated by molecular simulation, the diffusion coefficient of water molecules, and interlayer cations in a single layer hydrate were basically consistent with the experimentally measured data [
 <xref rid="B16-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. Therefore, MD simulation can be used as a new technology in the study of montmorillonite.
</p>
