<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Using density functional perturbation theory (
 <xref rid="R46" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>46</italic>
 </xref>) and the finite differences method (
 <xref rid="R47" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>47</italic>
 </xref>), we calculated the magnitude of the piezoelectric coefficient of WTe
 <sub>2</sub> (see table S1 and fig. S5 for details). The calculated value of the longitudinal piezoelectric coefficient (
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sub>33</sub>) is about 6.5 pm/V. We find that this calculated value is about an order of magnitude larger than the experimentally measured value of ~0.7 pm/V (see fig. S6 and corresponding text in section S5). However, the experimentally determined rather low value of the piezoelectric constant is understandable if one were to consider that we likely extract the piezoresponse within the Debye length of WTe
 <sub>2,</sub> which is ~1.6 nm (see section S6 for details on the calculation of Debye length). Moreover, the calculation is done for a uniform system, while in the measurements, the electric field distribution is likely highly nonuniform. While the detection of piezoresponse at these small length scales of few nanometers is challenging, it is nevertheless not unrealistic. Furthermore, we are aware of electrically induced extrinsic mechanisms (e.g., electrostatic effects and/or electrochemical processes) that can manifest as a piezoelectric- or a ferroelectric-like effect in PFM studies of nominally nonferroelectric materials. However, the experimental data in the present study of WTe
 <sub>2</sub> cannot be explained by these spurious extrinsic mechanisms (see section S7 for a detailed discussion). We note that the Debye length of ~1.6 nm is relatively short compared to the material thicknesses investigated in our study. Nevertheless, one can obtain depth-sensitive data from electrical measurements for thicknesses larger than the Debye length in WTe
 <sub>2</sub> (
 <xref rid="R48" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>48</italic>
 </xref>). In our study, we have observed ferroelectric domains in thick bulk crystals and ferroelectric switching in ~15-nm films. The question of the physical extent of these domains is an interesting one. One possibility is that the piezoresponse and ferroelectric domains come only from within a Debye length of the surface. However, it is also possible that the ferroelectric domains extend much deeper into the material because ferroelectricity and ferroelasticity are often coupled in conventional ferroelectrics and because ferroelastic domains have been predicted for bulk WTe
 <sub>2</sub> (
 <xref rid="R43" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>43</italic>
 </xref>). In this latter scenario, ferroelectric domains could potentially propagate through elastically mediated wall motion, where fluctuation in bond lengths by electric fields initiated on the surface (within the Debye length) generates strain down into the bulk of the material and large domains could propagate through into the depth of the material (
 <xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>6</italic>
 </xref>). We hope that our study will stimulate further theoretical and experimental studies to answer this question.
</p>
