<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>PbTi
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>V
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> possesses strong coupling between magnetic- and electric-order parameters for V concentration &gt; 12.3%. Lower substituted compositions are nonmagnetic ferroelectrics. Also, from the other side, the inclusion of Ti at the V site increases the chance of forming a 3D arrangement of V cations rather than 2D. The strong covalency between Ti/V and O and notable covalency between Pb and O bring the noncentrosymmetric distortion and stabilize the ferroelectric ground state. The ferroelectric-to-paraelectric transition is accompanied by a magnetic-to-nonmagnetic transition for 
 <italic>x</italic> &gt; 0.123. There is a large volume contraction during the above transition, indicating a strong lattice–ferroelectric coupling and strong magnetovolume effect. The calculations show high values of spontaneous electrical polarizations, which are mainly due to the displacement of the apical oxygen in the BO
 <sub>6</sub> octahedra in the paraelectric phase due to strong Ti/V–O covalent interaction. Therefore, PbTi
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>V
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> is aseries of multifunctional compounds having giant magnetoelectric effect where one can change the magnetic properties drastically (even from magnetic to nonmagnetic, as shown here) by applying electric field and vice versa, strong magnetovolume effect, induce 2D magnetism as well as orbital ordering by electric field, strong ferroelectric–lattice coupling, etc. Also, recent experimental studies by Pan et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref>
 </sup> show that for lower V concentration, this series shows good NTE response, and also a temperature-induced tetragonal-to-cubic transition occurs, which makes this series more interesting for the researchers to investigate its magneto/electro/multicaloric properties. With all of these properties coexisting in the series, PbTi
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>V
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> can be useful for many multifunctional device applications.
</p>
