<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0090">The growth of large crystalline domains in the HTL with a thickness of a few tens of nanometers has been suggested as one of the degradation causes of PSCs at elevated temperatures (
 <xref rid="bib19" ref-type="bibr">Malinauskas et al., 2015</xref>). Therefore we investigated the influence of continuous thermal stress on the microstructure of solution-deposited glassy films with the aid of X-ray diffraction analysis. As depicted in 
 <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figures 4</xref>E and 4F, the as-deposited thin films are amorphous for both O5H-OMeDPA and spiro-OMeTAD. Circular dichroism spectrum has proved the racemic feature of the solution-processed O5H-OMeDPA film. After 12-h heating at 60°C, the O5H-OMeDPA film maintains the amorphous characteristic, whereas the spiro-OMeTAD control evolves into a crystalline film verified by the occurrence of multiple X-ray diffraction (XRD) peaks. The crystalline phase of the annealed spiro-OMeTAD thin film matches well with the single-crystal structure reported by Shi et al. (
 <xref rid="bib25" ref-type="bibr">Shi et al., 2016</xref>). During crystallization, molecules in the thin film will move, forming closely packed phases and cracks simultaneously. The heat-induced phase transition is likely to deteriorate the interfacial contacts, impacting the hole extraction and transportation behaviors. Also, the change in film morphology will weaken the blocking effect of the HTL on Au diffusion into the perovskite layer, which severely affects the device performance under working conditions (
 <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">Domanski et al., 2016</xref>). In recent years, certain interface materials have been used to suppress metal diffusion (
 <xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr">Hou et al., 2017</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr">Chen et al., 2017</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">Christians et al., 2018</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib29" ref-type="bibr">Wu et al., 2019</xref>), which is a promising approach to further improve the stability of O5H-OMeDPA-based devices. It is also reported that additives can accelerate the crystallization of spiro-OMeTAD (
 <xref rid="bib33" ref-type="bibr">Zhao et al., 2017</xref>). Hence, we also compared the morphologies and XRD patterns of the doped O5H-OMeDPA films before and after thermal aging at 60°C. No remarkable change upon aging was observed from AFM images (
 <xref rid="mmc1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Figure S13</xref>). Also, the 60°C aged film is still amorphous (
 <xref rid="mmc1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Figure S14</xref>). Overall, the superior photo- and thermal stability of the O5H-OMeDPA-based PSCs demonstrated here highlights the grand potential of a racemic semiconducting glassy film of helicenes for organic optoelectronic devices.
</p>
