<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>On the basis of the vibrational analyses of model SNCs in this study, hydroxyl groups appear to be responsible for the broad band around 580 to 590 cm
 <sup>−1</sup>, as demonstrated by the agreement between the simulated and experimental SHINER spectra for Sn oxide SNCs. The stoichiometric formulae for the Sn oxide SNCs obtained from the simulations were Sn
 <sub>60</sub>O
 <sub>112</sub>H
 <sub>24</sub>, Sn
 <sub>28</sub>O
 <sub>48</sub>H
 <sub>12</sub>, and Sn
 <sub>12</sub>O
 <sub>25</sub>H
 <sub>16</sub>. A closer look at the optimized chemical structures of the model Sn oxide SNCs reveals unique characteristics resulting from the structural distortion relative to the structure of bulk crystals. A statistical analysis of all the Sn─O bond length in the simulated SNC structures exhibits that the average bond length and the FWHM of the length distribution curve both increase with decreasing atomicity (fig. S10, A to D), in the same manner as the FWHM values of the broad peaks in the SHINER spectra increase (
 <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3D</xref>). Deviations from the bulk structure were more pronounced in the case of smaller SNCs, indicating that the Sn
 <sub>12</sub> SNCs had a highly distorted atomic configuration with longer Sn─O bonds on average. Here, it is important to point out that the peak maxima in the SHINER spectra were red-shifted with decreases in Sn atomicity. This red shift indicates that the Sn─O bond strength in the SNCs decreases with decreasing atomicity, which is consistent with the data showing elongation of the Sn─O bonds with decreasing atomicity (fig. S10). During CO oxidation, Sn oxide catalysts work as oxygen donors, and so, it is likely that a lower Sn─O bond strength will promote bond cleavage to provide more oxygen species to enhance the CO oxidation process. In addition, it is interesting to observe that all the Sn─O bonds longer than 2.2 Å are located at the edges of the clusters, which represent the active sites for CO oxidation, and the content of surface hydroxyl groups was increased from Sn
 <sub>60</sub> to Sn
 <sub>12</sub> (fig. S10E). Therefore, Sn oxide SNCs with 12 Sn atoms were found to have higher hydroxyl group coverage ratio together with lower bond strengths, as demonstrated via complementary approaches with the experimental SHINERS data and theoretical simulations. These results explain well the unusual catalytic activities of smaller SNCs during the CO oxidation reaction.
</p>
