<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Among the extensive list of materials tested as catalysts, dopants, or additives for improving hydriding and dehydriding reactions of NaAlH
 <sub>4</sub>, the Ti, Sc, and Ce compounds stand out due to their effectiveness [
 <xref rid="B132-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">132</xref>]. However, most of the theoretical and experimental studies to unravel the action mode of the catalyst have focused on Ti-compounds [
 <xref rid="B134-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">134</xref>]. Nevertheless, after almost 20 years of the discovery of the benefits of using a catalyst, some fundamental questions are still not adequately addressed. Here are some points to consider:
 <list list-type="order">
  <list-item>
   <p>Morphology/particle size effects. Beattie et al. demonstrated that Ti-doped NaAlH
    <sub>4</sub> particles presented few morphological changes as compared with un-doped materials [
    <xref rid="B135-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">135</xref>]. By-products of the addition of materials, such as TiCl
    <sub>3</sub>, i.e., Ti-Al alloys, and NaCl, can act as grain refiners for Al and NaH phases, keeping particle sizes small [
    <xref rid="B136-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">136</xref>]. In general, much effort is put to reduce particle sizes and to avoid the sintering of particles, and thus maintaining the hydriding/dehydriding performance.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Location of Ti and substitution of atoms. The Ti atoms can be located in the bulk, in interstitial positions, at the subsurface, or the surface. The Ti preferred position depends on the doping level and synthesis technique (impregnation vs. ball milling), or in theoretical calculations, the choice of reference states. The Ti atoms can be located in NaH, Al, Na
    <sub>3</sub>AlH
    <sub>6</sub>, or NaAlH
    <sub>4</sub> phases. Theoretical studies have been performed basically to include all of these possibilities. Some studies have unraveled the interactions of Ti (or Ti-compounds) with NaH and Al. Other reports indicated interactions of Ti (or Ti-compounds) with Na
    <sub>3</sub>AlH
    <sub>6</sub> and NaAlH
    <sub>4</sub>. Contradictory results/conclusions frequently come across.
   </p>
   <p>Additionally, many studies point to atom substitution and formation of defects. The replacement of Al by Ti in NaAlH
    <sub>4</sub> could be possible, yet this configuration is metastable [
    <xref rid="B137-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">137</xref>,
    <xref rid="B138-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">138</xref>]. Løvvik situates the substitution in the second metal layer from the surface [
    <xref rid="B137-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">137</xref>,
    <xref rid="B138-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">138</xref>]. Other DFT calculations suggest that the most frequent Ti-defect in NaAlH
    <sub>4</sub> is a defect that is formed by the substitution of Al by Ti and the addition of two hydrogen ions; this defect has a −1 charge [
    <xref rid="B139-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">139</xref>].
   </p>
   <p>The substitution of Na by Ti and other metal atoms also has been investigated. Marashdeh et al. classified the catalysts as “good” (Sc, Ti, Zr) and “bad” (Pt, Pd) according to their ability to exchange places with a Na atom on a (001) surface of NaAlH
    <sub>4</sub> [
    <xref rid="B140-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">140</xref>]. In the “zipper model”, Ti-species, at the surface or at a grain-boundary, displace subsurface Na atoms and eject them to the NaAlH
    <sub>4</sub> surface. Subsequently, the Na atoms react quickly with other species and destabilize the surface, which returns the Ti-species to a surface location [
    <xref rid="B134-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">134</xref>,
    <xref rid="B140-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">140</xref>]. For Na
    <sub>3</sub>AlH
    <sub>6</sub>, Michel et al. found a competition between Ti substitution on the Na sites (+1 charge defect) and Ti substitution on the Al site, with an additional bound to H atom (neutral site) [
    <xref rid="B139-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">139</xref>]. 
   </p>
   <p>For the hydrogenation reaction, the reports indicate that Ti near an Al surface (subsurface) promotes H
    <sub>2</sub> dissociation and H spillover on the Al surface [
    <xref rid="B141-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">141</xref>]. Wang et al. remind us, in favor of this role of subsurface Ti, that metallic aluminum does not absorb diatomic hydrogen from the gas phase by itself. Meanwhile, atomic hydrogen strongly reacts with aluminum surfaces to form alanes [
    <xref rid="B142-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">142</xref>]. Thus, subsurface Ti would promote H
    <sub>2</sub> dissociation and enhance H mobility and adsorption [
    <xref rid="B142-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">142</xref>]. These effects constitute essentially the “hydrogen pump” action mechanism that was proposed for Ti [
    <xref rid="B134-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">134</xref>]. Theoretical calculations of subsurface Sc, V or Nb substitution of Al indicate that these materials could also perform as a catalyst [
    <xref rid="B143-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">143</xref>]. Wang et al. also remind us that Ti, Zr, V, Fe, Ni, Nb, Y, La, Ce, Pr, Nd, and Sm are expected to be good catalysts based on their ability to “mix” well with Al [
    <xref rid="B142-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">142</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Progressive changes of the oxidation state of Ti-species. While Ti
    <sup>+3</sup> species is the most recurrent initial oxidation state of the Ti-catalyst, several reports conclude that the oxidation state changes to Ti
    <sup>0</sup>, followed by the formation of Ti
    <italic>
     <sub>x</sub>
    </italic>-Al
    <italic>
     <sub>y</sub>
    </italic> alloys, and finally the formation of Al
    <sub>3</sub>Ti [
    <xref rid="B134-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">134</xref>,
    <xref rid="B144-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">144</xref>,
    <xref rid="B145-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">145</xref>,
    <xref rid="B146-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">146</xref>]. However, Al
    <sub>3</sub>Ti seems to be an inefficient catalyst, as compared to other Ti or Ti-compounds [
    <xref rid="B134-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">134</xref>,
    <xref rid="B147-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">147</xref>]. Perhaps the formation of Ti
    <italic>
     <sub>x</sub>
    </italic>-Al
    <italic>
     <sub>y</sub>
    </italic> alloys and Al
    <sub>3</sub>Ti is the reason for the long-term (after hydriding/dehydriding cycling) decay of hydrogen storage capacity [
    <xref rid="B148-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">148</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Formation of Ti-Al-H complexes. Theoretical calculations suggest that the replacement of Na by Ti near o connected with [AlH
    <sub>4</sub>]
    <sup>−</sup> would lead to the formation of Ti-Al-H complexes that can help during the dehydrogenation/rehydrogenation reactions [
    <xref rid="B149-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">149</xref>,
    <xref rid="B150-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">150</xref>,
    <xref rid="B151-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">151</xref>]. TiAl
    <sub>2</sub>H
    <sub>7</sub> and TiAl
    <sub>2</sub>H
    <sub>2</sub> are two optimized structures of the Ti-Al-H complexes [
    <xref rid="B150-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">150</xref>]. The effect of the Ti-Al-H complexes would be to reduce the desorption energy of hydrogen [
    <xref rid="B149-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">149</xref>,
    <xref rid="B151-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">151</xref>] and to break H-H and Al-H bonds as a result of balanced electron-accepting/back-donation [
    <xref rid="B151-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">151</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Additional effects. Other effects, such as the formation of mobile species or vacancies, the changes in the Fermi level of reacting species, or the destabilization of Al–H bonds, can also influence the hydrogenation/dehydrogenation reactions [
    <xref rid="B134-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">134</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
