<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To study the in-plane alignment of the crystallites in more detail, pole figures can easily be generated within 
 <italic>GIDVis</italic>. Here, there are some advantages of the described approach compared with laboratory-based pole-figure investigations. The first is the greatly reduced measurement time, which is here about 30 min for a large range of 
 <italic>q</italic> values compared with at least 15 h for a single 
 <italic>q</italic> value using in-house texture goniometers. From 180 GIXD measurements of a 360° sample rotation, pole figures can be obtained for any value of the scattering angle covered in the images by extracting it from the present data set. This limitation is often reflected in the fact that reciprocal-space mapping, although a very powerful technique, is in fact rarely done in the home laboratory (Resel 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2007
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb25"> ▸</xref>), and usually epitaxy is tested for known phases only. The use of synchrotron radiation and the approach we implement makes the calculation of pole figures and their inspection for materials of unknown crystal structure reasonable and thus possible. Because of the geometry chosen in GIXD, even pole figures with very low 
 <italic>q</italic> values can be calculated, which are often hard to access with classical texture goniometers owing to the strong background of the primary beam. Besides these advantages, elimination of the blind areas of the area detector would require three measurements with slightly different detector positions. Yet, as the information is often redundant because of higher-order reflections or scattering into another quadrant of a large detector, this is of minor importance for this kind of experiment. A real limitation of the GIXD geometry is its inherent insufficiency for measuring close to the specular direction (
 <italic>i.e.</italic> low 
 <italic>q
  <sub>x</sub>
 </italic> and 
 <italic>q
  <sub>y</sub>
 </italic> and thus 
 <italic>q
  <sub>xy</sub>
 </italic> values) due to the external reflection of the beam. Here, classical pole-figure geometries (
 <italic>e.g.</italic> Eulerian cradles) would be required, but at the expense of lacking the advantages of GIXD measurements.
</p>
