<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The site-symmetry approach (Evarestov &amp; Smirnov, 1987
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb9"> ▸</xref>, 1993
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb10"> ▸</xref>; Hatch 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1988
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb16"> ▸</xref>; Stokes 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1991
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb33"> ▸</xref>; Kovalev, 1993
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb21"> ▸</xref>) is a powerful method which connects the local properties of atoms in crystals with the symmetry of states of the whole crystalline system, 
 <italic>i.e.</italic> it establishes the symmetry relationships between the localized states in the crystal (vibrations of atoms and atomic orbitals) and crystal extended (phonon and electron) states over the entire Brillouin zone. The site-symmetry method is based on the procedure of induction of representations of the crystal space group from the irreducible representations (irreps) of the site-symmetry groups of the constituent units (atoms, clusters and layers) according to which the local excitations are transformed. In this way, the symmetry of phonon, electron, exciton, biexciton 
 <italic>etc.</italic> states can be described by the crystal single- and double-valued representations induced by the irreps of the site-symmetry group. Tables of induced representations were deduced by Evarestov &amp; Smirnov (1987
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb9"> ▸</xref>, 1993
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb10"> ▸</xref>), Hatch 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (1988
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb16"> ▸</xref>), Stokes 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (1991
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb33"> ▸</xref>) and Kovalev (1993
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb21"> ▸</xref>), and later the programs 
 <italic>SITESYM</italic> and 
 <italic>DSITESYM</italic> (Elcoro 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb8"> ▸</xref>) available on the Bilbao Crystallographic Server were developed to calculate the site-symmetry induced representations of space and double groups, respectively.
</p>
