<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par13">being 
 <italic>α</italic> a positive real number, and {|
 <bold>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>ij</italic>
 </sub>|} are the relative distances between the pairs of particles. We study a system of point particles which self-propel and interact with this potential in two dimensions. Depending on the stiffness of the potential (in particular, 
 <italic>α</italic> &gt; 2 is needed), the passive system (i.e. without the active self-propulsion) shows the occurrence of a peculiar aggregation phase at equilibrium
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>: particles form stable clusters, which arrange into a periodic configuration. In two dimensions the triangular or hexagonal lattice is the only stable pattern, occurring for small enough temperature 
 <italic>T</italic> at a large density. The number of particles, 
 <italic>N</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>c</italic>
 </sub>, of each cluster depends on the global density and on the typical interaction length, 
 <italic>R</italic>, while the typical inter-cluster distance is determined just by 
 <italic>R</italic>. When the particles are no longer point-like but of small finite size
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR64">64</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR66">66</xref>
 </sup> similar properties are found, with a new low-temperature phase -the so-called crystal cluster-crystal phase- in which particles inside the clusters also show an ordered structure. The cluster-formation phenomenon despite the repulsive interaction between all the particles can be physically interpreted by considering the force balance between the intra-cluster repulsion (the force felt by particles inside clusters) and the inter-cluster effective interaction, that is, the force exerted by neighboring clusters
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. The increasing of temperature enlarges the typical size of clusters, destroying any structure for 
 <italic>T</italic> sufficiently large.
</p>
