<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <italic>A. veronii</italic> strain A134 cultures were grown in 20 L LB medium for two weeks and the cells were removed from the medium by centrifugation. The spent medium was freeze-dried and extracted with a 45:45:10 mixture of ethyl acetate/methanol/water yielding 28 g of crude extract. After each step of separation, 
 <sup>1</sup>H-NMR spectra and biological activity assays were performed in order to guide further separations. The extract was partitioned successively between petroleum ether, a mixture of 1:1 chloroform/methanol and water. The chloroform/methanol soluble material (18.5 gr) was separated on a reversed-phase C-18 open column eluted with a step-gradient of decreasing polarity, from 100% water to 100% methanol and 100% ethyl acetate. Fractions 5–9, which inhibited 
 <italic>M. aeuroginosa</italic> strain MGK growth, were combined (1.2 gr) and further separated on a size exclusion Sephadex LH-20 column eluted with a 1:1 mixture of chloroform/methanol to afford two active fractions (9 and 10, 33.8 mg). The combined active fraction was separated on a preparative Phenomenex Hydro-RP HPLC column eluted with an isocratic solvent mixture of 2:1 0.1% aqueous TFA/CH
 <sub>3</sub>CN to afford in fraction 6 (t
 <sub>R</sub> 21.3 min, 1.5 mg, 0.005% yield of dry crude extract weight) lumichrome and in fraction 11 (t
 <sub>R</sub> 39.0 min, 0.4 mg, 0.001%) yield 9-chlorolumichrome (
 <bold>1</bold>). The combined non-active fractions (3–8, 0.42 g) from the size exclusion column were further separated on a Cosmosyl C-8 HPLC column eluted with 3:1 0.1% aqueous TFA/CH
 <sub>3</sub>CN to afford in fraction 2, cyclo-tyrosylprolyl (t
 <sub>R</sub> 14.8 min, 9.8 mg, 0.033% yield), in fraction 3, cyclo-valylproly (t
 <sub>R</sub> 15.8 min, 12.8 mg, 0.043% yield), in fraction 5, cyclo-isoleucylprolyl (t
 <sub>R</sub> 18.4 min, 8.4 mg, 0.028% yield), in fraction 9, cyclo-phenylalanylprolyl (t
 <sub>R</sub> 26.0 min, 79.6 mg, 0.265% yield) and in fraction 11, cyclo-tryptophylprolyl (t
 <sub>R</sub> 18.4 min, 7.3 mg, 0.024% yield). Fraction 6 (50.2 mg) and fraction 13 (16.1 mg) from the latter separation were further separated on the same column eluted with 45:55 MeOH/Water. Fraction 6 yielded in fraction 3, pure 
 <bold>2</bold> (t
 <sub>R</sub> 27.4 min, 1.4 mg, 0.005% yield), while fraction 13 yielded in fraction 1, indole-3-glyoxylamide (t
 <sub>R</sub> 28.8 min, 3.4 mg, 0.011% yield) and in fraction 3, pure 
 <bold>3</bold> (t
 <sub>R</sub> 38.3 min, 1.2 mg, 0.004% yield).
</p>
