<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>When X-rays are incident on a thin plane-parallel perfect crystal in the symmetric Bragg geometry, the refracted beam in the crystal reaches the back surface as illustrated in Fig. 1
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>). A part of the beam is reflected (
 <bold>S</bold>
 <sub>4</sub>) and the rest is emitted from the back surface as the transmitted beam (
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>t</sub>). The refracted beam is referred to as the beam corresponding to the Poynting vector excited at a point on the dispersion surface defined in the dynamical theory of diffraction. The refracted beam is called the wavefield by Authier (2001
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb1"> ▸</xref>). In the two-wave approximation, it is composed of two waves: one is propagating in the forward direction and the other in the diffracted-wave direction. In an anomalous transmission condition, the divergence of the refracted beam is much larger than that of the incident wave (Authier, 2001
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb1"> ▸</xref>). If the divergence angle of the refracted beam is large enough, interference fringes can be formed between once (
 <bold>S</bold>
 <sub>1</sub>)- and twice (
 <bold>S</bold>
 <sub>2</sub>)-reflected beams from the back surface (abbreviated as IFRB) as shown in Fig. 1
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>). Similar interference fringes can be observed in the transmitted beam (IFTB) from the back surface. If the crystal is small along the incident azimuth direction (
 <italic>x</italic>) compared with the propagation length of the X-ray, interference fringes can be observed in the emitted beams from the lateral surface both in the diffracted- (IFLSD) and the transmitted-wave directions (IFLST). Both IFLSD and IFLST have been observed by Fukamachi 
 <italic>et al.</italic> (2004
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb10"> ▸</xref>, 2005
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb9"> ▸</xref>) from a thin Ge plane-parallel crystal. These fringes were formed by interference between the beams directly propagating to the lateral surface (
 <bold>S</bold>
 <sub>3</sub>) and once reflected from the back surface (
 <bold>S</bold>
 <sub>4</sub>) (Hirano 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2008
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb15"> ▸</xref>, 2009
 <italic>a</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb13"> ▸</xref>,
 <italic>b</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb14"> ▸</xref>; Fukamachi, Hirano 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2011
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb5"> ▸</xref>).
</p>
