<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>With the rapid development of the Internet of Things (IoT), there is an increasing number of decentralized sensors that are widely applied in daily activities and industrial productions.
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0001" ref-type="ref">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0002" ref-type="ref">2</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0003" ref-type="ref">3</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0004" ref-type="ref">4</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0005" ref-type="ref">5</xref> Among these applications, wind speed sensor plays an essential role in environmental sensing, such as weather forecast and environment monitoring.
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0006" ref-type="ref">6</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0007" ref-type="ref">7</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0008" ref-type="ref">8</xref> A number of sensors have been developed based on triboelectric nanogenerators (TENGs), which is known for the portability, facile fabrication, and low cost. These TENG‐based sensors have been considered as one of the most effective mechanical energy conversion technologies as they enable the generation of high open‐circuit voltage at a low frequency.
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0009" ref-type="ref">9</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0010" ref-type="ref">10</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0011" ref-type="ref">11</xref> Particularly, TENG‐based wind speed sensors have been tremendously developed by varying sensing principles, including the wind‐induced rotation,
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0012" ref-type="ref">12</xref> vertical contact‐separation motions,
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0013" ref-type="ref">13</xref> and fluttering behavior.
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0014" ref-type="ref">14</xref> Y. Yang et al.
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0015" ref-type="ref">15</xref> reported a TENG‐based wind speed sensing system, which displays a sensitivity of 0.09 µA/(m/s) and a detection limit 6 m s
 <sup>−1</sup> by utilizing the wind‐induced vibration. Based on an anemometer TENG and a wind vane TENG, J. Y. Wang et al.
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0016" ref-type="ref">16</xref> presented a wind sensor with a sensing range from 2.7 to 8.0 m s
 <sup>−1</sup>, which generates an output short‐circuit current of 6.3 µA at wind speed of 6 m s
 <sup>−1</sup>. In another work, P. H. Wang et al.
 <xref rid="advs1381-bib-0017" ref-type="ref">17</xref> demonstrated a triboelectric‐electromagnetic hybrid wind speed sensor with a maximal loading current of 6 µA and a lower detection limit of 3.5 m s
 <sup>−1</sup>. However, the applications of these traditional TENG‐based wind speed sensors are limited by the extremely low output current at the level of µA. Therefore, strategies for enhancing the output current are in great demand when designing an efficient wind speed sensor.
</p>
