<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Supramolecular coordination complexes (SCCs) represent a promising class of compounds which have been used in a variety of molecular systems [
 <xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–
 <xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Taking advantage of the vacant cavity inside these complexes, SCCs have been applied in drug delivery [
 <xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>–
 <xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>], supramolecular catalysis [
 <xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>–
 <xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>], X-ray structure determination [
 <xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>–
 <xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>] and stabilization of reactive species [
 <xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>–
 <xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. The use of reversible metal–ligand coordination bonds gives rise to systems that allow for adaption to external stimuli such as pH, anions, electric potential, concentration and light [
 <xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>–
 <xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. Using light to dynamically control the shape and function of SCCs is a very promising strategy as it is a noninvasive stimulus that can be easily applied with high spatiotemporal control, without producing any waste. Systems have been reported where photoisomerization of azobenzene-derived anions encapsulated in supramolecular palladium complexes caused immediate crystallization [
 <xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. Moreover, azobenzenes have been used to functionalize both the interior [
 <xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>] and exterior [
 <xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>] of SCCs to photochemically control guest binding and release. Furthermore, incorporation of dithienylethene into the ligands connecting the metal centers has been used to control host–guest interactions [
 <xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>–
 <xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>], structural composition [
 <xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>], and sol–gel transition [
 <xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]. However, dithienylethene undergoes a limited structural change upon photoisomerization and, up to now, photoswitchable ligands based on other types of photochromic switches have not been reported in the literature.
</p>
