<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Heterogeneous catalytic reactions such as electrochemical water spitting are closely related to the surface electronic structures of the catalysts, such as the surface states and surface atomic termination (
 <xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>1</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>2</italic>
 </xref>). The topological phase materials, with rich exotic physical properties, provide an ideal platform to explore the interplay between surface states, electron transfer, and surface catalytic reactions (
 <xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>3</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>4</italic>
 </xref>). Three-dimensional (3D) topological insulators have robust metallic surface states that cover the entire material. Unlike the easily destroyable surface states derived from dangling bonds, vacancies, or doping, topological surface states (TSSs) are a result of the inversion of the bulk bands at the surface. Thus, they are robust against surface modifications and defects (
 <xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>5</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>7</italic>
 </xref>). The electron spin is in a lock-up state with its momentum due to the spin-orbit coupling at the crystal surface. This could notably depress backscattering and Anderson localization of conduction electrons, which are imperative for materials that are always accompanied with, to some extent, surface defects (
 <xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>8</italic>
 </xref>). However, the insulating properties of topological insulators are a challenge for the electron migration when used as electrocatalysts, which will lead to lower apparent catalytic activity in comparison with that of a highly conducting catalyst (
 <xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>9</italic>
 </xref>). Topological semimetals such as Weyl semimetals and topological nodal line semimetals are good candidates for electrocatalysis due to their high conductivity, nontrivial topologically protected surface states, and suitable carrier density around Fermi level (
 <xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>7</italic>
 </xref>).
</p>
