<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The oxygen evolution process (OER) is a kinetically sluggish process that involves the formation of bonds and electron transfer between the catalytic sites and the adsorbates (
 <xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>10</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>11</italic>
 </xref>). Thus, the reaction kinetics are jointly controlled by the geometric properties (size, shape, crystallinity, etc.) and electronic structure (work functions, 
 <italic>d</italic>-band center positions, spins, etc.) of the catalysts. Recently, 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub> orbital filling and spin states of the OER active sites have been identified to be a reasonable descriptor of catalytic activity based on the idea that the 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub> orbitals can form strong bonds with the oxygenated adsorbates (
 <xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>12</italic>
 </xref>). It is found that depending on the spin states of the transferred electrons, either ground-state triplet oxygen molecule or hydrogen peroxide can be produced. This greatly affects the needed overpotential to drive the reaction (
 <xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>13</italic>
 </xref>). Thus, it is expected that excellent OER catalytic activities can be achieved by introducing elemental vacancies, applying strain, or tuning transition-metal coordination and spin states (
 <xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>14</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>17</italic>
 </xref>). However, the strategies based on extrinsic modifications are inevitably accompanied with crystal collapse and distortion, making the exploration of their influence on catalytic activity more difficult. Here, taking the bulk single crystal of the topological semimetal Co
 <sub>3</sub>Sn
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>2</sub> as a proof-of-concept study, we demonstrate a unique strategy to combine the advantages of a normal semimetal and a topological insulator with robust surface states, which could notably enhance the OER kinetics. Co
 <sub>3</sub>Sn
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>2</sub> was recently discovered as the first magnetic Weyl semimetal with time-reversal symmetry breaking, showing a giant anomalous Hall effect in the bulk and potential TSSs on the crystalline surface (
 <xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>18</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>19</italic>
 </xref>). At room temperature, the band structure of Co
 <sub>3</sub>Sn
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>2</sub> naturally hosts the electronic structure of a topological semimetal. We observed high conductivity, as well as robust surface states, derived by Co atoms on the Kagome lattices and located just above the Fermi level. The 
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub> orbital of the surface Co atoms is partially filled and points to the 
 <italic>p</italic> orbital of the adsorbed hydroxide ions, thus favoring electron transfer and strengthening the bonds between the adsorbate and catalytic sites. When used as an electrocatalyst for the OER, the bulk single-crystal Co
 <sub>3</sub>Sn
 <sub>2</sub>S
 <sub>2</sub> shows high activity and comparable to that of reported Co-based nanostructures with a much larger surface area. The present work reveals a valuable method to develop an efficient OER electrocatalyst by manipulating the surface states and spin states.
</p>
