<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par23">The observed F
 <sub>o</sub>
 <sup>2</sup> values were then treated with a full-matrix least-squares refinement in the 
 <italic>C</italic>2/
 <italic>c</italic> space group by using the SHELX-97 program
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>
 </sup>, starting from the atomic coordinates of sample TS7 N.2
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup> and taking into account the 
 <italic>M</italic>21 and O2B1 split sites
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>
 </sup>, that were refined with isotropic displacement parameters. The atomic scattering curves were taken from 
 <italic>the International Tables for X-ray Crystallography</italic>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup>. Neutral versus ionized scattering factors were refined for all sites not involved in chemical substitutions to ensure charge neutrality
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>
 </sup>. Complete ionization was assumed for Mg and Fe in the 
 <italic>M</italic>1 site, for Ca and Mg in the 
 <italic>M</italic>2 site and for Fe in the 
 <italic>M</italic>21 site. Individual weights and the weighting scheme suggested by the program were used. The extinction correction was applied with the procedures of the SHELX-97 program. Table 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1</xref> reports the mean atomic numbers (m.a.n.) in electrons per formula unit (e.p.f.u.) at the crystallographic sites (
 <italic>M</italic>1, 
 <italic>M</italic>2, 
 <italic>M</italic>21) obtained when the structure refinement reached convergence, before introducing the chemical constraints. For all samples the calculated mean atomic numbers from the refinements unconstrained agree within less than 1 standard deviation with the values of electrons per formula unit (e.p.f.u.) calculated from the EMPA (Table 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S2</xref>). Therefore, this enabled us to use the results from the EMPA as chemical constraints for the structural refinements, following the procedure and taking into account the same constraints as in
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup> assuming 1 standard deviation as the error, in order to determine the clinopyroxene site distribution. The site populations obtained from the structural refinements with chemical constraints and the distribution coefficients (
 <italic>k</italic>
 <sub>D</sub>) with relative propagated errors are reported in Table 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S3</xref>.
</p>
