<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0720">The question can be raised whether the ensemble and with it the temperature, which, as a rule, determine the experimental reality, brings an element of classicality into the quantum system, regardless of whether the chaotic dynamics of the transient state in individual molecules is taken into account. The answer is yes, because in the standard theory of many-phonon transitions, we already obtain the result for the shape of the optical band as a continuous function (as a result of the dispersion of phonon frequencies [
 <xref rid="bib72" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>]), rather than discrete lines, as in atomic physics. In this experiment, we have the same shape of the optical band as a continuous function. However, by applying the adiabatic approximation, this result for the shape of the optical band as a continuous function in the standard theory of many-phonon transitions is obtained completely within the framework of quantum mechanics. This fact allows us to consider many-phonon transitions in the standard theory as “purely” quantum transitions, and not as quantum-classical transitions, as we do in the new theory, where classicality already arises in the transient state of each single molecule (each donor-acceptor couple in the case of electron transfers) in the ensemble, and to consider the most standard theory of many-phonon transitions not as a theory belonging to mesoscopic physics, but as a quantum-mechanical theory. Concomitantly, it is essential that taking into account only the ensemble of molecules and the associated temperature to simulate an experimental situation, without introducing chaos into the transient state of each single molecule, does not solve the problem associated with the appearance of a singularity in the transition rates in the case of going beyond the adiabatic approximation. In short, classicality, which is introduced into quantum mechanics by an ensemble of molecules and temperature, is not capable of damping the essential singularity in the transition rates.
</p>
