<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0725">The physical nature of the singularity is discussed in this article in several aspects: 1) the incomparability of the masses of electrons and nuclei in the presence of full-fledged dynamics of both nuclei and electrons (Sections 
 <xref rid="sec2.1" ref-type="sec">2.1</xref> and 
 <xref rid="sec2.4.3" ref-type="sec">2.4.3</xref>); 2) quantum transitions in a potential box with a moveable wall (Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.6" ref-type="sec">2.6</xref>); and 3) internal inconsistency of the Franck-Condon principle (Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.5" ref-type="sec">2.5</xref>). For example, consider the aspect due to the internal inconsistency of the Franсk-Condon principle. This internal inconsistency is associated with the impossibility in the framework of quantum mechanics to formalize the qualitative picture of the transition proposed by the Franсk-Condon principle, which assumes that in the adiabatic approximation, the same oscillator behaves like a classical and quantum system in the same transition act. Namely, according to the Franck-Condon principle, in the oscillator there is a classical movement of the nuclei to the turning point at which the quantum transition to a new electronic state occurs. Therefore, the Franck-Condon principle with its quantum-classical paradigm is a precursor to the creation of quantum-classical mechanics with its dozy chaos in the transient state of an individual molecule. In the new theory, which gives new physical results in the cases of weak and medium dozy chaos, the Franck-Condon principle acts as an effective simulator of strong dozy chaos. Thus, the new theory of quantum-classical mechanics is not another section of mesoscopic physics with its phenomenological approach, but a natural generalization of the quantum-mechanical theory of many-phonon transitions [
 <xref rid="bib72" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>], where the dozy-chaos energy 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M622" altimg="si455.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>γ</mi>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">≡</mo>
    <mn>0</mn>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>,
 <xref rid="fn23" ref-type="fn">23</xref> in the case of 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M623" altimg="si456.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>γ</mi>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">≠</mo>
    <mn>0</mn>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>, that is, taking into account the chaotic dynamics of the transient state in elementary electron transfers in condensed matter, and also in molecules [
 <xref rid="bib65" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>] (see Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.8" ref-type="sec">2.8</xref>) and supramolecular systems in the future. This is a generalization similar to the broad meaning in which Schrödinger's equation as a postulate in quantum mechanics is a generalization of the Hamilton-Jacobi equation for action in classical mechanics, and in general, quantum mechanics is a generalization of classical mechanics, where Planck's constant 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M624" altimg="si457.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>ℏ</mi>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">≡</mo>
    <mn>0</mn>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>, in the case of 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M625" altimg="si458.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>ℏ</mi>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">≠</mo>
    <mn>0</mn>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> (see Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.7" ref-type="sec">2.7</xref>). Comparisons between quantum-classical mechanics and other theoretical approaches, where mixing quantum and classical mechanics is undertaken (see 
 <italic>e.g.</italic> [
 <xref rid="bib100" ref-type="bibr">100</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib101" ref-type="bibr">101</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib102" ref-type="bibr">102</xref>]), will be given elsewhere.
 <xref rid="fn24" ref-type="fn">24</xref>
</p>
