<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The photocatalytic activity was evaluated in a self-made quartz reactor (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="nanomaterials-09-01173-f002">Figure 2</xref>; the volume is 3.2 L) at normal temperature and pressure. The environment in the reactor was consistent with indoor conditions. In the experiment, the photocatalyst was sprayed onto a glass plate by ethanol suspension, and then the glass plate was put into the quartz reactor. After the quartz reactor was sealed, 1.5 µL of liquid toluene (C
 <sub>7</sub>H
 <sub>8</sub>, 99%) was injected using a microsyringe (the toluene concentration was 105 ppm). The conversion formula is as follows: 
 <disp-formula id="FD1-nanomaterials-09-01173">
  <label>(1)</label>
  <math id="mm1">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <msub>
      <mi mathvariant="normal">V</mi>
      <mi mathvariant="normal">T</mi>
     </msub>
     <mo>=</mo>
     <mfrac>
      <mrow>
       <mfrac>
        <mi mathvariant="normal">M</mi>
        <mrow>
         <msub>
          <mi mathvariant="normal">V</mi>
          <mi mathvariant="normal">m</mi>
         </msub>
        </mrow>
       </mfrac>
       <msub>
        <mrow>
         <mrow>
          <mo>×</mo>
          <mo>(</mo>
          <mi mathvariant="normal">C</mi>
         </mrow>
        </mrow>
        <mi mathvariant="normal">V</mi>
       </msub>
       <mo>×</mo>
       <msup>
        <mrow>
         <mn>10</mn>
        </mrow>
        <mrow>
         <mo>−</mo>
         <mn>6</mn>
        </mrow>
       </msup>
       <mo stretchy="false">)</mo>
       <mo>×</mo>
       <msub>
        <mi mathvariant="normal">V</mi>
        <mi mathvariant="normal">R</mi>
       </msub>
      </mrow>
      <mrow>
       <mrow>
        <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">ρ</mi>
        <mo>×</mo>
        <mn>99</mn>
        <mo>%</mo>
       </mrow>
      </mrow>
     </mfrac>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </disp-formula> where V
 <sub>T</sub> (µL) is the volume of liquid toluene, M (92.14 g/mol) is the molar mass of toluene, V
 <sub>m</sub> (24.5 L/mol) is the molar volume of gas at normal temperature and pressure, C
 <sub>V</sub> (ppm) is the gaseous toluene concentration, V
 <sub>R</sub> (3.2 L) is the volume of the self-made quartz reactor, ρ (0.865 g/cm
 <sup>3</sup>) is the density of toluene, and 99% is the purity of liquid toluene. We waited for toluene to be mixed evenly, and a UV lamp (18 W, 254 nm) was turned on at the front of the irradiation reactor. The light intensity was 10.96 mW/cm
 <sup>2</sup>, measured by a PM120VA spectro-irradiator. The toluene concentration was detected by an online FID detector (SIGNAL GROUP, USA) at an interval of 30 min.
</p>
