<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Many experiments were performed to investigate the friction properties of nano-textured surfaces. An early study [
 <xref rid="B7-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>] showed that the nanoscale grain holes on the polysilicon surface could help to reduce the real contact area and sticking, and enlarging the hole size induced a further reduction of sticking. Zou et al. [
 <xref rid="B8-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>] compared the adhesion and friction performances of a silica nanoparticle-textured (SNPT) surface with a silicon oxide films surface, and the improved adhesion and friction performances of the SNPT surface were attributed to its reduced contact area. Nair and Zou [
 <xref rid="B9-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>] investigated the friction behaviors of nano-textured samples fabricated by aluminum-induced crystallization of amorphous silicon. Compared with the smooth surface, nano-textured surfaces reduced the friction forces greatly, and a higher texture height induced lower friction forces. Zhao et al. [
 <xref rid="B10-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>] prepared Au surfaces with micro/nano hierarchical structures and investigated the effects of textures on nanotribological properties. The nanotribological performances could be greatly improved by designing a suitable surface topography, and the friction force decreased as cylindrical pillar area density and height increased. Zhang et al. [
 <xref rid="B11-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>] found that Au nanoparticle-textured surfaces with a higher texture height could reduce the friction forces more efficiently. Yu et al. [
 <xref rid="B12-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>] studied the friction behaviors of the surfaces with grooves at the nano-, micro-, and macroscales. The materials included copper alloys, 52,100 steel, tungsten carbide, and silicon stamps, and the sliding direction played a key role in affecting the COFs. Wu et al. [
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>] used the surface of the fluorine-doped tin oxide wafer as a nanodot-textured surface, and they also prepared the nanorod-textured surface and nanocomposite-textured surface to investigate the effects of different shapes. The nanorod-textured surface showed better adhesion and friction performances. In the work of Steck et al. [
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>], a novel strategy for fabricating deformation-resistant nano-textured surfaces was developed, and the IP-DIP/Al
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> core-shell nanostructures showed 85% lower COFs than the bare IP-DIP nanodots.
</p>
