<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The experiments have obtained lots of valuable results, and numerical simulations on the nanoscale friction behaviors were also performed, of which molecular dynamics (MD) simulation was the most widely used one. Zhang et al. [
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>] found that the surface roughness tended to increase kinetic friction between Al–Al or α-Al
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub>/α-Al
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> interfaces. Chen et al. [
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>] performed MD simulations to investigate a Fe tip sliding on a Fe substrate with textured surface. The textured surfaces showed lower friction forces than a smooth surface, and a surface with parallel grooves presented lower friction than that of a rectangular-dimpled textured surface. Li et al. [
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>] studied nanoscale high-speed grinding behaviors of Cu by examining the effects of texture density, texture direction and texture shape. The surface with a lower texture density reduced the grinding forces and average COFs effectively, while the influence of texture orientation was slight, due to a high cutting depth. Santhapuram et al. [
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>] performed MD simulations on the friction properties of an aluminum surface with cylindrical and spherical textures, and the COFs depended on texture shape and tip radius. Using a multiscale method, Tong et al. [
 <xref rid="B19-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>] investigated the friction behaviors of the sliding contacts between rigid tips and textured surfaces, and a higher texture height and larger texture spacing could reduce the friction forces for the rectangular textures, but the model was a two dimensional one. In further work, they performed coarse-grained MD simulations on the friction behaviors of the textured Ag coatings [
 <xref rid="B21-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. The friction properties were influenced by the texture width, depth, orientation and shape, and the textured surface with 0° orientation and a rectangular shape showed lower average friction forces. For a textured gold film, the average friction forces and the surface temperature of the substrate were decreased when increasing the texture depth [
 <xref rid="B22-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>].
</p>
