<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>There are always defects in materials, due to various reasons, which change the properties of the materials. Some defects are beneficial to materials, and point defects increase the conductivity of a semiconductor material. On the other hand, the defects may play a negative role; the dislocation defects made the material easy to fracture and reduced the thermal conductivity of single-walled carbon nanotubes [
 <xref rid="B23-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. Due to the existence of defects, there were more cracks and local stress concentration points, which greatly reduced the mechanical properties of graphene. Meanwhile, the fracture strength was reduced, due to local stress points caused by defects [
 <xref rid="B25-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. For a carbon honeycomb with a single atom vacancy, the tensile strength was decreased by 11.5% in the cell axis direction, but only 5% in the other two directions. The position of vacancy also affected the mechanical properties in cell axis direction [
 <xref rid="B26-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. Kopta et al. [
 <xref rid="B27-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>] performed AFM experiments between Si-tips and the mica, and the results showed that the rupture of the Si–O bond might produce defects. When defects were accumulated beyond a critical concentration, they were grown to wear, which had a noticeable contribution towards friction. From the experiments of Ref. [
 <xref rid="B28-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>], the authors found that the vacancies increased the friction in graphene significantly. Guo et al. [
 <xref rid="B29-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>] carried out molecular-force-field calculations to study the interlayer friction between graphene sheets with defects. They found that the change of interlayer distance and the defects might provide a way to realize ultralow friction and control the friction properties in graphene sheets. Using MD simulations, Liu et al. [
 <xref rid="B30-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>] studied the friction characteristics of a nanotube and a graphene. They placed a vacancy defect at the center of a single-layer graphene, and a high positive lateral force was presented when the tip approached the defect. Sun et al. [
 <xref rid="B31-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>] investigated the friction behaviors of a diamond tip sliding over a graphite by MD simulations. For defective graphite with a defect in the surface, a single vacancy in the interior layer decreased the COFs. For the metal materials, Chen et al. [
 <xref rid="B32-nanomaterials-09-01617" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>] developed an MD model to study the effects of vacancy defects on the friction forces of the single crystal iron, and the average friction forces increased with the defect concentration.
</p>
