<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>After the development of the equations corresponding to the rosette analysis, it is interesting to analyze the obtained results shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f009">Figure 9</xref>a,b. The cell shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f009">Figure 9</xref>a is within the tension region of stress distribution generated by the dislocation. The axis 
 <bold>a
  <sub>1</sub>
 </bold> is oriented in the crystallographic direction [1000]. Green lines limit the influence region of each atom and are no longer circles but ellipses. These lines fit the configuration of the elementary cell, which is contained in an ellipse very closely similar to the shapes of the green ellipses defining equilibrium positions of atoms. These ellipses are similar to those that in classical continuum kinematics define principal strains. The computed principal strains are: 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm14">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <msubsup>
      <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">ε</mi>
      <mn>1</mn>
      <mi mathvariant="normal">E</mi>
     </msubsup>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> = 0.0501, 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm15">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <msubsup>
      <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">ε</mi>
      <mn>2</mn>
      <mi mathvariant="normal">E</mi>
     </msubsup>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> = 0.0487, where the upper script “E” indicates the Eulerian strain. The principal direction 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm16">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <msubsup>
      <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">ε</mi>
      <mn>1</mn>
      <mi mathvariant="normal">E</mi>
     </msubsup>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> lays along crystallographic direction [1000] while the other principal direction 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm17">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <msubsup>
      <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">ε</mi>
      <mn>2</mn>
      <mi mathvariant="normal">E</mi>
     </msubsup>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> is perpendicular to it. Similar results were obtained using numerical methods based on molecular dynamics for the analysis of homogeneous states of deformation [
 <xref rid="B17-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. In 3-D, it can be assumed that the original spheres of 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f004">Figure 4</xref> become ellipsoids. Since initial isotropy of the field of one atom is broken, each elementary cell behaves as an anisotropic crystal (similar to photoelasticity).
</p>
