<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Photovoltaics (PV) show great potential in meeting the needs of the world’s energy consumption. Silicon-based solar cell technologies have over 90% of the PV market today, but the research community has been yearning for new materials that are cheap, flexible and efficient in solar cells. Band gap value and absorption coefficient of the material are the two major factors that decide whether the material can be of interest for photovoltaic (PV) applications. We have earlier reported several promising non-silicon materials with intermediate band gaps for photovoltaic applications [
 <xref rid="B1-materials-12-02667" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-materials-12-02667" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. There is an increasing interest in the family of ternary compounds with the general formula III-III-VI
 <sub>2</sub> (where III = Al, Ga, In, Tl; VI = Se, Te, S)—known as dichalcogenides [
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-02667" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. In a recent published article, we carried out in-depth analysis of TlBiS
 <sub>2</sub> (thallium-based) and calculated electronic and optical properties for the photovoltaic applications [
 <xref rid="B4-materials-12-02667" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. Thallium-bearing ternary materials have been studied in optoelectronics [
 <xref rid="B5-materials-12-02667" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>], but not extensively investigated in photovoltaics due to the fact that thallium is toxic. Researchers have shown interest to the Hall effect analysis, the photoconductivity and recombination kinetics in dichalcogenide-TlGaTe
 <sub>2</sub> material [
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-02667" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-02667" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. From our earlier study on non-silicon solar cell materials [
 <xref rid="B8-materials-12-02667" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>], we identified that TlGaTe
 <sub>2</sub> has a strong absorption coefficient in the visible region, but a complete study of TlGaTe
 <sub>2</sub> is needed to confirm that it is potential material for PV applications. 
</p>
