<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the past five years, colloidal lead halide perovskite nanocrystals (NCs) of APbX
 <sub>3</sub> composition (A = cesium, formamidinium, or methylammonium; X = Cl, Br, or I) have emerged as a novel class of highly fluorescent semiconductor quantum dots with emission spectra spanning the entire visible range, characterized by narrow emission bands (&lt;100 meV) and near-unity photoluminescence quantum yields (PLQY).
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> They are widely researched toward applications in conventional liquid-crystal displays (LCDs) with red and green fluorescent NCs as downconverters in the backlighting;
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> in the upcoming display technologies such as front-pixel LCD architectures, wherein NCs serve as both light filters and fluorescent emitters;
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>
 </sup> or in LED displays exploiting electroluminescence of perovskite NCs.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> For these display technologies, perovskite NCs offer a compelling suite of attributes: the widest color gamut (due to spectral tunability and narrowband emission) fulfilling the BT.2020 standard,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>
 </sup> exceptionally low production costs, as well as satisfactory restriction of hazardous substances compliance.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref>
 </sup> Other applications of luminescent perovskite NCs may include solid-state lighting,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref>
 </sup> solar cell concentrators,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref>
 </sup> and scintillators for X-ray imaging.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref>
 </sup> These NCs are also increasingly recognized as highly potent single-photon emitters for the design of quantum light sources for quantum information technologies. Emission from single-perovskite NCs is characterized by narrow emission line width, fast radiative decays (10–1000 times faster than in any other colloidal NCs), and long exciton coherence times.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref>
 </sup> In the form of long-range ordered, self-assembled superlattices, these NCs exhibit an accelerated collective mode of emission at cryogenic temperatures, known as superfluerescence, wherein pockets of bundled photons are emitted.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
