<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We further tested the device stability and evolution of the electroluminescence. Increased driving voltage does not cause changes in the EL peak position (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.9b01915/suppl_file/nz9b01915_si_001.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Figure S7</ext-link>). The constant-current driving under initial brightness of 100 Cd/m
 <sup>2</sup> of the device with CsPb(Br
 <sub>0.76</sub>Cl
 <sub>0.24</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub> NCs results in the EL intensity drop to 20% of the initial value within 26 s, which, although fast, is comparable to the best blue-emitting perovskite LEDs made from both the NCs and quasi-2D perovskites.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref61">61</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref64">64</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref66">66</xref>
 </sup> We also observe red shift of the electroluminescence spectrum (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.9b01915/suppl_file/nz9b01915_si_001.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Figure S8</ext-link>). Such color instability is commonplace in perovskite devices and is caused by halide ion migration during the device operation.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref88">88</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref91">91</xref>
 </sup> In Br/I systems, the halide segregation is readily observed under illumination and without applied electric bias and is commonly assumed to occur under the action of the local electric field induced by free and trapped charge carriers.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref92">92</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref93">93</xref>
 </sup> In the case of electrical charge injection, this effect might be more pronounced because of possible charge imbalance and higher electrical field. While reported EQEs of perovskite LEDs are rapidly increasing, the stability of devices remains a major obstacle. Further studies are required to unveil the factors governing the long-term stability, which may include degradation of the charge-transporting layers or the perovskite layer. We tend to assume that the fundamental issue lies with the facile electrochemical reduction of Pb
 <sup>2+</sup> to metallic Pb. If true, this degradation path should be more pronounced for higher electronegativities of halide, e.g. for chlorides.
</p>
