<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Electroluminescence (EL) of layered 2D lead-halide perovskites had been known since the early 1990s.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref36">36</xref>
 </sup> The interest in PL from lead halide perovskites had revived in 2013–2014 (e.g., thin-film MAPbBr
 <sub>3</sub> LEDs),
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref37">37</xref>
 </sup> and these efforts had been motivated by and had paralleled the use of MAPbX
 <sub>3</sub> films in photovoltaics. Soon thereafter, the LED reports extended to the newcomer colloidal CsPbX
 <sub>3</sub> NCs,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref38">38</xref>
 </sup> as well as their FA and MA NC cousins.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref41">41</xref>
 </sup> Reduction of structural and electronic dimensionalities and efficient electronic passivation of the surfaces and interfaces—either using colloidal NCs as presynthesized inks for the deposition of the emissive layers or by inducing layering, compositional segregation and gradients, and nanograin formations in situ upon coating from precursors—had been sought as major means of enhancing the EL properties.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref42">42</xref>
 </sup> These structures benefit from the reduction of the exciton diffusion length, increasing exciton binding energy, and oscillator strength.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref42">42</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref43">43</xref>
 </sup> Rapid progress in the development of perovskite-based LEDs emitting in green
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref44">44</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref52">52</xref>
 </sup> and red
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref45">45</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref53">53</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref55">55</xref>
 </sup> led to the demonstration of the external quantum efficiencies (EQE) exceeding 20%.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref56">56</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref57">57</xref>
 </sup> As a general trend, NC-based perovskite LEDs fall somewhat behind their precursor-deposited thin-film counterparts; for instance, green LEDs based on NCs have thus far yielded lower best EQE value of 16.48% for Cs/FAPbBr
 <sub>3</sub> NCs,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref58">58</xref>
 </sup> while the majority of reports present values well below 10%. Development of blue perovskite LEDs lags far behind those emitting in green and red regions. For the NC-based LEDs the best EQE values are stagnant at 
 <italic>ca</italic>. 2% for the region of 460–490nm.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref50">50</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref59">59</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref62">62</xref>
 </sup> Congreve and co-workers optimized the device architecture for the deep-blue emitting devices by modifying the hole-transporting layer surface with Nafion perfluorinated ionomer (PFI) and reached 0.5% for LEDs emitting at 465 nm.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref60">60</xref>
 </sup> More recently, the same group introduced Mn
 <sup>2+</sup> doping for improving PLQY of CsPb(Br/Cl)
 <sub>3</sub> NCs, thereby boosting the EQE values to 2.12% at 466 nm.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref60">60</xref>
 </sup> With device brightness of 212 Cd/m
 <sup>2</sup>, this is currently the best-performing perovskite LED in the deep blue region. An alternative approach to blue perovskite LEDs is to form an emissive layer from lower dimensionality (i.e., 2D) perovskite materials with bulky cations such as butylammonium (BA), phenylethylammonium (PEA), or phenylbutylammonium (PBA), which separate few-octahedra-thick lead halide slabs, thereby introducing strong quantum confinement of the excitons and a blue shift of the emission.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref59">59</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref63">63</xref>
 </sup> Jun Xing et al. used similar, in situ formed 2D perovskites such as PEA
 <sub>2</sub>A
 <sub>1.5</sub>Pb
 <sub>2.5</sub>Br
 <sub>8.5</sub> to fabricate LEDs with EQE of 1.5% at 490 nm.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref64">64</xref>
 </sup> Mn
 <sup>2+</sup> doping of such films (PEA
 <sub>0.2</sub>Cs
 <sub>0.4</sub>MA
 <sub>0.6</sub>Pb
 <sub>(1–
  <italic>y</italic>)
 </sub>Mn
 <sub>
  <italic>y</italic>
 </sub>(BrCl)
 <sub>3</sub>) slightly improved device efficiency to 0.58% in the blue.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref61">61</xref>
 </sup> Such 2D materials generally exhibit good color stability due to the absence of halide segregation, which is a notable issue with mixed-halide perovskites.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref62">62</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref65">65</xref>
 </sup> State-of-the-art results for such materials show that highly confined (Cs/FA)PbBr
 <sub>3</sub> NCs formed in situ within the quasi-2D PBABr phase allowed achieving EQE of 9.5% at 483 nm while showing the brightness of 700 cd/m
 <sup>2</sup>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref66">66</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
