<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The lower performance of green and red NC-based LEDs, compared to the best-performing thin-film counterparts, is commonly attributed to the diverse roles played by long-chain surface capping ligands. On the one hand, the use of long-chain ligands allows for unmatched control over the NC size and shape as well as for ensuring morphological homogeneity within the NC ensemble. These ligands are paramount for the entire life cycle of NCs, from the synthesis of NCs to the retention of the long-term structural and colloidal integrity and for their processing into thin, homogeneous films. On the other hand, controlling and adjusting the inorganic–organic interface of colloidal perovskite NCs had proven to be cumbersome and far more complex as compared to the present state in the surface science of other semiconductor NCs. Structural softness, lattice polarity, and finite solubility in the wide variety of solvents are the factors causing overall lability of perovskite NCs. In this context, highly dynamic and loose binding of the capping ligands, which are thus far most effective in the perovskite NC synthesis [oleic acid (OA) and oleylamine (OLA)], hinders the efficient isolation and purification of NCs and necessitates the presence of the same or alternative ligand in the excess for maintaining the NC stability. This, in turn, imparts the density and other morphological characteristics of the NC films and hence the charge transport through the device. While solution- or solid-state ligand exchange strategies had been highly successful in mitigating these challenges with conventional semiconductor NCs (typically Cd-, Pb-, and other metal chalcogenides), little progress had been achieved with perovskite NCs. In the context of LED research, the most effective approach has been to use didodecyldimethylammonium bromide (DDAB) for a postsynthetic surface treatment
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref67">67</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref72">72</xref>
 </sup> or as an additive during the synthesis.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref45">45</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref73">73</xref>
 </sup> Concomitant passivations of undercoordinated Pb-atoms with bromide anions and strong affinity of the DDA-cation to the surface A-site give rise to both electronic passivation and hence near-unity PLQY values, as well as improved stability and processability, as had been thoroughly examined experimentally and computationally by us
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref74">74</xref>
 </sup> and others.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref75">75</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref77">77</xref>
 </sup> Pan et al. applied DDAB-treatment to CsPb(Br/Cl)
 <sub>3</sub> NCs in solutions, reaching 1.9% EQE at 490 nm; however, rather low brightness of 35 Cd/m
 <sup>2</sup> was reported.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref67">67</xref>
 </sup> Combined application of both DDAB and its chloride analog (didodecydimethyammonium chloride, DDAC) had been shown to yield EQE values of 0.86% at 480 nm and 0.1% at 458 nm.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref72">72</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
