<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Highly luminescent CsPb(Br
 <sub>1–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>Cl
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>)
 <sub>3</sub> NCs with adjustable chloride content (represented by 
 <italic>x</italic> as a molar proportion of chloride) were synthesized using hot-injection methodology with DDAX as a sole long-chain (C
 <sub>12</sub>) capping ligand. The synthesis, outlined in 
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>
 </xref>, was carried out in mesitylene as a solvent and under nitrogen atmosphere. PbBr
 <sub>2</sub> was first solubilized in mesitylene by mixing with DDAB or (DDAB–DDAC) and quickly heated to 150–160 °C to obtain a transparent colorless solution. PbBr
 <sub>2</sub> alone is not soluble in mesitylene; however, it forms lead-bromide anionic species (presumably PbBr
 <sub>3</sub>
 <sup>–</sup> and the like) when combined with DDAB at elevated temperatures (&gt;100 °C). Recently, Song et al. reported the use of the quaternary ammonium salts such as tetraoctylammonium bromide (TOAB) in the synthesis of CsPbBr
 <sub>3</sub> NCs at room temperature, followed by introducing DDAB ligands on the surface of the formed NCs.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref48">48</xref>
 </sup> While TOAB aids in solubilizing PbBr
 <sub>2</sub> at room temperature, it is too bulky for binding to the NC surface. We find that for the synthesis at elevated temperatures DDAB alone can play both roles (solubilizer and surfactant). As a source of Cl ions, DDAC was found to be more convenient than the addition of PbCl
 <sub>2</sub>; the latter exhibits very low solubility in nonpolar solvents. A separate Cs
 <sup>+</sup> stock solution was prepared by dissolving Cs
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub> in diisooctylphosphinic acid and toluene. The Cs solution was then swiftly injected into the first solution. An instant nucleation of NCs is seen as a rapid yellow-green coloration. In this synthesis, we completely omitted OA and OLA as capping ligands, which dynamically and loosely bind to the surface of lead halide perovskite NCs and easily desorb.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref78">78</xref>
 </sup> Earlier studies indicated that oleate ligands are mostly absent on the surface of such NCs,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref78">78</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref79">79</xref>
 </sup> and the main role of OA is the protonation of OLA. The trouble with OLA cation is that it rapidly loses its proton and desorbs from the NC surface. In contrast, DDA is a quaternary cation with a static positive charge, and hence, no acid is needed in the reaction mixture for adjusting the pH value. DDAX-stabilized NCs sustain two washing steps by the repetitive destabilization with the moderately polar solvent (acetone–toluene mixture) and redispersion in cyclohexane, as can be judged from the retention of optical characteristics (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.9b01915/suppl_file/nz9b01915_si_001.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Figure S1</ext-link>). We note that DDAX-coated NCs are not dispersible in toluene, which is a typical solvent of choice for NCs capped with longer-chain OLA and OA ligands. For the subsequent experimentation with LED devices, we have chosen to focus on weakly confined 9–10 nm large NCs and adjust their band gap energy by the halide composition. A detailed study on the size- and shape-control in this DDAX-based synthesis, as well as on the specifics of surface chemistry using NMR spectroscopy and molecular dynamics calculations, is underway and will be published elsewhere.
</p>
