<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The sample was a plane-parallel single Si crystal. The top (entrance) and bottom (back) surfaces of the crystal were polished by a non-disturbance polishing method at Sharan Inc. The size was 50 mm long, 15 mm wide and 0.28 mm thick. One end of the sample was clamped and the other end was free along the gravity direction as shown in Fig. 3
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>). The sample was bent due to gravity and the residual strain. The experiments were carried out using X-rays from synchrotron radiation at the bending-magnet beamline 15C, Photon Factory, Tsukuba, Japan. The measuring optical system is shown in Fig. 3
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>). The X-rays were σ-polarized and had a very narrow band of energy achieved by using an Si(111) double-crystal monochromator. The X-ray energy was 11 100 eV, which was determined by measuring XANES (X-ray absorption near-edge structure) from a thin Ge plate near the Ge 
 <italic>K</italic> absorption edge (11 103 eV) with an accuracy of ±0.5 eV. The distance from the source to slit 1 was 30 m and that from slit 1 to the sample was 300 mm. The vertical width of slit 1 was 0.02 mm. In Fig. 3
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>), 
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>h</sub>, 
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>r</sub>, 
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>t</sub>, 
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>lr</sub> and 
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>lt</sub> are the intensities of the diffracted wave, the reflected beam except for the diffracted beam, the transmitted beam, the emitted beam from the lateral surface in the diffracted-wave direction and that in the transmitted-wave direction, respectively. As shown in Fig. 3
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>), the X-rays were incident on the crystal with the azimuth perpendicular to the bending direction. The incident glancing angle was fixed at the angle where the rocking curve of 
 <italic>P</italic>
 <sub>r</sub> in Fig. 3
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>e</italic>) showed the peak and the anomalous transmission was maximized. The X-ray intensities were measured by the scintillation counters (SC1 and SC2) and recorded on a nuclear plate (ILFORD L4; emulsion thickness, 25 µm). The incident and reflected X-ray geometries with respect to the sample are shown for positive and negative values of β in Figs. 3
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>c</italic>) and 3
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>d</italic>), respectively. For observation of IFRB, it is important to make the value of |β| small. If 
 <italic>l</italic> denotes the distance from the free edge to the incident plane and 
 <italic>L</italic> that from the free edge to the fixed edge, |β| is proportional to 
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="a-75-00842-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> (Jongsukswat 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2013
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb18"> ▸</xref>). In the present experiment the distance 
 <italic>l</italic> was between 3.25 and 4 mm, and 
 <italic>L</italic> was 48 mm.
</p>
