<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref> shows the section topographs of Si(220) measured in the diffracted direction under only the gravity force. Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref> shows those measured in the transmitted-wave direction. The strain gradient was negative in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>) and Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>), and positive in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>) and Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>). The exposure time for taking one topograph was 120 min for Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>), 60 min for Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>), 15 min for Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>) and 30 min for Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>). In Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>) the interference fringes in the upper part are attributed to IFLSD and those in the lower part to IFRB. The vertical direction of the lower part corresponds to the distance 
 <italic>x</italic> from the incident point of the X-rays on the entrance surface and that in the upper part corresponds to the distance 
 <italic>z</italic> from the edge of the entrance surface on the lateral surface. The horizontal direction corresponds to distance 
 <italic>l</italic>. Ten dark lines are observed in IFRB as indicated by white lines. The plot of digitized intensities of IFRB is given on the left side of the figure, showing ten peaks in the range of 
 <italic>x</italic> between 5.5 and 8.5 mm. The number of interference fringes in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>) is larger than that in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>) where the number is three in the same range of 
 <italic>x</italic>. The distance between two adjacent dark lines in IFRB increases as a function of 
 <italic>x</italic>, which is a similar variation to that in IFMRB shown in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>). The distance between two adjacent dark lines in IFLSD in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>) is smaller than that in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>). The dark contrast indicated by the white arrow in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>) is accretions on the nuclear emulsion plate. In Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>a</italic>) the interference fringes in the upper part are attributed to IFTB and those in the lower part to IFLST. The number of dark lines in IFTB indicated by white lines is five in the same range of 
 <italic>x</italic>. The horizontal direction is the same as in Fig. 4
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>. The distance between two adjacent dark lines increases as a function of 
 <italic>x</italic>, which is a similar variation to that in IFRB. In Fig. 5
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref>(
 <italic>b</italic>) the interference fringes in the upper part are attributed to IFTB and those in the lower part to IFLST. The number of dark lines in ITFB for β &lt; 0 is almost the same as that for β &gt; 0 in the same range of 
 <italic>x</italic>.
</p>
