<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par15">Two base metals were used in this study: a commercial purity (99.5%) Al-1050 aluminum alloy and a ZK60 magnesium alloy containing 6.0 wt.% Zn and 0.72 wt.% Zr. These materials were received after extrusion to rods with diameters of 10 mm. The rods were sliced into disks with thicknesses of ~1.2 mm and polished on both sides to produce thicknesses of ~0.83 mm. The disks were processed by HPT under quasi-constrained conditions in a monotonic torsional manner at room temperature. Two sets of Al and Mg disks were processed together by HPT with the disks piled on the depression in the lower anvil in the order of Al/Mg/Al (thus, the volume ratio of Al:Mg is 2:1) without any special sample surface treatment
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup> (Illustrations are available in Extended Data Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>). Specifically, when a disk sample is processed in conventional HPT, the shear strain, γ, is computed by a relationship of the form
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>
 </sup>
 <disp-formula id="Equ2">
  <label>2</label>
  <alternatives>
   <tex-math id="M11">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal} \usepackage{amsmath} \usepackage{wasysym} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{upgreek} \setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt} \begin{document}$$\gamma =\frac{2\pi Nr}{h}$$\end{document}</tex-math>
   <math id="M12" display="block">
    <mi>γ</mi>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mfrac>
     <mrow>
      <mn>2</mn>
      <mi>π</mi>
      <mi>N</mi>
      <mi>r</mi>
     </mrow>
     <mi>h</mi>
    </mfrac>
   </math>
   <graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_53614_Article_Equ2.gif" position="anchor" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  </alternatives>
 </disp-formula>where 
 <italic>N</italic> is the number of revolutions and 
 <italic>r</italic> and 
 <italic>h</italic> are the radius and height (or thickness) of the disk, respectively. The HPT processing was conducted under a compressive pressure of 6.0 GPa for 100 turns at a rotational speed of 1 rpm and thus the edge of the sample receives a maximum shear strain of ~4,000. In addition, one of the disks was taken after processing and naturally aged at room temperature for 60 days to evaluate the microstructural stability. It is reasonable to note that the median plane of the sample stack shows some material loss due to outflow between the anvils and this tends to be excessive for Mg thereby reducing the initial overall composition of 26 at.% Mg from a volume ratio 2:1 to the observed 14.2 at.% Mg.
</p>
