<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">Semiconducting metal halide-based perovskite nanocrystals (NCs) have been studied extensively over the past several years due to their remarkable optoelectronic properties, low-cost solution processability, and scalable fabrication
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>. These superior properties make them promising materials in modern optoelectronic devices such as solar cells, light-emitting diodes (LEDs), photodetectors, and lasers
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. The previous studies reported that all-inorganic lead halide perovskites (CsPbX
 <sub>3,</sub> ‘X’-halides) with better moisture and thermal stability in comparison to their organometallic counterparts renders excellent photophysical properties such as high defect tolerance, high photoluminescence quantum yield (PLQY), narrow emission line-widths, and wide color gamut
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>. These are desirable for lighting applications, especially for the LEDs. Song 
 <italic>et al</italic>. for the first time, reported the blue, green, and yellow LEDs based on CsPbX
 <sub>3</sub> perovskite quantum dots (QDs)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>. Thereafter, the application of this type of material in white LEDs (WLEDs) is on the verge of rapid development. Pan 
 <italic>et al</italic>. demonstrated a WLED employing the green-emitting CsPbBr
 <sub>3</sub>-polymethyl methacrylate (PMMA) and red-emitting CdSe/ZnS-PMMA composite film in combination with GaN chips, which yields a luminous efficiency of radiation (LER) of 65 lm·W
 <sup>−1</sup> and the CIE color coordinates of (0.31, 0.32)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>. Bi 
 <italic>et al</italic>. incorporated the red-emitting CsPbX
 <sub>3</sub> perovskite QDs and yellow-emitting YAG:Ce phosphor with a commercial blue LED chip to achieve white light emission with a tunable correlated-color temperature (CCT) from 2854 K to 11,068 K, color-rendering index (CRI) of 89, LER of above 84.7 lm·W
 <sup>−1</sup>, and the CIE color coordinates optimized to (0.33, 0.32)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>. Li 
 <italic>et al</italic>. fabricated the WLEDs by using the green and red emissive CsPbX
 <sub>3</sub> QDs on a blue LED chip that leads to a tunable CCT in the range of 2500 K to 11,500 K and the color coordinates of (0.33. 0.30)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. The properties exhibited by the WLEDs based on halide perovskites are superior compared to the commercialized phosphor-based WLEDs, especially in regards to cost and color rendition
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
