<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">However, the lead commonly present in these materials currently precludes their practical utilization to a greater extent due to its toxicity. Therefore, the development of lead-free perovskites is the key to practical applications. As a result, much effort has been devoted to the development of lead-free or lead-reduced halide perovskites with suitable band gaps that are capable of preserving their optoelectronic properties by incorporating the non-toxic elements
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>
 </sup>. In this regard, the synthesis of lead-free perovskites using the tin (Sn
 <sup>2+</sup>) as a divalent cation with a potential application in solar cells has been demonstrated primarily, however, their poorer stability, smaller bandgap, and intrinsic defects yielding a low PLQY discourage further applications
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>
 </sup>. Jacobson 
 <italic>et al</italic>. replaced Pb
 <sup>2+</sup> completely by using Sr
 <sup>2+</sup>, however, the bandgap energy (E
 <sub>g</sub> = 3.6 eV) was found to be too large to serve as photon down-conversion materials in WLEDs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup>. The lead-free double perovskites with A
 <sub>2</sub>BB′X
 <sub>6</sub> structure (where ‘B’ is a monovalent cation and ‘B′’ is a trivalent cation) were also proposed as a candidate for the applications in optoelectronic devices
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>
 </sup>. These compounds have good stability, suitable bandgap energy, and are non-toxic in nature
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup>. However, the double perovskites tend to have an indirect bandgap, which is not favorable for the applications in optoelectronic devices
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
