<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">The incorporation of the homovalent or heterovalent metal cations at the B-site of halide perovskites to partially replace the Pb
 <sup>2+</sup> cations has also been explored as an alternative approach to reducing the toxicity of lead and make them environmental-friendly
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup>. Recently, we reported the synthesis of lead-reduced CsPb
 <sub>1-x</sub>Mg
 <sub>x</sub>X
 <sub>3</sub> (up to x = 20%) NCs for the fabrication of the WLEDs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>
 </sup>. Our experimental results showed that the as-synthesized NCs retained the superior optical properties and these NCs have been utilized to fabricate WLEDs with superior color quality. Partial replacement of Pb
 <sup>2+</sup> using Zn
 <sup>2+</sup> in lead halide perovskites and their potential applications in photovoltaic cells have been demonstrated
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>
 </sup>. Besides the reduction of lead content, the as-fabricated solar cells resulted in enhanced thermal stability and improved photovoltaic performance of the device structure. The partial substitution of the reduced B-site cations (compared to Pb
 <sup>2+</sup>) such as the transition metal ions can reduce the size of eight cubo-octahedral voids which has the potential to decrease all of the cubo-octahedral voids for A-site cations in the ABX
 <sub>3</sub> lattice. This results in a stable perovskite phase with superior thermal stability
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>
 </sup>. Furthermore, Shen 
 <italic>et al</italic>. observed that the application of Zn
 <sup>2+</sup>-alloyed CsPbI
 <sub>3</sub> NCs as a light emitter resulted in an LED with a peak external quantum efficiency of 15.1%
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>
 </sup>. However, there is no report on the fabrication of WLEDs using Zn
 <sup>2+</sup>-alloyed CsZn
 <sub>x</sub>Pb
 <sub>1-x</sub>X
 <sub>3</sub> NCs as color conversion layers.
</p>
