<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Garnets are a family of minerals widely used as gemstones. Garnet has the formula 
 <italic>A</italic>
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>B</italic>
 <sub>2</sub>(
 <italic>X</italic>O
 <sub>4</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub> (
 <italic>A</italic> = Fe, Ca, Mg, Y, La or rare earth; 
 <italic>B</italic> = Al, Fe, Ga, Ge, Mn, Ni or V; 
 <italic>X</italic> = Si, Ge or Al), where 
 <italic>A</italic>, 
 <italic>B</italic> and 
 <italic>X</italic> are cation sites with eight, six and four coordinated O ions, respectively. In nature the gemstones are generally silicates. This class of materials has recently attracted attention in the battery community as there are Li-stuffed garnet structures which show promise as a solid electrolyte material. A high conductivity of 10
 <sup>−3</sup> S cm
 <sup>−1</sup> has been observed in Li
 <sub>6.4</sub>La
 <sub>3</sub>Zr
 <sub>1.4</sub>Ta
 <sub>0.6</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub> at 298 K. Depending on how the samples of this compound are synthesized and what the composition is, multiple cubic phases are frequently observed. However, the difference in the lattice parameters of these phases is so small that they can only be separated using the very high resolution diffraction available at synchrotron sources. A similar phenomenon has also been observed in natural garnets and is proposed to be the source of the observed birefringence in these compounds (Antao, 2013
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb3"> ▸</xref>). In order to explore the resolution achievable on POWGEN, several samples of garnets were measured using two center wavelengths of 0.8 and 2.665 Å. X-ray data of these samples were available from the 11BM beamline at the Advanced Photon Source, which is one of the highest-resolution synchrotron powder diffractometers with a resolution of &lt;1.4 × 10
 <sup>−4</sup> Δ
 <italic>d</italic>/
 <italic>d</italic>. The highest resolution on POWGEN, like all other TOF diffractometers, is at the backscattering detectors. When the data are collected at 0.8 Å, the 
 <italic>d</italic> spacings covered by backscattering are from 0.1 to 0.6 Å, where there is a high degree of overlap of reflections. However, when the data are collected at a longer wavelength, the longer-
 <italic>d</italic>-spacing reflections are now measured at the backscattering detectors and as a result the peak splitting from the multiple cubic phases is clearly observed in the pattern. Data collected in the same range at both beamline 11BM at APS and POWGEN at SNS are shown in Fig. 9
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig9"> ▸</xref>. This example highlights that very small differences in lattice parameter can be detected at POWGEN, which is sometimes critical for following phase transitions and samples with mixtures of similar phases.
</p>
