<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Noise can be defined as an unwanted or unpleasant outdoor sound generated by human activity, and is one of the main environmental problems all over the world [
 <xref rid="B1-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. This kind of pollution can be controlled in each of the three phases into which its propagation is divided: (i) Noise generation at the source; (ii) transmission of noise from the source to the receiver, and (iii) noise reception. The most useful solution to control noise in its phase of transmission from the source to the receiver is the use of acoustic barriers or acoustic screens (ABs). In 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="sensors-19-04881-f001">Figure 1</xref>a, one can see an outline of the acoustic performance of these devices. Classical ABs are formed by continuous rigid material with a minimum superficial density of 20 kg/m
 <sup>2</sup> [
 <xref rid="B2-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>] (see an example in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="sensors-19-04881-f001">Figure 1</xref>b). However, these classical ABs present some drawbacks related with aesthetic and communication problems along with their limited technological performance in noise control, as they are not able to discriminate between types of sound and therefore the same AB is used to attenuate very different noises [
 <xref rid="B3-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. In order to obtain ABs with high noise control performance, new advanced materials called sonic crystals are being used, with the ABs formed by these materials called sonic crystal acoustic screens (SCASs). Sonic crystals can be defined as a heterogeneous material consisting of periodic arrays of acoustic scatterers embedded in air [
 <xref rid="B5-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>] (see 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="sensors-19-04881-f001">Figure 1</xref>c). A great effort has been made to analyze the physical properties of these new materials and to apply them to the field of environmental acoustics due to their excellent properties in noise control [
 <xref rid="B6-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>], or to analyze their behavior regarding wave propagation in viscoelastic materials instead of in air [
 <xref rid="B9-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]. One of these interesting properties is their permeability to wind and water as they are discontinuous materials. This permeability can help the placement of ABs in environments that until now were forbidden, as is the case of desert areas, where there is significant transportation of sand due to the existing wind. However, this possibility requires the use of specific techniques to estimate the volume of sand displaced in the presence of SCASs with great precision. 
</p>
