<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>For this purpose, we used photogrammetry, which can be defined as a set of methods for determining the geometric properties of objects from photographic images. A new photogrammetric technique, called the structured light system technique (SLST) [
 <xref rid="B11-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>], has been developed in the last years. SLST allows three-dimensional surface reconstruction of objects with low cost and very high accuracy. SLST is used successfully in a variety of fields, such as surgery [
 <xref rid="B13-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>], industry [
 <xref rid="B14-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>], and aeronautics [
 <xref rid="B15-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], or even in the documentation of cultural heritage [
 <xref rid="B13-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B18-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. Due to its specific characteristics of accuracy and cost, SLST seems the ideal technique to work together with the acoustic part to establish the noise abatement performance of any kind of AB—classical and SCAS—in sandy soils. The use of integrated photogrammetic-acoustic methods is not new and has been increasingly used in recent years in various fields of science and technology. Some examples of this use, without pretending to be exhaustive, have recently been proposed in the characterization of stone building materials, also using a laser scanner [
 <xref rid="B19-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>], in the reconstruction of natural and archeological underwater landscapes [
 <xref rid="B20-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>] or topography [
 <xref rid="B21-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>], to estimate the direction of drift and velocity of directional sonobuoys [
 <xref rid="B22-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>], for noise abatement in the design process of aircrafts in a wind tunnel [
 <xref rid="B23-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>], to develop a method to obtain dynamic three-dimensional modeling of channel tunnels [
 <xref rid="B24-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>], or finally to predict the collapse and instability of rocks’ mass structure in echelon flaws [
 <xref rid="B25-sensors-19-04881" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>].
</p>
