<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig4">
 <label>Fig. 4</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Calculated Fermi surface arcs (FPLO). 
   <bold>a</bold> Three-dimensional representation of the Fermi surface of YbMnBi
   <sub>2</sub> without canting. Colors correspond to Fermi velocities. Blue Fermi surfaces in the middle of the BZ are highly 3D and are occasionally seen in different experimental FS maps as diffused intensity, e.g., Figure 
   <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a</xref> and Supplementary Fig. 
   <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">8</xref>. 
   <bold>b</bold> Location of all Weyl points in the BZ for the case of 10° canting. The color of the WPs indicates the chirality. 
   <bold>c</bold> FS contour for the 
   <italic>k</italic>
   <sub>z</sub> corresponding to Weyl points #5 and #6, which are shown as small crosses in the places where the lens connects to the electron pocket. 
   <bold>d</bold> FS contours of the bulk bands and arcs corresponding to the upper (red) and lower (blue) surfaces obtained in 14-unit-cell-slab calculations, at 77 meV (slightly below the WP energy). 
   <bold>e</bold> Results of the same calculations as in (
   <bold>d</bold>) for the dispersion along a line perpendicular to the lens, cutting it at the midpoint between WPs #5 and #6. The arrow points to the closely separated topological surfaces states supporting the similar arcs on both surfaces. 
   <bold>f</bold> Spectral function calculated along the same line as for (
   <bold>e</bold>) for a semi-infinite-slab in the limit of extreme surface sensitivity (12 a
   <sub>B</sub> penetration depth). A topological surface state is clearly visible as sharp red feature on the blue background of the bulk continuum. 
   <bold>g</bold>–
   <bold>i</bold> Spectral function in momentum coordinates for different energies below and including the energy of the Weyl points #5 and #6. The Fermi arc is clearly seen as sharp red feature on the blue background of bulk FS crossings
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_11393_Fig4_HTML" id="d29e1269" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
