<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par28">Among solid-state lighting technology, white light-emitting diodes (WLEDs) are excellent candidates to replace incandescent lamps for their merits of high-energy conservation, long lifetime, high luminous efficiency, and polarized emissions [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. In general, WLEDs were recognized as one kind of the economical and efficient solid-state lighting sources [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. QD-LED technology is gradually developed over the past few years, because of high stability and high quantum yield (QY) of quantum dots (QDs) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. Recently, perovskites have attracted much attention, and they have been applied in many different fields [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. Perovskite solar cells with power conversion efficiency (PCE) exceeding 23% have been achieved because of their excellent absorption (Abs) coefficients, long carrier diffusion lengths, and high carrier mobilities [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. CsPbBr
 <sub>3</sub>-encapsulated PbSe wires have shown good optoelectronic performance including high responsivity (~ 10
 <sup>4</sup> A W
 <sup>−1</sup>) and fair response speed (~ ms), demonstrating their great potential application in photodetection fields [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. Additionally, perovskites have been introduced into photonic devices. The remarkable features of perovskite, such as rich phase compositions and low-temperature solution process ability, made perovskite can be applied in transistors [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. Low-threshold amplified spontaneous emission and lasing can be realized by CsPbX
 <sub>3</sub> QDs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. Most of all, perovskite QDs are the most promising material among QDs for LED application, due to high QY (up to &gt; 90%), intense photoluminescence (PL), simple preparation procedure, and highly tunable bandgaps (from 1.46 to 2.50 ev) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. However, the anion-exchange reaction between perovskites and instability of iodine (I)-containing perovskite largely restricted the development of perovskite QDs toward WLED application. Sun et al. proposed to use silica encapsulation to enhance stability and avoid anion exchange [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>]. The air stability of perovskite QDs was enhanced greatly, but the WLED stability is not good enough because of the significant dropping of red light. Then, Shen et al. used the anthracene shell to protect red-emitting perovskite QDs, which enhanced the LED stability against current [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>]. Zhong and coworkers directly used red-emitting K
 <sub>2</sub>SiF
 <sub>6</sub>:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> phosphor to replace iodine (I)-containing perovskite QDs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>]. Sun and coworkers also presented the same method to enhance the stability of LED [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Due to the sharp emission lines of perovskite QDs, they usually are used in backlight display application with blue-emitting LED chips [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. These WLEDs are not proper for solid-state lighting, because their CRI is quite low. Recently, several reports have prepared single-phase phosphor of perovskites, which possess broad linewidths. However, the QYs of this kind of material are relatively low [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>]. Another great problem is that the perovskite QDs contain lead, which is poison to health and environment [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>]. With the growing concerns about this risk, restrictions have been made to limit the use of Pb in consumer electronics. A lot of efforts have been done to explore and replace lead with less toxic elements like Sn, Ge, Bi, and Sb, which have analogous electronic band structure [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. However, their optoelectronic properties cannot be comparable with the Pb-based counterparts. Doping less toxic elements into perovskite lattice has been an alternative route, which can introduce new optical, electronic, and magnetic properties [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]. For example, Zhang et al. have prepared Mn-doped perovskite QDs with QYs up to 54% and the highest Mn substitution ratio was 46% [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]. Tang and coworkers reported Bi-doped lead-free inorganic perovskites. After doping Bi, the PLQY of Bi-doped Cs
 <sub>2</sub>SnCl
 <sub>6</sub> is enhanced to 78.9% [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>].
</p>
