<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the present study, we investigated the electrochemical properties of the magnesium-based intermetallic compounds as alternative anode active material for magnesium batteries. Even though the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> and the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Sb
 <sub>2</sub> have same crystal structure, the electrochemical activity of the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Sb
 <sub>2</sub> was almost negligible, while the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> showed highly reversible redox reaction at −2.1 V vs. Ag
 <sup>+</sup>/Ag. The XPS analyses of the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> thin films showed formations of the MgF
 <sub>2</sub>-based surface layer, which is the reduction product of the TFSA anion and also observed at the surface of the magnesium metal thin film. On the other hand, the excellent electrochemical activity of Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> in three electrolyte solutions: 1 mol L
 <sup>−1</sup> Mg(TFSA)
 <sub>2</sub> in AN, 0.5 mol L
 <sup>−1</sup> Mg(TFSA)
 <sub>2</sub> in BuMeG3, and 0.5 mol L
 <sup>−1</sup> Mg(TFSA)
 <sub>2</sub> in DME, suggests that the surface of the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> is not passivated even with the formation of the MgF
 <sub>2</sub> layer. We also investigated the stability of the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> and the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Sb
 <sub>2</sub> in ambient atmosphere and in water. The stability tests of the intermetallics revealed that the formation of the intermetallics is an effective way to avoid the passivation of the anode surface. The results also suggested the reversibility of the intermetallic anode is not only dependent on the passivation-free surface, but on the fast reaction kinetics. The BVS mapping showed that the Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> conduction pathway among tetrahedral sites well matches with the predicted fast Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> diffusion path by DFT modeling. Here we conclude that the formation of the intermetallics is effective strategy to avoid the passivation of anode surface, which hinders the reversible redox reaction. The fast Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> ion mobility in the solid phase is another key parameter to obtain the good reversibility applicable to a practical battery system.
</p>
