<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The implementation of the hydrogen economy requires the combination of renewable energies used for the production of hydrogen, and the utilization of this gas in fuel cells to recover the electrical energy and water as a byproduct. Fuel cells are called to replace combustion engines, showing great potential as energy conversion devices; they are able to transform the chemical energy of hydrogen directly into electrical energy with high efficiency and cleanness [
 <xref rid="B1-materials-12-01957" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-materials-12-01957" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-01957" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Among the fuel cells, the Solid Oxide Fuel Cells (SOFC) involve the most demanding technology from the point of view of the material selection. Due to the high operating temperatures (800–1000 °C), the enhanced reaction kinetics translates high efficiency in energy conversion, eliminating the problems that arise from the use of liquid electrolytes. As a drawback, these high operating temperatures mean a demanding stress for the different components, electrodes, solid electrolytes and interconnectors. Therefore, a reduction of the working temperature is mandatory, which entails the adoption of more performant materials to avoid diminishing the oxygen-reduction kinetics at the air electrode (cathode). An important strategy is to increase the active area of the electrode-electrolyte interface, with the development of new electrode materials that are able to transport ions and electrons simultaneously (known as Mixed Ionic and Electronic Conductors, MIECs) [
 <xref rid="B4-materials-12-01957" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. The use of MIEC materials reduces mechanical and chemical compatibility issues. Most of the known MIEC materials belong to the ABO
 <sub>3</sub> perovskite family, where A and B can be partially or totally substituted leading to a wide range of catalytic activities, oxygen stoichiometries and interesting transport properties [
 <xref rid="B5-materials-12-01957" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-01957" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>].
</p>
