<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The presence of background ions can have an indirect effect on the hydration of mineral constituent ions in solution. This may be important for Li-carbonate growth as Li
 <sup>+</sup> is predicted to have a coherent first hydration shell due to the strong electrostatic fields that are expected for small cations
 <sup>e.g.,</sup>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref56">56</xref>
 </sup> Of the monovalent, monatomic cations, Li
 <sup>+</sup> has the highest degree of covalent character in its interaction with the water molecules of its first hydration shell.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref57">57</xref>
 </sup> This effect results in a shorter distance between the water molecules and Li
 <sup>+</sup> ions, thus large enthalpy of hydration.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref56">56</xref>
 </sup> The presence of background ions is proposed to be able to disturb the hydration shell of ions facilitating nucleation and growth, known as “salting out”. Such decreases in solubility can be observed in carbonate phases, such as calcite, at high ionic strengths of solution.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref58">58</xref>
 </sup> In addition to the concentration of background ions in solution, the chemistry of the ions present is also proposed to effect the hydration of ions differently. For example, the presence of specific ions in solution that do not directly interact with a growing or dissolving surface have also been found to influence the rate of material addition
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>
 </sup> or removal,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref59">59</xref>
 </sup> respectively, to/from Ca- and Mg-bearing carbonate mineral surfaces. This effect is linked to the hydration characteristics of both the background and solute ions and their effect on the bulk water structure.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref60">60</xref>
 </sup> The changes in water structure measured using the Raman spectrometer implies that the presence of Li
 <sup>+</sup> leads to more extensive changes than expected for the solution ionic strength compared to Na
 <sup>+</sup> salts. In addition, the enthalpy of hydration for the different cations tested in these experiments follows the order Li
 <sup>+</sup> &gt; Na
 <sup>+</sup> &gt; K
 <sup>+</sup>.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref57">57</xref>
 </sup> Thus, given the elevated temperatures, which also disrupts Li
 <sup>+</sup> hydration,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref61">61</xref>
 </sup> the presence of the different background ions is not expected to alter the ability of the mineral to form. This hypothesis is consistent with the similar nucleation times observed for the experiments conducted with the two different concentrations of the monovalent cation and previous observations that high LiCl concentrations produce the salting out effect for Na-carbonate.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref55">55</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
