<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is clear from the simulations that the presence of water at the surfaces of zabuyelite has a large effect on surface stability and, therefore, the crystal morphology. As the presence of different ions may also influence surface hydration and can facilitate ion dehydration during growth,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref62">62</xref>
 </sup> the presence of different ions may also influence the crystal morphology. Both Na
 <sup>+</sup> and K
 <sup>+</sup> are unlikely to interact directly with the zabuyelite surfaces during growth based on the absence of changes in the surface groups of the zabuyelite observed with the ATR-IR and computational simulations of adsorption to hydrated zabuyelite surfaces. In addition, no large changes in morphology were predicted based on the presence of the two different ions, as was observed in the very similar aspect ratios for the crystals produced in the 1 M solutions with NaCl or KCl (
 <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">Table 
  <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">2</xref>
 </xref>). This indicates that the presence of Na
 <sup>+</sup> or K
 <sup>+</sup> will not make a significant difference for the surface hydration, thus mineral growth. Similarly, Cl
 <sup>–</sup> ions were also found not to interact directly with the surface. However, a change in the morphology is observed when 1 M of NaCl or KCl are present. For all three monatomic, monovalent ions, the most important faces on the elongated crystals are expected to be part of the {110} form. Therefore, the changes in the width of the crystals observed in the experiments cannot be attributed to the presence of Cl
 <sup>–</sup> versus Br
 <sup>–</sup> or the cations. Unlike the computational simulations and previous synthesis work where the faces with the largest areas were {110} forms,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref37">37</xref>
 </sup> the crystals formed in our experiments also express {010} and, in the case of sulfate, {100} forms. As the previous experiments were conducted at room temperature, as were the morphology simulations, it appears that additional crystal faces are stabilized during growth at 80 °C. The increase in the width
 <sub>{010}</sub> with increasing ionic strength, at the expense of the two additional faces at either side of the crystal (width
 <sub>{110}</sub>), implies that surface hydration disruption at the {010} can facilitate growth.
</p>
