<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Fig. 7
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7"> ▸</xref> shows a collection of core-level spectra for rhenium along with the corresponding 
 <italic>k</italic>-distributions. Technically, the change from valence-band mapping to a core level only requires setting the sample bias 
 <italic>U</italic>
 <sub>sa</sub> to the proper value, according to equation (3)
 <xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="fd3"/>. Only for very large changes of the kinetic energy might a slight refocusing of the objective lens be necessary. We recorded spectra and 
 <italic>k</italic>-patterns of the Re 4
 <italic>f</italic> doublet [(
 <italic>a</italic>,
 <italic>b</italic>), 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>B</sub> = 40.5/42.9 eV], the 5
 <italic>s</italic> line [(
 <italic>c</italic>,
 <italic>d</italic>), 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>B</sub> = 83 eV], the 4
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sub>5/2</sub> line [(
 <italic>e</italic>,
 <italic>f</italic>), 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>B</sub> = 261 eV], the 4
 <italic>p</italic>
 <sub>3/2</sub> line [(
 <italic>g</italic>,
 <italic>h</italic>), 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>B</sub> = 447 eV] and the 3
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sub>5/2</sub> line [(
 <italic>i</italic>,
 <italic>j</italic>), 
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>B</sub> = 1883 eV]. All core-level spectra and diffractograms show excellent signal-to-noise ratios after a few minutes of acquisition time. For core levels with very large cross sections, attenuators had to be inserted in the photon beam reducing the count rate to ∼2 Mcounts s
 <sup>−1</sup> to avoid multi-hit events originating from the Poisson statistics. Such events cannot be properly analyzed by the DLD and thus increase the background level (the photon pulse rate was 5 MHz). Using denser filling patterns of the storage ring, this problem would be eliminated and the 8 MHz count-rate capability of the detector could be fully exploited. The intensity scales in Fig. 7
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref> [except (
 <italic>c</italic>) and (
 <italic>g</italic>)] show the true zero, 
 <italic>i.e.</italic> despite the high-pass characteristic the background levels are not larger than in a hemispherical analyser. The spin–orbit splitting of Re 4
 <italic>d</italic> (13 eV), 4
 <italic>p</italic> (72 eV) and 3
 <italic>d</italic> (66 eV) is too large to fit into the selected energy interval at the given settings, hence only the line with the higher total angular momentum is recorded. Much larger energy ranges can be recorded at higher drift energies, 
 <italic>cf</italic>. Fig. 4(
 <italic>g</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>. All diffractograms are very pronounced and rich in detail, as will be discussed in Section 3.3
 <xref ref-type="sec" rid="sec3.3"/>.
</p>
