<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The fortuitous coincidence of the investigated spectrum with a signal originating from higher order of the monochromator [explained in Fig. 4(
 <italic>f</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4"> ▸</xref>] can also happen in core-level spectra. An example is shown in Fig. 7(
 <italic>k</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7"> ▸</xref>, where a group of 
 <italic>L</italic>
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>MM</italic> Auger lines falls onto the low-energy wing of the Re 4
 <italic>d</italic> line. The higher energy of the Auger signal is evident from the small circular region in which this signal is present, 
 <italic>i.e.</italic> these electrons are much faster than the true 4
 <italic>d</italic> core-level electrons. Spectrum (
 <italic>k</italic>) was taken in the area of the bright circle in (
 <italic>l</italic>). It is straightforward to estimate the energy of this Auger signal. At the given photon energy of 3.750 keV, the kinetic energy of the 4
 <italic>d</italic>
 <sub>5/2</sub> electrons is 3.484 keV (assuming a work function of 5 eV). These electrons are then retarded to 60 eV drift energy in the ToF section (
 <italic>i.e.</italic> their energy is reduced by 3424 eV). The Auger electrons arrived one period of the photon pulses (
 <italic>i.e.</italic> 192 ns) earlier. The fast Auger electrons from photon pulse #
 <italic>n</italic> coincide in time with the 4
 <italic>d</italic> electrons from photon pulse #
 <italic>n</italic> − 1. Using the simulation program with the proper lens settings, we arrive at an initial kinetic energy of the Auger electrons of ∼6000 eV, following photoemission from an inner shell by third-order photons with 
 <italic>h</italic>ν = 11.250 keV. Consulting Auger tables we arrive at the 
 <italic>L</italic>
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>MM</italic> cascade with kinetic energies of ∼5970 eV (∼6219 eV) for the 
 <italic>L</italic>
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>M</italic>
 <sub>2</sub>
 <italic>M</italic>
 <sub>5</sub> (
 <italic>L</italic>
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>M</italic>
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>M</italic>
 <sub>4</sub>) transitions. Note that the energy scale of the Auger signal is much wider due to the much higher drift energy of these electrons. Changing the photon energy to 3.500 keV shifts the undesired Auger signal out of the recorded time window [Figs. 7(
 <italic>e</italic>) and 7(
 <italic>f</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7"> ▸</xref>].
</p>
