<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par24">The combination of X-ray and neutron total-scattering data with a 3D distribution of diffuse-scattering intensity has proven to be effective for unraveling complex nanoscale perturbations of the average structure, such as encountered in PMN; our tests demonstrated that a complete picture could not be recovered using any of these techniques alone. The reconstructed chemical and displacive nanoscale ordering in PMN agrees well with the reported STEM images
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>, which attests to the fidelity of the present structural models and of the information that can be extracted from quantitative STEM measurements. The obtained atomistic picture invalidates the notion of chemical or polar-ordered regions dispersed in a disordered matrix, instead suggesting continuously varying order parameters. The displacements of Pb and Nb atoms at both 300 K and 200 K exhibit preference for the 〈111〉 directions, in contrast to previously proposed spherical-shell distributions. The 〈111〉 displacements are spatially correlated, but an additional higher-level correlation exists that is manifested in a preference for neighboring 〈111〉 clusters to represent 71° variants, resulting in a hierarchical assembly of PNRs; displacement-magnitudes follow this latter correlation. Preference for the 71° variants has also been noted in the most recent MD simulations of PMN
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>, which together with our results point to the significance of this effect. Consistent with the previously made inferences, the PNRs grow on cooling to 200 K. In addition, nanoscale regions with ordered antiparallel Pb displacements are shown to exist alongside the PNRs. While we observe no spatial coincidence between the PNRs and CORs, chemical ordering is still expected to affect the behavior of polar displacements, as can be inferred from the dependence of Pb displacements on the local Mg/Nb ratio. Our results suggest that the existing models of PMN that ignore the continuously varying degree of chemical ordering and overlook the inter-PNR correlations should be reconsidered. Understanding the origins of the inter-PNR correlation, its evolution with temperature and chemical substitutions, and ultimately its significance for the dielectric response represent topics for future theoretical and experimental research on PMN and its solid solutions. A logical step would be to perform similar refinements but add the 3D neutron diffuse scattering
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup> to the data suite, which should provide more accurate correlations of the oxygen displacements.
</p>
