<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>During variable pressure experiments, changes appear in the molecular geometries
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref>
 </sup> (e.g., interatomic distances and angles) due to the compression of molecular packing.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref>
 </sup> But these geometrical changes do not directly allow the deduction of changes in the electronic structure, which represents perhaps the most appealing and sensitive way of examining inter- and intramolecular interactions of compressed molecular crystals. The ability to experimentally observe electronic structure modifications under pressure is relatively recent.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref>
 </sup> Macchi’s work on 
 <italic>syn</italic>-1,6:8,13-biscarbonyl[14]annulene (BCA) (see 
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>
 </xref>) represents a major breakthrough.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref>
 </sup> This BCA crystal was chosen to be studied because its charge density at ambient pressure revealed an unusual bond path that links the two bridgehead carbonyl groups in almost 
 <italic>C</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>v</italic>
 </sub> molecular symmetry but shifts toward one of the resonant forms
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref>
 </sup> of an ideal aromatic system when high pressure is applied, as shown in 
 <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>
 </xref>. Applying pressure weakens the electron delocalization in the double bonds of the annulene ring that is observed at ambient pressure, distorting the systems to the 
 <italic>C</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>s</italic>
 </sub> subsymmetry point group of 
 <italic>C</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>v</italic>
 </sub>. As for the packing, BCA crystallizes with four molecules in the unit cell, with no change in space group (monoclinic 
 <italic>P</italic>2
 <sub>1</sub>/
 <italic>n</italic>) detected when increasing the pressure up to 7.7 GPa.
</p>
