<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>With 14 conjugated carbon atoms, the BCA annulene backbone is pseudo-Hückel aromatic (4
 <italic>n</italic>+2 π electrons) with a distortion from planarity imposed by the two carbonyl bridges.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref49">49</xref>
 </sup> Under ambient conditions, BCA has an experimentally verified 
 <italic>C</italic>
 <sub>2
  <italic>v</italic>
 </sub> symmetry.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref50">50</xref>
 </sup> In 
 <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>
 </xref> (where the basins are colored proportionally to the maximum DORI
 <sub>int</sub> found under each condition), the insight obtained from the DORI domains goes beyond geometrical effects. DORI captures the “electronic” equivalence of the bonds that is imposed by the symmetry. At high pressure, the additional stress perturbs the BCA electron delocalization and distorts the electron density of the annulene electron skeleton. This results in an inhomogeneous contraction of the C–C bonds reflected by the drastic changes in the DORI covalent patterns. (All DORI
 <sub>int</sub> and DORI
 <sub>vol</sub> are given in the 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acs.jpclett.9b00220/suppl_file/jz9b00220_si_001.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Supporting Information</ext-link>.) In particular, as attested by the electron density integrated within the DORI [
 <italic>f</italic>] domains (i.e., DORI
 <sub>int</sub>), the left side of the molecule shows an alternation between compressed (e.g., C1–C14, C2–C3, C4–C5, C6–C7) and loose (e.g., C2–C1, C5–C6) bonds, whereas the right side maintains a partial electron delocalization and smaller electronic compression of the C–C bonds (see 
 <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>
 </xref>). Those observations are in line with other indicators (e.g., electron density at the bond critical points,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref36">36</xref>
 </sup> delocalization indices,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref51">51</xref>
 </sup> and extremely localized molecular orbitals
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref52">52</xref>
 </sup>) and with quantum-chemical computations (see comparisons with gas-phase and periodic density functional theory (DFT) computations in the 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acs.jpclett.9b00220/suppl_file/jz9b00220_si_001.pdf" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Supporting Information</ext-link>). The electron density measured at high pressure integrated within the DORI [
 <italic>f</italic>] domains attests to the charge density accumulation in specific bonds of the annulene ring (see 
 <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure 
  <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>
 </xref>), which desymmetrizes the molecule. DORI, however, has the advantage of giving a more intuitive visual picture of the pressure-induced modifications of the covalent pattern using an experimental electron density as the sole ingredient.
</p>
