<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//Springer-Verlag//DTD A++ V2.4//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName A++V2.4.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.4?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName springer2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Nat Commun</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Nat Commun</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Nature Communications</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2041-1723</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group UK</publisher-name><publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6868216</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13293</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-13293-0</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Divalent europium-doped near-infrared-emitting phosphor for light-emitting diodes</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Qiao</surname><given-names>Jianwei</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Guojun</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Yayun</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Qinyuan</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>Zhiguo</given-names></name><address><email>xiazg@scut.edu.cn</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1764 3838</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.79703.3a</institution-id><institution>State Key Laboratory of Luminescent Materials and Devices and Institute of Optical Communication Materials, </institution><institution>South China University of Technology, </institution></institution-wrap>510641 Guangzhou, China </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0369 0705</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.69775.3a</institution-id><institution>The Beijing Municipal Key Laboratory of New Energy Materials and Technologies, School of Materials Sciences and Engineering, </institution><institution>University of Science and Technology Beijing, </institution></institution-wrap>100083 Beijing, China </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>20</day><month>11</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>20</day><month>11</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>10</volume><elocation-id>5267</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>23</day><month>7</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>1</day><month>11</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2019</copyright-statement><license license-type="OpenAccess"><license-p>
<bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International cLicense, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this license, visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">Near-infrared luminescent materials exhibit unique photophysical properties that make them crucial components in photonic, optoelectronic and biological applications. As broadband near infrared phosphors activated by transition metal elements are already widely reported, there is a challenge for next-generation materials discovery by introducing rare earth activators with 4<italic>f</italic>-5<italic>d</italic> transition. Here, we report an unprecedented phosphor K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> that gives an emission band centered at 740&#x02009;nm with a full-width at half maximum of 160&#x02009;nm upon 460&#x02009;nm blue light excitation. Combined structural and spectral characterizations reveal a selective site occupation of divalent europium in LuO<sub>6</sub> and K2O<sub>6</sub> polyhedrons with small coordination numbers, leading to the unexpected near infrared emission. The fabricated phosphor-converted light-emitting diodes have great potential as a non-visible light source. Our work provides the design principle of near infrared emission in divalent europium-doped inorganic solid-state materials and could inspire future studies to further explore near-infrared light-emitting diodes.</p></abstract><abstract id="Abs2" abstract-type="web-summary"><p id="Par2">Here the authors report a near-infrared K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor for non-visible light source application. The selective site occupation of Eu<sup>2+</sup> in LuO<sub>6</sub> and K2O<sub>6</sub> polyhedrons is found to be&#x000a0;responsible for the light emission and these insights could serve as design principles for discovery and design of such phosphors.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Solid-state chemistry</kwd><kwd>Optical materials</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">https://doi.org/10.13039/501100001809</institution-id><institution>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>51722202</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>Zhiguo</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2019</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par3">Near-infrared (NIR) light source has attracted attention for applications in medical fields, bio-sensing, food processing industry, and night-vision technologies<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup>. Traditional NIR light sources, such as halogen lamps and tungsten-halogen lamps, suffer from large sizes, low efficiency, short lifetime, and heat dissipation<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref></sup>. As an emerging field, researchers have made considerable efforts to explore new NIR emitters, such as InAs-ZnSe polymer nanocrystal, CH<sub>3</sub>NH<sub>3</sub>PbI<sub>3&#x02013;<italic>x</italic></sub>Cl<sub><italic>x</italic></sub> organometal halide perovskite, PbS@MAPbX<sub>3</sub> (X&#x02009;=&#x02009;I, Br) quantum dots, and Pt(II) complex based organic light-emitting diodes (LED)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup>. However, the low efficiency, poor stability or complex fabrication technique restrict their development. As a contrast, the high luminous efficiency, long operating life, and compact sizes make NIR LEDs useful, however, a narrow full-width at half maximum (FWHM) below 50&#x02009;nm seriously limit their applications in 3D sensing, food analyzing, and other specific fields<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup>. Therefore, discovery of broadband-emitting NIR light sources is a necessary and urgent requirement. In this regard, phosphor-converted light-emitting diodes LEDs (pc-LEDs) have attracted increasing interests considering more opportunities for tunable emission during the phosphors&#x02019; screening, and availability of simpler strategies for both materials design and fabrication of NIR pc-LEDs<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup>. Furthermore, the low cost of NIR phosphors is beneficial. However, one of the most significant challenges is the discovery of blue light pumped and efficient broadband NIR-emitting phosphors.</p><p id="Par4">Numerous studies on exploring NIR phosphors have been realized by doping transition metal ions (Cr<sup>3+</sup>, Ni<sup>2+</sup>, and Mn<sup>4+</sup>), Bi<sup>3+</sup> or rare earth ions (Pr<sup>3+</sup>, Nd<sup>3+</sup>, Tm<sup>3+</sup>, and Yb<sup>3+</sup>) into inorganic host materials<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref></sup>. However, the sharp line emission of rare earth ions with 4<italic>f</italic>-4<italic>f</italic> transition is not broad enough for the desired applications, and the absorption region is also very narrow and weak. The Ni<sup>2+</sup> doped materials show broad emission band around NIR region, but the low efficiency and IR laser excitation suspends the application<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref></sup>. Recently, Cr<sup>3+</sup> ion has been considered as an ideal NIR luminescent center, which can exhibit broad-band emission ~650&#x02013;1200&#x02009;nm with <sup>4</sup>T<sub>2</sub>&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;<sup>4</sup>A<sub>2</sub> transition<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>. However, mixed valence of Cr<sup>6+</sup> ions simultaneously exist in most Cr<sup>3+</sup> doped phosphors, which seriously quench NIR luminescent efficiency<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref></sup>. As one of important rare earth activators with 4<italic>f</italic>-5<italic>d</italic> transition, Eu<sup>2+</sup>-activated phosphors normally possess high efficiency and have been applied in the field of commercial white LEDs. More importantly, the tunable emission in the visible range is very popular to discover useful phosphors, and the typical examples include Sr[LiAl<sub>3</sub>N<sub>4</sub>]:Eu<sup>2+</sup> (red), <italic>&#x003b2;</italic>-SiAlON:Eu<sup>2+</sup> (green) and BaMgAl<sub>10</sub>O<sub>17</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> (blue)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup>. If Eu<sup>2+</sup>-doped phosphors can realize NIR emissions, it would launch a new era in NIR light source. However, in addition to the recent report on Ca<sub>3</sub>Sc<sub>2</sub>Si<sub>3</sub>O<sub>12</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup>, no other Eu<sup>2+</sup>-doped phosphors can achieve NIR emissions with the peak beyond 700&#x02009;nm<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. Unfortunately, though Ca<sub>3</sub>Sc<sub>2</sub>Si<sub>3</sub>O<sub>12</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> gives a broad-band emission ranging from 720 to 1100&#x02009;nm, it cannot be pumped by blue LEDs due to the lack of blue light absorption of the sample<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. Therefore, discovery of Eu<sup>2+</sup> activated NIR phosphors for blue light-pumped LEDs is an essential and difficult task for the emerging photonic, optoelectronic and biological applications.</p><p id="Par5">The emission energy distribution of Eu<sup>2+</sup> is generally related with the average bond lengths, coordination numbers and the symmetry of the cations and corresponding polyhedron occupied by Eu<sup>2+</sup><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup>. Many strategies, including neighboring-cation substitution, chemical unit cosubstitution and cation-size-mismatch have been used to tune visible photoluminescence of Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref></sup>. However, there is still a challenge to realize the NIR emission for the difficulties of obtaining strong crystal field splitting (CFS) and large centroid shift originating from Eu<sup>2+</sup>. Recently, our group has reported a new approach showing that Eu<sup>2+</sup> selectively occupies a site with small coordination number, which tends to large redshift as found in Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> with red emission<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>. If the cations&#x02019; sites occupied by Eu<sup>2+</sup> in Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> are substituted by smaller ions, this effect will produce a larger CFS and even realize NIR emission. Accordingly, we have designed a Eu<sup>2+</sup>-doped K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> NIR phosphor from isostructural Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> by substituting the large Rb<sup>+</sup> and Y<sup>3+</sup> ions with small K<sup>+</sup> and Lu<sup>3+</sup> ions to further increase the CFS effect<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par6">Here in this work, we show that K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> is the first Eu<sup>2+</sup>-doped NIR phosphor under 460&#x02009;nm blue light excitation and gives a broad-band emission peaking at 740&#x02009;nm in the NIR region (600&#x02013;900&#x02009;nm). Structural and spectral analysis results indicate that the selective Eu<sup>2+</sup> site occupation in LuO<sub>6</sub> and K2O<sub>6</sub> polyhedrons contributes to the NIR light emission in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup>. The as-fabricated phosphor-converted LEDs have the potential to be used for non-visible light source, and the result could initiate the exploration of Eu<sup>2+</sup>-doped NIR phosphors and other NIR spectroscopy applications.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2" sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Crystal structure of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup></title><p id="Par7">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref> shows the simulated X-ray diffraction (XRD) profile of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> and the measured XRD patterns for the K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:<italic>x</italic>Eu<sup>2+</sup> (<italic>x</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0&#x02013;0.05) with different Eu<sup>2+</sup>-doping concentrations. All diffraction peaks can be well indexed by hexagonal cell (<italic>P</italic>6<sub>3</sub>/<italic>mmc</italic>), and the parameters are similar to those of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> phase, confirming the successful synthesis of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphors<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref></sup>. To further understand the phase structure and sites occupation of Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions, Rietveld refinement were performed for K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:<italic>x</italic>Eu<sup>2+</sup> (<italic>x</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0, 0.01, 0.02, and 0.04), as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref> and Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>. All the refinements demonstrated low <italic>R</italic>-factors (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>). Moreover, Supplementary Tables&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref> and <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref> listed the parameters of atoms&#x02019; coordinates and bond lengths of the studied phases for the comparison.<fig id="Fig1"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>XRD patterns and crystal/local structure descriptions of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu. <bold>a</bold> Simulated and measured XRD patterns of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> and K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:<italic>x</italic>Eu<sup>2+</sup> (<italic>x</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0.01&#x02013;0.05). <bold>b</bold> Rietveld refinement and <bold>c</bold> crystal structure of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>. <bold>d</bold> Cell volume <italic>V</italic>(<italic>x</italic>) dependence of the Eu doping concentration (<italic>x</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0, 0.01, 0.02, 0.04). Small nonlinear trend can be associated with K&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;Eu replacement except for Lu&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;Eu substitution. <bold>e</bold> Dependence of the average bond length of Lu, K1, and K2 in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:<italic>x</italic>Eu<sup>2+</sup> (<italic>x</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0, 0.01, 0.02, 0.04)</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_13293_Fig1_HTML" id="d29e908"/></fig></p><p id="Par8">K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> host (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref>) offers one Lu sites with 6-fold coordination, and two different K sites: K1 (9-fold) and K2 (6-fold), for the possible occupation by Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions. The cell volume increases with <italic>x</italic> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref>), indicating that some Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions occupy Lu sites since the radius of Lu<sup>3+</sup> is smaller than that of Eu<sup>2+</sup> (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>). However, the unit cell volume, <italic>V</italic>(<italic>x</italic>) shows a nonlinear increasing trend with increasing Eu content, thus another occupation mechanism should exist simultaneously, which competes with the main trend and reduces cell volume. Such mechanism can be ascribed to K&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;Eu replacement because K ion is bigger than Eu ion (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>. To further explore the Eu<sup>2+</sup> selective site occupation, Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1e</xref> illustrates the average bond lengths of LuO<sub>6</sub>, K1O<sub>9</sub>, and K2O<sub>6</sub> polyhedron in different concentration of Eu<sup>2+</sup> doped K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> by extracting the data from Rietveld refinement. With increasing Eu<sup>2+</sup> doping concentration, the average bond lengths of K1-O remain nearly unchanged, while the bond lengths of K2-O and Lu-O change significantly. In addition, the d(K2-O) and d(Lu-O) exhibit the same trend. It is owing to the fact that the occupation of Eu in Lu sites will lead to longer d(Lu-O) bond length, simultaneously, the amount of Eu in K2 sites is reduced and thus d(K2-O) bond lengths also become longer. Therefore, one can conclude that the main doping mechanism is ascribed to the synergetic effect of Lu&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;Eu and K&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;Eu replacements in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>, which is similar to the site occupation of Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions in isomorphic Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>. The scanning electron microscopy (SEM) images and elemental mapping images in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref> reveal that K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> microcrystals are in well crystallized and K, Lu, Si, and O elements are homogeneously distributed.</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Photoluminescence properties of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup></title><p id="Par9">Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref> gives the room temperature photoluminescence emission (PL) and excitation (PLE) spectra of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup>. When monitored at 740&#x02009;nm, K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> gives an ultra-broad excitation band and a maximum excitation peak is found ~460&#x02009;nm in the range of 250 and 600&#x02009;nm. Such a broad excitation band should be ascribed to the 4&#x02009;f&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;5d transition of two different Eu<sup>2+</sup> sites in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>, as verified by the structural analysis discussed previously, and some sharp lines are related with the spectrophotometer itself. Supplementary Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3a</xref> illustrates the diffuse reflection spectra of Eu<sup>2+</sup> doped and undoped K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> samples. K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> host shows nearly no absorption from 300 to 800&#x02009;nm, however, K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> exhibits an ultra-broad absorption band from 250 to 600&#x02009;nm with the introduction of Eu<sup>2+</sup> in the host. K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> exhibits a white body color under natural light suggesting a band gap of about 5&#x02009;eV (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3b</xref>). The diffuse reflection spectra of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> are in accordance with the excitation spectrum discussed above. Such a broad absorption band from ultraviolet to visible light region leads to deep red body color under natural light (the inset of Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref>) and favors its application for blue light-pumped pc-LEDs. Thus, the NIR emission spectrum under 460&#x02009;nm excitation reveals a broadband emission centered at 740&#x02009;nm with FWHM ~160&#x02009;nm (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref>). This emission is originated from the typical 5d&#x02009;&#x02192;&#x02009;4&#x02009;f transition of Eu<sup>2+</sup>. The asymmetric spectral profile demonstrates that there exists more than one luminescent center in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup>. To verify this point, the PLE/PL spectra depending on the different experimental conditions are measured in detail. With the increase of excitation wavelengths from 300 to 360&#x02009;nm, the normalized emission spectra display a large redshift from 695&#x02009;nm to 745&#x02009;nm (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2b</xref>). But a small blueshift in emission is observed when the excitation wavelength is increased beyond 360&#x02009;nm. Also, the peak at 315&#x02009;nm in the normalized excitation spectra gradually decreased as the monitored wavelength increased from 660 to 800&#x02009;nm (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4a</xref>). These results proved that multiple luminescent centers existed in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup>. Moreover, under the excitation of the laser LED light source with different excitation wavelengths at 375&#x02009;nm and 450&#x02009;nm, Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4b</xref> gives the normalized PL spectra of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup>, suggesting the simillar spectral profiles.<fig id="Fig2"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>Photoluminescence properties of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphors. <bold>a</bold> PL and PLE spectra of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> measured/monitored at 460 and 740&#x02009;nm, and the inset shows the photograph of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> with deep red body color under natural light. <bold>b</bold> Room temperature PL spectra of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> under different excitation wavelength from 300 to 470&#x02009;nm. <bold>c</bold> The emission spectrum of the K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> and Gaussian fitting curves. <bold>d</bold> Decay curves and fitting results of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu measured at 80&#x02009;K and 300&#x02009;K under 450&#x02009;nm pulse laser diode excitation</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_13293_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e1305"/></fig></p><p id="Par10">The broad emission band upon the excitation of 460&#x02009;nm is exactly deconvoluted into two Gaussian spectral profiles with two peaks at 13900&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (719&#x02009;nm) and 12750&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (784&#x02009;nm), suggesting that Eu<sup>2+</sup> substitute two different cations in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2c</xref>). Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2d</xref> shows the PL decay curves of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> measured at low temperature (80&#x02009;K) and at room temperature (300&#x02009;K) under 450&#x02009;nm pulse laser diode excitation. The decay curves were comparatively fitted by mono- (<italic>n</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;1), bi- (<italic>n</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;2) and triple- (<italic>n</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;3) exponential functions:<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup><disp-formula id="Equ1"><label>1</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M1">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$I = \mathop {\sum }\limits_{i = 1}^n A_i\exp \left( { - \frac{t}{{\tau _i}}} \right),\;\;\;\;\;\left( {n = 1,2,3} \right)$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M2"><mml:mi>I</mml:mi><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:munderover accent="false" accentunder="false"><mml:mrow><mml:mo> &#x02211;</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>n</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:munderover><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>A</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>i</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mi>exp</mml:mi><mml:mfenced close=")" open="(" separators=""><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mi>t</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>&#x003c4;</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>i</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac></mml:mrow></mml:mfenced><mml:mo>,</mml:mo><mml:mspace width="0.16em"/><mml:mspace width="0.16em"/><mml:mspace width="0.16em"/><mml:mspace width="0.16em"/><mml:mspace width="0.16em"/><mml:mfenced close=")" open="(" separators=""><mml:mrow><mml:mi>n</mml:mi><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn><mml:mo>,</mml:mo><mml:mn>2</mml:mn><mml:mo>,</mml:mo><mml:mn>3</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:mfenced></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_13293_Article_Equ1.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula>where <italic>I</italic> denotes luminescence intensity, <italic>t</italic> represents time; <bold><italic>&#x003c4;</italic></bold><sub><italic>i</italic></sub> is lifetime for different components; and <italic>A</italic><sub><italic>i</italic></sub>
<italic>is</italic> the corresponding fitting constants. As compared in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2d</xref>, the decay curve measured at 80&#x02009;K is well fitted by both the bi- and triple-exponential function, and two fitting curves nearly overlap. However, the decay curves at 300&#x02009;K can be only fitted by the triple-exponential function, which is ascribed to an additional room temperature nonradiative transition owing to the lattice thermal vibration. Accordingly, the average lifetime values are 1.58&#x02009;&#x003bc;s (at 300&#x02009;K) and 2.28&#x02009;&#x003bc;s (at 80&#x02009;K), respectively. The detailed fitting results are presented in Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5</xref>. Moreover, the decay times are shortened with increasing Eu concentration (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5a</xref>) due to the energy transfer between different Eu<sup>2+</sup> luminescent centers. Upon the excitation of 340&#x02009;nm pulse laser diode, the average lifetime (1.69 &#x003bc;s) is longer than that under 450&#x02009;nm excitation (1.58&#x02009;&#x003bc;s) (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5b</xref> and Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5</xref>), which is attributed to the more contribution of long-lived emitters to average decay time under 340&#x02009;nm excitation.</p><p id="Par11">To evaluate the robustness of phosphors to heat and moisture, two sets of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu samples were exposed to the extremely environmental condition at 80% relative humidity and 80&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. The results suggest that the chemical stability of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> is relatively good (see details in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">6</xref>). The Eu<sup>2+</sup> content rarely changed to Eu<sup>3+</sup> depending on the prolonging duration time suggesting the good stability. One can also note that a small amount of Eu<sup>3+</sup> can be detected for the freshly prepared materials (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">7</xref>). Samples with different Eu<sup>2+</sup>-doping concentrations (<italic>x</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0.005&#x02013;0.05) have been prepared to optimize the PL intensity of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:<italic>x</italic>Eu<sup>2+</sup>. As displayed in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">8a</xref>, the emission intensities increase slightly till up to <italic>x</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0.01 and then decrease with further increase in <italic>x</italic>. Based on the Dexter&#x02019;s theory and the Eu-Eu distances in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref></sup>, energy transfer among the nearest neighbor ions accounts for the observed concentration quenching (see details in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">8a</xref>). The internal quantum efficiency of selected K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> is measured to be about 15% (<italic>&#x003bb;</italic><sub>ex</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;460&#x02009;nm). Furthermore, one can find that the normalized emission peaks of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:<italic>x</italic>Eu<sup>2+</sup> show no shift as Eu<sup>2+</sup> doping content increase (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">8b</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Mechanism of NIR emission in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup></title><p id="Par12">First of all, we need to correlate the Eu<sup>2+</sup> site contribution and different emission center by considering local environments of activators. The Eu<sup>2+</sup> emission is dependent on the CFS. In general, when the average bond length (<italic>d</italic><sub>av</sub>) is shorter and the distortion indices (<italic>D</italic>) is larger, then there will be a larger CFS<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref></sup>. The average bond lengths, <italic>d</italic>(Lu-O) and <italic>d</italic>(K2-O) in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> are 2.22&#x02009;&#x000c5; and 2.77&#x02009;&#x000c5;, respectively. The distortion indices are 0 for both LuO<sub>6</sub> and K2O<sub>6</sub> polyhedron. Thus, we believe that the higher energy emission (719&#x02009;nm) peak is associated with Eu<sup>2+</sup> occupying K2 sites, while the lower energy emission (784&#x02009;nm) peak is attributed to Eu<sup>2+</sup> occupying Lu sites. The conclusions of the site occupation for Eu<sup>2+</sup> in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> are consistent with the results in Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor reported by our group<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par13">It is well-known that the free Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions possess a large energy gap (4.2&#x02009;eV) between the 5<italic>d</italic> excited state and the 4&#x02009;<italic>f</italic> ground state<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref></sup>. Once Eu<sup>2+</sup> are introduced into a given compound, the resulting emission wavelengths are affected by centroid shift, crystal splitting, and Stokes shift effects<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref></sup>. For K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor, the centroid shift and Stokes shift have weak effect on the redshift because of the low covalence between Eu<sup>2+</sup> and O<sup>2&#x02212;</sup> ions and the highly symmetric LuO<sub>6</sub> and K2O<sub>6</sub> polyhedrons, respectively<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref></sup>. The CFS depends especially on the coordination numbers, distortion index and size of the polyhedrons<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. The substitution of Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions in LuO<sub>6</sub> and K2O<sub>6</sub> polyhedrons, and thus a design principle of selective occupation of Eu<sup>2+</sup> at small coordination numbers takes effect. It results in large CFS, which in turn leads to a large redshift. A comparison of the local environment of Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> and Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> benefits further understanding of the abnormal NIR emission in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>. Firstly, they are isomorphic, and Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions occupy the same crystallographic lattices in both materials, and the distortion index of YO<sub>6</sub>/LuO<sub>6</sub> and K2O<sub>6</sub> polyhedron are all 0<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>. Thus, the effect of polyhedral distortion on the NIR emission can be neglected. Secondly, the <italic>d</italic><sub>av</sub> values of Lu-O and K2-O in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> are 2.22&#x02009;&#x000c5; and 2.77&#x02009;&#x000c5;, respectively, which are much smaller than that of Y-O and K2-O (2.29&#x02009;&#x000c5; and 2.86&#x02009;&#x000c5;) in Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>, resulting in a larger CFS in 5d energy levels and a larger redshift<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref></sup>. Therefore, the NIR light emission (740&#x02009;nm) in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> is reasonable compared with the red emission (622&#x02009;nm) in Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup>. In summary, the selective occupation of Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions in polyhedrons with small coordination numbers and small average bond length contribute to the NIR emission and the broad excitation band in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup>.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Thermal quenching of PL</title><p id="Par14">Normally, the thermal effect of the NIR phosphor is crucial for the LED application, and thus the thermal quenching behavior of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> was investigated at different temperature from 80 to 500&#x02009;K. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a</xref> demonstrates that the emission intensity decreases slowly with the increase of temperature owing to the enhanced nonradiative transition probabilities. As given in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3b</xref>, the integrated intensity at 150&#x02009;&#x000b0;C retains ~59% of that at room-temperature. According to Dorenbos&#x02019;s model, the activation energy &#x02206;<italic>E</italic> was calculated by using the following empirical formula:<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref></sup><disp-formula id="Equ2"><label>2</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M3">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\Delta E = \frac{{T_{0.5}}}{{680}}eV$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M4"><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">&#x00394;</mml:mi><mml:mi>E</mml:mi><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>T</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>0.5</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>680</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>V</mml:mi></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_13293_Article_Equ2.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula>where <italic>T</italic><sub>0.5</sub> denotes the quenching temperature, and it is defined as the temperature when the emission declines to half of its initial intensity. Here, &#x02206;<italic>E</italic> is calculated to be ~0.65&#x02009;eV.<fig id="Fig3"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>Thermal quenching properties of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor. <bold>a</bold> PL spectra and <bold>b</bold> normalized emission intensities of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> as a function of temperature in 300&#x02013;500&#x02009;K under 460&#x02009;nm excitation. <bold>c</bold> Normalized temperature-dependent PL spectra in 80&#x02013;500&#x02009;K at intervals of 60&#x02009;K. <bold>d</bold> Schematic energy level diagram of Eu<sup>2+</sup> in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>. &#x003b5;<sub>c</sub>(A) denotes the centroid shift of 5<italic>d</italic>-levels of Eu<sup>2+</sup>, &#x003b5;<sub>cfs</sub>(A) shows the CFS effect in connection with coordination number of cations and polyhedrons&#x02019; size, &#x00394;<italic>E</italic><sub>A</sub> represents the photoionization barrier</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_13293_Fig3_HTML" id="d29e2038"/></fig></p><p id="Par15">One can find from Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a</xref> that the emission peaks shift to shorter wavelength (blueshift) at evaluated temperature from 300 to 500&#x02009;K. Furthermore, the temperature-dependent PL spectra under excitation of 460&#x02009;nm of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> were measured from 80 to 500&#x02009;K, and the normalized spectra are presented in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3c</xref>. The emission peaks demonstrate a remarkable blueshift from 790&#x02009;nm (80&#x02009;K) to 710&#x02009;nm (500&#x02009;K) with increasing temperature, and the FWHM of emission bands gradually broadens with the increase of temperature. These observations are associated with the different response of Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions located at the Lu and K2 sites to the temperature. In addition, the emission peaks at high temperature (790&#x02009;nm) and low temperature (710&#x02009;nm) are close to the two Gaussian fitted peaks at room temperature (784&#x02009;nm, 719&#x02009;nm) in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2c</xref>. This further validates the feasibility of the previous analysis about the site occupation of Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions.</p><p id="Par16">Thus, a simple schematic Eu<sup>2+</sup> energy level diagram in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> host is depicted in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d</xref>. Based on the thermal ionization model proposed by Dorenbos, the smaller the gap (photoionization barrier <italic>&#x00394;E</italic><sub>A</sub>) between the bottom of conduction band and the upper edge of 5d energy level, the greater is the thermal quenching<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref></sup>. In K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup>, the larger CFS of Eu<sup>2+</sup> occupied in Lu site produces a smaller <italic>&#x00394;E</italic><sub>A</sub>, and thus a poor thermal stability compared with Eu<sup>2+</sup> in the K2 site (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d</xref>). Similarly, the larger CFS of Eu<sup>2+</sup> in K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> results in a smaller <italic>&#x00394;E</italic><sub>A</sub>, and thus it enables a poor thermal stability compared with that of Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>. Therefore, the blueshift occurred when heated. At low temperature of 80&#x02009;K, the thermal ionization of 5<italic>d</italic> electrons becomes weak, and the dominant emission peak centers at longer wavelength (790&#x02009;nm) associated with the more contribution from Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions occupying Lu sites. In contrast, thermal quenching behavior at high temperatures has a much weaker effect on the Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions in K2 sites than on the Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions in Lu sites, resulting in a relatively stronger emission at short wavelength. Therefore, with temperature increasing, the blueshift and the broadening of emission spectra occur simultaneously.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>NIR pc-LED device and applications</title><p id="Par17">A pc-LED with NIR emission was fabricated by combining K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor and the commercial blue light-emitting InGaN chip (460&#x02009;nm). The emission spectrum of the lighted lamp was monitored by a visible-NIR continuous fiber spectrophotometer. The broad-band PL spectrum and the as-obtained and lighted NIR pc-LED lamps are given in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4a</xref>. The slight spectral deviation from the lamp and the powder is related with the calibration difference of the used spectrometers. Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4b</xref> demonstrates the PL spectra of LED device upon different forward bias currents (20&#x02013;120&#x02009;mA). The NIR emission output power increase with the increase of forward currents and reaches 21.5&#x02009;mW when the forward current is 100&#x02009;mA (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">6</xref>). Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4c</xref> shows the photographs obtained by different cameras under natural light and NIR pc-LED light, respectively. Nothing can be detected by NIR camera once the NIR pc-LED is off. In contrast, the NIR camera can capture black-and-white images while the NIR pc-LED lamp is lighted. These results indicate the application of the K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor in night-vision technologies, and other potential fields including medical and food industries can be also expected for such NIR phosphors.<fig id="Fig4"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><p>NIR application of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu based pc-LEDs. <bold>a</bold> Photographs and PL spectrum of as-fabricated pc-LED combining a commercial blue LED and K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:0.01Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor. <bold>b</bold> PL spectra of the pc-LED upon various forward bias currents. <bold>c</bold> Photographs under natural light and NIR pc-LED light captured by the corresponding visible camera and a NIR camera</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_13293_Fig4_HTML" id="d29e2252"/></fig></p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec8" sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par18">To conclude, we have designed and successfully synthesized the Eu<sup>2+</sup>-activated broad-band-emitting NIR phosphor with super-broad excitation band from 250 to 600&#x02009;nm. Under 460&#x02009;nm blue light excitation, K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> shows an unprecedented broad NIR emission band peaking at 740&#x02009;nm and also demonstrates a high FHWM of 160&#x02009;nm. Eu<sup>2+</sup> selectively occupancy at Lu and K2 sites, and the small coordination numbers and small average bond lengths lead to the as-observed NIR emission with characteristic 4<italic>f</italic>-5<italic>d</italic> transition of Eu<sup>2+</sup>. The as-fabricated NIR pc-LEDs based on K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphors have been applied in night-vision devices and demonstrated potential applications. This finding gives the feasibility of the feasible strategy to discover Eu<sup>2+</sup> doped NIR phosphor with large redshift by occupying polyhedrons with small coordination numbers. More importantly, it initiates a new way to explore NIR phosphors, i.e. achieve NIR emission by Eu<sup>2+</sup> doping in the solid-state materials.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec10"><title>Materials and synthesis of the NIR phosphor</title><p id="Par19">K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:<italic>x</italic>Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphors with different Eu<sup>2+</sup> content (<italic>x</italic>&#x02009;=&#x02009;0&#x02013;0.05) were prepared by employing solid-state reactions. The stoichiometric mixtures of K<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> (A.R.), Lu<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> (99.99%), SiO<sub>2</sub> (A.R.), and Eu<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> (99.99%) were thoroughly grounded and transferred into an alumina crucible. After that, the mixed starting materials were sintered at 1350&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 6&#x02009;h in a forming gas atmosphere (N<sub>2</sub>:H<sub>2</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;80:20), and finally quenched to room temperature. As a typical synthesis, 3.8&#x02009;g raw materials (K<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>, Lu<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, SiO<sub>2</sub>, and Eu<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>) in the given stoichiometric ratio can produce ~2.3&#x02009;g products.</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Characterization</title><p id="Par20">A D8 Advance X-ray diffractometer (XRD, Bruker Corporation, Germany) was used to collect the XRD patterns, and the operation voltage and current were set as 40&#x02009;kV and 40&#x02009;mA, respectively. Structural characterization and Rietveld refinement were conducted using TOPAS 4.2 software<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref></sup>. Diffuse reflectance spectra were collected using a Hitachi UH4150 ultraviolet-visible-near infrared spectrophotometer. Photoluminescence emission and excitation spectra were measured by a FLSP920 fluorescence spectrophotometer, and both visible and NIR PMT detectors were applied. PL spectra of K<sub>3</sub>LuSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> and as-fabricated NIR pc-LED were comparatively measured by a fiber spectrophotometer (NOVA high sensitive spectrometer, idea optics, China), and the 375-nm and 450-nm laser diode acted as the excitation source. The temperature-dependent spectra were evaluated by a FLS920 spectrophotometer equipped with a MercuryiTc temperature control instrument (OXFORD). Liquid nitrogen was used to cool temperature. The decay time was measured by a FLS920 instrument equipped with 450&#x02009;nm and 340&#x02009;nm pulse laser diode. The statistical photons are 5000 and 10,000, respectively, for the measurements at low temperature (80&#x02009;K) and room temperature (300&#x02009;K), and the decay curvers were fitted by the FAST software attached with FLS920 spectrophotometer. All the photophysics properties measurements were repeated at least three times to confirm the data. The quantum efficiency was measured using a Hamamatsu absolute photoluminescence quantum yield spectrometer C11347 Quantaurus-QY. The photoelectric properties and emission spectra of the fabricated pc-LEDs were measured by a Morpho 3.2 software equipped with a NOVA Laboratory Class Spectrometer. Photographs for the application of NIR pc-LEDs are taken by a NIR and a visible camera.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary information</title><sec id="Sec12"><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1"><media xlink:href="41467_2019_13293_MOESM1_ESM.pdf"><caption><p>Supplementary Information</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM2"><media xlink:href="41467_2019_13293_MOESM2_ESM.pdf"><caption><p>Peer Review File</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Peer review information</bold>
<italic>Nature Communications</italic> thanks Eszter Borbas and the other, anonymous, reviewer(s) for their contribution to the peer review of this work. Peer reviewer reports are available.</p></fn><fn><p><bold>Publisher&#x02019;s note</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Supplementary information</title><p><bold>Supplementary information</bold> is available for this paper at 10.1038/s41467-019-13293-0.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>This work is supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Nos.: 51722202 and 51972118), Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities (D2190980), and the Guangdong Provincial Science &#x00026; Technology Project (2018A050506004).</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>Z.X. initiated and guided the research. J.Q. synthesized the samples and wrote the manuscript, and Z.X. and Q.Z. revised it. G.Z. and Y.Z. discussed the luminescence properties and made the NIR pc-LED device. All authors discussed the results and commented on the manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The data that support the plots within this paper and other findings of this study are available from the corresponding author upon reasonable request.</p></notes><notes notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par21">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ly</surname><given-names>KT</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Near-infrared organic light-emitting diodes with very high external quantum efficiency and radiance</article-title><source>Nat. Photon.</source><year>2016</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>63</fpage><lpage>68</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Eggebrecht</surname><given-names>AT</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Mapping distributed brain function and networks with diffuse optical tomography</article-title><source>Nat. Photon.</source><year>2014</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>448</fpage><lpage>454</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nphoton.2014.107</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hybrid graphene metasurfaces for high-speed mid-infrared light modulation and single-pixel imaging</article-title><source>Light Sci. Appl.</source><year>2018</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>51</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41377-018-0055-4</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 30839521?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30839521</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Osborne</surname><given-names>BG</given-names></name></person-group><source>Encyclopedia of Analytical Chemistry: Applications, Theory and Instrumentation.</source><year>2006</year><publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc><publisher-name>John Wiley &#x00026; Sons, Ltd.</publisher-name></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tessler</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Medvedev</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name><surname>Kazes</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Kan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Banin</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Efficient near-infrared polymer nanocrystal light-emitting diodes</article-title><source>Science</source><year>2002</year><volume>295</volume><fpage>1506</fpage><lpage>1508</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.1068153</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 11859189?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11859189</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>ZK</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Bright light-emitting diodes based on organometal halide perovskite</article-title><source>Nat. Nanotechnol.</source><year>2014</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>687</fpage><lpage>692</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nnano.2014.149</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25086602?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25086602</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gong</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Highly efficient quantum dot near-infrared light-emitting diodes</article-title><source>Nat. Photon.</source><year>2016</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>253</fpage><lpage>257</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nphoton.2016.11</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lukovic</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>LED-based Vis-NIR spectrally tunable light source - the optimization algorithm</article-title><source>J. Eur. Opt. Soc. -Rapid Publ.</source><year>2016</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>19</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s41476-016-0021-9</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Next-generation narrow-band green-emitting RbLi(Li<sub>3</sub>SiO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor for backlight display application</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2018</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>e1802489</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adma.201802489</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 30091153?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30091153</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Progress in discovery and structural design of color conversion phosphors for LEDs</article-title><source>Prog. Mater. Sci.</source><year>2016</year><volume>84</volume><fpage>59</fpage><lpage>117</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.pmatsci.2016.09.007</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Mining unexplored chemistries for phosphors for high-color-quality white-light-emitting diodes</article-title><source>Joule</source><year>2018</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>914</fpage><lpage>926</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2018.01.015</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qiao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Eu<sup>2+</sup> site preferences in the mixed cation K<sub>2</sub>BaCa(PO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub> and thermally stable luminescence</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2018</year><volume>140</volume><fpage>9730</fpage><lpage>9736</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jacs.8b06021</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 29985612?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29985612</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Li<sub>2</sub>SrSiO<sub>4</sub>:Ce<sup>3+</sup>, Pr<sup>3+</sup> phosphor with blue, red, and near-infrared emissions used for plant growth LED</article-title><source>J. Am. Ceram. Soc.</source><year>2016</year><volume>99</volume><fpage>218</fpage><lpage>225</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jace.13952</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Damasco</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Size-tunable and monodisperse Tm<sup>3+</sup>/Gd<sup>3+</sup>-doped hexagonal NaYbF<sub>4</sub> nanoparticles with engineered efficient near infrared-to-near infrared upconversion for in vivo imaging</article-title><source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source><year>2014</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>13884</fpage><lpage>13893</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/am503288d</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25027118?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25027118</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Benayas</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Nd:YAG near-infrared luminescent nanothermometers</article-title><source>Adv. Opt. Mater.</source><year>2015</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>687</fpage><lpage>694</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adom.201400484</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nyk</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Ohulchanskyy</surname><given-names>TY</given-names></name><name><surname>Bergey</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Prasad</surname><given-names>PN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>High contrast in vitro and in vivo photoluminescence bioimaging using near infrared to near infrared up-conversion in Tm<sup>3+</sup> and Yb<sup>3+</sup> doped fluoride nanophosphors</article-title><source>Nano Lett.</source><year>2008</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>3834</fpage><lpage>3838</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/nl802223f</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 18928324?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18928324</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Divalent nickel-activated gallate-based persistent phosphors in the short-wave infrared</article-title><source>Adv. Opt. Mater.</source><year>2016</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>562</fpage><lpage>566</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adom.201500656</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>De Clercq</surname><given-names>OQ</given-names></name><name><surname>Korthout</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Poelman</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>LaAlO<sub>3</sub>:Mn<sup>4+</sup> as near-infrared emitting persistent luminescence phosphor for medical imaging: a charge compensation study</article-title><source>Materials</source><year>2017</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>1422</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/ma10121422</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cr<sup>3+</sup>&#x02010;doped broadband NIR garnet phosphor with enhanced luminescence and its application in NIR spectroscopy</article-title><source>Adv. Opt. Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>1900185</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adom.201900185</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Transparent Ni<sup>2+</sup>-doped lithium aluminosilicate glass&#x02013;ceramics with broadband infrared luminescence</article-title><source>J. Alloy. Compd</source><year>2008</year><volume>457</volume><fpage>506</fpage><lpage>509</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2007.03.034</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rajendran</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Super broadband near-infrared phosphors with high radiant flux as future light sources for spectroscopy applications</article-title><source>ACS Energy Lett.</source><year>2018</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>2679</fpage><lpage>2684</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.8b01643</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A high efficiency broad-band near-infrared Ca<sub>2</sub>LuZr<sub>2</sub>Al<sub>3</sub>O<sub>12</sub>:Cr<sup>3+</sup> garnet phosphor for blue LED chips</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem. C</source><year>2018</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>4967</fpage><lpage>4976</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C8TC01216D</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zabiliute</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Butkute</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Zukauskas</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Vitta</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Kareiva</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Sol-gel synthesized far-red chromium-doped garnet phosphors for phosphor-conversion light-emitting diodes that meet the photomorphogenetic needs of plants</article-title><source>Appl. Opt.</source><year>2014</year><volume>53</volume><fpage>907</fpage><lpage>914</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1364/AO.53.000907</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 24663271?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24663271</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Reibstein</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Spiecker</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Wondraczek</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Broadband NIR photoluminescence from Ni<sup>2+</sup>-doped nanocrystalline Ba&#x02013;Al titanate glass ceramics</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem.</source><year>2012</year><volume>22</volume><fpage>2582</fpage><lpage>2588</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C1JM14292E</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>KB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Structural and optical properties of BaMgAl<sub>10</sub>O<sub>17</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><year>2002</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>5045</fpage><lpage>5052</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cm020592f</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hirosaki</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Characterization and properties of green-emitting <italic>&#x003b2;</italic>-SiAlON:Eu<sup>2+</sup> powder phosphors for white light-emitting diodes</article-title><source>Appl. Phys. Lett.</source><year>2005</year><volume>86</volume><fpage>211905</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.1935027</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pust</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Narrow-band red-emitting Sr[LiAl<sub>3</sub>N<sub>4</sub>]:Eu<sup>2+</sup> as a next-generation LED-phosphor material</article-title><source>Nat. Mater.</source><year>2014</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>891</fpage><lpage>896</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nmat4012</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 24952748?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24952748</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Berezovskaya</surname><given-names>IV</given-names></name><name><surname>Dotsenko</surname><given-names>VP</given-names></name><name><surname>Voloshinovskii</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name><surname>Smola</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Near infrared emission of Eu<sup>2+</sup> ions in Ca<sub>3</sub>Sc<sub>2</sub>Si<sub>3</sub>O<sub>12</sub></article-title><source>Chem. Phys. Lett.</source><year>2013</year><volume>585</volume><fpage>11</fpage><lpage>14</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.cplett.2013.08.100</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Suehiro</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Takeda</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirosaki</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Down-conversion nitride materials for solid state lighting: recent advances and perspectives</article-title><source>Chem. Rev.</source><year>2018</year><volume>118</volume><fpage>1951</fpage><lpage>2009</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.7b00284</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 29392943?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29392943</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Chemical unit cosubstitution and tuning of photoluminescence in the Ca<sub>2</sub>(Al<sub>1&#x02212;x</sub>Mg<sub>x</sub>)(Al<sub>1&#x02212;x</sub>Si<sub>1+x</sub>)O<sub>7</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2015</year><volume>137</volume><fpage>12494</fpage><lpage>12497</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jacs.5b08315</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 26389578?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26389578</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qiao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Site-selective occupancy of Eu<sup>2+</sup> toward blue-light-excited red emission in a Rb<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>:Eu phosphor</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2019</year><volume>58</volume><fpage>11521</fpage><lpage>11526</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201905787</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shannon</surname><given-names>RD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Revised effective ionic radii and systematic studies of interatomic distances in halides and chalcogenides</article-title><source>Acta Cryst. Sect. A</source><year>1976</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>751</fpage><lpage>767</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/S0567739476001551</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Vidican</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>MD</given-names></name><name><surname>zur Loye</surname><given-names>HC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Crystal growth, structure determination, and optical properties of new potassium-rare-earth silicates K<sub>3</sub>RESi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> (RE = Gd, Tb, Dy, Ho, Er, Tm, Yb, Lu)</article-title><source>J. Solid State Chem.</source><year>2003</year><volume>170</volume><fpage>203</fpage><lpage>210</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0022-4596(02)00029-4</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dexter</surname><given-names>DL</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A theory of sensitized luminescence in solids</article-title><source>J. Chem. Phys.</source><year>1953</year><volume>21</volume><fpage>836</fpage><lpage>850</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.1699044</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Denault</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Consequences of optimal bond valence on structural rigidity and improved luminescence properties in Sr<sub>x</sub>Ba<sub>2&#x02013;x</sub>SiO<sub>4</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> orthosilicate phosphors</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><year>2014</year><volume>26</volume><fpage>2275</fpage><lpage>2282</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cm500116u</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dorenbos</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Relation between Eu<sup>2+</sup> and Ce<sup>3+</sup> f&#x02194;d-transition energies in inorganic compounds</article-title><source>J. Phys. Condens. Matter</source><year>2003</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>4797</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/0953-8984/15/27/311</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dorenbos</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>5d-level energies of Ce<sup>3+</sup> and the crystalline environment. IV. Aluminates and &#x0201c;simple&#x0201d; oxides</article-title><source>J. Lumin.</source><year>2002</year><volume>99</volume><fpage>283</fpage><lpage>299</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0022-2313(02)00347-2</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>DiSalvo</surname><given-names>FJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Clarke</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Ternary nitrides: a rapidly growing class of new materials</article-title><source>Curr. Opin. Solid State Mater. Sci.</source><year>1996</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>241</fpage><lpage>249</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S1359-0286(96)80091-X</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>CH</given-names></name><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>HD</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>MW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Luminescence characteristics of green light emitting Ba<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>4</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> phosphor</article-title><source>J. Mater. Sci. Lett.</source><year>2003</year><volume>22</volume><fpage>1351</fpage><lpage>1353</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1023/A:1025739412154</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dorenbos</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Thermal quenching of Eu<sup>2+</sup> 5d&#x02013;4f luminescence in inorganic compounds</article-title><source>J. Phys. Condens. Matter</source><year>2005</year><volume>17</volume><fpage>8103</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/0953-8984/17/50/027</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qiao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Engineering of K<sub>3</sub>YSi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> to tune photoluminescence with selected activators and site occupancy</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>7770</fpage><lpage>7778</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.9b02990</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Topas</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name></person-group><source>1: General profile and structure analysis software for powder diffraction data.</source><year>2008</year><publisher-loc>Germany</publisher-loc><publisher-name>Bruker AXS, Karlsruhe</publisher-name></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>