<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is well known that the PCE of perovskite solar cells depends heavily on the quality and morphology of thin films. Snaith's group introduced BA into 3D double‐cation perovskite FA
 <sub>0.83</sub>Cs
 <sub>0.7</sub>Pb(I
 <sub>0.6</sub>Br
 <sub>0.4</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub>. They obtained fully crystallized 2D/3D BA
 <italic>
  <sub>x</sub>
 </italic>(FA
 <sub>0.83</sub>Cs
 <sub>0.7</sub>)
 <sub>1−</sub>
 <italic>
  <sub>x</sub>
 </italic>Pb(I
 <sub>0.6</sub>Br
 <sub>0.4</sub>)
 <sub>3</sub> perovskite films by annealing as‐cast precursor films in air for 80 min at 175 °C. The presence of BA not only accelerated and evolved the high crystallinity of thin films, but also induced the change of lattice parameters of the 3D perovskite phase. The heterostructures between 2D and 3D perovskite phases passivated the interfacial grain boundary, thus inhibiting nonradiative recombination and achieving enhancement of performance and stability of perovskite solar cells.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0061" ref-type="ref">61</xref> Very recently, Zhu's group fabricated a 2D perovskite (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(Cs
 <sub>0.02</sub>MA
 <sub>0.64</sub>FA
 <sub>0.34</sub>)
 <sub>4</sub>PbI
 <sub>6</sub> film with Cs
 <sup>+</sup>–MA
 <sup>+</sup>–FA
 <sup>+</sup> triple cations by a simple spin coating at room temperature. Compared with 2D perovskite film with a monocation, the 2D triple‐cation perovskite has smoother, denser surface morphology, larger apparent grain size, and smaller grain boundary, leading to a longer carrier life and a higher conductivity.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0062" ref-type="ref">62</xref> Recently, Gao's group reported a simple method for high quality of RPP films by incorporating dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) and MACl in the precursor solution, followed by one‐step spin coating and solvent annealing process. During crystallization, the synergistic effect of DMSO and MACl led to uniform morphology, good crystallinity, and reduced energy disorder.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0063" ref-type="ref">63</xref>
</p>
