<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Beyond Li-ion batteries have been widely investigated last decade (Larcher and Tarascon, 
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). Alternative anode active material using electrochemical deposition-dissolution process of less-noble metal is one strategy for the development of high-energy battery system (Lin et al., 
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>). Among various choices of the less-noble metal anodes, magnesium is one of the potential candidates as the high-energy anode active material, because the volumetric capacity: 3,800 mAh cm
 <sup>−3</sup> is 1.9 times higher than that of lithium metal, and no dendritic growth during the deposition process (Matsui, 
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>). On the other hand, the surface of the magnesium metal is easily passivated in conventional electrolyte solutions such as magnesium perchlorate dissolved in propylene carbonate (Lu et al., 
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">1999</xref>). Therefore, the choice of the electrolyte solutions for rechargeable magnesium batteries is very limited. Typically the organohaloaluminate electrolyte solutions, which are widely studied by Aurbach et al. in early 2000s (e.g., Aurbach et al., 
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">2000</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">2003</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">2007</xref>), show highly reversible deposition/dissolution of magnesium metal, however since these electrolyte solutions contain halides: Cl
 <sup>−</sup> or Br
 <sup>−</sup>, the potential window of the organohaloaluminate electrolyte solutions is limited. In addition the corrosive properties of the halides initiate the dissolution of the cathode current collector at high cell voltage &gt;2.5 V (Muldoon et al., 
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">2012</xref>). Therefore, finding halide-free electrolyte solutions has been standing in the center of the electrolyte development for high-voltage magnesium batteries. Recently, Tutusaus et al. reported a new class of the magnesium salt having boron cluster anion monocarborane CB
 <sub>11</sub>
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M1">
   <msub>
    <mrow>
     <mtext>H</mtext>
    </mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mn>1</mn>
     <msup>
      <mrow>
       <mn>2</mn>
      </mrow>
      <mrow>
       <mo>-</mo>
      </mrow>
     </msup>
    </mrow>
   </msub>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> dissolved in glymes showed reversible deposition/dissolution of magnesium without corrosive properties (Tutusaus et al., 
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>). A fluorinated alkokyborate-based electrolyte: magnesium hexafluoroisopropylaluminate (Mg[B(hfip)
 <sub>4</sub>]
 <sub>2</sub>) also shows excellent reversibility without the corrosive properties (Zhao-Karger et al., 
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>). Even with the excellent electrochemical properties of these new class of the electrolytes, the oxidation stabilities of these solutions are still limited up to 3.5 V vs. Mg due to the ether-based solvents.
</p>
