<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Even with the several reports concerning the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> as the anode active material for Mg-ion batteries, there still remains room to understand why the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> shows the compatibility with various electrolytes solutions. Also the fast reaction kinetics of the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> among various Mg-based intermetallic anodes, are still under investigation. In the present study, we attempted to understand the origin of the wide compatibility and the fast kinetics of the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> as the alternate anode active material for magnesium batteries. We investigated the electrochemical properties of the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> composite electrodes, synthesized by a conventional solid-state process. In order to conduct comparative studies, another intermetallic anode: Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Sb
 <sub>2</sub> was also investigated, because of its structural and chemical similarities to the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>. The Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Sb
 <sub>2</sub> has same crystal structure to the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>, in both magnesiated and demagnesiated phases. In addition the binary phase diagram of Mg-Sb system shows that the expected electrochemical reaction is a two-phase reaction of Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Sb
 <sub>2</sub> and Sb, which is exact same as the two phase reaction in the Mg-Bi system. We also fabricated Mg metal and Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> thin film electrodes using rf-sputtering coater to investigate the correlation between the surface layer and the overpotential of the magnesium metal and the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub>. The surface layer on the magnesium metal and the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> thin films were characterized using X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). In order to evaluate the stability of the surface layer on the intermetallic anodes, the hydrolysis process of the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> and the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Sb
 <sub>2</sub> were investigated. The Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> diffusion pathways in the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Bi
 <sub>2</sub> and the Mg
 <sub>3</sub>Sb
 <sub>2</sub> were estimated by bond-valence sum (BVS) mapping (Adams, 
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>) to discuss the reaction kinetics of these two intermetallic anodes.
</p>
