<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">Low values of charge carrier mobilities in organic thin films is a fundamental issue affecting their applications to integrated circuits, displays and memory devices requiring fast processing
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup>. Unlike single crystals where band-like transport is observed
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>, intrinsic thermal and structural disorder in organic thin films lead to localization of charge carriers in the tail of a Gaussian density of states (GDOS)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup> which results due to randomness in positional and energetic disorder in polycrystalline and amorphous thin films. Carriers then need some activation energy to hop between neighboring sites leading to (i) low carrier mobility and (ii) positive temperature coefficient of mobility. The real challenge with polycrystalline organic thin films lies in achieving delocalized band-like conduction resulting in high mobility comparable with that in pure organic single crystals. Although, delocalized charge transport with high mobilities has been observed in pure single crystal
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup> however, organic single crystals cannot be used in large area rolable and foldable electronic devices. Poor device integration and cross-talk between devices are also the drawbacks of single crystals. Considerable efforts have been put
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup> towards improving the performance of organic thin films based devices by engineering the growth parameters, substrate/organic interface and device parameters but, high mobilities comparable with that in single crystals could not be achieved. Observation of negative temperature coefficient in polycrystalline thin films have previously been observed and interpreted in terms of large thermal fluctuations in electronic coupling rather than band transport
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. Hence, an understanding of the crossover from localized to delocalized band-like transport in polycrystalline organic thin film is essential. We show that temperature coefficient of mobility can be changed from positive to negative corresponding to a transition from hoping to band-like transport as the Fermi level is modulated by injecting sufficient numbers of carriers. The observed values of carrier mobilities in the band transport regime are two orders of magnitude higher than those in the hoping regime. Our experimental results are supported by theoretical calculations for hoping mobility estimates using Marcus theory
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup> and density functional theory (DFT) band mobility.
</p>
