<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">The structural orders can be a key to understanding the pathways and phase selections. Taking into account the large size and affinity disparity between Al and Sm atoms, the structural features in the Al-Sm system is most easily visualised by focusing on the the solute Sm-centered short-range order (SRO). The Al-Sm system has already exhibited a rich collection of Sm-centered ordering in known crystalline compounds, including Al
 <sub>2</sub>Sm, Al
 <sub>3</sub>Sm, Al
 <sub>4</sub>Sm and Al
 <sub>11</sub>Sm
 <sub>3</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>. A discussion of Sm-centered SRO in these stable compounds can be found in ref.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>. Nevertheless, the target Al-rich system (glassy structures are attainable from 7 to 13 at.% Sm) has a different composition from the above compounds, and a new Sm-cenered ordering was found in the Al-10 at.% system
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>. This Sm-centered SRO transcends liquid, glass and crystalline states. The SRO that develops in an undercooled liquid and glass plays an important role in phase selection during devitrification processes. The amorphous Al-Sm alloys realized in melt-spun ribbon and magnetron sputtered thin films devitrify following completely different pathways. Constant-heating-rate (CHR) devitrification of Al-10.2 at% Sm ribbon exhibits a polymorphic transformation that results in a cubic 
 <italic>ε</italic>-Al
 <sub>60</sub>Sm
 <sub>11</sub> phase
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup> with a lattice parameter of ~14 Å, space group 
 <inline-formula id="IEq1">
  <alternatives>
   <tex-math id="M1">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal} \usepackage{amsmath} \usepackage{wasysym} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{upgreek} \setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt} \begin{document}$$Im\bar{3}m$$\end{document}</tex-math>
   <math id="M2">
    <mi>I</mi>
    <mi>m</mi>
    <mover accent="true">
     <mn>3</mn>
     <mo>¯</mo>
    </mover>
    <mi>m</mi>
   </math>
   <inline-graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_43079_Article_IEq1.gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  </alternatives>
 </inline-formula> (No. 229) and with 6 unique Wyckoff positions. The thin film of the same chemical composition develops compositional inhomogeneities before the formation of fcc-Al and a hexagonal 
 <italic>θ</italic>-Al
 <sub>5</sub>Sm phase (i.e. Al
 <sub>20</sub>Sm
 <sub>4</sub> in ref.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>) with space group 
 <italic>P</italic>6
 <sub>3</sub>22. (No. 182) and with 5 Wyckoff positions. Selection is also composition dependent, and the 
 <italic>θ</italic>-phase is observed as the initial crystallized phase with fcc-Al during CHR devitrification of an Al-14.1% Sm melt-spun ribbon. The 
 <italic>ε</italic>-Al
 <sub>60</sub>Sm
 <sub>11</sub> and 
 <italic>θ</italic>-Al
 <sub>5</sub>Sm phases share the same Sm-centered first-shell atomic packing “3-6-6-1” motif 
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup> (referred to as “T6” in ref.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>). The same 3-6-6-1 motif is found dominant in undercooled liquids, indicating a clear structural inheritance from the liquid to its devitrified crystalline phases.
</p>
