<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Since the metabolome of 
 <italic>A. veronii</italic> has not been previously studied, we decided to separate and characterize by NMR and MS those metabolites that were present in its extract in sufficient quantities. In the current research we isolated from the culture medium of 
 <italic>A. veronii</italic> strain A134, which inhibited the growth of 
 <italic>M. aeuroginosa</italic> strain MGK, three new metabolites, 9-chlorolumichrome (
 <bold>1</bold>), veronimide (
 <bold>2</bold>) and veronipyrazine (
 <bold>3</bold>), along with the known lumichrome, indole-3-glyoxylamide, cyclo-tyrosylprolyl [
 <xref rid="B11-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>], cyclo-valylprolyl [
 <xref rid="B12-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>], cyclo-isoleucylprolyl [
 <xref rid="B13-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>], cyclo-phenylalanylprolyl [
 <xref rid="B12-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>] and cyclo-tryptophylprolyl [
 <xref rid="B12-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. Due to the minute quantities of 
 <bold>1</bold>–
 <bold>3</bold>, they were tested only for the growth inhibition of 
 <italic>M. aeuroginosa</italic> strain MGK by cell counting, but they were found to be inactive. The only active metabolite we isolated from the culture medium was lumichrome [
 <xref rid="B5-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. The abovementioned metabolites, 
 <bold>1</bold>–
 <bold>3</bold>, are most probably derived from the enzymatic transformation of primary metabolites rather than products of secondary metabolism by special biosynthetic genes. Lumichrome and 9-chlorolumichrome (
 <bold>1</bold>) are possibly derived from the hydrolysis of the sugar unit of riboflavin, which is followed by chlorination, probably by a flavin-dependent holgenase [
 <xref rid="B14-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>] (
 <xref ref-type="scheme" rid="metabolites-09-00110-sch001">Scheme 1</xref>). Veronimide (
 <bold>2</bold>) seems to be an oxidation product of cyclo-isolecinylprolyl, probably resulting from the action of cytochrome-P450 or a similar oxidizing enzyme, which produces the peroxy-derivative 
 <bold>2a</bold>. Intermediate 
 <bold>2a</bold> is most probably converted to the corresponding alcohol 
 <bold>2b</bold>, which in turn is rearranged to veronimide (
 <bold>2</bold>) (
 <xref ref-type="scheme" rid="metabolites-09-00110-sch001">Scheme 1</xref>). Veronipyrazine (
 <bold>3</bold>) is most probably derived from the reduction of one of the amide carboxamides and the subsequent double dehydration of cyclo-alanyl(4-hydroxy)phenylglycyl (
 <xref ref-type="scheme" rid="metabolites-09-00110-sch001">Scheme 1</xref>). These findings for 
 <italic>A. veronii</italic> strain A134, and those published for 
 <italic>A. salmonicida</italic> subsp. 
 <italic>achromogenes</italic> strain NY4 [
 <xref rid="B4-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>], suggest that 
 <italic>Aeromonas</italic> spp. are capable of transforming primary metabolites to secondary-like metabolites but have very low capacity to produce secondary metabolites. How and whether these abilities are associated with their pathogenesis deserves further investigation.
</p>
