<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par33">For X-ray total scattering, the energy-integration range is always significantly broader than a span of phonon energies and therefore these data reflect instantaneous atomic positions. For EXAFS, a characteristic X-rays-sample interaction time is ≈10
 <sup>−15</sup> s thus also probing an instantaneous PDF. In the case of neutron total scattering, the actual energy-integration range is limited by the so-called Placzek shift and reportedly can be less than 10 meV
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup>. However, for a given material, the exact value of this limit will vary between different instruments and is somewhat uncertain
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>
 </sup>. According to previous studies of PMN using a dynamic PDF
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup>, at 
 <italic>T</italic> ≥ 450 K, the off-centering of Pb, which is manifested in the splitting of the nearest-neighbor Pb–O peak with the appearance of short Pb–O distances at ≈2.4 Å, is purely dynamic. Our variable-temperature X-ray PDF (X-PDF) data (Supplementary Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">17a</xref>) demonstrate that this splitting and the short Pb–O distances are observable at least up to 490 K, as expected since X-ray total scattering reveals both static and dynamic correlations. Our neutron PDF (N-PDF) at 490 K (Supplementary Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">17b</xref>) also features a clearly identifiable splitting of the Pb–O distribution with a peak at ≈2.4 Å, as confirmed by the presence of anomalies in the second derivative of the PDF signal (Supplementary Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">17c</xref>). Considering that the onset energy for a phonon that involves the off-centering of Pb is ≈15 meV
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>
 </sup>, we conclude that the integration range for our neutron total-scattering measurements extends at least past this energy, and thus the low-energy atomic vibrations are captured in the data.
</p>
