<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Semiconductor nanomaterials, such as 0D quantum dots (QDs), 1D quantum rods (QRs), and 2D nanoplatelets offer high photoluminescence (PL) quantum yields (QY), saturated emission colors due to the reasonably narrow PL linewidth, and precisely tunable emission wavelengths based on both control of the composition and on the quantum confinement effect.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0001" ref-type="ref">1</xref> These materials are thus considered nowadays as components for wide‐color‐gamut displays and light‐emitting devices (LEDs).
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0002" ref-type="ref">2</xref> There are two basic types of QD (or QR) LEDs: photoluminescent LEDs, relying on phosphors as color down‐converters such as a blue LED backlight unit (BLU) for liquid crystal displays (LCDs), and electroluminescent LEDs, where the active materials emit light as the recombination layer for injected charge carriers in a diode structure device.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0003" ref-type="ref">3</xref> While there are still multiple issues which have to be resolved for the electroluminescent devices, such as balanced and efficient carrier injection and long‐term stability, photoluminescent LEDs have already been commercialized for the LCD backlight applications.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0004" ref-type="ref">4</xref> Back in 2013, Sony released the first QD‐enabled display (Triluminous TV), in which the Color IQ optical subsystem, developed by the company QD Vision, was used to enhance the available color gamut of the LCD panels.[qv: 2b] QD Vision Inc. claimed that QD‐based LCDs are 25% more efficient in comparison to organic LEDs (OLEDs), and that LCDs equipped with QD enhanced backlights show a higher luminance.[qv: 4a,5] Later Samsung, TCL, and LG brought several flagship QD LCD TVs to their premium display markets.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0006" ref-type="ref">6</xref> It has been estimated that the display market may grow to over USD $200 billion in the coming years, while the market for the required nanomaterials, primarily QDs, was estimated to grow to over USD $10 billion by 2020.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0007" ref-type="ref">7</xref> Touch Display Research Inc. predicted that by 2025 more than 60% of TVs and over 50% of monitors may adopt semiconductor QDs and related materials.[qv: 4a] Additionally, they estimated that the total market for QDs was worth more than USD $7.0 billion in 2017 and is expected to grow up to USD $10 billion by 2020.[qv: 4a] This is comparable to the OLED market size.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0006" ref-type="ref">6</xref>, 
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0008" ref-type="ref">8</xref> The use of QDs in displays is thus maturing, and there are many opportunities for new concepts and innovative device designs, while the search for better light‐emitting materials is on‐going. Initial commercial products (such as the Sony TV) used CdSe‐based QDs, as the most well studied kind of QDs, and also because these QDs exhibit solid performance in terms of color quality and high PL QY. However, environmental concerns and governmental regulatory restrictions limiting the use of the toxic element cadmium, have hindered sales of those products in some markets. InP‐based QDs have been explored in the Samsung QD TVs, due to the reduced toxicity and thus the unrestricted use of this material in consumer products in most markets. However, indium is a rare element which is already heavily used in other applications, and the color saturation of InP QDs does not match that of CdSe QDs, due to their wider emission linewidth. Lead halide perovskite nanocrystals
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0009" ref-type="ref">9</xref> have recently emerged as another promising light‐emitting material for displays, due to their ease of synthesis and exceptionally narrow emission linewidths. Unfortunately, the large degree of ionic character in these materials limits their stability, this in addition to the presence of toxic Pb, may become a limiting factor for commercialization. For the older class of II‐VI materials, both 1D QRs and 2D nanoplatelets offer an added advantage for LCDs, because they can emit linearly polarized light.
 <xref rid="advs1374-bib-0010" ref-type="ref">10</xref> At the same time, those anisotropic non‐spherical nanocrystals require a proper processing, as they need to be assembled with a high degree of orientational order so as to gain the benefit of the linear polarized emission as an ensemble.
</p>
