<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We generally believe that the non-ohmic current of a solid dielectric in a high electric field mainly appears as a space charge limited current (SCLC), which is mainly due to the rapid proliferation of carrier concentration with the enhancement of the electric field. Both the electrode effect and the bulk effect cause nonlinear propagation of carriers in the medium, causing the carrier concentration in the medium to become a function of the electric field strength. Therefore, the high electric field non-ohmic current characteristics may have two phenomena of electrode characteristic control and body characteristic control [
 <xref rid="B21-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
 <xref rid="B29-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. Since the solid dielectric is low in bulk conductivity, it is generally believed that the transport process of carriers in the ohmic conductance region of the weak electric field is dominated by the hopping conductance of the impurity ions [
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B24-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>], and the current belongs to the bulk limiting process. However, when the conditions (temperature, electric field) change, the high-field non-ohmic conductance will change from the body effect limit to the electrode effect limit, and the high electric field download stream transport process belongs to the amorphous state [
 <xref rid="B30-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>,
 <xref rid="B31-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]. In theory, the slope of the space charge limited current zone should be 2 in the double logarithmic coordinates. From the measurement results of the non-ohmic region of the T2 region of 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-02657-f007">Figure 7</xref>, it can be seen that the slope of the high field strength curve of the four different density polyethylene materials ranges from 2 to 4 regardless of the voltage form, and the slope gradually decreases with the increase of crystallinity. The slope of the high field strength conductance curve for polyethylene and its nanocomposites is reported to vary from 2 to 5 [
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B31-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,
 <xref rid="B32-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. Montanari studied the conductance mechanism of different kinds of polyethylene. It is believed that the slope of the curve in the logarithmic coordinates of the high field strength region is greater than 2, and there is a space charge limiting current effect [
 <xref rid="B29-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. Moreover, the slope of the high field strength region cannot be applied to judge the quality of the material, which can only be utilized for the difference in the conductivity mechanism of the material [
 <xref rid="B22-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. In the T3 region, the electric field strength is further increased to a maximum of 200 kV/mm. According to 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-02657-f005">Figure 5</xref>, we can see that the slope value of the T3 region is supposed to be 2 according to the theory. However, according to 
 <xref rid="materials-12-02657-t003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>, we can see that the results obtained in the experiment are as follows: only the slope of LDPE in the T3 region is about 2.132, which is very close to 2, while the slopes of LLDPE, MDPE and HDPE in the T3 segment are close to 1. This phenomenon may be due to the deeper traps in the dielectric material when the field strength is particularly high and excited. Thus, when the field strength reaches the electric field corresponding to the second inflection point in the conductance characteristic curve, the carrier may be trapped by the deeper trap, which leads to the phenomenon that the slope of the conductance characteristic curve of the T3 region is much smaller than that of the T2 region.
</p>
