<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0760">The formal mathematical techniques are discussed in this section. It is well-known that the standard theory of many-phonon transitions [
 <xref rid="bib72" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>] extensively uses the following techniques [
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib79" ref-type="bibr">79</xref>]: the generating polynomial (generating function) technique of Krivoglaz and Pekar [
 <xref rid="bib76" ref-type="bibr">76</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib77" ref-type="bibr">77</xref>], which is similar to the Darwin-Fowler method [
 <xref rid="bib72" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib78" ref-type="bibr">78</xref>] from statistical physics (see Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.4.3" ref-type="sec">2.4.3</xref>, 
 <xref rid="fn9" ref-type="fn">footnote 9</xref>), the operation calculus of Feynman and Lax [
 <xref rid="bib94" ref-type="bibr">94</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib124" ref-type="bibr">124</xref>], the density matrix technique of Kubo and Toyozawa [
 <xref rid="bib125" ref-type="bibr">125</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib126" ref-type="bibr">126</xref>], and the quantum field theory technique (see Ref. [
 <xref rid="bib72" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>]). Among all methods, the simplest and physically transparent method is the technique of generating functions of Krivoglaz and Pekar. The simplicity and transparency of this technique is due to the fact that it is formulated in terms of the wave function. However, this technique takes into account only the main effect of the electron-phonon interaction — shifts of normal phonon coordinates. The change in the phonon frequencies during electronic transitions and other less significant effects can be taken into account on the basis of the remaining aforementioned techniques. Since the processes of elementary electron-charge transfers in condensed matter and other electron-phonon transitions, in which the dynamics of the transient state must be taken into account, are much more complicated than the standard case of electron-phonon transitions, it is obvious that a generalization of the standard theory of many-phonon transitions should be started, using the simplest technique of Krivoglaz and Pekar. In my technique [
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib75" ref-type="bibr">75</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib79" ref-type="bibr">79</xref>] that generalizing the technique of Krivoglaz and Pekar, as previously shown (Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.4.6" ref-type="sec">2.4.6</xref>), all of the intermediate electron-phonon states arising during elementary electron-charge transfers are precisely taken into account. The use of a more sophisticated formal technique, for example, the technique of Feynman path integrals [
 <xref rid="bib127" ref-type="bibr">127</xref>], would greatly complicate the whole problem rather than simplify it. I believe that the next main stage in the development of the quantum-classical mechanics of elementary electron transfers [
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib79" ref-type="bibr">79</xref>] will be based on a generalization of the Kubo-Toyozawa density-matrix technique or the quantum field theory technique.
</p>
