<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A third reaction is the decomposition of KH; however, this reaction is not of interest in hydrogen storage applications. An explanation of “commonly accepted” is required; for KAlH
 <sub>4</sub> dehydrogenation and rehydrogenation reactions pathways are still not fully understood. Dehydrogenation pathway involving reactions (34) and (35) are similar to LiAlH
 <sub>4</sub> and NaAlH
 <sub>4</sub>, and it is supported by pressure –composition isotherm (PCI) curves that present two plateaus (1 bar and 10 bar) at 355 °C [
 <xref rid="B166-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">166</xref>,
 <xref rid="B167-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">167</xref>]. Additionally, some DFT calculations indicate that K
 <sub>3</sub>AlH
 <sub>6</sub> is sufficiently thermally stable to behave as an intermediary [
 <xref rid="B168-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">168</xref>]. Santhanam et al. reported the synthesis of K
 <sub>3</sub>AlH
 <sub>6</sub> by 12 h of the mechanical milling of KAlH
 <sub>4</sub> and 2KH [
 <xref rid="B169-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">169</xref>]. However, a number of experimental reports indicate the presence of other reaction intermediaries, such as KAlH
 <sub>2</sub> [
 <xref rid="B170-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">170</xref>], AlH
 <sub>3</sub> [
 <xref rid="B171-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">171</xref>], K
 <italic>
  <sub>x</sub>
 </italic>AlH
 <italic>
  <sub>y</sub>
 </italic> [
 <xref rid="B167-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">167</xref>], or other phases with partially known crystallography [
 <xref rid="B172-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">172</xref>]. Some of them were observed during the in-situ synchrotron radiation powder X-ray diffraction experiments; however, they have not been isolated [
 <xref rid="B172-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">172</xref>]. The controversial results indicate a possible dependency of the dehydrogenation path of KAlH
 <sub>4</sub> on the operating conditions, as pointed out by Ares et al. [
 <xref rid="B164-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">164</xref>]. Additives, such as TiCl
 <sub>3</sub> [
 <xref rid="B164-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">164</xref>,
 <xref rid="B167-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">167</xref>], or salts, such as NaCl and LiCl (the other product of the ball milling metathesis) [
 <xref rid="B165-materials-12-02724" ref-type="bibr">165</xref>], could modify the reaction kinetics. 
</p>
