<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In total, there exist 15M-1 atomic sites per unit cell. As revealed by the SXRD analysis (
 <xref rid="S0003-S2003-S3002">Sections 3.3.2</xref> and 
 <xref rid="S0004-S2001">4.1</xref>), the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites equivalent to Al3 sites in the parent orthorhombic structure (hereafter called Al3-equivalent sites) are occupied almost exclusively by Al atoms while those equivalent to Al2 sites (hereafter called Al2-equivalent sites) are occupied by both Fe and Al atoms. The exception is the Al25 site, closest to the twin boundary, where the occupancy of Fe toms is less significant compared with other Al2-equivalent sites (
 <xref rid="F0006">Figure 6(a</xref>)). Therefore, it is reasonable to assume that the Al3-equivalent sites are occupied exclusively by Al atoms while the Al2-equivalent sites are occupied evenly by Fe and Al atoms (50%:50%), except for the Al2-equivalent site closest to the twin boundary that are occupied exclusively by Al atoms. The numbers of Fe/Al atoms in each of the sites for several M values (from 7 to 23) are given in 
 <xref rid="T0004">Table 4</xref>. As a result, the Fe content (chemical composition) in the compound is expressed as (9M-3)/(30M-2), increasing from 28.85 for M = 7 to 29.65 at.%Fe for M = 23 (bottom line in 
 <xref rid="T0004">Table 4</xref>) and with the limit of 30.0 at.%Fe for M →∞. A similar conclusion can be drawn by considering the compositions of the motif structure and twin boundary with their respective layer thicknesses expressed with the M value. Since the layer thicknesses of the motif structure and the twin-boundary region are respectively M-3 times and three times the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis constant of the parent orthorhombic structure (
 <xref rid="F0009">Figure 9</xref>), the overall composition is expressed as (Fe
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>7</sub>)
 <sub>3M-9</sub>(Fe
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>8</sub>)
 <sub>8</sub> = Fe
 <sub>9M-3</sub>Al
 <sub>21M+1</sub>. This tendency qualitatively agrees with our results: Al-30.0 at.%Fe for M = 15 and 31.0 at.%Fe for M = 19. Because the η″ phase always appears with twin-related domains (with fringe contrast in bright-field TEM images) regardless of the M value, they should be enriched in Al compared to the motif structure (Fe
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>7</sub>) by the incorporated amount of the twin boundary (Fe
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>8</sub>), and so the overall chemical composition is expressed as Fe
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>7+
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>.
</p>
