<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par15">We used the hot-injection method with a slight modification for the synthesis of CsZn
 <sub>x</sub>Pb
 <sub>1-x</sub>X
 <sub>3</sub> NCs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>
 </sup>. Shortly, the preparation of 
 <italic>the</italic> Cs-oleate precursor was performed by adding cesium carbonate (Cs
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub>, 0.243 g) to oleic acid (OA, 0.75 mL), and octadecene (ODE,12 mL) into 50 mL flask. The mixture was dried under vacuum for approximately 1 h at 120 °C and then heated under N
 <sub>2</sub> to 150 °C until all Cs
 <sub>2</sub>CO
 <sub>3</sub> had reacted with OA. Then, 0.188 mmol of PbX
 <sub>2</sub> [PbBr
 <sub>2</sub> (0.069 g), PbCl
 <sub>2</sub> (0.052 g), and PbI
 <sub>2</sub> (0.087 g)] or their mixtures (in desired ratio) and 0.188 mmol of ZnX
 <sub>2</sub> [ZnBr
 <sub>2</sub> (0.042 g), ZnCl
 <sub>2</sub> (0.026 g), and ZnI
 <sub>2</sub> (0.060 g)] were taken into 25 mL flask with ODE (5 mL), OA (0.5 mL), and oleylamine (0.5 mL) separately, and were dried using vacuum oven for 1 h at 120 °C. Note that the Trioctylphosphine (1 mL per 5 mL of ODE) was added into the aforementioned mixture for the synthesis of chloride-based NCs. These mixtures were stirred at 90 °C on a hot plate until the PbX
 <sub>2</sub> and ZnX
 <sub>2</sub> salts were completely dissolved. To the solution obtained by mixing the proportionate amount of PbX
 <sub>2</sub> and ZnX
 <sub>2</sub> precursors, the Cs-oleate solution (0.4 mL, preheated to 100 °C before injection) was quickly injected into the mixture. This was followed by the immediate transference of the mixture into the ice-water bath where the mixture was allowed to cool for a certain time (∼2 min). The cooling process results in the crude solution of the NCs that were subjected to centrifugation at 3500 rpm for 10 minutes. Then, the precipitated NCs were separated from the supernatant, thereby transferring the NCs in toluene for storage. In addition, the composition of halides was attenuated on CsZn
 <sub>x</sub>Pb
 <sub>1-x</sub>X
 <sub>3</sub> (15% Zn
 <sup>2+</sup>) to obtain the desired tunable emission. Finally, the colloidal solution of the samples was used for the characterization and device fabrication.
</p>
