<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Nowadays, many scholars have studied the hydration properties of montmorillonite using molecular simulation technology and have achieved some gratifying results in this field. Seppälä et al. studied the influence of layer charge on the structure of interlayer water and diffusion of water and cations by the methods of DFT (Density Functional Theory) and molecular dynamics, and found that the diffusion coefficient increased with the increase of water content and decrease of layer charge [
 <xref rid="B16-materials-12-02318" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. Greathouse studied the diffusion mechanism of water and cations in montmorillonite interlayers. The result showed that calculated activation energies for ion and water diffusion in Na-montmorillonite were similar to each other and to the water hydrogen bond energy, suggesting the breaking of water–water and water-clay hydrogen bonds as a likely mechanism for interlayer diffusion [
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-02318" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Miranda-Pascuala used the Monte Carlo method to intensively study the expansion characteristics of Na-MMT, Mg-MMT, and Na/Mg-MMT, and found that when there were multiple cations existing in the interlayer of montmorillonite, the properties of montmorillonite mainly depended on the cations with the highest content in the interlayer of montmorillonite [
 <xref rid="B17-materials-12-02318" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Zhang et al. used molecular dynamics simulations to investigate the swelling properties, hydration behaviors, and mobility of the interlayer species of (Nax, Cay)-montmorillonites with different water contents. The results showed that in all montmorillonites, the mobility of Na
 <sup>+</sup> was always much greater than that of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> due to their different hydration shells, Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> hydration complexes were pronounced more stable than those of Na
 <sup>+</sup>, and in montmorillonites with high Ca
 <sup>2+</sup>/Na
 <sup>+</sup> ratio, the inhibitory effects of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> hydration complexes on the mobility of Na
 <sup>+</sup> were clearly revealed [
 <xref rid="B18-materials-12-02318" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>].
</p>
