<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p content-type="flushleft">Gas hydrates spontaneously form in Nature and can be produced in the laboratory by mixing ice with small hydrophobic gas molecules at modest pressures (
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="i9">
   <mo>∼</mo>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>100 bar) and temperatures close to ice melting. Under these conditions, they adopt crystalline clathrate structures, where the guest molecules are confined in nanometric polyhedral cages that are formed by the hydrogen-bonded H
 <sub>2</sub>O or D
 <sub>2</sub>O network. The amount of gas that can be stored in these structures is very significant, orders of magnitude beyond what is expected from the solubility of gas in water at normal conditions. Typical water to gas ratios are indeed close to 6 in most ice clathrates, even though their stoichiometry strongly depends on their formation conditions. Energy-relevant hydrocarbons, like methane, and greenhouse gases, like carbon dioxide, easily form clathrates, which are therefore expected to play a role for energy harvesting and in addressing the global demand for fossil energy and CO
 <sub>2</sub> mitigation (
 <xref rid="r1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>). For this reason, and for their role as model systems for the study of the hydrophobic interaction, gas clathrates have been the subject of intense research for almost 40 y (
 <xref rid="r2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>). Rather recently (
 <xref rid="r3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>
 <xref rid="r4" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r5" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>) experiments have shown that clathrate structures do not collapse when subject to high pressures, but transform into denser structures with even smaller water to gas ratios. These structures, known as filled ices, consist of water networks that stem from distorted ice phases, hosting gas molecules in their voids or channels. This way, low-density ice phases, as ice I
 <italic>c</italic> or ice II, can be stabilized at much higher pressure than in pure ice upon inclusion of gas species (
 <xref rid="r5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, 
 <xref rid="r6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>)&gt; and a new metastable phase of ice (ice XVII) could be obtained by emptying a high-pressure hydrogen hydrate recovered at ambient pressure (
 <xref rid="r7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>).
</p>
