<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this paper we report results of high-resolution high-pressure Raman spectroscopy and ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations including nuclear quantum effects (NQE) on CH
 <sub>4</sub>–D
 <sub>2</sub>O methane hydrate at pressures up to 150 GPa. Additional vibrational modes show up in the Raman spectra at 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="i13">
   <mo>∼</mo>
   <mn>100</mn>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> GPa, which are not compatible with the MH-III phase, together with a significant change in the width of the methane stretching modes. AIMD simulations indicate the existence of a distinct high-pressure methane hydrate phase, in the following named methane hydrate IV (MH-IV), whose water skeleton is isomorphic with ice I
 <italic>h</italic>. We note that 2 distinct hypothetical structures, not experimentally observed so far, were named MH-IV and MH-V in a recent work (
 <xref rid="r17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>). Based on the Roman numbering scheme that has been adopted for the ice phases (
 <xref rid="r18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>), and for the sake of clarity, we named the present methane hydrate phase MH-IV, which naturally follows the MH-III phase by increasing pressure. This phase is stable in the probed pressure range up to 150 GPa and accounts for the additional detected Raman modes. The MH-IV structure is also consistent with previous X-ray diffraction investigations (
 <xref rid="r13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>
 <xref rid="r14" ref-type="bibr"/>
 <xref rid="r15" ref-type="bibr"/>–
 <xref rid="r16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>) and represents the highest-pressure gas hydrate phase known up to now. The transition from MH-III to MH-IV is shown to proceed in 3 steps as pressure increases: 1) symmetrization of the hydrogen bonds in MH-III at 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="i14">
   <mo>∼</mo>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>30 GPa (giving rise to a structure we name “MH-IIIs”), 2) structural change from MH-IIIs to the MH-IV phase at 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="i15">
   <mo>∼</mo>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>40 GPa, and 3) symmetrization of the hydrogen bonds of MH-IV at 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="i16">
   <mo>∼</mo>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>50 GPa (giving rise to “MH-IVs”).
</p>
