<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <p>The results of studies on the influence of periodically stacked nanolayer inclusions, introduced into the face-centered cubic (f.c.c.) hard sphere crystal, on Poisson’s ratio of the obtained nanocomposite system are presented. The monolayers are orthogonal to the 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm1">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mo>[</mo>
      <mn>001</mn>
      <mo>]</mo>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula>-direction. They are formed by hard spheres with diameter different from the spheres forming the matrix of the system. The Monte Carlo computer simulations show that in such a case the symmetry of the system changes from the cubic to tetragonal one. When the diameter of the inclusion spheres increases at certain range, a decrease of the negative Poisson’s ratio in the 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm2">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mrow>
       <mo>[</mo>
       <mn>101</mn>
       <mo>]</mo>
      </mrow>
      <mrow>
       <mo>[</mo>
       <mover accent="true">
        <mn>1</mn>
        <mo stretchy="false">¯</mo>
       </mover>
       <mn>01</mn>
       <mo>]</mo>
      </mrow>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula>-directions is observed, i.e., the system enhances its partial auxeticity. The dependence of the maximal, average, and negative parts of the minimal Poisson’s ratio on the direction of the applied load are shown in a form of surfaces in spherical coordinates, plotted for selected values of nanolayer particle diameters. The most negative value of the Poisson’s ratio found among all studied systems was 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm3">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <mo>−</mo>
      <mn>0.11</mn>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula> (at pressure 
  <inline-formula>
   <math id="mm4">
    <mrow>
     <mrow>
      <msup>
       <mi>p</mi>
       <mo>*</mo>
      </msup>
      <mo>=</mo>
      <mn>100</mn>
     </mrow>
    </mrow>
   </math>
  </inline-formula>, which is about ten times higher than the melting pressure) what is almost twice more negative than in the f.c.c. crystal of identical hard spheres. The observed effect weakens along with the decrease of pressure and becomes hardly noticeable near melting. This study indicates that modifying only the size of the inclusion particles one can change Poisson’s ratio of nanocomposites at high pressures.
 </p>
</abstract>
