<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Recently, many researchers have focused their attention on rare-earth-doped phosphor materials for solid-state lighting, especially in white light-emitting diodes (w-LEDs). Commercialized w-LEDs are made up of a blue-emitting LED chip and a yellow-emitting phosphor (Y
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>5</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>:Ce
 <sup>3+</sup> (YAG:Ce)). However, they exhibit a low color-rendering index (CRI) because they generate weak red emission.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
 </sup> To solve the problem, optimal phosphors should be newly developed. Therefore, new classes of phosphors based on metal silicates, metal sulfides, metal oxy-nitrides, and metal nitrides have been developed.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> Liu et al. reported that Li
 <sub>2</sub>CaSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (with a tetragonal phase, space group 
 <italic>I</italic>4̅2
 <italic>m</italic>) has high absorption from the UV to the near-UV region and a strong emission at ∼480 nm with a narrow bandwidth.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> Orange-yellow-emitting Li
 <sub>2</sub>SrSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (with a trigonal crystal system and belonging to space group 
 <italic>P</italic>3
 <sub>1</sub>21) was prepared and compared to the commercialized YAG:Ce phosphor by Varadaraju et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> Recently, the crystal structure and PL properties of Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>-doped Li
 <sub>2</sub>BaSiO
 <sub>4</sub> have been elucidated and discussed by Kulshreshtha et al.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup> and Kim et al.,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup>, i. e., the hexagonal crystal system (belonging to space group 
 <italic>P</italic>6
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>cm</italic>) and green emission at ∼508 nm, respectively. Based on the structures of the host materials in Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4</sub> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba), it is presumed that the luminescent properties of these phosphor materials may be closely related to the chemical environment around the Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>-activator ion. It is well known that alkaline-earth silicon–oxynitride phosphors with the RE-ion activator (RE = Ce
 <sup>3+</sup>, Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>, Yb
 <sup>3+</sup>, etc.) have been intensively studied in recent years because they are potential candidate materials for improving the low luminous efficiency and low CRI for w-LEDs.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>
 </sup> The N
 <sup>3–</sup> ions substituted partially for O
 <sup>2–</sup> ions in the host lattice could change the electronic structure of Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> owing to their difference in electronegativity, ionic radius, and magnitude of crystal field splitting, as well as the nephelauxetic (cloud expanding) effect of the two ions,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>
 </sup> which results in the change of the PL properties of the phosphors before and after N
 <sup>3–</sup> doping. Song et al. mentioned that the partial nitridation of Li
 <sub>2</sub>SrSiO
 <sub>4–3
  <italic>x</italic>/2
 </sub>N
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (
 <italic>x</italic> = 0.01) phosphors induced a highly enhanced PL intensity by as high as 190%.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref>
 </sup> Therefore, it is presumed that their results for the N
 <sup>3–</sup> doping effect on an increase of the luminescent intensity are meaningful even though the N
 <sup>3–</sup> contents doped into the crystal sites were not determined. However, systematic research for the N
 <sup>3–</sup> doping effect of Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4</sub> (M = Ca and Ba) has not been pursued to the best of our knowledge. Furthermore, the present study is also motivated by the desire to devise a white near-UV LED because Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>-activated Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4</sub> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors exhibit blue, orange-yellow, and green emission, respectively. Herein, we report on the highly enhanced luminescence of N
 <sup>3–</sup>-substituted Li
 <sub>2</sub>MSiO
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) and a white near-UV LED using three phosphors.
</p>
