<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this work, the impact of the host material composition on the temperature-dependent luminescent properties of vanadium-doped nanocrystalline garnets was investigated. It was demonstrated that the incorporation of Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> ions into the Y
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>5−x</sub>Ga
 <sub>x</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub>:V structure enables modification of the emission color of the phosphor by the stabilization of the vanadium ions on the V
 <sup>4+</sup> oxidation state. Taking advantage from the fact that V
 <sup>4+</sup> ions, due to their similar ionic radii, mainly occupy the octahedral site of Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> ions, the enlargement of their amount leads to the increase of their emission intensity. Moreover, a growing number of V
 <sup>4+</sup> ions cause a shortening of the average V
 <sup>5+</sup>–V
 <sup>4+</sup> distance facilitating interionic energy transfer between them. Conducted studies regarding the influence of temperature on the emission intensities of the vanadium ions at different oxidation states reveal that the most susceptible to thermal quenching is the V
 <sup>5+</sup> emission intensity. On the other hand, due to the V
 <sup>5+</sup> → V
 <sup>4+</sup> energy transfer, the V
 <sup>4+</sup> emission intensity increases with temperature. The higher the amount of Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> ions in the host, the more evident the enhancement of V
 <sup>4+</sup> emission intensity and the lower the threshold temperature above which this enhancement occurs. Taking advantage form the fact of opposite temperature dependence of V
 <sup>5+</sup> and V
 <sup>4+</sup> emission intensities, their ratio was used to create the bandshape luminescent thermometer, to the best of our knowledge, the highest relative sensitivity of V-based luminescent thermometers up to date S
 <sub>max</sub>, 2.64%/°C, 2.56%/°C and 2.49%/°C for Y
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>2</sub>Ga
 <sub>3</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub> (at 0 °C), Y
 <sub>3</sub>AlGa
 <sub>4</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub> (at −20 °C) and Y
 <sub>3</sub>Ga
 <sub>5</sub>O
 <sub>12</sub> (at −100 °C), respectively. With an increase of the Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> concentration, the value of the relative sensitivity, as well as the temperature at which 
 <italic>S
  <sub>max</sub>
 </italic> was observed, can be modified. Additionally, it was found that the higher the contamination of Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> ions, the more evident the change of the chromatic coordinates of emitted light with temperature changes in a −150 °C–300 °C temperature range. As was proven in this manuscript, the introduction of the Ga
 <sup>3+</sup> ions in the garnet host enables modification of the performance of nanocrystalline luminescent thermometer like: its usable temperature range, maximal value of the relative sensitivity, as well as the temperature at which maximal sensitivity can be obtained. The dominant effect, which is responsible for described modification of the luminescent properties of V doped luminescent thermometers, is the increase of the V
 <sup>5+</sup> → V
 <sup>4+</sup> energy transfer probability associated with the growing number of the crystallographic sites that can be occupied by the V
 <sup>4+</sup> ions. This shortens the average distance between the interaction ions, facilitating energy transfer process.
</p>
