<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this work, the hydration properties of the four kinds of montmorillonite were simulated by Materials Studio7.0 simulation software (Accelrys, San Diego, CA, America) [
 <xref rid="B23-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]. According to 
 <xref rid="ijms-20-03997-t001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref> and 
 <xref rid="ijms-20-03997-t002" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>, the semi-unit crystal structure formula of montmorillonite was assumed to be M
 <sub>x+y</sub>(Al
 <sub>2-x</sub>Mg
 <sub>x</sub>)(Si
 <sub>4-y</sub>Al
 <sub>y</sub>)O
 <sub>10</sub>(OH)
 <sub>2</sub> nH
 <sub>2</sub>O, where M is the exchangeable cations distributed between the montmorillonite layers(Ca
 <sup>2+</sup>), and x+y is the semi-unit layer charge density. The structure belongs to the monoclinic C2/m space group, the crystal layer is constant: a = 0.523 nm, b = 0.906 nm, and the c value is variable [
 <xref rid="B19-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B30-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>] when the structural unit layer is anhydrous, c = 0.960 nm; and if there are water molecules existing between the layers, the c value will vary with the amount of water molecules and the type of exchangeable cations between layers. 
 <xref rid="ijms-20-03997-t003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref> is the atomic coordinates of montmorillonite in the three-dimensional model. Based on these parameters, the montmorillonite model can be built. At present, most researchers use super-cells of 4a × 2b × 1c and 4a × 4b × 1c for simulation research [
 <xref rid="B21-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B31-ijms-20-03997" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]. Considering the research purpose and content of this work, 8a × 4b × 1c super large unit cell was established to simulate the hydration properties of montmorillonite, which can not only meet the needs of high-level layer charge montmorillonite modeling, but also ensure that the simulated layer charge is consistent with the actual experimental samples.
</p>
