<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In CoSi and its dilute alloys with FeSi and NiSi, the Seebeck coefficient calculated in CRTA approximation deviates from the experiment, both in absolute value and in composition corresponding to the 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm142">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mo>|</mo>
     <mi>S</mi>
     <mo>|</mo>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> maximum. The largest experimental value of 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm143">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mo>−</mo>
     <mn>80</mn>
     <mspace width="0.166667em"/>
     <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">μ</mi>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>V/K at 300 K was reached for stoichiometric CoSi composition [
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>], while CRTA approximation predicted a value of 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm144">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <mo>−</mo>
     <mn>45</mn>
     <mspace width="0.166667em"/>
     <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">μ</mi>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>V/K, which was reached at 1% of Ni doping. Deviation could be caused by both the change of electronic band structure in alloys, and by energy dependence of relaxation time. For example, for stoichiometric CoSi, contribution to the Seebeck coefficient from heavy hole-like bands in constant relaxation time approximation prevail, leading to a positive Seebeck coefficient in contrast to experiment. In CoSi and its solid solutions with a small addition of Ni or Fe, the magnitude of Seebeck coefficient can be quite well described taking into account electron–phonon interactions and point-defect scattering [
 <xref rid="B90-materials-12-02710" ref-type="bibr">90</xref>]. The energy dependences of these scattering rates, obtained by means of first-principle calculations, appeared to be proportional to the total density of states, implying the importance of interband scattering. In CoSi, the Fermi level is situated just below the node at the 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm145">
   <mrow>
    <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">Γ</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> point (
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm146">
   <mrow>
    <mrow>
     <msub>
      <mi>ϵ</mi>
      <mi mathvariant="sans-serif">Γ</mi>
     </msub>
     <mo>=</mo>
     <mn>0</mn>
    </mrow>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>) near the minimum of the density of states (the energy dependence of DOS for CoSi is similar to that of FeSi, which is plotted in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-02710-f005">Figure 5</xref>a). A stronger increase and larger DOS values below the Fermi level, compared to the above 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="mm147">
   <mrow>
    <msub>
     <mi>ϵ</mi>
     <mi>F</mi>
    </msub>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>, lead to stronger scattering of charge carriers below the Fermi level and results in a large negative Seebeck coefficient, in agreement with the experiment. For the same reason, resistivity of Fe-doped CoSi samples becomes larger compared to Ni-doped ones. Therefore, in the case of semimetallic monosilicides, band structure is important for the description of transport properties both directly and for describing the energy dependence of the relaxation time, since CRTA is not a good approximation in this case.
</p>
