<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par13">The real part of the electric permittivity exhibits dispersion for temperatures above 30 K, having a higher magnitude in the 30–150 K temperature range. The shapes of the 
 <italic>ɛ</italic>’(T) curves are frequency dependent, where the maximum anomalous behavior is obtained for the 
 <italic>ε</italic>’(T) curve measured at 1 kHz. As the frequency increases, the amplitude of the anomaly decreases and moves towards higher temperatures. In addition, the observed anomalies in the imaginary part of 
 <italic>ɛ</italic>”(T) are also frequency dependent in the whole studied temperature range. These features in 
 <italic>ε</italic>’(T) and 
 <italic>ε</italic>”(T) evidence for the existence of a dielectric relaxation process in GMO thin film, whose activation energy is 80 meV, higher than the reported value 22 meV found in bulk GMO
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>. The 
 <italic>ɛ</italic>”(T) curve measured at 1 kHz exhibits a small anomaly at 105 K, which is associated with the antiferrodistortive phase transition of the STO substrate. Due to the relatively small amplitude of this anomaly and the fact that it is only observed at a single frequency along with the different temperature dependence of the measured dielectric constant regarding the actual dielectric response of STO, we realize that the contribution of the STO to the overall dielectric response is negligible small. A closer look at the 
 <italic>ɛ</italic>”(T) curve measured at 10 kHz reveals a small but clear anomaly at T
 <sub>1</sub> near 35 K. The results here described strongly contrast with the ones reported for orthorhombic GMO thin films onto (010)-YAlO
 <sub>3</sub>, where a cusp-like anomaly in 
 <italic>ɛ</italic>’(T) curve is observed
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>. Though the temperatures corresponding to the anomalies in 
 <italic>ɛ</italic>’(T) and 
 <italic>ɛ</italic>”(T) curves found in this work and in ref. 
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup> are similar, the difference between the 
 <italic>ɛ</italic>’(T) curve shapes evidences for different mechanisms underlying the dielectric properties of tetragonal and orthorhombic GMO films
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
