<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par15">In the absence of a polling electric field, no anomaly in the temperature dependence of the TSDC could be observed. An anomaly in the temperature dependence of the TSDC is apparent at 32 K, in experiments for which the sample was cooled down under the poling field, while experiments using inverse poling fields result in the respective reversed TSDC signal. Moreover, the temperature for which the anomaly in the temperature dependence of the TSDC is ascertained does not depend on the strength of the poling electric field. However, as it is expected, the amplitude of the anomaly increases by increasing the poling electric field. The heating rate dependence of TSDC was also studied after poling the film with a 1.0 kV/m electric field, in order to determine its actual origin. As it can be seen in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4(b)</xref>, the amplitude of TSDC increases and becomes broader with increasing heating rate, possibly due to thermal inertia effects of the measuring system, but the peaks maxima, signaled by the vertical green dotted line, remain at 32 K, independently of the heating rate. This outcome reflects the spontaneous origin of the TSDC associated with the stabilization of a ferroelectric phase, and excludes others charge displacement origins, as those observed in electrets and related compounds, wherein the driving force is the restoration of charge neutrality through disorientation of electric dipoles, and diffusion of immobilized space charges, among others
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>
 </sup>. In order to determine the temperature dependence of the in-plane component of the electric polarization associated with the ferroelectric phase, we have carried out the time integration of the pyroelectric current from Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4(b)</xref> that was measured at the lowest electric poling field, in order to avoid induced contributions expected from applying higher poling fields. In this case, the in-plane component of the electric polarization value around 40 nC.cm
 <sup>−2</sup> is obtained below 32 K, of similar order of the saturation values found in bulk TbMnO
 <sub>3</sub> and DyMnO
 <sub>3</sub> below 20 K
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>. Shimamoto 
 <italic>et al</italic>. have reported the emergence of an electric polarization of ∼1μC.cm
 <sup>−2</sup> along the 
 <italic>a</italic>-axis in 10 nm thick orthorhombic GMO thin films onto (010)-YAlO
 <sub>3</sub> substrates
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>. This value is more than one order of magnitude larger than the one found in the tetragonal GMO films, which can be explained by the different nature of the ferroelectric phase in orthorhombic and tetragonal GMO films, ascertained by the different temperature dependences of the electric permittivity. Moreover, the difference between the values referred to above also stems from the fact that we were only measuring the in-plane component of the electric polarization.
</p>
