<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par17">Previously published works on several rare-earth manganites thin films (GdMnO
 <sub>3</sub>, TbMnO
 <sub>3</sub>, HoMnO
 <sub>3</sub>) generally report that a distorted orthorhombic structure is obtained using STO(001) substrates
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup>. Contrarily, we have obtained in a totally strained epitaxial GMO film, a previously unprecedented tetragonal structure up to a 35 nm thickness. It is worth to note that such a tetragonal like structure was also obtained in a TbMnO
 <sub>3</sub> film, though up to a much less thickness of 2 nm
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. The observation of a pyroelectric current in thicker orthorhombic GMO films onto STO(001), whose temperature dependence resembles the one observed in this work
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>, points out for a common source of the improper ferroelectric phase in GMO films with different structures. Though tempting, it is not at all adequate to visualize the behavior of such GMO tetragonal films using the same interpretative models found for the orthorhombic rare-earth manganites
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup>. Actually, the tetragonal symmetry of GMO thin film imposes constrains to the packing and mobility of the MnO
 <sub>6</sub> octahedra, corresponding to significant rearrangements on the Mn-O-Mn orbitals overlap and respective alterations in charge transfer and magnetic interactions. Moreover, the contribution of twin-like domain structure ascribed to the high temperature electric polarization in orthorhombic GMO films
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup> is not apparently applicable in our case, since such domain structure is not observed in tetragonal GMO films. Thus, the proposed mechanisms to explain the stabilization of the ferroelectric phase in orthorhombic GMO thin films have to be revised.
</p>
