<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par5">GMO thin films have been deposited onto different substrates by using both chemical and physical routes
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. Up to now, two different crystal symmetries were reported for GMO thin films. Orthorhombic GMO thin films have been the most frequently obtained
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. GMO thin films, with 10 nm thickness, were successfully deposited on oriented (010)-YAlO
 <sub>3</sub> substrates by pulse laser deposition method
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. The films are orthorhombic at room conditions and exhibit a polar phase below 30 K, with a remanent polarization about ~1μC/cm
 <sup>2</sup> at 10 K. The rather large value of the electric polarization has been ascribed to the stabilization of an antiferromagnetic phase, characterized by an incommensurate Mn
 <sup>3+</sup> spin ordering, which successively locks into a commensurate E-type state
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. GMO films onto (100)-oriented Si substrate, prepared by sol-gel method, with 230 nm average thickness, are paramagnetic above 80 K, showing a ferromagnetic response below 15 K. The temperature dependence of the magnetization, measured in both zero-field cooling (ZFC) and field-cooling (FC) conditions, shows an anomaly at T~27 K that has been assigned to the magnetic transition taking place in this temperature range in the bulk material
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. More recently, a ferroelectric state, with rather high Curie temperature (T
 <sub>C</sub> = 75 K) and a strong ferromagnetic component emerging below 105 K, was reported in orthorhombic GMO thin films (average thickness 110 nm) deposited by pulsed laser method onto (001)-oriented SrTiO
 <sub>3</sub> substrates
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>. A stabilization of an 
 <italic>ac</italic>-plane spiral spin order below 105 K was proposed to explain the stabilization of the ferroelectric phase and a nano-scale twin-like domain structure was appointed as essential for the rather high temperature ferroelectric and ferromagnetic phases observed in the orthorhombic GMO films
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
