<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par10">Figure 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(a)</xref> shows a representative XRD pattern in the 20–65° 2Θ-range, recorded at room conditions, of the 35 nm GMO thin film deposited onto (001)-oriented SrTiO
 <sub>3</sub> (hereafter designated by STO(001)). The XRD pattern exhibits the strongest Bragg peaks approximately centered at 2Θ = 22.53° (001), 46.38° (002), 72.55° (003) and 104.24° (004), which are indexed to SrTiO
 <sub>3</sub> crystal, confirming the high quality and the (001)-orientation of the substrate, with 
 <italic>a</italic>
 <sub>STO</sub> = 3.905(0) Å
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. One significant diffraction peak centered at 2Θ = 47.60° spreading ± 0.03° (
 <italic>d</italic> = 1.91 ± 0.01 Å), is indexed to reflections from planes (040) of the GMO film, ascribing 
 <italic>b</italic> = 7.64(0) Å
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>. It is worth to stress that the XRD pattern recorded for this films does not clearly shows the Laue´s oscillations. The lack of interference fringes can result from the high quality of the epitaxial growth of the GMO film, due to no relevant interface mismatch with the STO(001) substrate
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>. Figure 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(b)</xref> shows the symmetric reciprocal space map centered at the main reflection peak arising from (002) STO planes, located at 2Θ = 46.47° and Ω = 23.23°. The single satellite reflection derived from the (040) GMO planes is only + 0.4° offset in Ω and exhibits a small dispersion ∆(2Θ) ≤ 0.6°, closely conforming the profile of the substrate peak, which is indicative of the tight epitaxial fitting of the film to the substrate. Figure 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(c)</xref> shows the asymmetric map centered at 2Θ = 61.24° and Ω = 18.09°, depicting a single peak, with a limited spread with ∆(2Θ) and ∆Ω ≤ 1°, indexed to the (203) planes of the GMO film. All the peaks arising from the GMO film are well defined, relatively narrow and do not show mirroring, broadening nor diverging features from the respective centers. Consequently, there are no typical indications of maculae, neither domains due to a twinned crystalline structure, not even of significant lattice relaxation throughout the whole film thickness. Therefore, the film grows epitaxially in a single uniform crystallographic phase. The symmetric pole figure presented in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1(d)</xref>, centered at 2Θ = 25.65° (
 <italic>d</italic> = 3.470 Å), encompasses and maximizes the reflections from the (111) planes of the GMO film, whereas the STO (111) reflections are found at 2Θ = 39.96°. The projected 4-fold peaks clearly configure a square, which evidences that the in-plane 
 <italic>a</italic> and 
 <italic>c</italic> parameters of the GMO film are forcibly identical. Moreover, these well-defined peaks are precisely aligned with the substrate edges corresponding to the respective (100)
 <sub>STO</sub> and (010)
 <sub>STO</sub> axes, which is a clear indication that the in-plane 
 <italic>a</italic> and 
 <italic>c</italic> axes of GMO film are oriented at 45° to the in-plane STO axes. Accordingly, 
 <italic>a</italic> and 
 <bold>
  <italic>c</italic>
 </bold> are estimated to be 5.48(9) Å, approximately (−0.6%) the diagonal spacing √2.
 <italic>a</italic>
 <sub>STO</sub> = 5.522(5) Å of the substrate. These sets of results are unequivocally consistent with a tetragonal symmetry with preferential oriented growth along 
 <italic>b</italic> axis perpendicular to the substrate surface, as schematically represented in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>. The present study demonstrates that the ~35 nm GMO thin films obtained in this work do not follow the expected orthorhombic symmetry found in GMO thin film with larger thickness, obtained using pulse laser deposition technique
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>. Possible effects of oxygen off-stoichiometry, that could be traced to an excess expansion of 
 <italic>b</italic> parameter
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>, are negligible and within the same ~1% error margin of the calculated cell parameters. Bragg peaks that are ascribed to other crystallographic and chemical phases could not be detected.
</p>
