<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">In 2015, the lighting sector in the US was responsible for ~15% of the country’s entire electricity consumption. The US department of energy has estimated the potential energy savings due to SSL (Solid State Lighting) technology to be up to 75% in the year 2035 compared to a non-SSL scenario
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. The commercial breakthrough for SSL came with the invention of phosphor converted white LEDs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>, generally referred to as white pc-LEDs. This technology employs a primary blue LED-chip, while parts of the emitted blue light are converted to longer wavelengths by using mixtures of luminescent materials to obtain white light (additive colour mixing)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. This approach yields high colour quality (e.g. colour rendering index (CRI) values greater than 90) and high luminous efficacy of radiation (LER). The colour rendering index (CRI) is a dimensionless index, describing the ability of a white light source to render the colours of illuminated objects to the human visual perception
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>. For high-CRI applications an additional index, R9, is included to describe the rendering of deep red coloured objects
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>
 </sup>. The luminous efficacy of radiation (LER) is defined as the ratio of the total luminous flux (lumens) to the spectral power (watts)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>. A high CRI value is currently obtained at the cost of LER, as can be seen in commercially available illumination grade pc-LEDs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. This trade-off is mostly caused by broad emission bands of red phosphors and the reduction in sensitivity of the human eye towards the near infrared region
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>. In order to sufficiently cover the red spectral region (emission maximum 610–620 nm)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>, while minimizing the efficacy loss caused by low eye sensitivity at long wavelengths, new red phosphors with exceptionally narrow emission bands near the optimal wavelength are required
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
