<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par5">Until now, only very few red emitting phosphors fulfil the high demands of commercial LED applications; namely a high conversion efficiency at LED operating conditions as well as degradation resistance over LEDs lifetime. For example, Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> doped nitride materials like (Ba,Sr)
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>5</sub>N
 <sub>8</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup> (
 <italic>λ</italic>
 <sub>max</sub> ~590 to 625 nm, full width at half maximum (FWHM) ~2050 to 2600 cm
 <sup>−1</sup> or ~71 to 101 nm), (Ca,Sr)SiAlN
 <sub>3</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup> (
 <italic>λ</italic>
 <sub>max</sub> ~610 to 660 nm, FWHM ~2100 to 2500 cm
 <sup>−1</sup> or ~78 to 108 nm) and the recently published Sr[LiAl
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>]:Eu
 <sup>2+ </sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>, (
 <italic>λ</italic>
 <sub>max</sub> ~654 nm, FWHM ~1180 cm
 <sup>−1</sup> or ~50 nm), commonly abbreviated as SLA, have made their way into commercially available white pc-LEDs. The first two examples both suffer from very large FWHM and therefore low LER values, which is unattractive for high-performance applications. White pc-LEDs are characterized by a correlated colour temperature (CCT), which is the chromaticity position along the Planckian locus
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup>. Sr[LiAl
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>]:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>-containing warm-white pc-LEDs (CCT equals 2700 K, CRI greater than 90) have already demonstrated an LER gain of 14% compared to a commercial high-CRI pc-LED due to the significantly reduced FWHM of Sr[LiAl
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>]:Eu
 <sup>2+ </sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup>
 <sup>.</sup> However, the rather long and hardly tuneable spectral position of Sr[LiAl
 <sub>3</sub>N
 <sub>4</sub>]:Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> still causes considerable amounts of radiation in spectral regions with low human eye sensitivity. The only known red-emitting phosphor combining a very narrow FWHM (43 nm, 1170 cm
 <sup>−1</sup>) with an emission maximum in the desired spectral region (
 <italic>λ</italic>
 <sub>max</sub> equals 615 nm) is SrMg
 <sub>3</sub>SiN
 <sub>4</sub>:Eu
 <sup>2+ </sup>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>, which suffers from high thermal quenching, rendering it unsuitable for application in pc-LEDs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
