<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" xml:lang="EN"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ACS//DTD ACS Journal DTD v1.02 20061031//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName ACSJournal-v102.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.02?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName acs2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">ACS Omega</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">ao</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="coden">acsodf</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>ACS Omega</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2470-1343</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical
Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6921264</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsomega.9b02410</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>First-Principles-Based
Force Field for 2,6-Diamino-3,5-dinitropyrazine-1-oxide
(LLM-105)</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Xian</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">&#x02021;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" id="ath2"><name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>Qun</given-names></name><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="other">*</xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath3"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Jinshan</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath4"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Mingli</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">&#x02021;</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>&#x02020;</label>Institute
of Chemical Materials, <institution>China Academy of
Engineering Physics (CAEP)</institution>, Mianyang 621900, <country>China</country></aff><aff id="aff2"><label>&#x02021;</label>Institute
of Atomic and Molecular Physics, <institution>Sichuan
University</institution>, Chengdu 610065, <country>China</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>E-mail: <email>zq84229@163.com</email>. Phone: <phone>18683664393</phone>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>04</day><month>12</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>17</day><month>12</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><volume>4</volume><issue>25</issue><fpage>21054</fpage><lpage>21062</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>30</day><month>07</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>19</day><month>11</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019 American Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2019</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Chemical Society</copyright-holder><license><license-p>This is an open access article published under an ACS AuthorChoice <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/page/policy/authorchoice_termsofuse.html">License</ext-link>, which permits copying and redistribution of the article or any adaptations for non-commercial purposes.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p content-type="toc-graphic"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_0009" id="ab-tgr1"/></p><p>2,6-Diamino-3,5-dinitropyrazine-1-oxide (LLM-105) is
a highly promising
energetic material (EM) with high safety. Understanding its microscopic
response mechanisms within the external stimulus is meaningful for
the design of EMs. In order to comprehend the complicated phenomena,
it is necessary to employ molecular simulation methods to investigate
the response mechanisms with the force field (FF) at an atomic level.
In this work, we developed a tailored FF for LLM-105 based on first-principles
calculations. The validity of the FF was evaluated by molecular dynamics
simulations. The structural parameters of LLM-105 predicted by FF
are in good agreement with the experimental values, such as lattice
constant, bond length, bond angle, dihedral angle and center of mass,
and so forth. Moreover, the FF possesses good performance to describe
the structural response on pressure accurately. In general, our work
not only builds a balanced FF in gas and condensed phases, but also
provides a useful tool to study the properties about LLM-105 at a
large scale, which is helpful to improve the understanding about the
balance between energy and safety in EMs.</p></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-old-9</meta-name><meta-value>ao9b02410</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-new-14</meta-name><meta-value>ao9b02410</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>ccc-price</meta-name><meta-value/></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Energetic materials (EMs),
including pyrotechnics, propellants,
and explosives, are widely applied for civil, industrial, and military
purposes.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup> With the progress and development of the
society, the requirements for EMs increase, such as high energy density,
thermal stability, thermal and shock, storability, and low handling
hazards.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref></sup> Because of a delicate balance between high
energy and high safety, a great challenge is to search a new balance
point for EMs using chemical synthesis and crystal engineering technology.
Among EMs, 1,3,5-triamino-2,4,6-trinitrobenzene (TATB) and 1,1-diamino-2,2-dinitroethylene
(FOX-7) are always considered to be representatives at the balance
point.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref></sup> Besides TATB and FOX-7, 2,6-diamino-3,5-dinitropyrazine-1-oxide
(LLM-105) are a highly promising candidate. Compared with main traditional
EMs like 2,4,6-trinitrotoluene, 1,3,5-trinitro-1,3,5-triazine (RDX),
and octahydro-1,3,5,7-tetranitro-1,3,5,7-tetrazocine (HMX), LLM-105
possesses outstanding thermal stability and insensitivity to friction,
spark, impact, and shock.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref></sup></p><p>It is
interesting to reveal how to keep the balance in high energy materials with
great safety. In addition, under the Hugoniot relation, which governs
the detonation process, the energy, pressure, and volume of an explosive
before and after a shock are involved. Prediction of the lattice structure
is therefore, important to locate the detonation performances of EMs.
As we know, energy release and stability maintenance of EMs should
be both related to the response under external stimuli. Since the
discovery of LLM-105 in the mid-1990, numerous studies have been attracting
attention to thermal studies, equation of state (EOS) measurements,
and sensitivity of LLM-105.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref></sup> Xu et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref></sup> measured the
mechanical and thermal sensitivity of LLM-105. Zhang et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref></sup> investigated the morphology, particle size distribution,
internal structure, sensitivity, and thermal decomposition properties
of submicrometer-sized LLM-105 using scanning electron microscopy
and X-ray diffraction. Gump et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref></sup> employed
synchrotron angle-dispersive X-ray diffraction and diamond anvil cells
to ascertain the isothermal equations of the state of LLM-105 at static
high pressure and temperature. Williamson et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref></sup> presented experiments combined with a range of diagnostic
instrumentation to describe the impact response of LLM-105, demonstrating
the low-level reaction in it, consisting of hotspot ignition, comparatively
little light output, and substantial levels of gas production. Recently,
Xu et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref></sup> have studied the structural
stability of LLM-105 under different pressures and temperatures by
X-ray diffraction, pressure-dependent Raman and infrared spectra,
indicating that a structure phase transition occurs at approximately
30 GPa. Although many experiments have been performed, it is vague
to comprehend the microscopic response mechanisms within the external
stimulus.</p><p>It is necessary to apply molecule simulation methods
to investigate
the response mechanisms at the microscopic level. Recently, multiple
studies have employed density functional theory (DFT) methods to simulate
the structure and EOS under high pressure.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> At the B3LYP/6-31G** level, He et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref></sup> demonstrated systematically the existence of
the intramolecular hydrogen bonds (HBs) in LLM-105 and revealed the
influence of H-bonds on its properties. Wu et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref></sup> reported the effect of high-pressure on the geometric,
electronic, and absorption properties of LLM-105 at the PW91 level,
proposing that there exists multiple phase transitions at different
pressures. Manaa et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref></sup> performed dispersion-corrected
DFT calculations on the unreacted EOS of crystal LLM-105 under a hydrostatic
compression of up to 45 GPa. Stavrou et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup> implemented dispersion-corrected first-principles molecular dynamics
(MD) simulations to explore the EOS and the behavior of LLM-105 at
various pressures, finding that the ambient pressure phase remains
stable up to 20 GPa. Moreover, Zong et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> investigated the structure, mechanical properties, vibrational spectra,
and EOS of LLM-105 under a hydrostatic pressure of up to 100 GPa with
the PBE level.</p><p>However, the theoretical research studies mentioned
are performed
on the system with a small quantity of atoms. Virtually, many phenomena
are always largely complicated and consist of thousands of atoms,
such as shock response, thermal diffusion, hot points, and defects.
Thus, the methods based on the empirical force field (FF) are usually
employed to investigate the mechanisms. Generally, some general FFs
were chosen to simulate the condensed phase of EMs, such as Amber<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref></sup> and Compass.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup> However,
to derive more dependable results for a particular material property,
the tailor-made FFs are always applied to the simulations about the
specific systems. Smith and Bharadwaj constructed a FF for HMX according
to the DFT energies.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup> Mathew and Sewell
used MD with a tailor-made FF to investigate the surface-initiated
melting of TATB.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref></sup> With the combination
of symmetry-adapted perturbation theory and DFT [SAPT(DFT)],<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref></sup> a series of intermolecular interaction potential have been parameterized
for RDX,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref></sup> TATB,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref></sup> and FOX-7.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref></sup> Furthermore, Song et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref30">30</xref></sup> developed all-atom, nonempirical, and tailor-made
FFs for &#x003b1;-RDX, which can be reliably applied into crystal and
density predictions and the sensitivity and detonation estimations.
Because of its good accuracy, it is successful in describing the phenomenon
for the respective molecules. However, it is not found that molecule-tailored
FFs for LLM-105 have been established.</p><p>While the prediction
of the lattice structures of EMs remains challenging,
the new FF is helpful for studying the behaviors of neat LLM-105 under
high pressures, which is crucial for the prediction of its detonation
performance. In this work, we developed a tailored FF for LLM-105
based on first-principles calculations. After parameterization has been carried out step by step, the validity
of the FF has been evaluated by the MD simulations. The FF possesses
good performance to describe the LLM-105 molecular and crystal structures
and present structural response on pressure. Our work provides not
only a tailored FF for LLM-105, but also a powerful tool to explore
the response mechanisms of LLM-105 at the atomic scale, which is helpful
to improve the understanding about the balance between energy and
safety in EMs.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><label>2</label><title>Computational Methods</title><sec id="sec2.1"><label>2.1</label><title>Force Field</title><p>LLM-105, with four formula
units per unit cell, is a highly dense molecular solid that crystallizes
in a monoclinic, P2<sub>1</sub>/<italic>n</italic> space symmetry
group. It exhibits an extensive network of HBs and &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;
stacking in its crystal structure as shown in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>a, which was drawn by mercury 3.9.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">31</xref></sup> The topology of the LLM-105 molecule has been
displayed in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>b, which possesses only one stable conformation in the gas phase.
The corresponding atom types are presented in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>c. It is noted that a few atom types are
applied for the FF construction.</p><fig id="fig1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>(a) LLM-105 crystal structure and intermolar
hydrogen bond in the
crystal; the atom indexes (b) and atomic type (c) in the force field
parameters.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_0001" id="gr1" position="float"/></fig><p>The initial molecular structure of LLM-105 (Cambridge
Structural
Database: refcode YEKQAG03) was obtained from the work by Liu et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> After optimization with the PBE0/aug-cc-pVDZ<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref></sup> level, more than 1000 dimer structures were generated randomly referring
to the method introduced by refs (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref>) and (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref>). To obtain the accurate intermolecular energy, the combination
with PBE0/aug-cc-pVDZ and exchange-hole dipole moment dispersion correction
(XDM)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref></sup> were employed. The XDM dispersion model has demonstrated good performance
in sublimation enthalpies and absolute lattice energies of molecular
crystals.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref40">40</xref></sup> Moreover, some studies<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref41">41</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref43">43</xref></sup> obtained accurate energy ranking in the crystal-structure prediction
of molecular crystals with the DFT&#x02013;XDM method. As a whole,
the FF form is similar with Amber FF.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref44">44</xref></sup> The nonbonding interaction is expressed with the electrostatic and
van der Waals (vdW) terms. As shown in <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">1</xref></xref>, the point charge model and the vdW potential
were chosen to describe the two terms, respectively. Instead of the
Lennard-Jones (LJ) potential in Amber, the vdW interaction is expressed
using the Buckingham (BKH) potential. This FF form has been applied
to describe HMX by Smith and Bharadwaj.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup><disp-formula id="eq1"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_m001" position="anchor"/><label>1</label></disp-formula>where, <italic>q</italic><sub><italic>i</italic></sub> is the charge on atom <italic>i</italic>, and <italic>r</italic><sub><italic>ij</italic></sub> is the distance between atom <italic>i</italic> and <italic>j</italic>, <italic>A</italic><sub><italic>ij</italic></sub>, <italic>B</italic><sub><italic>ij</italic></sub>, and <italic>C</italic><sub><italic>ij</italic></sub> are the parameters
in the BKH potential. A revised electrostatic potential fitting charge
(RESP) scheme was used to obtain the point charge.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref45">45</xref></sup> RESP charges always show good agreement with the electrostatic
component of the ab initio interaction energies. BKH has more reasonable
short-range interactions and is more suitable to describe the EMs
in high pressure. In order to obtain reasonable BKH parameters, the
FIT potential parameters<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref46">46</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref47">47</xref></sup> were chosen for the
initial values directly, and the fitting bounds were confined to be
0.9 and 1.1 times of the parameter. In addition, the least-square
method was used to optimize the parameter referring to the dimer energies
in the condition of constrained charge.</p><p>For bonding interactions,
a series of perturbed structures were
generated based on one of the equilibrium conformations according
to the redundant internal coordinates, and optimized with the constrained
structural parameters at the PBE0/aug-cc-pVDZ level, and the harmonic
style functions were chosen for bond and angle terms (<italic>E</italic><sub>bond</sub> and <italic>E</italic><sub>angle</sub>), as follow<disp-formula id="eq2"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_m002" position="anchor"/><label>2</label></disp-formula><disp-formula id="eq3"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_m003" position="anchor"/><label>3</label></disp-formula>where <italic>k</italic><sub>b</sub> and <italic>k</italic><sub>&#x003b8;</sub> are the force constants of bond and
angle terms, <italic>b</italic> and <italic>b</italic><sub>0</sub> are the actual and balanced bond lengths, while &#x003b8; and &#x003b8;<sub>0</sub> are the actual and balanced bond angles. A fourier style
potential was chosen to describe dihedral terms (<italic>E</italic><sub>dihedral</sub>)<disp-formula id="eq4"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_m004" position="anchor"/><label>4</label></disp-formula>where <italic>k</italic><sub>&#x003d5;<italic>i</italic></sub>, <italic>n</italic><sub><italic>i</italic></sub>, &#x003d5;, and <italic>d</italic><sub><italic>i</italic></sub> are
the force constants, scale factor, and actual and balanced dihedral
angels. To fix the nitro group planer, a harmonic improper term was
chosen for nitro groups (<italic>E</italic><sub>improper</sub>)<disp-formula id="eq5"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_m005" position="anchor"/><label>5</label></disp-formula>where <italic>k</italic><sub>&#x003c8;</sub> and &#x003c8; are the force constants and improper angle, and the
initial bonding parameters were obtained from Amber FF parameters.
In order to get reliable results, the bounds of parameters were set
to be 0.8&#x02013;1.2 of the initial parameters, and the evolutionary
algorithm was employed to optimize the parameters with minimization
of the following score function (<italic>E</italic><sub>score</sub>)<disp-formula id="eq6"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_m006" position="anchor"/><label>6</label></disp-formula>where <italic>K</italic> is
the slope determined by the linear fitting between the referenced
DFT energy <italic>E</italic><sub>ref</sub> and FF calculated energy <italic>E</italic><sub>FF</sub> with the optimizations at several structural
parameter constraints. The <italic>E</italic><sub>score</sub> can
be applied to balance between the slope and root mean square error.
It is worth noting that all improper force constants <italic>k</italic><sub>&#x003c8;</sub> were fixed at 1.12 kcal mol<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> rad<sup>&#x02013;2</sup> during the parameterization. In all DFT/MM
optimization and energy calculation were performed with Gaussian 09<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref48">48</xref></sup> and LAMMPS<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref49">49</xref></sup> packages.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.2"><label>2.2</label><title>MD Simulation</title><p>In our MD simulations,
the calculations were carried out with the <italic>NPT</italic> ensemble.
The time step length and cutoff distance of vdW interaction were set
to 0.5 fs and 12 &#x000c5;, respectively. In order to ensure that all
the edge lengths of the cell were at the least twice cutoff distance,
a bulk supercell of a 5 &#x000d7; 2 &#x000d7; 3 crystallographic unit cell
was used. All structure relaxations were performed for 100 ps from
0 to 20 GPa at 300 K. After equilibration at each pressure, atomic
configurations were recorded every 1000th step, and the last 20&#x02009;000
step trajectories were gathered. By statistical average, we obtained
the mean lattice parameters, atom coordinates, volume, center of mass,
etc. In addition, a gaseous molecular structure was also optimized
with the FF. All calculations in this part were implemented in the
LAMMPS program.</p></sec></sec><sec id="sec3"><label>3</label><title>Results</title><sec id="sec3.1"><label>3.1</label><title>Geometry in the Gaseous Phase</title><p>The LLM-105 molecule is a planar structure
with <italic>C</italic><sub><italic>2v</italic></sub> point group
symmetry in the gaseous phase. Thus, atom types were defined referring
to the chemical groups and their connections. <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>a shows the structural overlap between FF
and DFT. Overall, the structure from the FF is very similar with that
from DFT. In detail, <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref></xref> compares the structural parameters optimized at the PBE0/aug-cc-pVDZ
and fitted FF levels. Because of the planar structure, dihedral and
improper angles are not included. Obviously, the parameters from the
FF are in good agreement with those from DFT. The mean error (ME)
of bond lengths is about 0.006 &#x000c5;, and the ME of bond angles is
about 0.1&#x000b0;. The root mean squared error (RMSE) of bond lengths
and angels are 0.015 &#x000c5; and 1.0&#x000b0;. The maximum error (MAXE)
about bond lengths existing in the bond between C1 and N12 is about
0.20 &#x000c5;. Among bond angles, the MAXE is about 1.9&#x000b0; in the
angle C2&#x02013;N3&#x02013;C4.</p><fig id="fig2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Overlap for molecules from DFT and FF in the
gaseous phase (a);
a front (b) and a lateral view (c) from the experiment and FF in the
crystal form.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_0002" id="gr2" position="float"/></fig><table-wrap id="tbl1" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>Structural Parameters Optimized at
the DFT and FF Levels</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" border="0"><colgroup><col align="left"/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/></colgroup><thead><tr><th style="border:none;" align="center">structural parameters</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">DFT</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">FF</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">&#x00394;(FF&#x02013;DFT)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="4" style="border:none;" align="center"><bold>Bond Lengths
(&#x000c5;)</bold></td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(C1&#x02013;C2)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.419</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.402</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;0.018</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(C2&#x02013;N3)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.308</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.323</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.016</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(C1&#x02013;N12)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.371</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.391</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.020</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(C1&#x02013;N14)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.325</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.345</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.020</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(C2&#x02013;N6)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.459</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.464</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.005</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N14&#x02013;H19)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.015</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.025</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.010</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N14&#x02013;H18)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.010</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.022</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.013</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N6&#x02013;O8)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.233</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.224</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;0.009</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N6&#x02013;O7)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.206</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.221</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.015</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N12&#x02013;O13)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.290</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.275</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;0.015</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">ME</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.006</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">RMSE</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.015</td></tr><tr><td colspan="4" style="border:none;" align="center"><bold>Angles (deg)</bold></td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(H18&#x02013;N14&#x02013;H19)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">126.0</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">127.8</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.8</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C2&#x02013;C1&#x02013;N12)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">116.2</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">116.1</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;0.1</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C1&#x02013;N12&#x02013;C5)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">122.0</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">122.5</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.5</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(N3&#x02013;C2&#x02013;N6)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">116.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">116.8</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.5</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C2&#x02013;C1&#x02013;N14)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">129.5</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">130.2</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.7</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C1&#x02013;N14&#x02013;H19)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">115.4</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">113.9</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;1.5</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C1&#x02013;N14&#x02013;H18)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">118.6</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">118.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;0.3</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C2&#x02013;N3&#x02013;C4)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">119.5</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">121.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.9</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(N12&#x02013;C1&#x02013;N14)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">114.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">113.7</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;0.6</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C1&#x02013;C2&#x02013;N3)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">123.1</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">122.0</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;1.1</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(O7&#x02013;N6&#x02013;O8)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">125.0</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">123.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;1.6</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C2&#x02013;N6&#x02013;O7)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">118.5</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">119.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.8</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C2&#x02013;N6&#x02013;O8)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">116.5</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">117.3</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.8</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C1&#x02013;C2&#x02013;N6)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">120.6</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">121.2</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.6</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C1&#x02013;N12&#x02013;O13)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">119.0</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">118.8</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;0.3</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">ME</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.1</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">RMSE</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.0</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec id="sec3.2"><label>3.2</label><title>Lattice Structure</title><p>After the 200&#x02009;000
step <italic>NPT</italic> simulation, the equilibrium crystal structure
was obtained with averaging lattice parameters and atom coordinates
in last 20&#x02009;000 step trajectories. <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref> shows the overlap between simulated and
experimental structures. In the 15/15 similarity standard, the displacement
between two structures is calculated be 0.16 &#x000c5; by pymatgen,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref50">50</xref></sup> which reflects that the structure from the FF
is very similar with that from the experiment. <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">2</xref></xref> compares the lattice parameters based on
DFT,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> FF simulations,
and experimental measure.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref51">51</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref52">52</xref></sup> Compared to the experimental and DFT calculated
values, our FF gives a slightly smaller lattice cell. The lattice
parameters were predicted to be 5.64, 15.55, and 8.24 &#x000c5; for a,
b, and c axis, respectively. The lengths of a, b, and c decreases
by about 0.08, 0.30, and 0.18 &#x000c5;, or 1.4, 1.9, and 2.1%, respectively,
and the lattice angle &#x003b2; varies little, which is predicted to
be 100.96&#x000b0;. Because of the little shorter axis, the lattice volume
is reduced from 748 &#x000c5;<sup>3</sup> to 711 &#x000c5;<sup>3</sup>,
by about 5.0%. Although our FF gives a smaller volume, the molecular
position and orientation are in good agreement with the experimental
measurements.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> Because of the symmetry,
the position is described with the fraction coordinate of the centroid
of a chosen molecule, and the orientation is expressed with three
angles between <italic>x</italic>, <italic>y</italic>, and <italic>z</italic> axis and the vector from N3 to N4 on the molecule. In
the result from the FF, the position is predicted to be (0.560, 0.869,
and 0.549) for the molecule, which are very similar with (0.559, 0.867,
and 0.553) from the experiment.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> Also
the orientation angles are simulated to be (145.65, 67.38, and 114.38&#x000b0;),
which are consistent with those from experimental measures.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup></p><fig id="fig3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Overlap between simulated (normal color) and experimental
structures
(green).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_0003" id="gr3" position="float"/></fig><table-wrap id="tbl2" position="float"><label>Table 2</label><caption><title>Structural Parameters, Bulk Modulus
and Its Derivative of the LLM-105 Crystal from FF, DFT, and Experiments</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" border="0"><colgroup><col align="center"/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="center"/></colgroup><thead><tr><th style="border:none;" align="center">&#x000a0;</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">FF</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">LDA<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref></sup></th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">PW91<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref></sup></th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">PBE<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup></th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">PBE-D2<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup></th><th style="border:none;" align="center">EXP<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref51">51</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref52">52</xref></sup></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center"><italic>a</italic>&#x000a0;(&#x000c5;)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">5.64</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">5.84</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">6.01</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">5.64</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">5.81</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">5.71&#x02013;5.75</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center"><italic>b</italic>&#x000a0;(&#x000c5;)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">15.55</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">15.58</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">18.28</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">15.96</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">16.05</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">15.60&#x02013;15.87</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center"><italic>c</italic>&#x000a0;(&#x000c5;)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">8.24</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">8.22</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">8.71</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">8.46</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">8.40</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">8.41&#x02013;8.48</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center">&#x003b2;&#x000a0;(deg)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">100.96</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">99.51</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">100.75</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">100.93</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">101.01&#x02013;101.22</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center"><italic>V</italic><sub>0</sub> (&#x000c5;<sup>3</sup>)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">711.00</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">737.24</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">939.20</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">747.38</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">769.51</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">746.21&#x02013;750.08</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center">center
of mass</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.560</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">0.559</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.869</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">0.867</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.549</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">0.553</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center">orient (deg)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">145.65</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">145.65</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">67.38</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">67.38</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">114.38</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">114.38</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center"><italic>B</italic><sub>0</sub></td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">13.8</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">16.5</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">12.7</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">11.19&#x02013;16.2</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="center"><italic>B</italic>&#x02032;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">11.7</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x000a0;</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">9.4</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">9.4</td><td style="border:none;" align="center">8.30&#x02013;18.54</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Further, the charges in the molecular structure between
those predicted
by the FF and experimental measure<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> are
focused on. Because of crystal packing and HB formation, the symmetry
on molecular structures has been broken, and the molecule is not kept
with a planar structure longer. <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>b,c also gives a front view and a side lateral view
of the overlap structure. The structure from the FF is consistent
with that from the experiment.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup><xref rid="tbl3" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl3" ref-type="other">3</xref></xref> lists the main deformation
which is found around the interaction sites such as nitro and amino
groups. Apparently, the FF can also be applied to give similar molecular
structural parameters with the experimental values.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> The dihedral angle of C1&#x02013;C2&#x02013;N6&#x02013;O8
varied from 0.00&#x000b0; in gaseous to 18.82&#x000b0; in crystal phase,
and the FF gave an accurate prediction about the dihedral angle with
18.82&#x000b0; in the crystal. The other dihedral angle (D(N3&#x02013;C4&#x02013;N9&#x02013;O11))
about C&#x02013;NO<sub>2</sub> is estimated to be &#x02212;3.48&#x000b0;
by the FF and in good agreement with the experimental value.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> After the crystal packing, all N&#x02013;H
bonds are shortened to 0.860 &#x000c5; from 1.010 &#x000c5;, and the angles
of nitrogen atoms in amino groups increase to about 120&#x000b0;. Also
the bond N12&#x02013;O13 with the last hydrogen bond O13 bond is lengthened
from 1.275 to 1.321 &#x000c5;. The experimental values<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> of B(N&#x02013;H), A(H&#x02013;N&#x02013;H), and B(N12&#x02013;O13)
are 0.860 &#x000c5;, 120.01&#x000b0;, and 1.321 &#x000c5;, respectively.</p><table-wrap id="tbl3" position="float"><label>Table 3</label><caption><title>Structural Parameters Optimized at
the FF Levels and Experimental Values</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" border="0"><colgroup><col align="left"/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/><col align="char" char="."/></colgroup><thead><tr><th style="border:none;" align="center">structural parameter</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">EXP</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">FF</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">&#x00394;(FF-EXP)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="4" style="border:none;" align="center"><bold>Bond Lengths
(&#x000c5;)</bold></td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N15&#x02013;H16)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.860</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.860</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.000</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N15&#x02013;H17)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.860</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.860</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.000</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N14&#x02013;H18)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.860</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.860</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.000</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N14&#x02013;H19)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.860</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.860</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.000</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">B(N12&#x02013;O13)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.321</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">1.321</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.000</td></tr><tr><td colspan="4" style="border:none;" align="center"><bold>Bond Angles
(deg)</bold></td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C1&#x02013;N14&#x02013;H18)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">120.01</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">120.01</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;0.01</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C1&#x02013;N14&#x02013;H19)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">119.98</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">119.98</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.00</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(H18&#x02013;N14&#x02013;H19)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">120.01</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">120.01</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.01</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C5&#x02013;N15&#x02013;H16)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">120.00</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">120.01</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.00</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(C5&#x02013;N15&#x02013;H17)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">120.02</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">120.01</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.00</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">A(H16&#x02013;N15&#x02013;H17)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">119.98</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">119.98</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.00</td></tr><tr><td colspan="4" style="border:none;" align="center"><bold>Dihedral
Angles (deg)</bold></td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">D(C1&#x02013;C2&#x02013;N6&#x02013;O8)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">18.82</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">18.82</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.00</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">D(N3&#x02013;C2&#x02013;N6&#x02013;O8)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;159.43</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;159.43</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.00</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">D(C5&#x02013;C4&#x02013;N9&#x02013;O10)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;2.67</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;2.67</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.00</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">D(N3&#x02013;C4&#x02013;N9&#x02013;O11)</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;3.48</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">&#x02013;3.48</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.00</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Because of less charge in the molecule, the cell difference
between
the simulation and experiment should be attributed to the description
about the intermolecular interaction. <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref> shows four main dimer structures with the
great intermolecular interaction. <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>a,b is typical &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking
dimers, called &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;1 and &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;2,
respectively. In addition, <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>c,d shows doublet HB systems, marked with HB1 and HB2.
Three structural parameters are applied to compare the simulated and experimental
&#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking dimers:<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup> the distance between the two geometry centers of the six-member
rings (<italic>R</italic><sub>gc</sub>), the distance between the
two &#x003c0;-planes constructed by the six-member rings (<italic>R</italic><sub>pl</sub>), and the angle between the normal vector of a plane
and the vector from the center to the other (Anc). Overall, few differences
can be found on Anc, while both distances are shortened slightly.
In &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;1, the experimental <italic>R</italic><sub>gc</sub> and <italic>R</italic><sub>pl</sub> are 4.113 and 3.212
&#x000c5;, while the simulated ones are 3.960 and 3.096 &#x000c5;. The <italic>R</italic><sub>gc</sub> and <italic>R</italic><sub>pl</sub> were
decreased by 0.153 and 0.116 &#x000c5;, respectively. For &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;2
in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>b, the differences
on <italic>R</italic><sub>gc</sub> and <italic>R</italic><sub>pl</sub> were less with 0.102 and 0.052 &#x000c5;. Compared with the structures
with &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking, the HB dimers have slightly
larger structural charges as shown in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>c,d. Here, the length (<italic>R</italic><sub>HB</sub>) and angle (<italic>A</italic><sub>HB</sub>) of the
HB were applied to describe the HB dimer. The <italic>R</italic><sub>HB</sub> between H18(A) and O8(B) is shorten by 0.141 &#x000c5; and
that between O13(A) and H19(B) is decreased by 0.201 &#x000c5;. However,
the <italic>A</italic><sub>HB</sub> of N14&#x02013;H19&#x02013;O13 and
N14&#x02013;H18&#x02013;O8 varied little. Thus, one can conclude that
shorter equilibrium distances between molecules should contribute
to the smaller lattice crystal.</p><fig id="fig4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Four main dimer structures in intermolecular
interaction energy:
(a,b) dimers with &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking; (c,d) dimers with
hydrogen bonds. Estimated values are outside of parentheses, and experimental
values in the parentheses.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_0004" id="gr4" position="float"/></fig><p>Although the FF tends to give a smaller lattice
volume, we test
the FF estimation on pressure response of the crystal structure under
pressure in the range from 0 to 20 GPa. Additionally a series of <italic>NPT</italic> simulations were performed to obtain the equilibrium
crystal structure at the different pressures. Using the lattice parameters,
the density and relative density of LLM-105 under various pressures
are derived as shown in <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.9b02410/suppl_file/ao9b02410_si_001.pdf">Figure S4</ext-link>. The
density increases rapidly under low pressures (&#x0003c;3 GPa) and increases
slowly but in a nearly linear way under high pressures. The predicted
density and relative density are more or less greater than the measured
ones but the discrepancies are less than 0.2 g/cm<sup>3</sup> or 3.4%.
The pressure-dependent relative cell volumes and lattice parameters
are shown in <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>a,b, respectively, together with the results of the experimental
measurement and theoretical calculations. It is evident that the results
agree well with the experimental data and DFT calculations.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup> Similar with the experiment, the <italic>b</italic>-axis is more compressible than <italic>a</italic> and <italic>c</italic> axes when pressure is applied. The EOS is critical in describing
the properties of materials. Thus, we conducted unweighted fits of
the pressure&#x02013;volume data using a third-order Birch&#x02013;Murnaghan
(B&#x02013;M) EOS as follow<disp-formula id="eq7"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_m007" position="anchor"/><label>7</label></disp-formula>where, <italic>B</italic><sub>0</sub> is the
bulk modulus and <italic>B</italic>&#x02032; is the pressure derivative
of <italic>B</italic><sub>0</sub>, <italic>V</italic> is the volume
corresponding the pressure, and <italic>V</italic><sub>0</sub> is
the equilibrium volume at zero pressure. The fitted <italic>B</italic><sub>0</sub> and <italic>B</italic>&#x02032; from the FF are 13.8
GPa and 11.7, respectively, which are close to the experimental values
of 15 GPa and 9 in ref (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>) and 14.6 GPa and 10.6 in ref (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>). The <italic>B</italic><sub>0</sub> and <italic>B</italic>&#x02032; are also summarized in <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref></xref> and compared to the experimental and calculated values.
Apparently, the calculated results are in agreement with other experimental<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup> or other theoretical values.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> Compared with DFT estimations, the FF seem give a better prediction
on <italic>B</italic><sub>0</sub> and <italic>B</italic>&#x02032;.</p><fig id="fig5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Pressure-dependent
relative cell volumes (a) and lattice parameters
(b) from the FF, experiment, and DFT.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_0005" id="gr5" position="float"/></fig></sec></sec><sec id="sec4"><label>4</label><title>Discussion</title><p>The packing features of
a crystal can be expressed using a cluster.
As a crystal with <italic>P</italic>2<sub>1</sub>/<italic>n</italic> and <italic>Z</italic>&#x02032; = 1, the cluster contains a center
LLM-105 molecule and its 14 closed neighbors, which form 14 dimers
as shown in <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>. Further, 14 dimers can be divided into eight groups according to
the structure similarity. In <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref></xref>, the molecules with same color means the same dimer
can be constructed with one of them and the center molecule. <xref rid="tbl4" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl4" ref-type="other">4</xref></xref> lists the intermolecular
interaction energies of the dimers and the corresponding energy decomposition
with CE-B3LYP<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref53">53</xref></sup> based on the experimental
structure. In the energy decomposition scheme, the interaction energy (<italic>E</italic><sub>int</sub>) is expressed in terms of electrostatic (<italic>E</italic><sub>ele</sub>), polarization (<italic>E</italic><sub>pol</sub>),
dispersion (<italic>E</italic><sub>disp</sub>), and exchange-repulsion
(<italic>E</italic><sub>rep</sub>) as the following equation<disp-formula id="eq8"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_m008" position="anchor"/><label>8</label></disp-formula>where, <italic>k</italic><sub>i</sub> (i =
es, pol, disp, and rep) is the fitted scale factor for the corresponding
energy component. Because of the lack of explicit physical meanings,
total energies (<italic>E</italic><sub>tot</sub>) without any scale
factors were also provided in <xref rid="tbl4" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl4" ref-type="other">4</xref></xref>. Overall, &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking and the
HB should dominate the crystal packing. Among all dimers, &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;
stacking interactions are slightly stronger than those of the HB in
either <italic>E</italic><sub>tot</sub> or <italic>E</italic><sub>int</sub>. &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;1, &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;2, HB1,
and HB2 in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref> possess the greatest <italic>E</italic><sub>int</sub>. Although
the number of &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking dimers is less than
HBs, the overall <italic>E</italic><sub>tot</sub> of &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;
stacking is similar to that of HBs because of their greater strength.
From the energy decomposition, it is found that the interaction is
contributed mainly by the electrostatic and dispersion. The dispersion
effect plays a main role in &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking, while
the electrostatic term governs HB interaction.</p><fig id="fig6" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>LLM-105 molecule and
its close neighbors. The center molecule and
the same color neighbor can construct the same dimer in geometry.
14 neighbors can be divided into eight groups.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_0006" id="gr6" position="float"/></fig><table-wrap id="tbl4" position="float"><label>Table 4</label><caption><title>Intermolecular Interaction Energies
of the Neighbor Dimers and the Corresponding Energy Decomposion with
CE-B3LYP (kcal/mol)</title></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_0008" id="gr8" position="float"/></table-wrap><p>To analyze the discerption on intermolecular interaction
further,
the potential energy curves about the four main dimers are represented
in <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>. As a whole,
the FF can be used to give a similar description on no-bonding interaction
with that obtained at the PBE0-XDM/aug-cc-pVDZ level. Except HB2,
the equilibrium distances and well depths are in great agreement with
those by DFT. The curves of &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;2 from FF and DFT
are nearly overlapping, and the equilibrium distance of &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;2
should be shorter by less than 0.1 &#x000c5;, and the well depth of HB1
are increased by less than 0.6 kcal/mol. Although our FF can give
three reasonable curves, the greater error can be found on HB2. Obviously,
the equilibrium distance is decreased by about 0.2 &#x000c5;, which is
very similar with that in the crystal. Despite this, the curve from
the FF possesses a good shape like that from DFT as shown in <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref></xref>d. This might be
why our FF can give a good bulk modulus at the same time of obtaining
a smaller volume.</p><fig id="fig7" position="float"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>Potential energy curves from the FF and DFT for the four
main dimers:
(a,b) the dimers with &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking; (c,d) dimers
with hydrogen bonds.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_0007" id="gr7" position="float"/></fig><p>Moreover, the interaction with &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;
stacking
is stronger than that with HBs, which agrees with results from CE-B3LYP.
In &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0;1 and 2, the interaction energies with PBE0-XDM
are estimated to be &#x02212;11.53 and &#x02212;9.28 kcal/mol, respectively,
greater than the energy with the doublet HBs of &#x02212;8.05 kcal/mol.
The greater interaction energy prefers a greater weight during parameterization,
which might make the no-bonding parameters more suitable to describe
the &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; interaction. Because of the dominance by
the electrostatic effect, the description accuracy of HB interaction
should be dependent on the atomic charges. The atomic charges in the
FF were obtained referring to the gaseous molecular structure rather
than the structure in the crystal, and the effect of the crystal environment
on the electrostatic potential were ignored. Moreover, few atomic
types make a charge average. All of these might be responsible for
the poorer description on HB interaction. Nevertheless, the parameters
of the FF are obtained mainly from the unimolecular properties of
LLM-105 calculated by DFT, which should describe LLM-105 systems without
any preference. Overall, the FF with a general FF form can be applied
to investigate the properties of LLM-105.</p></sec><sec id="sec5"><label>5</label><title>Conclusions</title><p>We have developed an all-atom
FF for LLM-105 compounds. As a remarkable
energetic crystal, its fundamental properties have been focused on
using several ab initio methods but the FF. Considering the compatibility
of the force filed, a modified Amber function form was chosen for
describing the interaction in LLM-105, in which the BHK vdW potential
is used instead of the LJ potential. The electrostatic energy was
represented with the interaction among the RESP charges, and vdW parameters
were fitted using the potential energies of more than 1000 dimers
estimated at the PBE0/aug-cc-pVDZ level with the XDM dispersion correction.
Then, the bonding parameters were fitted from a series of perturbation
structures based on the equilibrium structure in the gas phase.</p><p>By the MD simulations, the molecular and crystal structures were
relaxed, and the pressure response of the lattice was predicted. All
results are in good agreement with the experimental measures. The
molecular structure from the FF is consistent with that from DFT.
Although the FF tends to give smaller lattice parameters, the structure,
orient, and relative position of the molecules in the crystal concur
with the experiment. Moreover, the bulk modulus and its pressure derivative
are predicted to be 13.8 GPa and 11.7, which are closer to the experimental
measure than several DFT results. Moreover, the packing features of
the LLM-105 crystal were analyzed with the intermolecular interaction
using an energy decomposition scheme. In LLM-105, the intermolecular
interaction is contributed mainly by the electrostatic and dispersion
effects. The &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking and HB dominate the crystal
packing, and &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; stacking dimers have greater strength
than HBs. We found that the FF will give a better equilibrium distance
of the &#x003c0;&#x02013;&#x003c0; system, but underestimate slightly on
the bond length of the HB. Because of the underestimation, the FF
tends to give a decreased volume by about 5%. The developed FF is
used to simulate the behaviors of neat LLM-105 under a shock. To predict
its detonation parameters, other FFs have to be developed for the
reactions and resulting products. In general, we provide a reliable
FF tool for the complicated phenomenon of LLM-105 at a large scale.</p></sec></body><back><notes id="notes1" notes-type="si"><title>Supporting Information Available</title><p>The Supporting Information is
available free of charge at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsomega.9b02410?goto=supporting-info">https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsomega.9b02410</ext-link>.<list id="silist" list-type="simple"><list-item><p>The fitted force field parameters of LLM-105, the test
results for the vdW parameters fitted in different bounds of FIT parameters,
the pressure-dependent relative cell volumes from the FF, experiment,
and DFT, and the structural parameters, bulk modulus and its derivative
of LLM-105 at different BKH parameters fitted with the bounds (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsomega.9b02410/suppl_file/ao9b02410_si_001.pdf">PDF</ext-link>)</p></list-item></list></p></notes><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="sifile1"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="ao9b02410_si_001.pdf"><caption><p>ao9b02410_si_001.pdf</p></caption></media></supplementary-material></sec><notes notes-type="COI-statement" id="NOTES-d7e2525-autogenerated"><p>The
authors declare no
competing financial interest.</p></notes><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>The authors thank financial support from the National
Natural Science Foundation of China (grant no. 21603203).</p></ack><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit1"><name><surname>Jadhav</surname><given-names>H. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Talawar</surname><given-names>M. B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sivabalan</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dhavale</surname><given-names>D. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Asthana</surname><given-names>S. N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Krishnamurthy</surname><given-names>V. N.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Synthesis, characterization and thermolysis studies
on new derivatives of 2,4,5-trinitroimidazoles: Potential insensitive
high energy materials</article-title>. <source>J. Hazard. Mater.</source>
<year>2007</year>, <volume>143</volume>, <fpage>192</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>197</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2006.09.014</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17097226</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit2"><name><surname>Koch</surname><given-names>E.-C.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Special
Materials in Pyrotechnics: V. Military Applications of Phosphorus
and its Compounds</article-title>. <source>Propellants, Explos., Pyrotech.</source>
<year>2008</year>, <volume>33</volume>, <fpage>165</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>176</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/prep.200700212</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit3"><name><surname>Christe</surname><given-names>K. O.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wilson</surname><given-names>W. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sheehy</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Boatz</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>N<sup>5+</sup>:
A Novel Homoleptic Polynitrogen Ion as a High Energy Density Material</article-title>. <source>Angew. Chem., Int. Ed.</source>
<year>1999</year>, <volume>38</volume>, <fpage>2004</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2009</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/(sici)1521-3773(19990712)38:13/14&#x0003c;2004::aid-anie2004&#x0003e;3.0.co;2-7</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit4"><name><surname>Kr&#x000f6;ber</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Teipel</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Crystallization of
Insensitive HMX</article-title>. <source>Propellants, Explos., Pyrotech.</source>
<year>2008</year>, <volume>33</volume>, <fpage>33</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>36</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/prep.200800205</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit5"><name><surname>Aminov</surname><given-names>Y. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gorshkov</surname><given-names>M. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zaikin</surname><given-names>V. T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kovalenko</surname><given-names>G. V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Nikitenko</surname><given-names>Y. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rykovanov</surname><given-names>G. N.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Deceleration of Detonation Products
of a TATB-Based High Explosive</article-title>. <source>Combust., Explos.
Shock Waves</source>
<year>2002</year>, <volume>38</volume>, <fpage>235</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>238</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1023/a:1014915302270</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit6"><name><surname>Sorescu</surname><given-names>D. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Boatz</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>D. L.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Classical
and Quantum-Mechanical
Studies of Crystalline FOX-7 (1,1-Diamino-2,2-dinitroethylene)</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. A</source>
<year>2001</year>, <volume>105</volume>, <fpage>5010</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5021</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jp010289m</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit7"><name><surname>Tarver</surname><given-names>C. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Urtiew</surname><given-names>P. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tran</surname><given-names>T. D.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Sensitivity
of 2,6-Diamino-3,5-Dinitropyrazine-1-Oxide</article-title>. <source>J. Energ. Mater.</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>23</volume>, <fpage>183</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>203</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/07370650591001853</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit8"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>An</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Geng</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Preparation and Properties
of An Insensitive Booster Explosive Based on LLM-105</article-title>. <source>Propellants, Explos., Pyrotech.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>38</volume>, <fpage>136</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>141</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/prep.201100099</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit9"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Nie</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Preparation and Properties of Submicrometer-Sized LLM-105
via Spray-Crystallization Method</article-title>. <source>Propellants,
Explos., Pyrotech.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>39</volume>, <fpage>653</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>657</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/prep.201300174</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit10"><name><surname>Gump</surname><given-names>J. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Stoltz</surname><given-names>C. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mason</surname><given-names>B. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Freedman</surname><given-names>B. G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ball</surname><given-names>J. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Peiris</surname><given-names>S. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Equations of state
of 2,6-diamino-3,5-dinitropyrazine-1-oxide</article-title>. <source>J. Appl. Phys.</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>110</volume>, <fpage>073523</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.3646492</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit11"><name><surname>Williamson</surname><given-names>D. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gymer</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>N. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Walley</surname><given-names>S. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jardine</surname><given-names>A. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Glauser</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>French</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wortley</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Characterisation of
the impact response of energetic materials: observation of a low-level
reaction in 2,6-diamino-3,5-dinitropyrazine-1-oxide (LLM-105)</article-title>. <source>RSC Adv.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>27896</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>27900</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c6ra03096c</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit12"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Pressure-
and Temperature-Dependent Structural Stability of LLM-105 Crystal</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>123</volume>, <fpage>1110</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1119</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.8b10837</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit13"><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>W.-D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>N.-B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tian</surname><given-names>A.-M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Long</surname><given-names>X.-P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Intramolecular
H-bonds in LLM-105 and its derivatives: a DFT study</article-title>. <source>J. Mol. Struct.: THEOCHEM</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>723</volume>, <fpage>217</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>222</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.theochem.2004.12.044</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit14"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiang</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>First-principles
study of the structural transformation,
electronic structure, and optical properties of crystalline 2,6-diamino-3,5-dinitropyrazine-1-oxide
under high pressure</article-title>. <source>J. Mol. Model.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>19</volume>, <fpage>5159</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5170</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00894-013-1995-5</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24105300</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit15"><name><surname>Manaa</surname><given-names>M. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kuo</surname><given-names>I. F. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fried</surname><given-names>L. E.</given-names></name>
<article-title>First-principles
high-pressure unreacted
equation of state and heat of formation of crystal 2,6-diamino-3,
5-dinitropyrazine-1-oxide (LLM-105)</article-title>. <source>J. Chem.
Phys.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>141</volume>, <fpage>064702</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.4891933</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25134585</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit16"><name><surname>Stavrou</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Manaa</surname><given-names>M. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zaug</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kuo</surname><given-names>I. F. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Pagoria</surname><given-names>P. F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kalkan</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Crowhurst</surname><given-names>J. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Armstrong</surname><given-names>M. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The high
pressure structure and equation of state of 2,6-diamino-3,5-dinitropyrazine-1-oxide
(LLM-105) up to 20 GPa: X-ray diffraction measurements and first principles
molecular dynamics simulations</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>143</volume>, <fpage>144506</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.4932683</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26472388</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit17"><name><surname>Zong</surname><given-names>H.-H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>W.-B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>S.-L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Structural, mechanical properties, and vibrational spectra of LLM-105
under high pressures from a first-principles study</article-title>. <source>J. Mol. Model.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>23</volume>, <fpage>275</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00894-017-3446-1</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28891015</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit18"><name><surname>Bergh</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Caleman</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A Validation study
of the general Amber force field
applied to energetic molecular crystals</article-title>. <source>J.
Energ. Mater.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>34</volume>, <fpage>62</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>75</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/07370652.2014.998797</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit19"><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>H. M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Comparative
study on structure, energetic and mechanical properties of a &#x003b5;-CL-20/HMX
cocrystal and its composite with molecular dynamics simulation</article-title>. <source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>2</volume>, <fpage>13898</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>13904</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c4ta01150c</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit20"><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>G. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bharadwaj</surname><given-names>R. K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Quantum
Chemistry Based Force Field for Simulations
of HMX</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. B</source>
<year>1999</year>, <volume>103</volume>, <fpage>3570</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3575</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jp984599p</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit21"><name><surname>Mathew</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sewell</surname><given-names>T. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>D. L.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Anisotropy in surface-initiated melting
of the triclinic molecular crystal 1,3,5-triamino-2,4,6-trinitrobenzene:
A molecular dynamics study</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2015</year>, <volume>143</volume>, <fpage>094706</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.4929806</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26342382</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref22"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit22"><name><surname>Misquitta</surname><given-names>A. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jeziorski</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Szalewicz</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Dispersion Energy from Density-Functional
Theory Description of Monomers</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source>
<year>2003</year>, <volume>91</volume>, <fpage>033201</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/physrevlett.91.033201</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12906414</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref23"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit23"><name><surname>Misquitta</surname><given-names>A. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Szalewicz</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Intermolecular forces from asymptotically
corrected
density functional description of monomers</article-title>. <source>Chem. Phys. Lett.</source>
<year>2002</year>, <volume>357</volume>, <fpage>301</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>306</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/s0009-2614(02)00533-x</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref24"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit24"><name><surname>Misquitta</surname><given-names>A. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Szalewicz</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Symmetry-adapted
perturbation-theory calculations of
intermolecular forces employing density-functional description of
monomers</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>122</volume>, <fpage>214109</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.1924593</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15974730</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref25"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit25"><name><surname>He&#x000df;elmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jansen</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>
<article-title>First-order
intermolecular interaction energies from
Kohn-Sham orbitals</article-title>. <source>Chem. Phys. Lett.</source>
<year>2002</year>, <volume>357</volume>, <fpage>464</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>470</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/s0009-2614(02)00538-9</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref26"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit26"><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Correlated
intermolecular interaction
components from asymptotically corrected Kohn-Sham orbitals</article-title>. <source>Sci. China, Ser. B: Chem.</source>
<year>2004</year>, <volume>47</volume>, <fpage>466</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>479</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1360/04yb0078</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref27"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit27"><name><surname>Podeszwa</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bukowski</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rice</surname><given-names>B. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Szalewicz</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Potential
energy surface for cyclotrimethylene trinitramine dimer from symmetry-adapted
perturbation theory</article-title>. <source>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2007</year>, <volume>9</volume>, <fpage>5561</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5569</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/b709192c</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17957312</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref28"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit28"><name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>D. E.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Intermolecular
Forces and Molecular Dynamics Simulation of 1,3,5-Triamino-2,4,6-trinitrobenzene
(TATB) Using Symmetry Adapted Perturbation Theory</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. A</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>117</volume>, <fpage>3507</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3520</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jp4005289</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23565605</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref29"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit29"><name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>D.
E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rob</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rice</surname><given-names>B. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Podeszwa</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Szalewicz</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A molecular
dynamics study of 1,1-diamino-2,2-dinitroethylene (FOX-7) crystal
using a symmetry adapted perturbation theory-based intermolecular
force field</article-title>. <source>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>13</volume>, <fpage>16629</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>16636</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c1cp21342c</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21860866</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref30"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit30"><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>H.-J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>F.-L.</given-names></name>
<article-title>All-atom,
non-empirical, and tailor-made force field for &#x003b1;-RDX from first
principles</article-title>. <source>RSC Adv.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>4</volume>, <fpage>40518</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>40533</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c4ra07195f</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref31"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit31"><name><surname>Macrae</surname><given-names>C. F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Edgington</surname><given-names>P. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>McCabe</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Pidcock</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shields</surname><given-names>G. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Towler</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>van de Streek</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Mercury: visualization
and analysis of crystal structures</article-title>. <source>J. Appl.
Crystallogr.</source>
<year>2006</year>, <volume>39</volume>, <fpage>453</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>457</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/s002188980600731x</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref32"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit32"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.-J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.-L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Synthesis,
Crystal structure and
catalytic properties of two energetic complexes containing 2,6-diamino-3,5-dinitropyrazine-1-oxide</article-title>. <source>Chin. J. Inorg. Chem.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>696</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>704</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref33"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit33"><name><surname>Perdew</surname><given-names>J. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Burke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ernzerhof</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Generalized Gradient Approximation
Made Simple</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source>
<year>1996</year>, <volume>77</volume>, <fpage>3865</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3868</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/physrevlett.77.3865</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10062328</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref34"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit34"><name><surname>Dunning</surname><given-names>T. H.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Gaussian
basis sets for use in correlated molecular calculations. I. The atoms
boron through neon and hydrogen</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>1989</year>, <volume>90</volume>, <fpage>1007</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1023</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.456153</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref35"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit35"><name><surname>Becke</surname><given-names>A. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>E. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A density-functional model of the dispersion interaction</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>123</volume>, <fpage>154101</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.2065267</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16252936</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref36"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit36"><name><surname>Becke</surname><given-names>A. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>E. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Exchange-hole dipole
moment and the dispersion interaction</article-title>. <source>J. Chem.
Phys.</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>122</volume>, <fpage>154104</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.1884601</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15945622</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref37"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit37"><name><surname>Becke</surname><given-names>A. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>E. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Exchange-hole dipole moment and the dispersion interaction
revisited</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2007</year>, <volume>127</volume>, <fpage>154108</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.2795701</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17949133</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref38"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit38"><name><surname>&#x000c1;ngy&#x000e1;n</surname><given-names>J. G.</given-names></name>
<article-title>On the
exchange-hole model of London dispersion forces</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2007</year>, <volume>127</volume>, <fpage>024108</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.2749512</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17640120</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref39"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit39"><name><surname>He&#x000df;elmann</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Derivation
of the dispersion energy as an explicit density- and exchange-hole
functional</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2009</year>, <volume>130</volume>, <fpage>084104</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.3077939</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19256594</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref40"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit40"><name><surname>Otero-de-la-Roza</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>E. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A benchmark for non-covalent interactions in solids</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Phys.</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>137</volume>, <fpage>054103</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.4738961</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22894328</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref41"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit41"><name><surname>Whittleton</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Otero-de-la-Roza</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>E. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Exchange-Hole Dipole Dispersion Model
for Accurate Energy Ranking in Molecular Crystal Structure Prediction</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Theory Comput.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>13</volume>, <fpage>441</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>450</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jctc.6b00679</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27977188</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref42"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit42"><name><surname>LeBlanc</surname><given-names>L. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Otero-de-la-Roza</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>E. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Composite and Low-Cost Approaches
for Molecular Crystal Structure Prediction</article-title>. <source>J. Chem. Theory Comput.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>14</volume>, <fpage>2265</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2276</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jctc.7b01179</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29498837</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref43"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit43"><name><surname>Rice</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>LeBlanc</surname><given-names>L. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Otero-de-la-Roza</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fuchter</surname><given-names>M. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>E. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Nelson</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jelfs</surname><given-names>K. E.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A computational exploration of the
crystal energy and charge-carrier mobility landscapes of the chiral
[6]helicene molecule</article-title>. <source>Nanoscale</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>10</volume>, <fpage>1865</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1876</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c7nr08890f</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29313040</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref44"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit44"><name><surname>Case</surname><given-names>D. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheatham</surname><given-names>T. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Darden</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gohlke</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Merz</surname><given-names>K. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Onufriev</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Simmerling</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Woods</surname><given-names>R. J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The Amber biomolecular simulation
programs</article-title>. <source>J. Comput. Chem.</source>
<year>2005</year>, <volume>26</volume>, <fpage>1668</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1688</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcc.20290</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16200636</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref45"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit45"><name><surname>Bayly</surname><given-names>C. I.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cieplak</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cornell</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kollman</surname><given-names>P. A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A well-behaved electrostatic
potential based method using charge restraints for deriving atomic
charges: the RESP model</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem.</source>
<year>1993</year>, <volume>97</volume>, <fpage>10269</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>10280</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/j100142a004</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref46"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit46"><name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>D. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cox</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Nonbonded potentials for azahydrocarbons:
the importance
of the Coulombic interaction</article-title>. <source>Acta Crystallogr.,
Sect. B: Struct. Sci.</source>
<year>1984</year>, <volume>40</volume>, <fpage>404</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>417</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/s010876818400238x</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref47"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit47"><name><surname>Cox</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hsu</surname><given-names>L.-Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>D. E.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Nonbonded
potential function models
for crystalline oxohydrocarbons</article-title>. <source>Acta Crystallogr.,
Sect. A: Cryst. Phys., Diffr., Theor. Gen. Crystallogr.</source>
<year>1981</year>, <volume>37</volume>, <fpage>293</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>301</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/s0567739481000703</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref48"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit48"><name><surname>Rayne</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Forest</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Performance of Gaussian-3 and Gaussian-4
level theoretical
methods in estimating gas phase enthalpies of formation for representative
and chlorofluorocarbons and hydrochlorofluorocarbons</article-title>. <source>J. Mol. Struct.: THEOCHEM</source>
<year>2010</year>, <volume>953</volume>, <fpage>47</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>48</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.theochem.2010.04.031</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref49"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit49"><name><surname>Plimpton</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Fast Parallel
Algorithms for Short-Range Molecular Dynamics</article-title>. <source>J. Comput. Phys.</source>
<year>1995</year>, <volume>117</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>19</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1006/jcph.1995.1039</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref50"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit50"><name><surname>Ong</surname><given-names>S. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Richards</surname><given-names>W. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jain</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hautier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kocher</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cholia</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gunter</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chevrier</surname><given-names>V. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Persson</surname><given-names>K. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ceder</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Python Materials Genomics
(pymatgen): A robust, open-source python
library for materials analysis</article-title>. <source>Comput. Mater.
Sci.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>68</volume>, <fpage>314</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>319</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.commatsci.2012.10.028</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref51"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit51"><name><surname>Gilardi</surname><given-names>R. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Butcher</surname><given-names>R. J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>2,6-Diamino-3,5-dinitro-1,4-pyrazine
dimethyl sulfoxide
solvate</article-title>. <source>Acta Crystallogr., Sect. E: Struct.
Rep. Online</source>
<year>2001</year>, <volume>57</volume>, <fpage>o757</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>o759</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1107/s1600536801014131</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref52"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit52"><name><surname>Averkiev</surname><given-names>B. B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Antipin</surname><given-names>M. Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yudin</surname><given-names>I. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sheremetev</surname><given-names>A. B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>X-ray structural
study of three derivatives of dinitropyrazine</article-title>. <source>J. Mol. Struct.</source>
<year>2002</year>, <volume>606</volume>, <fpage>139</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>146</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/s0022-2860(01)00862-6</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref53"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit53"><name><surname>Turner</surname><given-names>M. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Grabowsky</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jayatilaka</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Spackman</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Accurate and Efficient
Model Energies for Exploring Intermolecular Interactions in Molecular
Crystals</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>5</volume>, <fpage>4249</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4255</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jz502271c</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26273970</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>