<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Phosphor-converted light-emitting diodes (pc-LEDs) have been emerging as indispensable solid state light sources because of their unique merits such as energy savings, environment-friendliness, small footprint, long operational lifetime, and so on.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> However, the deficiency of far-red light components limits LEDs applications in natural light sources, plant cultivation, phototherapy, and so on.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> Typically, rare-earth (RE) ions like Eu
 <sup>3+</sup>, Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>, Pr
 <sup>3+</sup>, and Sm
 <sup>3+</sup> are doped as activators into numerous hosts for red/far-red emissions under ultraviolet (UV) or blue excitation,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup> but the wide applications are limited by the following features: (i) Eu
 <sup>3+</sup>, Pr
 <sup>3+</sup>, and Sm
 <sup>3+</sup> ions feature intra-4f parity-forbidden electronic transitions which have relatively weak absorption and therefore a low external quantum yield (QY);
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> (ii) Eu
 <sup>2+</sup> has an allowed 4f
 <sup>7</sup> → 4f
 <sup>6</sup>5d
 <sup>1</sup> transition with about 1000 times larger absorption than the intra-4f parity-forbidden transitions, but nearly all Eu
 <sup>2+</sup>-doped red/far-red phosphors exhibit a relatively low external QY ≤ 70%.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref>
 </sup> Besides, RE elements have additional issues due to potential supply risk and high cost, and hence non-RE activated phosphors become extremely important and currently arouse great interest.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> Moreover, the recent commercial success of potassium fluorosilicate-based phosphors (K
 <sub>2</sub>SiF
 <sub>6</sub>:Mn
 <sup>4+</sup>) in LED applications has spurred new interest in the properties of non-oxide materials.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref>
 </sup> The manganese(IV) system has shown that peak emission wavelengths can be broadly modified when moving from an oxide system to a fluoride system.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
