<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the current work, we systematically studied the structural configuration of the full Heusler compounds Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiSi and Ni
 <sub>2</sub>FeSi by employing the first-principles calculations based on density functional theory, in terms of the structural, electronic and magnetic properties. Besides, the effects of uniform and tetragonal strains have been also considered and discussed. Results show that both Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiSi and Ni
 <sub>2</sub>FeSi prefer XA-type atomic ordering rather than L2
 <sub>1</sub>-type in cubic phase due to the lower total energy. The obtained lattice constants agree with previous experimental and theoretical studies. Both Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiSi and Ni
 <sub>2</sub>FeSi show metallic band structures and large magnetic moments (greater than 3
 <italic>μ</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>B</italic>
 </sub>) at equilibrium condition. Under tetragonal distortion, total energy can be further decreased, leading to the possible phase transformation, but different atom site reordering behaviours have been observed: for Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiSi, tetragonal L1
 <sub>0</sub> structure has smaller total energy than tetragonal XA structure at 100% unit cell volume, which implies that atoms reorder from cubic XA-type to tetragonal L1
 <sub>0</sub>-type; for Ni
 <sub>2</sub>FeSi, the XA structure always has the lowest total energy, which means there is only structural transformation without atom reordering. This atom reordering behaviour under tetragonal phase transformation is very interesting and can open up a variation of studies for material property under distortion conditions. The total magnetic moments of Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiSi and Ni
 <sub>2</sub>FeSi are mainly contributed by Fe atoms, and Si atom can strongly suppress the moments of Fe atoms when Si atom is present in the nearest neighbours of Fe atoms. With strain applied, the distance between Fe and Si atoms plays an important role for the magnetic moment variation of Fe atom. Moreover, the metallic band structure is maintained for Fe
 <sub>2</sub>NiSi and Ni
 <sub>2</sub>FeSi under both uniform and tetragonal strains. Overall, this study provides a detailed theoretical analysis and can give valuable reference for further experimental research.
</p>
