<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0070">All of the results of the optical spectra match generally weak dozy chaos (
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M9" altimg="si7.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>γ</mi>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">&lt;</mo>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">&lt;</mo>
    <mi>E</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>, where 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M10" altimg="si8.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>E</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> is the so-called reorganization energy introduced in Section 
 <xref rid="sec2.4.1" ref-type="sec">2.4.1</xref>). Strong dozy chaos (
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M11" altimg="si9.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>γ</mi>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">≥</mo>
    <mi>E</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>) leads to the elucidation of the important patterns in the reactions of proton transfer [
 <xref rid="bib45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib47" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>] and comparatively fresh temperature-dependent effects on electron transfers in Langmuir-Blodgett films [
 <xref rid="bib20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>]. In the case of strong dozy chaos, the dynamics of quantum-classical transitions become weakly dependent on dozy chaos, and the electronic component of the complete electron-nuclear amplitude of transitions can be fitted by the Gamow tunnel exponential dependent on the transient phonon environment. This elementary method permit us to evade the consideration of the imaginary additive 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M12" altimg="si1.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>i</mi>
    <mi>γ</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> in the spectral representation of the complete Green's function and to word the physical nature of the transient state not in the concept of dozy chaos, but in the concept of a large number of tunnel and over-barrier energy states providing the “quantum” transition of an elementary charged particle. This method was worked out [
 <xref rid="bib52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>] long before the development of quantum-classical mechanics [
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>] (see the subsequent sections), and now we can say that the concept of a large number of tunnel and over-barrier states is the simplest version of the concept of dozy chaos.
</p>
