<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0020">A new theoretical approach to study of molecular quantum transitions and elementary electron transfers in condensed matter can be attributed accordingly to molecular and chemical physics. We call this new approach in theory dozy-chaos mechanics, or in another way, quantum-classical mechanics. The introduction of quantum-classical (dozy-chaos) mechanics into molecular and chemical physics has a forced character and is associated with the elimination of an essential singularity in the probabilities per unit time, or in other words, in the rate constants of quantum transitions in molecular systems. This singularity arises in quantum mechanics when it goes beyond the adiabatic approximation and follows from the incomparability of the masses of the electron (electrons) and nuclei and their joint motion in the process of molecular quantum transitions. The singularity is eliminated by changing the infinitesimal imaginary addition 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M1" altimg="si1.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>i</mi>
    <mi>γ</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> in the spectral representation of the complete molecular Green's function with its finite quantity [
 <xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. The matching of the new theory with experiments shows that the modulus of this imaginary addition 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M2" altimg="si2.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>γ</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> is much more than the quantum of nuclear oscillations 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M3" altimg="si3.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>ℏ</mi>
    <mi>ω</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>: 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M4" altimg="si4.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>γ</mi>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">&gt;</mo>
    <mo linebreak="goodbreak" linebreakstyle="after">&gt;</mo>
    <mi>ℏ</mi>
    <mi>ω</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> [
 <xref rid="bib14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. The value of 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M5" altimg="si2.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>γ</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula> could be treated as the energy width of the electron-vibrational virtual levels of the transient state, which provides a multiple exchange of motion and energy between different vibrational modes of the nuclei and the electron in the transient state. However, because of the aforementioned excessively large value of 
 <inline-formula>
  <math id="M6" altimg="si2.svg">
   <mrow>
    <mi>γ</mi>
   </mrow>
  </math>
 </inline-formula>, this exchange of motion and energy proves to be crash, and it causes chaos in the motion of both the nuclei and the electron that undergoes the transition. Since this chaos is absent in the initial and final states and present merely in the middle of molecular quantum transitions, it is called dozy chaos [
 <xref rid="bib14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>]. In chemical physics, the efficacy of the damping method for the aforementioned singularity was shown by the author with an example of the new (dozy-chaos) theory of elementary electron-charge transfers in condensed matter and its applications [
 <xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>] to the optical spectra in polymethine dyes and their aggregates [
 <xref rid="bib37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib44" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>] and its applications [
 <xref rid="bib20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>] to a number of other basic experimental data [
 <xref rid="bib46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib47" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>].
</p>
