<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Double perovskite RBaCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>6-
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> (R = Y, La–Ho: rare earth elements, 0 ≤ 
 <italic>x</italic> ≤ 1) has been investigated because of its various properties such as complicated magnetic structures, metal–insulator transition, and fast oxygen diffusion.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
 </sup> Experiments have shown that cobalt 3d spin ordering and oxygen vacancy formation play a key role in the emergence of the properties, but understanding of their impact on the properties is still quite limited. Regarding PrBaCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>5.5</sub>, a neutron and synchrotron experiment study
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> observed cobalt ions at the center of the oxygen octahedra (Co
 <sub>Oct</sub>) with the high spin (HS) state (
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2g</sub>
 <sup arrange="stack">4</sup>
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>g</italic>
 </sub>
 <sup arrange="stack">2</sup>, 
 <italic>S</italic> = 2) and a spin transition to the low spin (LS) state (
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2g</sub>
 <sup arrange="stack">6</sup>
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub>
 <sup arrange="stack">0</sup>, 
 <italic>S</italic> = 0) at high temperature, while cobalt spin state inside the oxygen pyramids (Co
 <sub>Py</sub>) remains in the intermediate spin (IS) state (
 <italic>t</italic>
 <sub>2g</sub>
 <sup arrange="stack">5</sup>
 <italic>e</italic>
 <sub>g</sub>
 <sup arrange="stack">1</sup>, 
 <italic>S</italic> = 1). This leads to an antiferromagnetic-to-ferromagnetic transition at 215 K and a ferromagnetic-to-paramagnetic transition at 245 K. Zhang et al. also found such magnetic phase transitions at 145 and 195 K in PrBaCo
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>5.5</sub> and proposed the temperature-induced spin transition of cobalt from IS to HS.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
 </sup> Another neutron diffraction study reported the absence of ferromagnetic ordering and observed an antiferromagnetic-to-ferrimagnetic transition at 237 K and a ferrimagnetic-to-paramagnetic transition at 255 K.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> This study suggests that the spin states of Co
 <sub>Oct</sub> and Co
 <sub>Py</sub> are, respectively, the mixed HS–IS and the mixed IS–LS states below 340 K; those acquire the IS state at higher temperature.
</p>
