<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="fig5" position="float">
 <label>Figure 5</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Dependence of TO and E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> modes on TSL period. (a) Calculated (open circles) and experimental (filled circles) frequencies of TO mode in the 
   <italic>x̅</italic>(
   <italic>zz</italic>)
   <italic>x</italic> configuration for GaP ZB, WZ, and TSL expressed as absolute shifts from the calculated and experimental ZB TO mode. The error bar of experimental frequencies is ±0.1 cm
   <sup>–1</sup> (smaller than the absolute error given by the spectral resolution, which is equal to 0.5 cm
   <sup>–1</sup>) because the data were acquired with the same experimental alignment. The dashed gray curve was obtained from a model computing the spectra in TSL as a linear combination of the ZB and WZ phases, weighting each contribution by the corresponding volume ratio: the total volume of one period 
   <italic>V</italic>
   <sub>tot</sub> is the NW cross section times the period of the TSL; the volume of the WZ 
   <italic>V</italic>
   <sub>wz</sub> is equal to the NW cross section times 2
   <italic>c</italic>, where 
   <italic>c</italic> is the thickness of an AB segment and 2 is the number of twin defects in every period; the volume of the ZB is derived by difference, 
   <italic>V</italic>
   <sub>tot</sub> – 
   <italic>V</italic>
   <sub>WZ</sub>. The inset shows the difference between the theoretical and experimental data and the gray curve (open circles and filled circles, respectively). (b) Calculated (open triangles) and experimental (filled triangles) intensity of the E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> mode in the 
   <italic>x̅</italic>(
   <italic>yy</italic>)
   <italic>x</italic> configuration for GaP ZB, WZ, and TSL. To allow a fair comparison, because the Raman intensity is not absolute we have rescaled the experimental intensities so that the experimental E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> mode intensity of the NW with the 9 nm period matches the calculated one, as in 
   <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure 
    <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>
   </xref>d. The dashed gray curve is the E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> mode intensity obtained with the weighted model. The inset shows the theoretical and experimental E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> frequency with respect to the WZ E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> frequency as a function of TSL period. The dashed gray curve represents the E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> frequency shift provided by the weighted model.
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="nl-2019-01775a_0005" id="gr5" position="float" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
