<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="fig3" position="float">
 <label>Figure 3</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Tunability of the phononic properties in twin superlattices. (a) Calculated spectra of a GaP TSL with 4 nm (open stars and blue solid line) and 9 nm (open triangles and cyan solid line) period length. (b) Measured spectrum of a GaP TSL nanowire with ∼9 nm period length. Deconvoluted components of the data fitting are displayed (E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> mode in black dashed line, TO, SO, and LO modes in gray solid line). (c) Measured spectrum of a GaP TSL nanowire with ∼12.5 nm period length. Deconvoluted components of the data fitting are displayed. The intensity scales of the spectra in (b,c) are directly comparable. (d) Intensity vs wavenumbers of the calculated (empty symbols) and measured (filled symbols) phonon modes arising from the SL from the spectra displayed in panels a–c. Colors refer to the corresponding period length. Stars are for 2L = 4 nm, triangles are for 2L = 9 nm, circles are for 2L = 12.5 nm, as summarized in the legend. Vertical dashed lines show the good agreement between calculated and experimental phonon frequencies of the TSL with period of 9 nm. This is also evident in 
   <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">Table 
    <xref rid="tbl2" ref-type="other">2</xref>
   </xref>. The blue diamond refers to data acquired on a NW with ∼26 nm period length. All theoretical and experimental spectra were obtained in the 
   <italic>x̅</italic>(
   <italic>yy</italic>)
   <italic>x</italic> configuration. In order to allow a fair comparison, all calculated and experimental frequencies are expressed as frequency shifts from the TO mode of the relative sample. Similarly, we have rescaled all the experimental intensities so that the E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> mode intensity retrieved experimentally on NW with the 9 nm period matches the E
   <sub>2</sub>
   <sup arrange="stack">H</sup> intensity calculated for a TSL with the same period.
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="nl-2019-01775a_0003" id="gr3" position="float" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
