<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Studies on the gram-negative bacteria 
 <italic>Aeromonas</italic> species, which are ubiquitous worldwide in water bodies, have mostly focused on pathogen species associated with fish and human infections [
 <xref rid="B1-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. However, very few studies have investigated the biosynthetic capacity of this group of microorganisms. The presence of secondary metabolites has been recognized in various 
 <italic>Aeromonas</italic> species [
 <xref rid="B2-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>] such as 
 <italic>Aeromonas hydrophila</italic>, in which GC-MS analysis suggests the presence of 23 antifungal bioactive compounds [
 <xref rid="B3-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. 
 <italic>Aeromonas salmonicida</italic> subsp. 
 <italic>achromogenes</italic> strain NY4, on the other hand, exhibits the capacity to oxidize phenanthrene and to produce a large number of resulting degradation products [
 <xref rid="B4-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. In a recent study we showed interspecies interactions between the non-pathogenic 
 <italic>Aeromonas veronii</italic> and a toxic cyanobacterium in a fresh body lake, implicating secondary metabolites in the cross-talk between these organisms. Enhanced lumichrome production by 
 <italic>A. veronii</italic> in response to the presence of culture media from the toxic cyanobacterium 
 <italic>Microcystis aeruginosa</italic> strain MGK and inhibition of MGK growth by applications of pure lumichrome implicated this metabolite in the cross-talk between these two microorganisms [
 <xref rid="B5-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. Analysis of its genome (accession no. PRJNA508461) using AntiSMASH [
 <xref rid="B6-metabolites-09-00110" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>] identified genes potentially encoding two unknown bacteriocins (ctg42_4, location: 1838–2506; ctg86_35, location: 34489–35346) and a gene cluster likely encoding a non-ribosomal peptide synthetase (ctg90_3, location: 1480–8956). Our present study aimed to identify novel secondary metabolites from 
 <italic>A. veronii</italic> strain A134, which yielded, among others, three new metabolites—9-chlorolumichrome (
 <bold>1</bold>), veronimide (
 <bold>2</bold>) and veronipyrazine (
 <bold>3</bold>) (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="metabolites-09-00110-f001">Figure 1</xref>). The structure elucidation of the new metabolites and their possible biogenesis are discussed below.
</p>
