<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>From the 1960s, works of Wolkestein [
 <xref rid="B1-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>] state the importance of electron theory to elucidate the relation between the catalytic and electronic properties of a catalyst and also the semiconductor nature of this type of material. Swaminathan [
 <xref rid="B2-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>] produced research about the opportunities and ways to improve catalyst technology, specifically in their development, cost reduction, and field applications [
 <xref rid="B2-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Among the catalysts, semiconductors such as TiO
 <sub>2</sub>, ZnO, and SnO
 <sub>2</sub> play a pivotal role, as they can use the electromagnetic spectra to degrade contaminants [
 <xref rid="B3-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. It has been reported that these semiconductor oxides also have acidic and basic natures [
 <xref rid="B2-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Therefore, they are useful as both solid acid and base catalysts. For this reason, efforts to develop new, cheaper, active, and selective catalysts are ongoing. Manganese oxides are among the most extensively studied raw, supported, or doped catalysts [
 <xref rid="B5-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="B6-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B8-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B10-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]; however, their electrical properties have been less studied [
 <xref rid="B12-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="B13-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>,
 <xref rid="B14-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. The family of the manganese oxide type of materials have variations in their structure depending on the way the Mn–O is linked together [
 <xref rid="B15-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Therefore, layer, tunnel, spinel, and compact structures can be found. Manganese oxides have also been used as a cathode in secondary batteries [
 <xref rid="B16-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Manganese, as a central atom in the octahedral coordination in these structures, mainly has the 4+ and 3+ oxidation states. However, average oxidations states of 3.5 and 3.8 are commonly found because of the presence of Mn
 <sup>4+</sup> and Mn
 <sup>3+</sup> in the same building blocks [
 <xref rid="B18-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. Birnessite is a special structure of this manganese oxide family. It is composed of Mn–O octahedra forming octahedral layers as clays, and it has monovalent or divalent ions surrounded by water molecules to compensate the electrical charge of its layers. Therefore, these monovalent or divalent cations are located in the region called the interlayer [
 <xref rid="B9-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B12-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. The cations in the interlayer region can be displaced by other species because of their mobile nature. Birnessite has been used in previous works as a catalyst in soot combustion processes and in methylene blue degradation, showing appreciable catalytic activity compared to traditional catalysts [
 <xref rid="B9-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="B11-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="B19-nanomaterials-09-01156" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. For this reason, the present work focuses on the charge transport mechanism for two birnessite material types, Mn4 and Mn8, synthesized at 400 and 800 °C, respectively, with the intention for a deeper understanding of the nature of this type of material for advanced applications.
</p>
