<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>One of the key questions addressed in the first pilot experiment was whether mapping of the electronic structure using 
 <italic>k</italic>-microscopy works in the hard X-ray range. Although valence-band features had been observed at high X-ray energies (Claesson 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2004
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb8"> ▸</xref>; Kamakura 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2004
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb28"> ▸</xref>; Sekiyama 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2004
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb65"> ▸</xref>; Plucinski 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2008
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb57"> ▸</xref>; Papp 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2011
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb56"> ▸</xref>; Gray 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2011
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb23"> ▸</xref>, 2012
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb24"> ▸</xref>; Keqi 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb31"> ▸</xref>; Nemšák 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb48"> ▸</xref>; Sato 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb58"> ▸</xref>; Kobayashi 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2014
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb33"> ▸</xref>), it seemed that they are strongly masked by quasi-elastic phonon scattering. The background of such electrons exhibits a characteristic spectral distribution given by the ‘matrix-element weighted density of states’ (Osterwalder 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1990
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb51"> ▸</xref>, 1996
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb52"> ▸</xref>; Herman 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 1992
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb26"> ▸</xref>). The point where density-of-states information dominates over direct transitions (termed XPS limit) was explored theoretically (Braun 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2013
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb4"> ▸</xref>; Nicolaï &amp; Minár, 2018
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb49"> ▸</xref>). Moreover, it was not clear whether the 
 <italic>k</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>z</italic>
 </sub>-resolution stays sufficiently high in the several-keV range. This is a necessary precondition for precise mapping of bulk bands. The transfer of photon momentum 
 <bold>
  <italic>k</italic>
 </bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>h</italic>v
 </sub> to the photoelectron leads to a substantial shift of the 
 <italic>k</italic>-pattern. The interplay of this shift with diffraction of the photoelectrons from the valence-band is still in an early stage of understanding (Schönhense 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <italic>a</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb64"> ▸</xref>). Last but not least, typical count rates of conventional HAXPES spectrometers seemed prohibitively low for extended 4D mappings. This would require 3D data arrays with good counting statistics taken at many different photon energies in order to vary 
 <italic>k</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>z</italic>
 </sub>. In this section we will show that mapping of the 4D spectral function ρ(
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sub>B</sub>,
 <bold>
  <italic>k</italic>
 </bold>) in a tomography-like manner as introduced in the soft X-ray range (Medjanik 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2017
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb47"> ▸</xref>) still works for hard X-rays, if the momentum conservation including the photon momentum is properly accounted for.
</p>
