<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is eye-catching that in Fig. 5(
 <italic>a</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref> and all other 
 <italic>k</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub>–
 <italic>k</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>y</italic>
 </sub> distributions different BZs look differently and the patterns do not exhibit the full sixfold symmetry which we would expect for Re(0001). Instead, a twofold symmetry modulates the pattern of sixfold rings. The center of this apparent twofold symmetry is marked by a cross in Fig. 5(
 <italic>b</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref>. The reason for this – at first sight puzzling – deviation from the expected symmetry becomes clear when we take into consideration that the final states lie on a curved energy isosphere [see details on top of Fig. 6(
 <italic>a</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>]. Due to the increased field of view of the present instrument, the curvature of the intersection contour of the sphere and the periodic 
 <italic>k</italic>-space pattern becomes substantial. In the previous experiments in the soft X-ray range, focusing on one BZ, this effect was just a small correction. The ‘symmetry point’ marked by X in Fig. 5(
 <italic>b</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5"> ▸</xref> corresponds to the top of the sphere and, with increasing distance from this point, the 
 <italic>k</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>z</italic>
 </sub>-value is reduced. In turn, the cut runs through different features of the 3D Fermi surface. As a guide to the eye, we marked the small circles in the Fermi-surface cut with arrows in (
 <italic>b</italic>). These circles appear when the sphere intersects a small Fermi-surface pocket located about midway between the ΓMK and ALH symmetry planes [
 <italic>cf</italic>. the BZ in Fig. 6(
 <italic>b</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>]. In the observed patterns, these circles lie on a ring because these points have the same distance from the top point X; see the dashed circle in the upper left inset of Fig. 6(
 <italic>a</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref>.
</p>
