<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Note that the top of the sphere is not located on the Γ–A line crossing the center of the BZ but is shifted according to the size and direction of the photon momentum vector. The role of 
 <bold>
  <italic>k</italic>
 </bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>h</italic>ν
 </sub> in HARPES is not at all trivial and influences the observed patterns substantially. The final-state sphere is just rigidly shifted in 3D 
 <italic>k</italic>-space. However, concerning the observed pattern, this shift shows up in a complex way which can only be understood in a full 3D 
 <italic>k</italic>-space transition model. Fig. 6(
 <italic>a</italic>)
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref> shows the plane which contains 
 <bold>
  <italic>k</italic>
 </bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>h</italic>ν
 </sub>, hence perpendicular to this plane there is no photon-momentum component. This causes the apparent two-fold symmetry. Experimentally, the direction perpendicular to the surface can be identified by the profile of the space-charge induced Lorentzian energy shift (Schönhense 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, 2018
 <italic>b</italic>
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bb62"> ▸</xref>) and by the center of the Kikuchi-type diffraction pattern (
 <italic>cf</italic>. Section 3.3
 <xref ref-type="sec" rid="sec3.3"/>). The point with initial states with 
 <italic>k</italic> = 0 is displaced from the perpendicular direction by |
 <bold>
  <italic>k</italic>
 </bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>h</italic>ν
 </sub>|cos22° as discussed above. Energy conservation (leading to a final-state energy isosphere) acting independent of momentum conservation including 
 <bold>
  <italic>k</italic>
 </bold>
 <sub>
  <italic>h</italic>ν
 </sub> (leading to a shift of this sphere in 
 <italic>k</italic>-space) gives rise to striking dissymmetries in the photoemission patterns. The scenario differs fundamentally from the conventional view of transitions from an initial band state into a free-electron-like parabola.
</p>
