<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par12">Here, we showed that with quantitative low-energy electron diffraction (QLEED) intensity analyses and density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we can visualize the local atomic configuration, the corresponding electron distribution, and local reactivity. The QLEED-determined Cu(410) structure exhibits alternating sequences of expansion (+) and contraction (−) (of the first 16 atomic interlayers) relative to the bulk-truncated interlayer spacing of ca. 0.437 Å, with a Pendry reliability factor 
 <italic>R</italic>
 <sub>P</sub>≃0.0797). The corresponding electron distribution shows smoothening relative to the bulk-determined structure. Thus, we demonstrate how high Miller index surface, viz., Cu(410), can serve as an intermediate stage for analyzing and understanding the role of defects on the atomically flat surface, e.g., how they change their physical and chemical properties, how adsorbates behave near surface defects, and the adsorption mechanism. [Note that the method presented here is not a “fail-proof” approach for surface structure determination. Results from previous studies indicate special care should be taken in determining the surface structures of more complex systems, e.g., oxide surfaces, with reconstructions, and defects (cf., e.g., refs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>
 </sup>)]. Further detailed structural study of the Cu(410) and the corresponding local reactivity
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>
 </sup> can be done by adsorbing hydrogen, oxygen or silicon, and LEED analyses. This detailed interlayer relaxation (including the perpendicular and lateral displacements of the surface atoms) of high Miller index Cu(410) may also yield a better understanding of the merits and limitations of widely used experimental and theoretical methods for surface structural analyses.
</p>
