<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">The future of bright electron sources relies on the close interplay between theoretical understanding and experimental verification of the material characteristics and their role for the electron beam properties. Photoemission based electron sources are the enabling concept for many electron accelerator based applications such as the free-electron laser or ultra-fast scattering instruments
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup>. Furthermore, they are essential components for a plethora of technological devices ranging from photovoltaic cells to radiation detectors. For accelerator applications great progress has been achieved in recent years with regards to the preparation and characterisation of photoemission electron sources, especially given the boundary conditions present in the harsh environment of the particle accelerator. The electron source, 
 <italic>i.e</italic>., the photocathode, shares the vacuum environment of the first accelerating section and is subject to strong radio-frequency or static electric fields. In parallel with the experimental progress in the preparation of photocathodes it is also now possible to understand many aspects of the process of the generation of the electron pulses after emission. What is still missing is a deeper understanding of the intrinsic material properties and their role in the formation of the initial electron beam characteristics. There is also lack in knowledge about the effects of the growth process or contamination typically present in the accelerator environment. Right now the frontier of materials for accelerator applications is represented by semiconductors with maximised quantum efficiency (QE) in the visible region and minimised transverse energy (MTE)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>
 </sup>. Compared to simple metals or conventional semiconductors such as GaAs, they feature relatively low electron affinity and band gap, both on the order of 1 eV, which are key requirements for high QE in the visible band. Furthermore, their vacuum requirements are more modest compared with GaAs photocathodes
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup>. Motivated by these intriguing properties, a number of groups worldwide are striving to produce and operate photocathodes for particle accelerators based on multi-alkali antimonides
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
