<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">For example, at the Helmholtz-Zentrum Berlin (HZB), Cs-K-Sb photocathodes have been grown, characterised, and transferred into the photoelectron gun of the energy-recovery linac (ERL) bERLinPro. In the photoelectron gun the photocathode is placed inside a superconducting radio-frequency (SRF) cavity at the location of peak electric field. The electric field in the SRF cavity oscillates with a frequency of 1.3 GHz. At a defined phase the photocathode is struck by short light pulses (some ps length) from a frequency-doubled (at 515 nm) laser locked to the frequency of the of the SRF cavity. During emission the electron pulses are subject to rapid acceleration with gradients on the order of 20 MV/m and reach relativistic velocities after a couple of cm. The goal for the ERL accelerator is to generate a beam of ultra-short electron pulses with high average power and high brightness. After usage of the beam in radiation generation processes the electron pulses are guided back through the main acceleration section and the energy is recovered and fed to freshly generated pulses from the electron source. For this electron source, the photocathode material should exhibit high QE for visible drive laser wavelength and low intrinsic emittance to reach high brightness. To keep the emittance low, the substrate and photocathode film must be smooth. Additionally, to ensure stable operation, the photocathode must be robust to the environment within the photoinjector. To fulfill these requirements, several ultra-high vacuum (UHV) systems have been built to grow, analyse and transfer Cs-K-Sb photocathodes into the accelerator. The interconnection between all these steps requires characterisation techniques that are compatible with the accelerator requirements. For example, destructive methods cannot be applied, meaning that the range of available tools is limited. Nevertheless, the alkali co-deposition procedure developed at HZB and the adopted characterisation techniques have demonstrated the possibility to obtain reproducible photocathodes with high QE
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>
 </sup>. In spite of these notable achievements, severe issues remain regarding the production of single-crystalline samples with a controlled amount of defects and impurities
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>
 </sup>. The growth procedures that are routinely adopted nowadays
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup> do not allow for an 
 <italic>a priori</italic> definition of the obtained stoichiometry and crystal structure starting from a given composition. As a result, in place of the desired single crystals, surface-disordered and polycrystalline photocathodes are often grown, which inhibit reproducible characterisation and in-depth understanding of the intrinsic material properties, which determine the operational characteristics of photocathodes.
</p>
