<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par4">
 <italic>Ab initio</italic> electronic-structure theory is ideally suited to fill this gap. In a recent work on CsK
 <sub>2</sub>Sb we demonstrated that all-electron density-functional theory (DFT) and many-body perturbation theory (MBPT) are able to unravel the electronic structure and the excitations of multi-alkali antimonides with unprecedented insight
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>
 </sup>. Most importantly, these methods are truly predictive, as they do not require the 
 <italic>a priori</italic> knowledge of any empirical parameter of the material but only its chemical composition and crystal structure. In this context, single-crystalline solids represented by unit cells including a few atoms and satisfying a large number of symmetry operations are most efficiently treated. These structures, however, hardly match realistic multi-alkali antimonide photocathodes, where different crystal structures and stoichiometries often coexist and where the quality of the obtained materials is largely limited by the experimental conditions. The massive presence of defects in the samples is a typical characteristic of the grown photocathodes which is hardly predictable 
 <italic>a priori</italic> and represents therefore a major complication from a theoretical perspective. Also experimentally, the strict conditions for 
 <italic>in situ</italic> growth, characterisation, and operation requested by the samples limit the possibilities for an accurate determination of their stoichiometry and composition even through well-established techniques such as x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. Overcoming this issue represents a challenge for the near future that demands new viable strategies to gain insight into the fundamental characteristics of photocathode materials, in spite of the limited knowledge of their structure and stoichiometry. First-principles methods for electronic structure theory can play a prominent role in this context, owing to their unprecedented predictive power in comparison with any other theoretical approach. For this reason, substantial advances can be achieved, by searching, identifying, and unravelling correlations between the crystalline multi-alkali antimonides modelled 
 <italic>ab initio</italic> and experimentally grown photocathodes. In this way it is possible to create a virtuous circle between theory and experiments where the former does not simply fit the results of the latter but is able to provide on its own information about the materials properties. In return, data generated in the lab can be compared to the results of calculations to rationalise the properties of the photocathode in realistic growth and operational conditions.
</p>
