<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="sec1">Designing materials with tailor-made phononic properties is crucial for many open problems within condensed matter and nanoscience, such as engineering efficient thermoelectric materials
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>
 </sup> and keeping a low thermal budget in nanoelectronics,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>
 </sup> as well as to envisage devices that can use heat for information processing.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref>
 </sup> Superstructures consisting of a periodic arrangement of two materials, that is, superlattices, can successfully exploit wave interference phenomena, such as the formation of forbidden bandgaps and the modification of the density of states and group velocities of phonons, to control the heat flow by tuning the material’s thermal conductivity.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
 </sup> A connection between the superlattice periodicity and coherent versus incoherent heat transport has been established, outlining two transport regimes dominated either by the corpuscular nature of phonons or by wave interference effects.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12">12</xref>
 </sup> Rough or defective interfaces have been shown to significantly reduce the coherence of phonon transport
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref>
 </sup> and thus much of the rich physics exhibited by phononic superlattices is directly connected to the sharpness of the interfaces defining the superstructure.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref>
 </sup> Typical issues that degrade the quality of ordinary heterojunctions, for example, lack of sharpness of the interface, lattice mismatch, and interdiffusion, become negligible or irrelevant in crystal phase superlattices,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>
 </sup> which are “homojunctions” where only the crystal structure changes, while the atomic species and the nature of chemical bonding stay the same. This type of superlattices can be realized in nanowires (NWs),
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref>−
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref>
 </sup> as the great progresses made in recent years in their synthetic growth
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref>
 </sup> enabled the epitaxial growth of novel crystal phases,
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref>
 </sup> which in bulk can only be observed under extreme conditions of temperature and pressure. The controlled switching between different crystal phases during the growth opened the way to crystal phase engineering where unconventional polytypes can be juxtaposed in an ordered fashion to the most common polymorphs and create crystal phase superlattices. Because of the specific nature of these interfaces, it is of great fundamental and applied interest to assess to what extent one can tune by design the properties of these systems, similarly to what can be achieved with conventional superlattices
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref27">27</xref>
 </sup> or phononic crystals.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
