<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Furthermore, due to the insufficient knowledge of calculation method for the height component of material plastic side flow, some researchers attempt to establish the distribution function with respect to the height component of material spring back and apply it to describe the deviation between the kinematic components (
 <italic>R</italic>
 <sub>tew</sub>(
 <italic>x</italic>)) and the final surface profile in one feed rate (
 <italic>F</italic>(
 <italic>x</italic>)). In fact, this function can be regarded as the general function as discussed in [
 <xref rid="B28-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. For instance, in the fabrication of the micro-freeform lens array, to accurately determine the process parameters required to generate the pre-designed surfaces, Zhu et al. adopt a piecewise function to express the distribution of spring back in relation to the minimum deformed chip thickness (
 <italic>h</italic>
 <sub>Dmin</sub>) as demonstrated in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="micromachines-10-00288-f005">Figure 5</xref> [
 <xref rid="B55-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>]. Furthermore, Huang et al. designed a linear function to analyze the amount of material spring back when the undeformed chip thickness ranges from minimum undeformed chip thickness to the maximum chip thickness [
 <xref rid="B56-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>]. Liu et al. claimed that when the undeformed thickness is larger than the minimum undeformed chip thickness, the material spring back amount is zero and hence established the distribution function for material spring back [
 <xref rid="B57-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>]. As an alternative, Guo et al. assumed that when the chip thickness is greater than the minimum undeformed chip thickness, the elastic recovery linearly decrease to a constant value which is in relation to material mechanical properties and cutting edge radius (
 <italic>r</italic>
 <sub>n</sub>), and a more complex piecewise function for material spring back is therefore established [
 <xref rid="B58-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">58</xref>]. 
</p>
