<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this work, the tool edge waviness is defined as the deviation between the actual tool shape profile and its corresponding least square circular arc, i.e., the nominal tool shape profile which is expressed in Equation (1). As shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="micromachines-10-00288-f002">Figure 2</xref>b, the red line (represented as the ideal tool shape) is the nominal tool shape profile, while the black line is the actual tool shape profile. To accurately capture the active part of the diamond tool, He et al. proposed a two-step method, and subsequently integrated it into the 3D surface topography model [
 <xref rid="B28-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. Kurniawan et al. employed a replication technique to acquire the actual tool edge profile [
 <xref rid="B29-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. Specifically, the tool edge profile is firstly duplicated on a soft material, for instance the aluminium alloy, and then used a 3D non-contact surface profiler to capture the active cutting edge profile. Meanwhile, Zong et al. explored the influence of tool edge waviness in diamond turning of potassium dihydrogen phosphate (KDP) crystals with finite element simulation method, and they pointed out that the tool edge waviness can affect the formation process of cutting chip, which further deteriorates the final achieved surface topography [
 <xref rid="B30-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]. In addition, Zuo et al. studied the micro/nano texture generation mechanism in double-frequency elliptical vibration diamond cutting, in which the rake face, flank face and tool cutting edge radius are further taken into account [
 <xref rid="B31-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]. Based on the theoretical and experimental results, they claimed that with consideration of rake face and flank face, the prediction accuracy is obviously improved, which reflects that the influence of rake face and flank face on surface generation is greater in the vibration-assisted diamond turning. 
</p>
