<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>However, the above solutions only supply the results of material spring back and plastic side flow components in the local position. For instance, in Equation (3), only the height value of material plastic side flow at the margin position is one feed rate is calculated. However, these values are not sufficient for the surface topography model in one feed rate, which means that the distribution functions responsible for the material plastic side flow and material spring back should be supplied. Kong et al. and To et al. studied the material plastic side flow and recovery in diamond turning process [
 <xref rid="B47-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>,
 <xref rid="B48-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>,
 <xref rid="B49-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>], and Kong et al. further pointed out that the effect of material plastic side flow is overwhelmed by the effect of material spring back when the depth of cut is extremely small. Furthermore, the influence of the distribution of the material spring back and plastic side flow on the surface profile in one tool feed is also discussed in [
 <xref rid="B47-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>]. As shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="micromachines-10-00288-f004">Figure 4</xref>, S
 <sub>1</sub> is the surface profile only considering the duplication effect of tool edge profile (including tool edge waviness). Due to the effect of the material plastic side flow, the height of the surface profile S
 <sub>1</sub> in one tool feed gradually increases from the center to the margin, and resultantly the surface profile S
 <sub>2</sub> forms. Further taking the effect of material spring back into account, the final surface profile on the machined surface can be expressed as S
 <sub>3</sub>. As demonstrated in [
 <xref rid="B25-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>,
 <xref rid="B45-micromachines-10-00288" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>], the value of the material plastic side flow obtains the maximum value at the margin point in one feed rate; this is due to the fact that the work material will flow and accumulate at the side part of the active cutting edge under the high pressure on the tool/workpiece interface. Meanwhile, the value of material spring back reaches the maximum value at the center part in one feed rate. 
</p>
