<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par2">As is well-known
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>
 </sup>, the X-ray diffraction topography method is a highly sensitive nondestructive diagnostics method for observing various crystal lattice defects like striations, grain boundaries, stacking faults, single clusters, and dislocations. All these defects change the positions of individual atoms of crystal cell relative to their regular position. The real crystal structure can be studied by the Laue diffraction topography method that provides the 2D image (2D projection) of crystal with defects. Based on the analytical approximate solutions of the X-ray optics problem by the stationary method (
 <italic>cf</italic>. the geometrical X-ray optics method in
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>
 </sup>), the theoretical fundamentals for an analysis of the X-ray diffraction scattering from macroscopical crystalline objects are elaborated and widely used (see
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>, and references therein for details). In particular, in
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>, in the case of the X-ray diffraction from the crystals with defects, the basic principles and theoretical analysis of the X-ray coherent diffraction intensity and incoherent (diffuse) scattering intensity, the latter is caused by the X-ray scattering from the statistical ensemble of crystal lattice defects, are comprehensively presented. In practice, to interpret and analyze the experimental 2D images of crystals with lattice defects, the defect images are compared with the corresponding ones that can be evaluated using numerical methods for solving the 
 <italic>dynamical</italic> Takagi–Taupin equations
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
