<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Indoor location-based services are challenging owing to the vast coverage required and the scalability of positioning systems [
 <xref rid="B5-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. At present, the mainstream interior positioning technologies include magnetic navigation, simultaneous localization and mapping (SLAM) [
 <xref rid="B6-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
 <xref rid="B7-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>], Wi-Fi positioning, radio frequency identification (RFID) positioning, and UWB positioning [
 <xref rid="B8-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="B9-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. There have been many studies on Wi-Fi indoor positioning technology. Xujian and Hao [
 <xref rid="B10-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>] proposed an improved Kalman-filtering-based WiFi indoor positioning algorithm. Zhang et al. [
 <xref rid="B11-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>] presented a domain-clustering-based WiFi indoor positioning algorithm. In UWB field, Ubisense Co. Ltd. from the UK has produced the UbisB 7000 positioning system based on UWB technology, which uses Time Difference of Arrival (TDOA) and Activity on Arrow (AOA) hybrid positioning algorithm to achieve 15 cm accuracy in typical applications. AETHER WIRE &amp; LOCATION Co. Ltd. of the United States introduced the localizers system with a range accuracy of 1cm and a node volume of 8 mm [
 <xref rid="B12-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. Their common shortcoming is that they are expensive. When these indoor positioning technologies are used independently, they tend to have poor positioning accuracy and low reliability. In addition, they are time-consuming and entail high costs. Although guiding a robot using magnetic navigation as a means of positioning does not appear to involve positioning errors, the robot stops when it encounters obstacles and it cannot make an autonomous detour. In addition, when an out-of-orbit accident occurs, the operation has to be resumed by the staff, and the flexibility is low. Another common method for robot positioning is based on SLAM, which allows independent navigation, obstacle avoidance, and path planning. Compared with magnetic navigation, the flexibility of the feeding robot is improved considerably. However, when faced with many obstacles or surrounded by humans, the radar cannot scan the surrounding environment sufficiently, resulting in a loss of coordinates. Wi-Fi [
 <xref rid="B13-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>] and RFID technologies cannot meet the precision requirements of indoor positioning for meal delivery robots. To improve accuracy, researchers have proposed the use of UWB technology. UWB signals have the advantages of high penetration, high multi-path resolution, and low transmitting power. UWB positioning can achieve centimeter-scale location accuracy without accumulating errors [
 <xref rid="B14-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B15-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Considering the environment in a restaurant, the use of only UWB technology results in low positioning accuracy, e.g., around 30–40 cm. In this situation, using an inertial measurement unit (IMU) is a good choice. The Inertial Navigation System (INS) has good short-term accuracy and does not rely on any external sources for determining position and attitude. Guan et al. [
 <xref rid="B16-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>] presented a low-cost, high-integrated, and small-size mems inertial navigation system. Combining an IMU with UWB technology can improve the positioning accuracy [
 <xref rid="B17-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B18-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. However, the stability is poor while turning or changing speed and the overall accuracy of the system is thus reduced [
 <xref rid="B19-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. In addition to the fusion of UWB and IMU technologies, visual odometer correction can improve the positioning accuracy. However, it increases the hardware cost. Moreover, the installation is complex, and the system is sensitive to light [
 <xref rid="B21-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. Moreover, a large number of network nodes are required to complete a wide range of indoor target tracking tasks, which is bound to introduce concerns related to network structure optimization as well as multi-node/multi-cluster coordination and communication. Among navigation technologies without beacons, the most commonly used method is the analysis of the pedestrian trajectory by an inertial navigation system [
 <xref rid="B22-sensors-19-04980" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. To overcome the shortcomings of a single technology for interior positioning, it is necessary to integrate such technology with multi-sensor information to realize a high-precision, high-reliability, and low-cost positioning system.
</p>
