<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In mullite the 
 <italic>T</italic> site is of major interest as Al/Si ordering mainly takes place on that site and it participates in both diclusters and triclusters. In the following example, the modulation functions describing the atomic domain of the 
 <italic>T</italic> site are determined for M40 #1. Fig. 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref> shows the 
 <italic>x</italic>
 <sub>2</sub> coordinates of Al2 (grey-blue) and Si2 (blue) atoms in 
 <italic>t</italic> space and the determined modulation function 
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="a-75-00260-efi1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> defined as
 <disp-formula id="fdu1">
  <graphic xlink:href="a-75-00260-efd1.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" position="float" orientation="portrait" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </disp-formula>
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="a-75-00260-efi2.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> is the dot product of the modulation wavevector 
 <bold>q</bold> and the average coordinate vector 
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="a-75-00260-efi3.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> plus the parameter 
 <italic>t</italic> defined by the physical space section. 
 <italic>n</italic> is the order of the harmonic term. The parameters that must be determined by least-square fitting to the embedded coordinates are the average coordinate 
 <inline-formula>
  <inline-graphic xlink:href="a-75-00260-efi4.jpg" mimetype="image" mime-subtype="gif" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </inline-formula> and the component amplitudes 
 <italic>A</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>n</italic>,
  <italic>i</italic>
 </sub> and 
 <italic>B</italic>
 <sub>
  <italic>n</italic>,
  <italic>i</italic>
 </sub>. Symmetry restrictions decrease the number of parameters for atoms occupying special positions. For example, a modulation of 
 <italic>x</italic>
 <sub>3</sub> is forbidden for all atomic domains except Al1 and O2. The displacive modulation functions can be determined for any atomic domain if sufficient coordinates of a specific average structure site are available. Here, there are four independent coordinate triplets for Al3 and O4 and 20 for Al1, O1 and O2. In the present example, meaningful modulation functions can be determined if the observables-to-parameter ratio for the fitting is larger than about 1.5. In Fig. 6
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6"> ▸</xref> the determined modulation function of 
 <italic>x</italic>
 <sub>2</sub> of the 
 <italic>T</italic> site is shown with harmonics of order 1 to 3.
</p>
