<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par6">If we follow the idea that Theo’s Flow was emplaced into a pre-existing V shape topography (valley), a possible scenario for the emplacement mechanism could be related to effusive submarine eruptions as suggested in the literature
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>
 </sup>. Magma–water interactions can occur deep within the Earth or near the surface as possibly happened for the Theo’s Flow. In such a case, convective cooling by water should be considered as the dominant cooling mechanism because it is more efficient than convective, radiative, and conductive cooling observed on the Earth surface
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. Fink and Griffiths
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup> and more recently Gregg
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup> proposed that the convective heat flux from the surface of a submarine lava flow leads to an almost immediate cooling of magma. As an example, after 1 s, a basalt erupting at 1423 K passes through the solidus and glass transition temperature at a depth of 2 mm and 0.5 mm, respectively. The rupture of crust is a reasonable process during surface eruption
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup> where the new and fast-formed crust can incur in rupture from which new blob of magma will come out. Active pillow lava lobe inflating on transverse and radial cracks with high-effusion-rate are plausible events for flows moving down to a steep slope. As an example, inflated Pahoehoe flows can display large inflation structures such as plateaus and cover several hundreds of square meters as observed in Iceland, and the inflation height can reach a maximum of 20 m in the case of submarine or subaqueous flows
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. Since Theo’s Flow is described as a120 m thick lava flow this would require superimposed flows each of the order of 10–50 m thick closely emplaced in time. Finally, the study of lava flows in submarine environments requires that the effective gravity force acting on the flow is considered. Due to the lower density difference between the lava and the water it is smaller in water than on Earth surface
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>. The reduced gravity (g’) is given by:
 <disp-formula id="Equ1">
  <label>1</label>
  <alternatives>
   <tex-math id="M1">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal} \usepackage{amsmath} \usepackage{wasysym} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{upgreek} \setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt} \begin{document}$$g^{\prime} =\frac{g\,(\rho -\rho w)}{\rho }$$\end{document}</tex-math>
   <math id="M2" display="block">
    <mrow>
     <mi>g</mi>
     <mo>′</mo>
    </mrow>
    <mo>=</mo>
    <mfrac>
     <mrow>
      <mi>g</mi>
      <mspace width=".25em"/>
      <mo stretchy="false">(</mo>
      <mi>ρ</mi>
      <mo>−</mo>
      <mi>ρ</mi>
      <mi>w</mi>
      <mo stretchy="false">)</mo>
     </mrow>
     <mi>ρ</mi>
    </mfrac>
   </math>
   <graphic xlink:href="41598_2019_53142_Article_Equ1.gif" position="anchor" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  </alternatives>
 </disp-formula>and it takes into account 
 <italic>ρ</italic> (the lava density) and density of the surrounding seawater 
 <italic>ρw</italic>. With a lava density of 2600 kg m
 <sup>−3</sup>, if we consider a shallow subaqueous environment where density of water is close to 1000 kg m
 <sup>−3</sup> and ambient water temperature ranges from 273 to 283 K, the effective gravity is 6.03 ms
 <sup>−2</sup>. Whereas, with the same lava density, at 1000 m deep and a temperature of 273 K where seawater has a density of 1046 kg m
 <sup>−3</sup>, the effective gravity is 5.85 ms
 <sup>−2</sup>. This implies that the buoyancy force countering the effect of the gravity is significantly higher in water and this greatly increases the ability of lava to inflate and also increases the thickness of the lava flow by about 30%
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>
 </sup>. Considering that in subaqueous environments the height of flows is on the order of 10 m we should therefore explore the possible scenario already proposed
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup> of superimposed lava flows rather than one single-flow unit.
</p>
