<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">The discoveries of quantum Hall effects
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>
 </sup> and topological insulators
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>
 </sup> have shed light on topologically protected gapless edge states that exist between phases with different topological characters
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>
 </sup>. The edge states preserve dissipationless particle/quasiparticle flow that could be useful for future applications in energy-efficient information transmission and processing. Recently, the concept of the edge states have been extended to other systems, such as ultracold atom systems in optical lattices
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>
 </sup>, and even to systems with bosonic quasiparticles, such as photonic crystals
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>, phonons
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>
 </sup>, and magnons
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>
 </sup> in solids. In electron systems, the topological characters are classified by the total topological invariant of the occupied bands, which is associated with quantized Hall conductance
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>
 </sup>. In contrast, for magnetic insulators, the electric conductance is zero by definition. Instead, thermally excited bosonic quasiparticles convey a heat transport, and hence thermal conductance is supposedly the key transport property that reflects the topological nature of the underlying quasiparticle dispersion relations
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>
 </sup>. Detailed knowledge on dispersion relations of the excited states are, therefore, necessary to explore and design the magnetic insulators with bosonic topological bands.
</p>
