<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Because of their organic-inorganic hybrid nature, organolead halide perovskites have different configurations of organic and inorganic parts, which establish the diversity of the material family. For instance, in 2D perovskite (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbX
 <sub>4</sub>, the long-chain phenylethylamine (PEA) molecules spatially separate the inorganic layers, making a multiple quantum well structure. However, in 3D cases such as MAPbX
 <sub>3</sub> and FAPbX
 <sub>3</sub>, smaller molecules (methylammonium and formamidinium) occupy vacancies among the octaheral [PbX
 <sub>3</sub>]
 <sup>−</sup> frame. When hydrostatic pressure is applied to organolead halide perovskites, both components contribute to the lattice structure change, leading to complicated structures and properties. For MAPbX
 <sub>3</sub> under high pressure, similar phenomena are observed from its bulk crystal (
 <xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>19</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>22</italic>
 </xref>) and nanocrystals (
 <xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>23</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>25</italic>
 </xref>), including bandgap narrowing, multiple phase transitions with bandgap “blue jump” at different pressures (
 <xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>20</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>23</italic>
 </xref>), and metalization at ultrahigh pressure up to 50 GPa (
 <xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>21</italic>
 </xref>). The photoluminescence (PL) of MAPbX
 <sub>3</sub> quenches rapidly and disappears at ~1.5 GPa, making the effective bandgap tunability with efficient PL very limited, generally less than 80 meV (
 <xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>20</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>23</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>25</italic>
 </xref>). The effective bandgap tunability of FAPbX
 <sub>3</sub> can be 40 meV greater (
 <xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>26</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>27</italic>
 </xref>) but still insufficient for tunable optoelectronic applications. The rapid quench of PL is attributed to lattice distortion and bending of chemical bonds (
 <xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>20</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>22</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>26</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>27</italic>
 </xref>). Molecular size and configuration play a key role in controlling the lattice and band structures of organolead halide perovskite under pressure.
</p>
