<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>2D perovskite with its unique multiple quantum well structure has inherent 2D crystal nature and out-of-plane quantum and dielectric confinements, making a novel platform to realize unique structure and optical properties under pressure. Recently more prominent band tunability with anisotropic compression of lattice has been reported on 2D perovskite (
 <xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>28</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>30</italic>
 </xref>). Here, we loaded 2D perovskite (PEA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> into a diamond anvil cell (DAC) and systematically studied its optical and structural behaviors under pressure, using steady-state and time-resolved PL (trPL), Raman spectroscopy, x-ray diffraction (XRD) with a synchrotron radiation, and first-principles calculation. Ultrabroad tunable emission has been observed, starting from 2.38 eV (0 GPa) and reaching full quenching at 1.84 eV (~6.2 GPa). The 320-meV tunability at 0 to 3.5 GPa is fully reversible and immediately responds to pressure changes, without a noticeable drop of emission intensity. This tunable high-efficiency emission is device friendly, as the performing pressure is relatively low and achievable without the need of DAC. For potential applications as tunable lasing, we have found evidence to show that the optical quality regarding the exciton radiative recombination rate is enhanced by pressure within the optical reversible region. The mechanism of the efficient light emission during the bandgap narrowing is well explained by analyzing the structure evolution based on XRD and first-principles calculation. As a result, strong anisotropic deformation of 2D perovskite crystal preserves the lattice structure and the [PbI
 <sub>6</sub>]
 <sup>4−</sup> octahedral geometry, thus sustaining the efficiency of band-edge exciton recombination. The prominent thickness reduction of the organic barrier layers releases the quantum confinement and contributes the most to the bandgap red shift of the reversible region.
</p>
