<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par14">Close agreement between our experimental observations and ab initio calculations make us confident that our theoretical approach should also adequately describe driving forces behind pressure-induced transformations in CaP
 <sub>2</sub>Be
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub> as well as reasons for formation of phases with unusual coordinations of phosphorus and beryllium. In order to gain this knowledge, we have investigated the behavior of the electronic structure of CaP
 <sub>2</sub>Be
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub> upon compression. Figure 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> summarizes calculated total electronic density of states (DOS) of different phases of hurlbutite. Analysis of the partial local DOS (Supplementary Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">9</xref>) demonstrates that all the occupied states of CaP
 <sub>2</sub>Be
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub> are of 
 <italic>s-</italic> and 
 <italic>p-</italic>character: the electronic states corresponding to 
 <italic>d</italic> orbitals are well above the highest occupied state at all the studied pressures, and therefore are not relevant for the phase transitions observed in this work. At the same time, one can clearly see in Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5a</xref> that the electronic structure of hurlbutite is characterized by well localized electronic states (peaks of the DOS are sharp and separated from each other by energy gaps). Upon compression, the states become broader, and the energy gaps between them disappear, starting from the high-energy part of the spectrum in hurlbutite-II, and proceeding all the way to the low-energy part of the spectrum in hurlbutite-IV. We, therefore, conclude that the sequence of structural transitions observed in the present study is associated with the electronic transitions from predominantly molecular orbitals at low pressure to the state with overlapping electronic clouds of anions orbitals. Both experimental observations of the BeO
 <sub>5</sub>/BeO
 <sub>6</sub> configurations and ab initio calculations are in line with previous quantum chemical calculations
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup> and demonstrate that the involvement of 
 <italic>d</italic> orbitals is not mandatory for the formation of species with trigonal–bipyramidal and octahedral geometries. Instead, an electron-deficient multicenter bonding can be proposed as a mechanism of formation of such exotic configurations and, generally, as a densification mechanism for the CaP
 <sub>2</sub>Be
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub> crystal structure adopting to high-pressure conditions
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>
 </sup>.
</p>
