<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par15">Pressure-induced increase of cation coordination number is repeatedly observed tendency
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>
 </sup> that was outlined as a general rule of high-pressure crystal chemistry in reviews of Prewitt and Downs
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup> and Grochala et al. (2007)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>
 </sup>. In inorganic oxocompounds this tendency is typically realized along with evolution of the oxygen sublattice toward the close packing arrangements
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup>. This is also the case for hurlbutite: upon pressurizing O and Ca cations firstly arrange into close packing assembly consisting both of distorted HCP and CCP elements (with P and Be occupying tetrahedral and trigonal bipyramidal voids in hurlbutite-II and -III) and later into ABCACABCBCAB arrangement (with P and Be filling octahedral voids in hurlbutite-IV). While the cation coordination and oxygen sublattice are traditional determinants of a crystal structure, the alternative view on the crystal chemistry of oxides was proposed by O’Keeffe and Hyde by introducing terms cation packing and anion coordination
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>
 </sup>. While this approach was found to be effective for a number of cases (e.g., elaborating on Al coordination in Al
 <sup>VI</sup>
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>3</sub> and Al
 <sup>IV</sup>PO
 <sub>4</sub>, describing olivine → spinel transition), we find that the classical way of structure representation is more appropriate for our cases. By studying high-pressure behavior of a group of isotopological compounds with general formulae MT1
 <sub>2</sub>T2
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub> (M = Ca, Ba, Sr; T = Si, B, Be, P), we conclude that the crystal structure response (and particularly formation of TO
 <sub>5</sub> species) is governed by interplay of two factors: compressibility of TO
 <sub>4</sub> tetrahedra and size of large M cation. The chemistry of the T site governs T[IV] → T[V] transition pressure (e.g., compare Be[V] and P[V] between 70–75 and 82–85 GPa in CaBe
 <sub>2</sub>P
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub>, respectively, and Si[V] at c.a. 22 GPa in CaB
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>
 </sup>). The size of the M cation is responsible for formation of close packing arrangement with trigonal bipyramidal voids, i.e., TO
 <sub>5</sub> species. Thus, in contrast to CaB
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub>, Si site in the structure of SrB
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub> does not change coordination to five-fold upon pressurizing but instead undergoes a splitting into two sites
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>
 </sup>. Further increase of M cation size results in complete absence of Si[V]: the high-pressure polymorphism is realized via direct Si[IV] → Si[VI] transition in the crystal structure of BaB
 <sub>2</sub>Si
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub>
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>
 </sup>. In the upcoming review article on high-pressure behavior of MT1
 <sub>2</sub>T2
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>8</sub> compounds we are going to elaborate on the crystal chemical regularities in detail.
</p>
