<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Piezoelectric pressure sensors are widely used in various pressure tests because of their simple structure, high sensitivity, and high precision. However, the nature structure of piezoelectric sensors makes them sensitive to acceleration, especially to axial acceleration. To measure transient pressure accurately, piezoelectric pressure sensors must compensate for the acceleration-induced effects. Typical methods to eliminate the acceleration-induced effects mainly focus on reducing the mass of the piezoelectric element or improving the mechanical rigidity of the piezoelectric element [
 <xref rid="B4-sensors-19-01052" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
 <xref rid="B5-sensors-19-01052" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. This inevitably leads to a decrease in the sensitivity of the sensor. For keeping the sensitivity of the sensor constant, an increasing compensation element of the pressure sensor is presented [
 <xref rid="B6-sensors-19-01052" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Nevertheless, this method reduces the inherent frequency of the sensor [
 <xref rid="B7-sensors-19-01052" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. The acceleration-induced effect of the pressure sensor was statically calibrated by Zu et al. [
 <xref rid="B8-sensors-19-01052" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. However, to eliminate the acceleration-induced error, the acceleration signal must be measured at the meantime, which makes the test system too complicated. Fortunately, this problem can be solved by designing proper digital filters. Hence, a reliable mathematical model might be a big challenge. Shang et al. adopted an empirical mode decomposition (EMD) method to model the acceleration-induced error of piezoelectric sensor [
 <xref rid="B9-sensors-19-01052" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. The EMD has many advantages, such as it is intuitive and can be deduced without a preset basis function. In addition, the random noises mixed in the output signal of pressure sensors can be eliminated effectively. Due to a lack of theoretical foundation, the empirical mode decomposition for acceleration-induced effects still has shortcomings in accuracy and reliability.
</p>
