<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We investigated the interplay between the binary silicon boride phases α-SiB
 <sub>3–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> and β-SiB
 <sub>3</sub> which have a similar composition but very different crystal structures. α-SiB
 <sub>3–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> is disordered and nonstoichiometric, with a homogeneity range 0.1 &lt; 
 <italic>x</italic> &lt;0.45. Its structure relates to the α-rhombohedral phase of boron (α-B
 <sub>12</sub>) and features Si
 <sub>2</sub> dumbbell units at the location of intericosahedral 3c2e bonds in α-B
 <sub>12</sub>. Additionally, Si replaces partly (25–30%) B atoms from the polar position of icosahedral units. Accordingly, the α-SiB
 <sub>3–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> structure consists of a mixture of B
 <sub>10</sub>Si
 <sup>p</sup>
 <sub>2</sub> and B
 <sub>11</sub>Si
 <sup>p</sup> clusters, which are highly strained because of the rather large size difference between B and Si atoms. In the structure model deduced from high-resolution SC-XRD data, the polar position is split into three sites (one Si and two B), which accounts well for the disparity of interatomic distances introduced by the occupational disorder of differently sized atoms. In contrast, the structure of β-SiB
 <sub>3</sub> is completely ordered with respect to B and Si sites. The Si partial structure constitutes polymeric zigzag chains of rhomboid Si
 <sub>4</sub> rings. Boron atoms form B
 <sub>12</sub> icosahedra, in which all of the B atoms attain an exo-bond to either a B atom of a neighboring B
 <sub>12</sub> unit or a silicon atom within the rhomboid chains. The highly ordered nature of β-SiB
 <sub>3</sub> is reflected in its Raman spectrum, which features narrow and distinct lines. In contrast, the Raman spectrum of α-SiB
 <sub>3–
  <italic>x</italic>
 </sub> is characterized by broad bands, which nevertheless show a clear relation to the vibrational modes of isostructural, ordered, B
 <sub>6</sub>P.
</p>
