<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f006">Figure 6</xref> shows the FFT of the crystal’s HRTEM pattern of 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f003">Figure 3</xref>c. The direction f
 <sub>x</sub> represents the family of crystallographic directions a1 = [1000] (see 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f005">Figure 5</xref>a). The scale of 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f006">Figure 6</xref> is S
 <sub>f</sub> = (0.0111) 1/nm per pixel. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f006">Figure 6</xref> gives a statistical spatial average of frequency changes of elementary cells in the analyzed region. This means that 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f006">Figure 6</xref> is a graphical representation of the ensemble of the spatial frequencies of the RVE of the observed area. The hexagon shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f006">Figure 6</xref> represents the average amplitude of 
 <bold>a</bold> = 3.073 Å at 300 K. The changes in hexagon’s corners positions with respect to the average position indicated in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f006">Figure 6</xref> reflect distortions of elementary cells caused by dislocations. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f004">Figure 4</xref> represents the elementary undeformed cell for which the atomic vector 
 <bold>a</bold> is constant. The 
 <bold>a</bold> vector reflects the spatial configuration of atomic bonds binding together atoms. Since atoms continuously oscillate under thermal excitation at the T temperature, 
 <bold>a</bold> is a statistical average over time. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-01804-f006">Figure 6</xref> shows that the 
 <bold>a</bold> vector is modified by the deformations caused by the dislocations. In the 2-D analysis, changes experienced by the elementary cell can be analyzed by superposing different changes in dimension and orientation of 
 <bold>a</bold>.
</p>
