<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">For the positive electrode materials of LIBs, lithium insertion and extraction change the crystal structure of the host crystals. The crystal-structural change is triggered by the changes in the electronic structure of the host material during the Li insertion/extraction process
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>
 </sup>. In addition, lithium ions diffuse into the host crystals along a direction that is dependent on the crystal structure. For example, diffusion of lithium ions in LiFePO
 <sub>4</sub> (olivine-type), LiCoO
 <sub>2</sub> (LCO, layered rock salt), and LiMn
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>4</sub> (spinel-type) is one-dimensional, two-dimensional, and three-dimensional, respectively
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>
 </sup>. To understand the above-mentioned complex phenomena, analytical techniques using synchrotron radiation X-rays have enabled a major advance: hard X-rays having a short wavelength can be used to clarify the crystal structure
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>
 </sup> and soft X-ray spectroscopies, which cover the 3
 <italic>d</italic> transition-metal 
 <italic>L</italic> and oxygen 
 <italic>K</italic> edges, are advantageous to obtain element-specific electronic-structure information on the host material
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>
 </sup>. Concerning the measurement area on the electrode materials, the recent development of X-ray optics has enabled a focusing of the X-ray beam down to the several tens of nanometer scale
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>
 </sup>. This has enabled us to observe various micro areas of the microcrystals of electrode materials and understand the stability of each micro region
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>
 </sup>. More important has been the rapid growth of the state-of-the-art 
 <italic>operando</italic> X-ray measurements, where X-ray progress can be performed during voltage/current operation of the battery
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>
 </sup>. All of the characteristics of synchrotron X-ray spectroscopies are essential for accurate observation and detailed understanding of the diffusion and domain wall kinetics of the intercalation electrode materials and even more complex charge-discharge mechanisms, including redox potential, capacity, and cycle stability of electrode materials.
</p>
