<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We have shown that mixed FA/MA cations and mixed halide (Br/I) lead perovskite for solar cells, fabricated under ambient conditions, can be stabilized by the introduction of 2.5% of ZnI
 <sub>2</sub>. By XRD, Zn(II) is proven to be incorporated in the perovskite structure despite its smaller ionic radius compared to Pb(II). UV–vis and XRD comparison of freshly made and aged samples containing Zn(II) show the same behavior after 14 days of storage under ambient conditions (60 days with CPACl). The incorporation of Zn(II) affects also photophysical properties of the perovskite as the PL emission is enhanced one order of magnitude in agreement with the passivation mechanism of defects and the lifetime is prolonged from 588 ns (for the pristine material) to 634 ns. In addition, to obtain dense, pinhole-free layers, we applied an amine hydrochloride additive, 3-CPACl. The introduction of this alkylammonium additive in the precursor solution results in a straightforward method to obtain reproducible and highly crystalline-oriented layers along the (100) and (200) crystallographic direction. Larger grains, homogeneous, and more compact layers are also observed in SEM images. Using Zn(II) and 3-CPACl in combination, the PL is enhanced with respect to the composition containing only Zn(II) and the lifetime extended to 1547 ns. Zn(II) is an effective isovalent dopant. The lattice contraction induced by the smaller zinc ion reduces the amount of point defects (atomic vacancies) by strain release and thereby enhances the PL lifetime. The combined effects of the alkylammonium additive and Zn(II) ions strongly reduce the amount of defect states (trap states that induce PL quenching and non-raditive charge loss in devices). We want to highlight the intriguing effect of including a transition metal as Zn(II) in the perovskite lattice also for perovskite fabricated under ambient conditions. Further work is needed to optimize the device interfaces and architecture to obtain more efficient solar cells under ambient conditions. We are optimistic that the one-step fabrication in air, together with the excellent stability enhanced by incorporation of Zn(II) and 3-CPACl, will spark these optimization efforts. A review on the effects of Zn(II) in perovskites is now available.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
