<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <p content-type="toc-graphic">
  <graphic xlink:href="ao-2018-03489g_0014" id="ab-tgr1" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </p>
 <p>The N
  <sup>3–</sup>-substituted Li
  <sub>2</sub>MSiO
  <sub>4</sub>:Eu
  <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors were systematically prepared and analyzed. Secondary-ion mass spectroscopy measurements revealed that the average N
  <sup>3–</sup> contents are 0.003 for Ca, 0.009 for Sr, and 0.032 for Ba. Furthermore, the N
  <sup>3–</sup> incorporation in the host lattices was corroborated by infrared and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopies. From the photoluminescence spectra of Li
  <sub>2</sub>MSiO
  <sub>4</sub>:Eu
  <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors before and after N
  <sup>3–</sup> doping, it was verified that the enhanced emission intensity of the phosphors is most likely due to the N
  <sup>3–</sup> doping. In Li
  <sub>2</sub>MSiO
  <sub>4</sub>:Eu
  <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors, the maximum wavelengths of the emission band were red-shifted in the order Ca &lt; Ba &lt; Sr, which is not consistent with the trend of crystal field splitting: Ba &lt; Sr &lt; Ca. This discrepancy was clearly explained by electron–electron repulsions among polyhedra, LiO
  <sub>4</sub>–MO
  <sub>
   <italic>n</italic>
  </sub>, SiO
  <sub>4</sub>–MO
  <sub>
   <italic>n</italic>
  </sub>, and MO
  <sub>
   <italic>n</italic>
  </sub>–M’O
  <sub>
   <italic>n</italic>
  </sub> associated with structural difference in the host lattices. Therefore, the energy levels associated with the 4f
  <sup>6</sup>5d energy levels of Eu
  <sup>2+</sup> are definitely established in the following order: Li
  <sub>2</sub>CaSiO
  <sub>4</sub>:Eu
  <sup>2+</sup> &gt; Li
  <sub>2</sub>BaSiO
  <sub>4</sub>:Eu
  <sup>2+</sup> &gt; Li
  <sub>2</sub>SrSiO
  <sub>4</sub>:Eu
  <sup>2+</sup>. Furthermore, using the Williamson–Hall (W–H) method, the determined structural strains of Li
  <sub>2</sub>MSiO
  <sub>4</sub>:Eu
  <sup>2+</sup> (M = Ca, Sr, and Ba) phosphors revealed that the increased compressive strain after N
  <sup>3–</sup> doping induces the enhanced emission intensity of these phosphors. White light-emitting diodes made by three N
  <sup>3–</sup>-doped phosphors and a 365 nm emitting InGaN chip showed the (0.333, 0.373) color coordinate and high color-rendering index (
  <italic>R</italic>
  <sub>a</sub> = 83). These phosphor materials may provide a platform for development of new efficient phosphors in solid-state lighting field.
 </p>
</abstract>
