<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Recently the authors [
 <xref rid="B1-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,
 <xref rid="B2-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="B3-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
 <xref rid="B4-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>] have carried out studies on the experimental mechanics determination of displacements and their derivatives at the macro and microscopic scales. Both fields were compared using the concept of representative volume element (RVE). In this paper, basic approaches to continuum mechanics are extended to the sub-nanometric level. Mechanics of materials covers multiple scale problems, depending on the type of the issues that are investigated. At each level exists an RVE that provides answers to posed questions. One very important relationship in the multiscale level analysis is the connection of the macro-analysis with the discontinuous nature of matter. Since the 19th century, efforts have been made to relate the macro-behavior of materials with the interactions between atoms and molecules. It was Augustin Louis Cauchy [
 <xref rid="B5-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>] the first author that introduced a mathematical model connecting the behavior of solids with their atomic structure. This initial analysis of the relationship between the continuum assumption and the discontinuous nature of solids is currently known as Cauchy-Born rule [
 <xref rid="B6-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. In the current form, the Cauchy-Born rule states that for small strains the position of atoms in a deformed crystalline medium can be predicted by the kinematics and dynamics of continuum mechanics in the range of small deformations and rotations. As it is going to be shown later on in this paper, the analysis of the relationship between atom positions and continuum displacement fields can be handled by extending Cauchy-Born rule from the small rotations and deformations to the range of deformations and rotations observed in crystalline metals. A very important role in this development is the concept of dislocation. Interestingly, this concept was introduced from a purely mathematical point of view, analyzing the unicity of the displacement function in the kinematics of the continuum. Volterra [
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>] in 1907 introduced the concept of dislocation, and later it was extended by Somigliana [
 <xref rid="B8-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>] and Love [
 <xref rid="B9-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. Volterra developed a geometrical type of dislocation that today is utilized in the mechanics of fracture, mode 1 utilized fracture mechanics. This abstract mathematical concept was adopted in the field of mechanics of materials to explain discrepancies between theoretical predictions and experimental measurements of the strength of crystals, by Taylor [
 <xref rid="B10-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>], Orowan [
 <xref rid="B11-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>], Polanyi [
 <xref rid="B12-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>] and Nabarro [
 <xref rid="B13-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]. A new discipline was thus developed [
 <xref rid="B14-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>], the mathematical theory of dislocations that analyzes the interactions of the inner components of matter in the processes of deformation beyond the kinematics of small deformations and rotations of continuum mechanics. A considerable amount of literature has been developed to deal with the relationship between the discrete nature of matter and the continuum approach [
 <xref rid="B15-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="B16-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
 <xref rid="B17-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
 <xref rid="B18-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>,
 <xref rid="B19-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="B20-materials-12-01804" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>].
</p>
