<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Thus, the aqueous SnO
 <sub>2</sub> QD solution was acquired after the completion of hydrolysis and oxidation. The grain size and Zeta potential of the SnO
 <sub>2</sub> QDs were analyzed by dynamic light scattering (DLS, Malvern Zetasizer Nano ZS 90, Malvern panalytical Ltd., Malvern, UK). The morphology was observed by high resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM, JEM-3200FS, JEOL, Tokyo, Japan). The solution was dried to powder for X-ray diffraction (XRD, Rigaku D/MAX-Ultima, Rigaku, Tokyo, Japan) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS, Thermo Scientific ESCALAB 250 XI, ThermoFisher Scientific, Waltham, MA, USA). A fluorescence spectrometer (FLS-980, Edinburgh Instruments, Edinburgh, UK) was used to characterize the fluorescence performances of the SnO
 <sub>2</sub> QDs. The wavelength of excitation in fluorescence characterization was 280 nm. The SnO
 <sub>2</sub> QD solution was diluted to 0.002 mol/L of Sn atoms and it was incorporated with heavy metal ions of Cd
 <sup>2+</sup>, Fe
 <sup>3+</sup>, Ni
 <sup>2+</sup> as well as Pb
 <sup>2+</sup>. The fluorescence response (
 <italic>S</italic>) was defined as the ratio of the maximum intensity of SnO
 <sub>2</sub> QDs (
 <italic>F</italic>
 <sub>0</sub>) to the one of SnO
 <sub>2</sub> QDs with heavy metal ion incorporation (
 <italic>F</italic>), as 
 <italic>S</italic> = 
 <italic>F</italic>
 <sub>0</sub>/
 <italic>F</italic>. The characterization of fluorescence was carried out immediately after the incorporation. In order to evaluate the applicability of SnO
 <sub>2</sub> QDs in the practical detection of heavy metal ions, several types of background water were employed, namely, deionized water, reclaimed water and sea water. The sea water was collected from Xinghai Bay of Yellow Sea, Dalian, China. There were no Ni
 <sup>2+</sup> ions in the deionized water and reclaimed water. The reclaimed water contained cations of Fe
 <sup>3+</sup> (&lt;0.3 mg/L) and Mn
 <sup>2+</sup> (&lt;0.1 mg/L) as well as several anions (&lt;1.0 mg/L). The main composition of sea water included cations of Na
 <sup>+</sup> (11.04 mg/L), K
 <sup>+</sup> (0.40 mg/L), Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> (0.42 mg/L) and Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> (1.33 mg/L) as well as anions of Cl
 <sup>−</sup> (19.86 mg/L) and SO
 <sub>4</sub>
 <sup>2−</sup> (2.77 mg/L). Ni
 <sup>2+</sup> was not taken into account because it was insignificant compared to other major solutes.
</p>
