<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p class="p">For metal nanoparticles, two regimes are of particular interest, that is, nanocrystals (typically 3 to 100 nm) and nanoclusters (ranging from subnanometer to ~2 nm) (
 <xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">1</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">4</italic>
 </xref>). The transition from nanoclusters to nanocrystals is a central issue in nanoscience (
 <xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">5</italic>
 </xref>). Therefore, the atomic structure determination of metal nanoparticles in the transition size range is of high significance for understanding the evolution from nanoclusters to nanocrystals, as well as the quantum size effect at the atomic level. However, the atomic structure determination is generally very challenging (
 <xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">6</italic>
 </xref>). Beginning in 2007, when the atomic structure of Au
 <sub class="sub">102</sub>(SR)
 <sub class="sub">44</sub> (where SR = thiol) was resolved (
 <xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">7</italic>
 </xref>), more than a dozen metal nanoclusters have been structurally solved (
 <xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">8</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">15</italic>
 </xref>); however, the structures of metal nanoclusters in the transition region have rarely been reported (
 <xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">16</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">18</italic>
 </xref>). In particular, the real structure of Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub>(SR)
 <sub class="sub">60</sub> has long remained mysterious (
 <xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">19</italic>
 </xref>). Although nanoclusters of larger or smaller sizes than Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub>(SR)
 <sub class="sub">60</sub> have been structurally solved by x-ray crystallography (XRC), the structure of Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub>(SR)
 <sub class="sub">60</sub> remains undetermined by XRC since precise determination of its formula by electrospray ionization mass spectrometry (ESI-MS) nearly a decade ago (
 <xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">20</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">22</italic>
 </xref>). Efforts to elucidate the structure of Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub>(SR)
 <sub class="sub">60</sub> have continued over the past decade. In 2009, Lopez-Acevedo 
 <italic class="italic">et al</italic>. (
 <xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">23</italic>
 </xref>) proposed a structural model based on density functional theory (DFT) simulations, which was backed up by the subsequent x-ray absorption spectroscopic analysis by MacDonald 
 <italic class="italic">et al</italic>. (
 <xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">24</italic>
 </xref>) and Yamazoe 
 <italic class="italic">et al</italic>. (
 <xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">25</italic>
 </xref>), nuclear magnetic resonance by Wong 
 <italic class="italic">et al</italic>. (
 <xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">26</italic>
 </xref>), and scanning transmission electron microscopy studies by Bahena 
 <italic class="italic">et al</italic>. (
 <xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">27</italic>
 </xref>). The proposed symmetric structure indicated that the nanoparticle should not be difficult to crystallize. Several groups acquired crystals of Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub> nanoparticles with various ligands, including phenylethanethiolate (PET; -SC
 <sub class="sub">2</sub>H
 <sub class="sub">4</sub>Ph) and para-mercaptobenzoic acid (
 <italic class="italic">p</italic>-MBA) (
 <xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">28</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">29</italic>
 </xref>). Koivisto 
 <italic class="italic">et al</italic>. (
 <xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">28</italic>
 </xref>) even observed strong diffraction patterns by small-angle x-ray diffraction (XRD), although they failed to do so by large-angle XRD, indicating that they obtained crystals with orientational disorders of the nanoparticles. Evidence of the disorder in the PET ligand layer of the nanoparticles was also observed in infrared (IR) spectroscopy analysis (
 <xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">28</italic>
 </xref>).
</p>
