<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p class="p">Despite tremendous efforts devoted to the crystal growth of Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub>(SR)
 <sub class="sub">60</sub> nanoparticles, it has long been questionable whether fine crystals of sufficient quality for XRC analysis could be obtained. On the basis of the previous work, we rationalize that the intra- and interparticle weak interactions should play critical roles in the crystal growth (
 <xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">18</italic>
 </xref>). On one hand, the intraparticle interactions lead to the assembled ligands on the surface of the nanoparticle and restrict the motion of the ligands; on the other hand, the interparticle interactions facilitate the ordered arrangement (assembly) of the nanoparticles and reduce the movement of the nanoparticles in the crystal. To make adequate intra- and interparticle weak interactions, the nature of the ligand, especially the rigidity, should be carefully considered. For example, too much flexibility in the ligands may lead to incompact intra- and interparticle interactions, while too much rigidity in the ligands may inhibit the formation of some intra- and interparticle interactions. This may at least partly explain why high-quality single crystals are difficult to obtain when Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub> is protected by either flexible PET or rigid 
 <italic class="italic">p</italic>-MBA (
 <xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">28</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">29</italic>
 </xref>). Therefore, we conclude that a ligand with rigidity falling between the flexible PET and the rigid 
 <italic class="italic">p</italic>-MBA may be a resolution of the major problem that high-quality single crystals of Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub>(SR)
 <sub class="sub">60</sub> have been difficult to produce for a decade. In this work, using PhCH
 <sub class="sub">2</sub>SH as the protecting ligand, we have now successfully grown single crystals of Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub>(SR)
 <sub class="sub">60</sub> and determined its structure by XRC, which confirms the “compact” and “adequate” intra- and inter-nanoparticle weak interactions as described above. Notably, other factors such as the purification of the product by preparative thin-layer chromatography (PTLC) (
 <xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr" class="xref">
  <italic class="italic">30</italic>
 </xref>) and the selection of suitable conditions for crystal growth also contributed to the successful production of single crystals of Au
 <sub class="sub">144</sub>(SR)
 <sub class="sub">60</sub>.
</p>
