<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par24">HP-RT XRD experiments to 21 GPa were carried out in a gas-membrane-driven diamond-anvil cell (DAC) equipped with diamonds of 350 µm of culet diameter. The tilleyite sample was placed together with two ruby chips at the center of a 100 µm diameter 40 µm thick pressure chamber drilled in a preindented rhenium gasket. High-purity Ne gas was also loaded in the DAC at room temperature using the Sanchez Technologies gas loading apparatus. Ne is fluid up to 4.7 GPa and acted as a quasi-hydrostatic medium in the pressure range of the study
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>
 </sup>. Pressure was determined using the ruby fluorescence method
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>
 </sup>, which provided pressure accuracies of 0.1 GPa below 14 GPa and 0.2 GPa up to 23 GPa. The equation of state of Ne was used as a second pressure gauge
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>
 </sup> above 5 GPa. 
 <italic>In situ</italic> angle-dispersive powder X-ray diffraction measurements were carried out at MSPD beamline at ALBA-CELLS synchrotron using a x-ray wavelength of 0.534 Å (Rh K edge)
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>
 </sup>. This beamline provides a X-ray beam focused down to ~20 × 20 µm
 <sup>2</sup>, and the diffracted signal was collected with a Rayonix CCD detector. The detector parameters were calibrated with LaB
 <sub>6</sub> powder standard, and integration to conventional 2
 <italic>θ</italic>-intensity data was carried out with the Dioptas software
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>
 </sup>. The indexing and refinement of the powder patterns were performed using the Chekcell
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>
 </sup>, Unitcell
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>
 </sup> and Powdercell
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>
 </sup> program packages.
</p>
