<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The carrier propagation of polyethylene in the high field strength region is a process from the limitation of body effect to the limitation of electrode effect. There are many interactions of conductive mechanisms [
 <xref rid="B10-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>], which cannot be fitted by a single conductive mechanism [
 <xref rid="B7-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="B21-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
 <xref rid="B32-materials-12-02657" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. It can be seen from 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-02657-f007">Figure 7</xref> that the current characteristics of the four different density polyethylenes in the high field strength region are not dominated by the space charge limiting current. If polyethylene is synergistically acted by a variety of conductance mechanisms in the high field strength region (non-ohmic region), for the two carrier propagation processes (Schottky effect or Poole–Frenkel effect) in the high field strength in 
 <xref ref-type="sec" rid="sec4dot2-materials-12-02657">Section 4.2</xref>, the distribution in the ln
 <italic>j</italic>-
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sup>1/2</sup> coordinate system may have no obvious law. However, if a certain conductivity mechanism plays a dominant role in a fixed temperature range and a certain field strength, the corresponding data in the range will exhibit a linear distribution in the ln
 <italic>j</italic>-
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sup>1/2</sup> coordinate system. In order to verify the above reasoning, the data of the four different density polyethylenes in the high field strength region (non-ohmic region) are plotted in the ln
 <italic>j</italic>-
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sup>1/2</sup> coordinate system, and the Poole–Frenkel effect and Schottky effect are more intuitively reflected. After leading conduction mechanism, conducting segmentation fitting of the image, and setting polyethylene relative permittivity 
 <italic>ε
  <sub>r</sub>
 </italic> = 2.35, we select the best intercept and compare it in the ln
 <italic>j</italic>-
 <italic>E</italic>
 <sup>1/2</sup> coordinate system when the slope is fixed. The result is shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-02657-f008">Figure 8</xref>.
</p>
