<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig2">
 <label>Fig. 2</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Helical motion of spiral droplets. 
   <bold>a</bold> Two-dimensional projection of the trajectory of a chiral droplet. The chirality of the droplet is expressed as a spiral pattern and the axis of the droplet (indicated by a black arrow) undergoes a precession along its helical trajectory. The data acquisition is done by manual z-tracking. 
   <bold>b</bold> Representation of a left-handed droplet moving along a right-handed helical trajectory. The geometry of the motion is characterized by its radius R and pitch P. 
   <bold>c</bold> Chiral molecules used as dopants to induce a cholesteric liquid crystal. CB15 is an enantiomerically pure chiral molecule. Me-
   <bold>m</bold> and Ph-
   <bold>m</bold> are molecular motors that modify the pitch of the liquid crystal helix and invert its handedness upon illumination. Ph-
   <bold>m</bold> induces larger twists than Me-
   <bold>m</bold>. 
   <bold>d</bold> Complete trajectories for chiral droplets doped with CB15 (left), Me-
   <bold>m</bold> (center), and Ph-
   <bold>m</bold> (right). 
   <bold>e</bold> Evolution of the confinement ratio 
   <italic>N</italic> in time (number of spiral turns on the surface of the droplet), for droplets incorporating chiral dopant CB15 (black square, initial pitch is 1.5 μm), Me-
   <bold>m</bold> (red circles, initial pitch is 4.3 μm) and Ph-
   <bold>m</bold> (blue triangle, initial pitch is 1.6 μm). In the case of Me-
   <bold>m</bold> and Ph-
   <bold>m</bold>, the concentration of dopant increases over time and eventually the droplet becomes isotropic. The solid lines are guides for the eye. The data are ensemble averaged and error bars correspond to the standard deviation. 
   <bold>f</bold> Dependence of radius R (circles) and pitch P (squares) from the chirality confinement 
   <italic>N</italic>. The error bars correspond to standard deviation. The data are ensemble averaged for six droplets doped with CB15
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="41467_2019_13201_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e535" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
