<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Employing CDots as color conversion layers in a WLED configuration is a relatively new concept, since the first discovery of these materials dates back only to 2004 [
 <xref rid="R46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>]. Since then, CDots have been widely studied. For instance, Feng et al. reported on the synthesis of carbon quantum dots for use as single light converters in WLEDs [
 <xref rid="R45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>]. CDots were prepared by a one-step hydrothermal method using glucose and polyethylene glycol 200. It is reported that the WLED showed a superior performance indicated by Commission Internationale de l'Éclairage (CIE) coordinates of (0.32, 0.37) and a CCT of 5584 K. In another study, Joseph et al. reported the synthesis of CDots by the electrochemical exfoliation of graphite [
 <xref rid="R47" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>]. The obtained CDots showed a broad band emission due to their heterogeneity in particle size and surface-functional groups. The authors explored the potential of CDots as UV-to-visible color converters using a 365 nm UV chip and could generate white light with CIE color coordinates of (0.35, 0.37), a CRI of 88 and a CCT of 4802 K. Furthermore, Xie et al. fabricated WLEDs using polymerizable silane‒prefunctionalized carbon dots (Si-CDots) [
 <xref rid="R48" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>]. These green low-cost polymerizable Si-CDots produced by a one-pot electrochemical synthesis have emission peaks located around 541–549 nm. These Si-CDots were used as the color conversion and encapsulation layers of a commercially available GaN blue LED chip. The authors report that the luminous efficacy of radiation (LER) of the resulting Si-CDot WLED is 70.93 lm/W, the CIE coordinates are (0.28, 0.35), and the CRI is 69. In another work, novel nitrogen-doped multiple-core@shell-structured AC-CDots (AC: Aphen and Citric acid) with a tricolor emission comprising red, green, and blue were, for the first time, synthesized via a one-pot hydrothermal approach by Zhang et al. [
 <xref rid="R49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>]. The authors further demonstrated that by combining the blue (430 nm), green (500 nm) and red (630 nm) fluorescence, the AC-CDots can produce a pure white-light emission spectrum. Finally, highly efficient CDot/gel glass, phosphor-based, trichromatic WLEDs were developed by Yuan et al. [
 <xref rid="R50" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>]. The authors doped green and red CDots into a matrix of methyltriethoxysilane and 3-(triethoxysilyl)propylamine, respectively, to prepare the CDot/gel glass. With this strategy, the authors achieved a LER of 71.75 lm W
 <sup>−1</sup> and a CRI of 93. Lastly, red emitting [
 <xref rid="R51" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>] and white emitting Cl-doped CDots have also been reported [
 <xref rid="R52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>].
</p>
