<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <p content-type="toc-graphic">
  <graphic xlink:href="ao9b02727_0017" id="ab-tgr1" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
 </p>
 <p>Binary silicon boride SiB
  <sub>3</sub> has been reported to occur in two forms, as disordered and nonstoichiometric α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub>, which relates to the α-rhombohedral phase of boron, and as strictly ordered and stoichiometric β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub>. Similar to other boron-rich icosahedral solids, these SiB
  <sub>3</sub> phases represent potentially interesting refractory materials. However, their thermal stability, formation conditions, and thermodynamic relation are poorly understood. Here, we map the formation conditions of α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> and β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub> and analyze their relative thermodynamic stabilities. α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> is metastable (with respect to β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub> and Si), and its formation is kinetically driven. Pure polycrystalline bulk samples may be obtained within hours when heating stoichiometric mixtures of elemental silicon and boron at temperatures 1200–1300 °C. At the same time, α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> decomposes into SiB
  <sub>6</sub> and Si, and optimum time-temperature synthesis conditions represent a trade-off between rates of formation and decomposition. The formation of stable β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub> was observed after prolonged treatment (days to weeks) of elemental mixtures with ratios Si/B = 1:1–1:4 at temperatures 1175–1200 °C. The application of high pressures greatly improves the kinetics of SiB
  <sub>3</sub> formation and allows decoupling of SiB
  <sub>3</sub> formation from decomposition. Quantitative formation of β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub> was seen at 1100 °C for samples pressurized to 5.5–8 GPa. β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub> decomposes peritectoidally at temperatures between 1250 and 1300 °C. The highly ordered nature of β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub> is reflected in its Raman spectrum, which features narrow and distinct lines. In contrast, the Raman spectrum of α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> is characterized by broad bands, which show a clear relation to the vibrational modes of isostructural, ordered B
  <sub>6</sub>P. The detailed composition and structural properties of disordered α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> were ascertained by a combination of single-crystal X-ray diffraction and 
  <sup>29</sup>Si magic angle spinning NMR experiments. Notably, the compositions of polycrystalline bulk samples (obtained at 
  <italic>T</italic> ≤ 1200 °C) and single crystal samples (obtained from Si-rich molten Si–B mixtures at 
  <italic>T</italic> &gt; 1400 °C) are different, SiB
  <sub>2.93(7)</sub> and SiB
  <sub>2.64(2)</sub>, respectively. The incorporation of Si in the polar position of B
  <sub>12</sub> icosahedra results in highly strained cluster units. This disorder feature was accounted for in the refined crystal structure model by splitting the polar position into three sites. The electron-precise composition of α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> is SiB
  <sub>2.5</sub> and corresponds to the incorporation of, on average, two Si atoms in each B
  <sub>12</sub> icosahedron. Accordingly, α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> constitutes a mixture of B
  <sub>10</sub>Si
  <sub>2</sub> and B
  <sub>11</sub>Si clusters. The structural and phase stability of α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> were explored using a first-principles cluster expansion. The most stable composition at 0 K is SiB
  <sub>2.5</sub>, which however is unstable with respect to the decomposition β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub> + Si. Modeling of the configurational and vibrational entropies suggests that α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> only becomes more stable than β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub> at temperatures above its decomposition into SiB
  <sub>6</sub> and Si. Hence, we conclude that α-SiB
  <sub>3–
   <italic>x</italic>
  </sub> is metastable at all temperatures. Density functional theory electronic structure calculations yield band gaps of similar size for electron-precise α-SiB
  <sub>2.5</sub> and β-SiB
  <sub>3</sub>, whereas α-SiB
  <sub>3</sub> represents a p-type conductor.
 </p>
</abstract>
