<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The opportunity for modification may persist during the fetal period and even after birth. Semi-landmarks corresponding to the torsion of the femoral neck were moved and located in different positions during the fetal period. These movements might be correlated with ∠FNA, because both semi-landmarks and ∠FNA used the same plane as reference (i.e., the plane passing through the midpoint of the femoral head, femoral neck, and greater trochanter). The angles were various, particularly in samples at the time of ossification. Furthermore, negative anteversion was even observed. The change in anteversion during the fetal period was prominent compared with ∠FNS and ∠OBS in the present study [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. Previous studies have reported variations in anteversion; specifically, the ∠FNA value ranged from -26° to 64° [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>], from 17° to 45° [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref013" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>], and from -14° to 41° [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref014" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. Torsion of the lower leg including the femur (anteversion) was continuously observed during the fetal period and after birth [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref023" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. Torsion of the femur may be prone to be affected by repetitive and persistent mechanical forces and intrauterine position [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref003" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Severe intrauterine compressive forces may result in congenital rotational limb deformities [
 <xref rid="pone.0221569.ref025" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. With respect to mechanical forces, muscle tensions and local forces exert rotary stress on the epiphysis, leading to the development of ∠FNA. Further studies should investigate the detailed mechanism concerning torsion of the femur.
</p>
