<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Yan et al. reported that replacing MA with FA in (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(MA)
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>−1</sub>Pb
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>I
 <sub>3</sub>
 <italic>
  <sub>n</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>+1</sub> perovskites not only effectively reduced the bandgap of the 2D perovskites, but also improved their ambient stability.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0082" ref-type="ref">82</xref> Particularly, the bandgap of (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(FA)
 <sub>2</sub>Pb
 <sub>3</sub>I
 <sub>10</sub> film is only 1.51 eV, which is much smaller than that of (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>(MA)
 <sub>2</sub>Pb
 <sub>3</sub>I
 <sub>10</sub> (1.89 eV)[qv: 15a] and contributes to a good PCE of 6.88%. Quarti et al. proved that the electronic properties of the 2D perovskites were influenced by the length of the organic alkyl chain, and a longer chain led to an increase in the bandgap.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0098" ref-type="ref">98</xref> Theoretical calculation of (C
 <sub>6</sub>H
 <sub>13</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> and (C
 <sub>12</sub>H
 <sub>25</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> indicates that this effect is caused by the distortion of the PbI
 <sub>6</sub> octahedral structure due to the long alkyl chains. So, the size of organic cations plays an important role in adjusting the inorganic layer structure, thus leading to the regulation of the bandgap.[qv: 4b,27b,99] According to a recent report,
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0026" ref-type="ref">26</xref> the length of the alkyl chain between the aromatic ring and the ammonium group, rather than the number of aromatic rings, is vital in the bandgap of 2D perovskites containing aromatic cations (Figure 
 <xref rid="advs1307-fig-0005" ref-type="fig">5</xref>c). In addition to the chain length and dielectric constant of cations discussed earlier, perovskite phase transition can also affect the structure and optical properties. Through in situ high‐pressure XRD, the shift of exciton bandgap of (BA)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> resulted from the change of Pb—I bond length and Pb—I—Pb bond angle derived from the pressure‐induced phase transition has been studied.[qv: 24b] The influence of structure phase transition of (C
 <italic>
  <sub>m</sub>
 </italic>H
 <sub>2</sub>
 <italic>
  <sub>m</sub>
 </italic>
 <sub>+1</sub>NH
 <sub>3</sub>)
 <sub>2</sub>PbI
 <sub>4</sub> (
 <italic>m</italic> = 4, 8, 9, 10, and 12) perovskites on bandgap was also observed between 235 and 310 K.
 <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0078" ref-type="ref">78</xref>
</p>
