<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig fig-type="Figure" xml:lang="en" id="advs1307-fig-0007" orientation="portrait" position="float">
 <label>Figure 7</label>
 <caption>
  <p>a) Absorption (black) and emission (red, excited at 380 nm) spectra for (
   <italic>N</italic>‐MEDA)[PbBr
   <sub>4</sub>]. b) Chromaticity coordinates (CIE) of white light emitters. Inset: photograph of luminescence from powders and solar spectrum (orange) with the visible region shaded in yellow and emission spectra of (
   <italic>N</italic>‐MEDA)[PbBr
   <sub>4</sub>] (red, excited at 380 nm) and (
   <italic>N</italic>‐MEDA)[PbBr
   <sub>3.5</sub>Cl
   <sub>0.5</sub>] (black, excited at 360 nm). Reproduced with permission.
   <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0011" ref-type="ref">11</xref> Copyright 2014, American Chemical Society. c) X‐ray crystal structure of the (110) perovskite (EDBE)PbBr
   <sub>4</sub>, and its emission spanning the entire visible spectrum. Inset: photographs of an (EDBE)PbBr
   <sub>4</sub> crystal. Reproduced with permission.[qv: 111a] Copyright 2014, American Chemical Society. d) Self‐trapping (A), trapping at permanent defects (B), and self‐trapping influenced by permanent defects (C) represented by a ball interacting with a rubber sheet. Reproduced with permission.
   <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0106" ref-type="ref">106</xref> Copyright 2018, American Chemical Society. e) Schematic of the adiabatic potential energy curves of the ground state (G), free‐exciton state (FE), free‐carrier state (FC), and various excited states (STEs) in a configuration space. The horizontal dashed line shows possible nonradiative decay processes of the STEs. Reproduced with permission.[qv: 18a] Copyright 2016, American Chemical Society. f) Normalized absorption (Abs), PL excitation (PLE, monitored at 620 nm), and PL (excited by 365 nm) spectra of (OAm)
   <sub>2</sub>SnBr
   <sub>4</sub> perovskite film. Inset: photograph of the colloidal suspension of (OAm)
   <sub>2</sub>SnBr
   <sub>4</sub> perovskites under UV light. Reproduced with permission.
   <xref rid="advs1307-bib-0056" ref-type="ref">56</xref> Copyright 2019, American Chemical Society.
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic id="nlm-graphic-21" xlink:href="ADVS-6-1900941-g007" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
