<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par7">However, so far no one has presented a stand-alone orientation map based on Raman scattering, due to several experimental and theoretical problems. In particular, polarized Raman experiments have so far been carried out by rotating the sample or rotating a set of wave plates in the incident laser or on scattered beams in the Raman setup
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>
 </sup>. Such optical layouts require multiple Raman spectra measurements using numerous combinations of the orientation of the polarization state of the incident laser and orientation of the analyzer
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>
 </sup>. Due to this, Raman orientation mapping would need sequential polarization measurements at each raster-scanning point, which would make such hypothetical mapping procedures very complex and extremely slow and thus practically impossible. In addition, existing experimental PRM setups introduce ambiguities in measurements, implying that the approach fails completely for some orientations. As an example, in a scheme with normal sample illumination and on-axis collection of scattered light, it is impossible to determine a rotation of a (111) Si wafer around the [111] axis (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>, Supplementary Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>, Supplementary Note 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>). Such problem can be partially avoided by tilting the sample or by realization of polarized off-axis Raman scattering registration
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>
 </sup> (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref>). However, as we show below, polarized Raman spectroscopy with off-axis registration also provides ambiguities in the determination of Euler angles, thus some combination of on-axis and off-axis channels must be used. To our knowledge, a theoretical investigation of the optimal number of on-axis/off-axis polarized Raman scattering channels in PRM has not been performed. Therefore, a measurement strategy for how to perform quantitative orientation mapping with an angular accuracy comparable with EBSD needs to be developed.
</p>
