<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The elemental ratios of the NC powders were measured using an XRF analyzer (ZSXmini II, Rigaku). Powder XRD profiles were obtained using an X-ray diffractometer (Rint-2200, Rigaku) with a Cu Kα radiation source and monochromator. The NC morphologies were observed by field-emission TEM (Tecnai G
 <sup>2</sup>, FEI). The TEM samples were prepared by vacuum drying a drop of a NC dispersion on carbon-reinforced collodion-coated copper grids (COL-C10, Oken Shoji) overnight. The EDX was performed on the same apparatus. FT-IR absorption spectra of the samples in KBr disks were recorded on an FT-IR spectrometer (FT/IR-4200, JASCO). UV–vis absorption spectra of the NC dispersions were measured using an optical absorption spectrometer (V-570, JASCO). The PL spectra of the NC dispersions were measured using a fluorescence spectrometer (FP-6500, JASCO). Each spectral response was calibrated using an ethylene glycol solution of rhodamine B (5.5 g L
 <sup>–1</sup>) and a standard light source (ESC-333, JASCO). Absolute PLQYs were measured using a quantum efficiency measurement system (QE-2000-311C, Otsuka Electronics). The PL decay curves were recorded on a fluorescence lifetime spectrometer (Quantaurus-Tau C11367, Hamamatsu Photonics). Herein, the PL decay curves were fitted with the following biexponential function
 <disp-formula id="eq4">
  <graphic xlink:href="ao9b01858_m004" position="anchor" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  <label>4</label>
 </disp-formula>where 
 <italic>t</italic> is time, 
 <italic>A</italic>
 <sub>1</sub> and 
 <italic>A</italic>
 <sub>2</sub> are the amplitudes, and τ
 <sub>1</sub> and τ
 <sub>2</sub> are the PL decay times. The average PL lifetime &lt;τ&gt; was calculated using 
 <xref rid="eq5" ref-type="disp-formula">eq 
  <xref rid="eq5" ref-type="disp-formula">5</xref>
 </xref>.
 <disp-formula id="eq5">
  <graphic xlink:href="ao9b01858_m005" position="anchor" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
  <label>5</label>
 </disp-formula>
</p>
