<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Ferroelectric materials have a spontaneous electric dipole moment, i.e., polarization, even in the absence of an external electric field. This spontaneous electric dipole moment can be repeatedly transitioned between two or more energetically equivalent states or directions upon application of an external electric field that breaks the degeneracy and forms the fundamental underpinning of numerous technological applications of ferroelectric materials (
 <xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>1</italic>
 </xref>). For piezoelectricity, noncentrosymmetric crystal structure is the only requirement (
 <xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>2</italic>
 </xref>). In contrast, for a polar material, not only must the crystal structure be noncentrosymmetric but also there should exist a unique polar axis. For a material to be considered a ferroelectric, it needs both to be polar and to show bistability of the polarization along the polar axis (
 <xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>2</italic>
 </xref>). Conventionally, ferroelectricity has often been associated with and observed in materials that are insulating or semiconducting rather than metallic because conduction electrons in metals screen out the static internal fields arising from a long-range dipolar order. In the 1960s, Anderson and Blount (
 <xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>3</italic>
 </xref>) proposed a new class of materials with these seemingly incompatible characteristics, i.e., metals with a polar axis and an inversion asymmetric crystal structure termed “ferroelectric metals.” Since then, an experimental demonstration of this concept for a room-temperature single-phase material has remained elusive. Metallic systems undergoing a centrosymmetric-to-noncentrosymmetric structural transition have been observed recently, e.g., in LiOsO
 <sub>3</sub> at 140 K (
 <xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>4</italic>
 </xref>) and Cd
 <sub>2</sub>Re
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> at 200 K (
 <xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>5</italic>
 </xref>), hinting at the possibility of sustaining ferroelectricity in a metal at room temperature. More progress has been made lately with a study (
 <xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>6</italic>
 </xref>) reporting on the observation of polar domains and strain-induced ferroelastic switching in bulk polar metal Ca
 <sub>3</sub>Ru
 <sub>2</sub>O
 <sub>7</sub> at room temperature. Another strategy that has also been commonly used, besides investigating metallic systems with a noncentrosymmetric crystal structure (
 <xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>7</italic>
 </xref>), is to dope well-established ferroelectric materials, such as BaTiO
 <sub>3-δ</sub> (
 <xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>8</italic>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>9</italic>
 </xref>) and Nb-doped PbTiO
 <sub>3</sub> (
 <xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>10</italic>
 </xref>). However, the ferroelectric instability weakens with increasing electronic density in these systems and will eventually be destroyed above a certain critical density (
 <xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>11</italic>
 </xref>). Furthermore, it is not clear that the ferroelectricity and metallicity coexist in a single phase in these materials (
 <xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>12</italic>
 </xref>), as other studies suggest a nanoscale phase separation into separate metallic and ferroelectric phases (
 <xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>13</italic>
 </xref>). Another approach to obtaining a ferroelectric metal has been to engineer interface-based polar metals in oxide heterostructures (
 <xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>14</italic>
 </xref>–
 <xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>16</italic>
 </xref>). Despite these investigations, the experimental realization of a native metal with bistable and electrically switchable spontaneous polarization states, the hallmark of ferroelectricity, is yet to be demonstrated. During the submission process of this manuscript, we became aware of a closely related work (
 <xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>17</italic>
 </xref>), in which ferroelectric switching has been demonstrated in device structures through electrical transport measurements for bilayer and trilayer WTe
 <sub>2</sub>. Fei 
 <italic>et al</italic>. (
 <xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">
  <italic>17</italic>
 </xref>) quantify and establish the temperature dependence of the polarization. However, a natural question arises as to whether ferroelectricity persists to samples thicker than three layers, or even to bulk crystals, and whether ferroelectric domains can be formed.
</p>
