<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Aluminized steels have received increasing attention in recent years, because of their excellent resistance to corrosion and oxidation at high temperatures as well as high optical reflectivity, leading to good design properties. They have been widely used in fields such as automobile exhaust systems, household appliances, and building materials in severe environments that Zn-coated steels cannot tolerate [
 <xref rid="CIT0001">1</xref>–
 <xref rid="CIT0006">6</xref>]. The global depletion of Zn resource has also driven the transition from Zn- to Al-coated steels [
 <xref rid="CIT0007">7</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0008">8</xref>]. Hot-dip aluminized steels are produced by immersing steel strips into a molten Al or Al-Si bath, followed by heat treatment to alloy the Al coating over the Fe substrate through thermal diffusion. A thin aluminum oxide layer formed on top of the coating is believed to act as a diffusion and thermal barrier, enhancing the corrosion and thermal resistance [
 <xref rid="CIT0002">2</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0003">3</xref>]. Below the aluminum oxide layer, the brittle intermetallic compound η-Fe
 <sub>2</sub>Al
 <sub>5</sub> forms as the major phase in the reaction layer, especially when the molten bath is pure Al, exhibiting a columnar texture elongated along its orthorhombic [001] direction [
 <xref rid="CIT0009">9</xref>–
 <xref rid="CIT0011">11</xref>]. Therefore, the η-Fe
 <sub>2</sub>Al
 <sub>5</sub> phase is expected to play a decisive role in determining the mechanical and other properties of hot-dip aluminized steels [
 <xref rid="CIT0012">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0013">13</xref>]. Furthermore, the η-Fe
 <sub>2</sub>Al
 <sub>5</sub> phase is also known to act as an inhibition layer during the galvanizing/galvannealing process to suppress the excessively rapid reaction of the Zn coating with the Fe substrate [
 <xref rid="CIT0014">14</xref>]. Thus, understanding the structural [
 <xref rid="CIT0011">11</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0015">15</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0016">16</xref>], thermodynamic [
 <xref rid="CIT0017">17</xref>–
 <xref rid="CIT0021">21</xref>], and mechanical [
 <xref rid="CIT0009">9</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0012">12</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0013">13</xref>] properties of η-Fe
 <sub>2</sub>Al
 <sub>5</sub> is indispensable for the development of Al- and Zn-coated steels.
</p>
