<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>According to Burkhardt et al. [
 <xref rid="CIT0015">15</xref>], the crystal structure of η-Fe
 <sub>2</sub>Al
 <sub>5</sub> belongs to the orthorhombic space group 
 <italic>Cmcm</italic>, consisting of an FeAl
 <sub>2</sub> framework structure (Fe and Al1 sites with full occupancies) and a chain of six Al sites with partial occupancies (0.32 and 0.24 for Al2 and Al3 sites, respectively) along the orthorhombic 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis (
 <xref rid="F0001">Figure 1</xref>). The relatively wide solid solubility range (Al-27 to 31 at.% Fe) reported for the η phase [
 <xref rid="CIT0019">19</xref>–
 <xref rid="CIT0021">21</xref>] is usually assumed to be realized by varying Al occupancies in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites. However, Becker et al. [
 <xref rid="CIT0022">22</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>] have recently reported that not only Al but also Fe atoms occupy the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites in the η phase with Fe-rich compositions, suggesting that the number density of atoms in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain does not depend much on the alloy composition in the solubility range, unlike the expectation from the crystal structure model by Burkhardt et al. [
 <xref rid="CIT0015">15</xref>]. Very recently, a few research groups including ours have independently found that there are several different low-temperature phases having crystal structures based on the η phase, with the Al/Fe atoms arranged in ordered manners in the orthorhombic 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain [
 <xref rid="CIT0022">22</xref>–
 <xref rid="CIT0024">24</xref>]. On the Al-rich side of the solubility range (~Al-27.3 at.%Fe), Al atoms in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain are arranged in an ordered manner to form a new phase (η′-Fe
 <sub>3</sub>Al
 <sub>8</sub>) with a tripled superlattice structure based on the parent η structure [
 <xref rid="CIT0024">24</xref>]. We have found that in the η′ phase, one-third of the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites corresponding to the Al3 sites in the η phase are occupied exclusively by Al atoms, while those corresponding to the Al2 sites are completely vacant. As a result, a total of two-ninths of the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain sites are occupied in an ordered manner [
 <xref rid="CIT0024">24</xref>]. Becker et al. [
 <xref rid="CIT0022">22</xref>,
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>] have reported, on the other hand, that when the alloy composition is on the Fe-rich side of the solubility range (~Al-29.4 at.%Fe), Al and Fe atoms in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain are arranged in an ordered manner to form another low-temperature phase (η″) [
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>]. Those authors believed that the η″ phase has an incommensurately modulated crystal structure of long periodicity along the orthorhombic 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis [
 <xref rid="CIT0023">23</xref>]. However, neither the occupation behavior of the Fe and Al atoms in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain (i.e. their fractions at each of the Al2 and Al3 sites) nor the origin of the incommensurability/modulation was clarified. It is of particular interest to know the preferential sites for Fe/Al atoms and the manner of their ordered arrangement in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain (if any), in view of the established principle for Al atoms in the 
 <italic>c</italic>-axis chain in the η′ phase on the Al-rich side of the solubility range [
 <xref rid="CIT0024">24</xref>].
</p>
