<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The Z-axis density distribution curves of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> in the montmorillonite layers with different layer charge characteristics are shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-12-02318-f003">Figure 3</xref>. From the figure we can find that the Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> in the interlayer were mainly concentrated in the range of −1.5 Å ~ +1.5 Å along the central axis of the montmorillonite. The change in the charge position in montmorillonite had a certain influence on the distribution of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> in the interlayer. When the layer charge as derived from aluminum-substituted silicon in the octahedron, such as Mi
 <sub>6-0</sub>, the Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> in the layers mainly showed a single peak and were concentrated in the range of −1.5 Å ~ +1.5 Å in the interlayer domain. In addition, the different charge densities of the montmorillonite had little difference in the Z-axis density distribution of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup>, indicating that the layer charge negative potential in the octahedron had little effect on the distribution characteristics of interlayer Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> because of the long-range spatial effect. As the amount of Mg
 <sup>2+</sup> substituted Al
 <sup>3+</sup> in the tetrahedron increases, the amount of Al
 <sup>3+</sup> substituted Si
 <sup>4+</sup> in the corresponding octahedron decreases, the Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> will shift toward the siloxane surface on both sides in the interlayers, and the Z-axis density distribution of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> will show a bimodal or trimodal distribution. The phenomenon was more pronounced in the high-charged montmorillonite such as M2, M3, and M4. Due to the short-term effect of space, the Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> was closer to the negative charge position in the tetrahedron in the interlayer, as part of the Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> were subjected to a large electrostatic attraction and moved toward the tetrahedron, so the Z-axis distribution of Ca
 <sup>2+</sup> exhibited a multi-peak distribution.
</p>
